<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 2-5-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Plant genetic resources&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are sourced from officially appointed National Focal Points (NFP) (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/agriculture/crops/thematic-sitemap/theme/seeds-pgr/gpa/national-focal-points/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/agriculture/crops/thematic-sitemap/theme/seeds-pgr/gpa/national-focal-points/en/&lt;/a&gt;) and regional and international agricultural research centres holding PGRFA &lt;em&gt;ex situ&lt;/em&gt; collections. Data providers report either (i) directly to FAO by using the spreadsheet contained in document List of descriptors for reporting on the Plant Component of SDG indicator 2.5.1 (see References) accessible from the WIEWS home page (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/wiews&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/wiews&lt;/a&gt;) or (ii) through published information systems which comply with the standard of the FAO/Bioversity Multi-crop Passport Descriptor List (MCPD) v. 2 (see References), e.g. EURISCO (&lt;a href=&quot;http://eurisco.ipk-gatersleben.de/&quot;&gt;http://eurisco.ipk-gatersleben.de/&lt;/a&gt;) and Genesys (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.genesys-pgr.org&quot;&gt;https://www.genesys-pgr.org&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are stored in the World Information and Early Warning System for plant genetic resources for food and agriculture (WIEWS - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/wiews&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/wiews&lt;/a&gt;), the FAO platform established to facilitate information exchange as well as periodic assessments of the state of the world&amp;#x2019;s plant genetic resources for food and agriculture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Animal genetic resources&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National Coordinators for Management of Animal Genetic Resources, nominated by their respective government, provide data to the Domestic Animal Diversity Information System (DAD-IS) (&lt;a href=&quot;http://dad.fao.org&quot;&gt;http://dad.fao.org&lt;/a&gt;). DAD-IS allows countries the storage of data on animal genetic resources being secured in either medium or long term conservation facilities as needed for the indicator.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
