<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 10-7-3, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;Data on deaths during migration are fragmented, incomplete and scattered among many different sources. The MMP database provides a global overview of data on migrant fatalities, but it is primarily dependent on secondary sources of information. Information is gathered from diverse sources such as official records &amp;#x2013; including from coast guards and medical examiners &amp;#x2013; and other sources such as media reports, non-governmental organizations (NGOs), and surveys and interviews of migrants. The reliability and completeness of data vary greatly from region to region, from country to country and over time. In addition to undercounting the absolute number of deaths which occur during migration, MMP data also lack identifying information in many cases (incl. age, gender, country of origin) which are vital to providing closure to families searching for loved ones lost during migration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#_Table_1:_Missing&quot;&gt;Table 1&lt;/a&gt; illustrates the wide variety of sources used in the MMP database, and gives some insight into the various advantages and disadvantages of each. For example, some of the data are collected directly from migrants who have survived a deadly incident, typically via NGO/humanitarian actors or surveys of migrants. Eyewitness testimonies are often the only source of information about migrant deaths, especially those which occur on remote routes or in the many areas of the world where no official data on deaths during migration is collected. However, eyewitness testimonies are nearly impossible to verify on remote routes, and there is a small risk of double-counting if migrants report the same incident when asked whether they are aware of a death or disappearance. Data from surveys are similarly invaluable due to the dearth of data on this topic, but are not representative as they typically capture only a small fraction of the total number of people on the move who may have witnessed a death. Similarly, media reports often provide information on migrant deaths that are not available from official sources, but may offer limited or even conflicting information, especially as the investigation and identification of bodies may occur after an initial report. As no State currently produces national-level data on deaths during migration (neither within their own territory nor of their nationals abroad) MMP data only represents documented, verified incidents and is best considered a very conservative estimate of the true number of lives lost during migration.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
