<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 16-1-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering data collected by both UNODC and WHO, national data on homicide are available for most Member States. However, data availability is lower in Africa, Asia and the Pacific and Western Asia than in the Americas and Europe. Furthermore, data availability for crucial disaggregations (by sex, or victim-perpetrator relationship) is more limited than for total homicide counts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1990-present day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommended disaggregation for this indicator are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- sex and age of the victim and the perpetrator (suspected offender)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- relationship between victim and perpetrator (intimate partner, other family member, acquaintance, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- means of perpetration (firearm, sharp object, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- situational context/motivation (organized crime, inter-personal violence, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tables III, IV and V of the International Classification of Crime for Statistical Purposes contains more information on these disaggregations, including definitions for each of the categories.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teniendo en cuenta los datos recogidos tanto por la ONUDD como por la OMS, se dispone de datos nacionales sobre homicidios para 174 países (al menos una observación entre 2009-2013). Se dispone de datos de series temporales sobre homicidios adecuados para el seguimiento para 141 países (al menos 3 observaciones, el más reciente entre 2011-2013).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Series de tiempo&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2010-2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La desagregación recomendada para este indicador es:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sexo y edad de la víctima y del autor (presunto delincuente)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;relación entre la víctima y el agresor (pareja, otro miembro de la familia, conocido, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;medio de perpetración (arma de fuego, objeto contundente, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;contexto situacional/motivación (crimen organizado, violencia de pareja, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt;Доступность данных&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Описание:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;С учетом данных, собираемых как УНП ООН, так и ВОЗ, национальные данные по убийствам доступны по 174 странам (по крайней мере, один элемент данных за период 2009-2013 годов). Данные временных рядов по убийствам, пригодные для мониторинга, доступны по 141 стране (имеются, по крайней мере, 3 элемента данных, самые последние - за период с 2011 по 2013 год).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Временные ряды&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2010-2014 годы &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Дезагрегирование:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Рекомендуемое дезагрегирование для этого показателя::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;пол и возраст потерпевшего и преступника (подозреваемого)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;отношения между жертвой и преступником (интимный партнер, другой член семьи,
знакомый и т. д.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;средство совершения преступления (огнестрельное оружие, тупой предмет и т.
д.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ситуационный контекст / мотивация (организованная преступность, насилие со
стороны интимного партнера и т. д.)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
