<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 16-1-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The indicator is calculated as the total number of victims of intentional homicide recorded in a given year divided by the total resident population in the same year, multiplied by 100,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;100&lt;/mn&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;,&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;000&lt;/mn&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;*&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;V&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;m&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;P&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the rate by sex, the number of victims of that sex should be divided by the population of the same sex. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In several countries, two separate sets of data on intentional homicide are produced, respectively from criminal justice and public health/civil registration systems. When existing, figures from both data sources are reported. Population data are derived from annual estimates produced by the UN Population Division.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In cases where data on intentional homicide victims are not available, the number of intentional homicide offences, that is the number of incidents involving one or more victims recorded by the police, can be used as a proxy.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador se calcula como el número total de víctimas de homicidio intencional registradas en un año determinado, dividido por la población total residente en el mismo año, multiplicado por 100.000.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;En varios países se producen dos conjuntos de datos separados sobre el homicidio intencional, respectivamente, a partir de la justicia penal y la salud pública/el registro civil. Cuando existen, se reportan las cifras de ambas fuentes de datos. Los datos de población proceden de las estimaciones anuales elaboradas por la División de Población de las Naciones Unidas.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель рассчитывается как общее число жертв преднамеренных убийств, зарегистрированных в данном году, деленное на общую численность постоянного населения в том же году, умноженное на 100 000. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В некоторых странах разрабатываются два отдельных набора данных об умышленных убийствах, которые подготавливаются соответственно системами уголовного правосудия и общественного здравоохранения / регистрации актов гражданского состояния. При их наличии представляется информация из обоих источников данных. Данные по населению получаются из годовых оценок, подготавливаемых Отделом народонаселения ООН. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
