<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REG_AGG field for indicator 16-1-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The method used for estimating the number of victims of intentional homicides at the global and regional level aims to make the best possible use of available data. For each regional aggregate, the number of victims of intentional homicides should correspond to the sum of all national data of such killings in the region, in each year. However, for many countries, data on intentional homicides are not available, or data are available only for some years. As a result, the sample of countries with available data is different for each year. If left unaddressed, this issue would result in inconsistencies, as regional aggregates would be drawn from a different set of countries each year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imputations for intentional homicides victims are performed on the country-level rate of intentional homicide victims per 100,000 population. If a country has just one available data point since the year 2000, all missing values are set equal to this single available data point. This approach therefore accounts for population growth over time and does not mean that the series is constant in absolute terms. If a country has two to eight available data points, the missing values between two data points are estimated by linear interpolation, and if there are missing values that are temporally before (or after) the earliest (or latest) available data point, the values at the beginning (or end) of the series are filled with the earliest (or latest) available data point. If a country has more than eight available data points in the respective time series, the missing values between two data points are estimated by linear interpolation, and if there are missing values that are temporally before (or after) the earliest (or latest) available data point, the values at the end of the time series are imputed using an exponential smoothing approach (for more information, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://afit-r.github.io/ts_exp_smoothing&quot;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt;). Finally, the regional rate is applied to countries without any data point &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the series have been imputed at the national level, they are aggregated at the regional level. Regional homicide totals are calculated for each year by multiplying the regional homicide rate per 100,000 population with the total population of the respective region (divided by 100,000). The regions are the ones from the United Nations &amp;#x201C;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/methodology/m49/&quot;&gt;Standard Country or Area Codes for Statistical Use&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#x201D;. Each country or area is included in one region only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, regional estimates are aggregated to compute the global number of intentional homicides. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las estimaciones globales y regionales se calculan como medias ponderadas de los datos nacionales, con ponderaciones proporcionadas por la población nacional resident.e&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Региональные агрегаты: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Глобальные и региональные оценки рассчитываются как средневзвешенные национальные данные, где вес определяется количеством постоянного населения страны. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
