<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 16-1-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is defined as the total count of victims of intentional homicide divided by the total population, expressed per 100,000 population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intentional homicide is defined as the unlawful death inflicted upon a person with the intent to cause death or serious injury (Source: International Classification of Crime for Statistical Purposes, ICCS 2015); population refers to total resident population in a given country in a given year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the ICCS intentional homicide is defined as the &amp;#x2018;&amp;#x2018;Unlawful death inflicted upon a person with the intent to cause death or serious injury&amp;#x201D;. This definition contains three elements characterizing the killing of a person as intentional homicide:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. The killing of a person by another person (objective element);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. The intent of the perpetrator to kill or seriously injure the victim (subjective element);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. The unlawfulness of the killing, which means that the law considers the perpetrator liable for the unlawful death (legal element).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This definition states that, for statistical purposes, all killings corresponding to the three criteria above should be considered as intentional homicides, irrespective of definitions provided by national legislations or practices.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definición:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador se define como el recuento total de víctimas de homicidio doloso dividido por la población total, expresado por cada 100.000 habitantes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El homicidio intencional se define como la muerte ilegal infligida a una persona con la intención de causar la muerte o lesiones graves (Fuente: Clasificación Internacional del Delito con Fines Estadísticos, ICCS 2015); la población se refiere a la población total residente en un país determinado en un año determinado.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En la ICCS el homicidio intencional se define como la &amp;#x2018;&amp;#x2018;Muerte ilegal infligida a una persona con la intención de causar la muerte o lesiones graves&amp;#x201D;. Esta definición contiene tres elementos que caracterizan el asesinato de una persona como homicidio intencional:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;El asesinato de una persona por otra persona (elemento objetivo);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La intención del autor de matar o herir gravemente a la víctima (elemento subjetivo);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La ilicitud del asesinato, lo que significa que la ley considera que el autor es responsable de la muerte ilícita (elemento legal).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Esta definición establece que, a efectos estadísticos, todos los asesinatos que se ajusten a los tres criterios anteriores deben considerarse homicidios dolosos, con independencia de las definiciones previstas en las legislaciones o prácticas nacionales.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Определение: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель определяется как общее число жертв умышленных убийств, деленное на общее количество населения, в расчете на 100 000 населения.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Преднамеренное убийство определяется как незаконное причинение смерти лицу с намерением вызвать смерть или тяжкие телесные повреждения (Источник: Международная классификация преступлений для статистических целей, МКПС 2015); понятие &quot;население&quot; относится к общей численности постоянного населения в данной стране в данном году.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В МКПС преднамеренное убийство определяется как «незаконное причинение смерти лицу с намерением вызвать смерть или тяжкие телесные повреждения». Это определение содержит три элемента, характеризующих убийство человека как преднамеренное убийство: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Убийство человека другим лицом (объективный элемент); &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Намерение преступника убить или нанести жертве тяжкие телесные повреждения
(субъективный элемент); &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Незаконность убийства, что означает, что закон считает виновного ответственным
за незаконное причинение смерти (правовой элемент). &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Это определение гласит, что для статистических целей все убийства, соответствующие трем указанным выше критериям, должны рассматриваться как преднамеренные убийства, независимо от определений, предусмотренных национальным законодательством или практикой.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
