<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 14-6-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;h2&gt;Rationale:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this indicator is to show a picture of the state of implementation of the instruments to combat IUU fishing, at a national, regional and global level. The first edition of the indicator will provide a baseline of the current state of implementation of these agreements. Subsequent indicator estimates will then be able to show any progress made by countries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the exact score will be important from one reporting year to the next for determining the progress made by a country, to aid the interpretation of this indicator, the score will then be converted into one of five bands as following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Score&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Bands&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;0 &amp;#x2013;&amp;lt; 0.2&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Band 1: Very low implementation of applicable instruments to combat IUU fishing&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;0.2 &amp;#x2013;&amp;lt; 0.4&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Band 2: Low implementation of applicable instruments to combat IUU fishing&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;0.4 &amp;#x2013;&amp;lt; 0.6&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Band 3: Medium implementation of applicable instruments to combat IUU fishing&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;0.6 &amp;#x2013;&amp;lt; 0.8&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Band 4: High implementation of applicable instruments to combat IUU fishing&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;0.8 &amp;#x2013; 1.0&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Band 5: Very high implementation of applicable instruments to combat IUU fishing&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, a State may receive an indicator score of &amp;#x201C;N/A&amp;#x201D;, in the case that none of the instruments are applicable. This would only be the case if the country is land locked and does not flag any vessels that conduct fishing or fishing related activities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Countries that do not submit a response to the questionnaire on which the indicator is based or do not approve the use of their responses to the questionnaire for use in this indicator, will not receive an indicator score.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
