<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 6-b-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the highly country- and context-specific nature of the indicator, no estimates are produced for countries that are missing data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operational mechanism by which individuals and communities can meaningfully contribute to water and sanitation management then the country will be excluded from the regional and global estimates for this indicator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global and regional estimates for a related indicator on the presence and use of participation policies and procedures at the national level for different water subsectors are also derived to support the target indicator. Similarly, countries with missing values are excluded from global and regional analysis for this indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel de país:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debido a la naturaleza altamente específica del país y del contexto del indicador, no se producen estimaciones para los países a los que les faltan datos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel regional y mundial:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mecanismo operativo por el cual los individuos y las comunidades pueden contribuir significativamente a la gestión del agua y el saneamiento, entonces el país será excluido de las estimaciones regionales y mundiales para este indicador. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las estimaciones globales y regionales para un indicador relacionado sobre la presencia y el uso de políticas y procedimientos de participación a nivel nacional para los diferentes subsectores del agua también se derivan para apoyar el indicador objetivo. Del mismo modo, los países con valores ausentes se excluyen del análisis global y regional para este indicador.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Traitement des valeurs manquantes : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Au niveau national : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En raison de la nature très spécifique de l&apos;indicateur en fonction du pays et du contexte, aucune estimation n&apos;est produite pour les pays dont les données sont manquantes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Au niveau régional et mondial : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mécanisme opérationnel par lequel les individus et les communautés peuvent contribuer de manière significative à la gestion de l&apos;eau et de l&apos;assainissement ; le pays sera alors exclu des estimations régionales et mondiales pour cet indicateur. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des estimations mondiales et régionales pour un indicateur connexe sur la présence et l&apos;utilisation de politiques et de procédures de participation au niveau national pour différents sous-secteurs de l&apos;eau sont également dérivées pour soutenir l&apos;indicateur cible. De même, les pays pour lesquels des valeurs sont manquantes sont exclus de l&apos;analyse mondiale et régionale pour cet indicateur. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt;Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Вследствие того, что показатель сильно зависит от страны и контекста, оценки по странам, по которым отсутствуют данные, не производятся. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Действующий механизм, с помощью которого отдельные лица и сообщества могут вносить значительный вклад в управление водными ресурсами и санитарией; затем страна будет исключена из региональных и глобальных оценок этого показателя. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Глобальные и региональные оценки для соответствующего показателя наличия и использования правил и процедур участия на национальном уровне для различных подсекторов водных ресурсов также получены для поддержки целевого показателя. Точно так же страны с отсутствующими значениями исключаются из глобального и регионального анализа по этому показателю.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
