<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 3-9-3, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mortality rate attributed to unintentional poisoning as defined as the number of deaths of unintentional poisonings in a year, divided by the population, and multiplied by 100 000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mortality rate in the country from unintentional poisonings per year. The ICD-10 codes corresponding to the indicator includes X40, X43-X44, X46-X49.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La tasa de mortalidad atribuida a las intoxicaciones involuntarias, definida como el número de muertes por intoxicaciones involuntarias en un año, dividido por la población y multiplicado por 100 000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tasa de mortalidad en el país por intoxicaciones involuntarias al año. Los códigos CIE-10 correspondientes al indicador incluyen X40, X43-X44, X46-X49.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Définition : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le taux de mortalité attribué aux empoisonnements involontaires est défini comme le nombre de décès par empoisonnement involontaire au cours d&apos;une année, divisé par la population et multiplié par 100 000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taux de mortalité par an dans le pays pour les empoisonnements involontaires. Les codes CIM-10 correspondant à l&apos;indicateur comprennent X40, X43-X44, X46-X49. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt;Понятия и определения&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Определение:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Смертность от неумышленного отравления определяется как количество смертей от неумышленных отравлений в год, деленное на численность населения и умноженное на 100000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Понятия:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Смертность в стране от неумышленных отравлений в год. Коды МКБ-10, соответствующие показателю, включают X40, X43-X44, X46-X49.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
