<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 16-1-3, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The total number of persons who have been victim of physical, psychological or sexual violence in the previous 12 months, as a share of the total population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator measures the prevalence of victimization from physical, psychological or sexual violence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Physical violence: This concept is equivalent to the concept of physical assault, as defined in the International Classification of Crime for Statistical Purposes (ICCS): the intentional or reckless application of physical force inflicted upon the body of a person. This includes serious and minor bodily injuries and serious and minor physical force. According to the ICCS, these are defined as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serious bodily injury, at minimum, includes gunshot or bullet wounds; knife or stab wounds; severed limbs; broken bones or teeth knocked out; internal injuries; being knocked unconscious; and other severe or critical injuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serious physical force, at minimum, includes being shot; stabbed or cut; hit by an object; hit by a thrown object; poisoning and other applications of force with the potential to cause serious bodily injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minor bodily injury, at minimum, includes bruises, cuts, scratches, chipped teeth, swelling, black eye and other minor injuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minor physical force, at minimum, includes hitting, slapping, pushing, tripping, knocking down and other applications of force with the potential to cause minor bodily injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sexual violence (ICCS): Unwanted sexual act, attempt to obtain a sexual act, or contact or communication with unwanted sexual attention without valid consent or with consent as a result of intimidation, force, fraud, coercion, threat, deception, use of drugs or alcohol, or abuse of power or of a position of vulnerability. This includes rape and other forms of sexual assault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychological violence: There is as yet no consensus at the international level of the precise definition of psychological violence and there is as yet no generally well-established methodology to measure psychological violence.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
