<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 3-1-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Missing values are treated at the country-level. This is done as follows. There is no treatment of missing values at the regional level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Predictor variable data:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complete and comparable predictor data is obtained by constructing time series estimates for predictor variables (covariates) from 1990 to 2019:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gross domestic product (GDP) per capita, measured in purchasing power parity (PPP) equivalent US dollars using 2011 as the baseline, was generated based on data from the World Bank Group and in instances supplemented by unofficial estimates derived by MMEIG using growth rates in United Nations GDP data and/or previous MMEIG GDP estimates.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;General fertility rate (GFR) was computed from data on live births and population size (number of women aged 15&amp;#x2013;49) from UNPD&amp;#x2019;s 2019 revision of World population prospects.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skilled birth attendant (SBA) data consist of time series derived using all available data from population-based national household survey data and countries&amp;#x2019; routine reporting mechanisms (WHO and UNICEF Joint Skilled Birth Attendant database). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Response variable data:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All-cause deaths for WRA, used to denominate maternal deaths in the statistic PM, are imputed when missing and in some cases overwritten. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimated all-cause deaths from WHO Global Health Estimates lifetables were used to impute and overwrite all-cause deaths in specialized studies in which the search went beyond registration systems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CRVS reported all-cause deaths were used to impute missing all-cause deaths in specialized studies in which the search was within registration systems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimated all-cause deaths from WHO Global Health Estimates were used to impute missing all-cause deaths in miscellaneous studies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt; Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; A nivel de país:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; A nivel regional y mundial:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Para fundamentar la proyección de las tendencias en los períodos en que los datos son escasos, o para los países con pocos o ningún dato, se utiliza el modelo estadístico BMaT para estimar la mortalidad materna. El modelo incluye factores que se sabe que están asociados con la mortalidad materna como covariables predictoras (PIB, TFG y SAB). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Traitement des valeurs manquantes :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Au niveau national :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Aux niveaux régional et mondial :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour éclairer la projection des tendances entre les périodes où les données sont rares, ou pour les pays qui ont peu ou pas de données du tout, le modèle statistique BMaT est utilisé pour estimer la mortalité maternelle. Le modèle comprend des facteurs connus pour être associés à la mortalité maternelle en tant que covariables prédictrices (GDP, GFR et SAB). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Статистическая модель BMaT используется для оценки материнской смертности при формировании прогноза, основанного на тенденциях, за периоды, когда данных недостаточно, или для стран, у которых данных мало или вообще нет. Модель включает факторы, которые, как известно, связаны с материнской смертностью, в качестве прогностического фактора ковариантов (валовой внутренний продукт (ВВП), общий коэффициент фертильности (ОКФ) и доля деторождений при квалифицированном родовспоможении (ДКР)). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
