<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The QUALITY_ASSMNT field for indicator 3-8-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;The World Health Organization and the World Bank generate indicator 3.8.2 following the methods, validation and treatment of missing values described in sections 4.c. to 4.d. Both institutions combine estimates at the meso-level. Eligibility of the estimates included in a joint global database at a country level and used to produce regional and global estimates is based on the following quality assessment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For the denominator of the health expenditure ratio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compare the average monthly total household per capita consumption or income in a benchmark source with the average monthly value estimated from the survey. The comparison is based on the ratio of both averages (benchmark source to the survey-based estimate). If the ratio is greater than 20% (when both averages are based on consumption) or 30% (when the benchmark source estimate is based on income and the survey-based one on consumption), the survey point is identified as an outlier in terms of consumption per capita and flagged for possible exclusion. Both averages are expressed in interntional dollars. The source for the benchmark average is either the Poverty and Inequality Platform&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-11&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-11&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (already expressed in international dollars), or derived from the World Development Indicators (WDI)&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-12&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-12&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; andcomputed as the household final consumption expenditures in constant international dollars divided by the total population. The average estimated from the survey is available in local nominal currency units. It is converted into internation dollars using purchasing power parities (PPP) for private consumption and consumer index prices. PPP data are downloadable from the World Bank&amp;#x2019;s (WDI) data website14 and the Poverty and Inequality Platform (PIP). Data on CPIs is also downloadable from the Poverty and Inequality Platform (PIP). PIP is the preferred data source for both CPIs and PPPs. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compare the poverty headcount estimated from the survey using international poverty lines with the poverty incidence reported in Poverty and Inequality Platform at the same poverty lines (benchmark value). When the absolute difference between the benchmark value and the survey-based estimate exceeds 10 percentage points, the survey-based point is identified as an outlier to track poverty using international poverty lines and flagged for possible exclusion. An extreme and moderate poverty line are used for this assessment. The latest value of international extreme poverty line is $2.15 per day per capita using 2017 purchasing power parities (PPPs) for private consumption and replaces the $1.90 poverty line based on 2011 PPPs. The latest value of the moderate international poverty line is $3.65 per person per day is based on 2017 PPPs which replaces the $3.20 poverty line based on 2011 PPPs. It corresponds to the typical standard used to assess national poverty levels in lower-middle-income countries. For more information about the latest purchasing power parity revision (PPP), please consult https://www.worldbank.org/en/news/factsheet/2022/05/02/fact-sheet-an-adjustment-to-global-poverty-lines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For the numerator of the health expenditure ratio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compare the average health expenditure ratio in the survey to a benchmark average health budget share. The latter is constructed from national health accounts data as the ratio of the aggregate measure of household out-of-pocket expenditures to the final consumption expenditure of households and profit institutions serving households, both in current local currency. When the absolute difference exceeds 5 percentage points, the survey point is identified as an outlier in terms of household budget share spent on health and flagged for possible exclusion. The macro-indicators are available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.who.int/nha/database&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Global Health Expenditure Database&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (GHED)&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-13&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-13&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These benchmarks are also used to decide which estimates to accept between two estimates for those countries and the years for which both institutions have the same data source. For a survey-based estimate of SDG indicator 3.8.2 to be included in the joint database and, therefore, in the country consultation conducted every two years previously described, it cannot be an outlier in consumption, nor in terms of the health budget share. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimates produced by the countries and shared through the country consultation are subject to the same quality assurance process. They are included in the joint database if they are not flagged neither in consumption nor in the health budget share.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-11&quot;&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://pip.worldbank.org/home&quot;&gt;https://pip.worldbank.org/home&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-11&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-12&quot;&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://datacatalog.worldbank.org/dataset/world-development-indicators&quot;&gt;https://datacatalog.worldbank.org/dataset/world-development-indicators&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-12&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-13&quot;&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.who.int/nha/database&quot;&gt;https://apps.who.int/nha/database&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-13&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</data>
</root>
