<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 3-5-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definitions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harmful use of alcohol, defined according to the national context as alcohol per capita consumption (aged 15 years and older) within a calendar year in litres of pure alcohol &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total alcohol per capita (15+ years) consumption (APC) is defined as the total (sum of three-year average recorded APC and unrecorded APC adjusted for tourist consumption) amount of pure alcohol consumed per adult (15+ years), in a calendar year, in litres of pure alcohol. Recorded alcohol consumption refers to official statistics at country level (production, import, export, and sales or taxation data), while the unrecorded alcohol consumption refers to alcohol which is not taxed and is outside the usual system of governmental control, such as home or informally produced alcohol (legal or illegal), smuggled alcohol, surrogate alcohol (which is alcohol not intended for human consumption), or alcohol obtained through cross-border shopping (which is recorded in a different jurisdiction). Tourist consumption takes into account tourists visiting the country and inhabitants visiting other countries. Positive figures denote alcohol consumption of outbound tourists being greater than alcohol consumption by inbound tourists, negative numbers the opposite. Tourist consumption is based on UN statistics, and data are provided by IHME. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recorded alcohol per capita (15+) consumption of pure alcohol is calculated as the sum of beverage-specific alcohol consumption of pure alcohol (beer, wine, spirits, other) from different sources. The first priority in the decision tree is given to government national statistics; second are country-specific alcohol industry statistics in the public domain based on interviews or fieldwork (GlobalData (formerly Canadean), International Wine and Spirit Research (IWSR), Wine Institute; historically World Drink Trends) or data from the International Organisation of Vine and Wine (OIV); third is the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations&amp;apos; statistical database (FAOSTAT), and fourth is data from alcohol industry statistics in the public domain based on desk review. For countries, where the data source is FAOSTAT the unrecorded consumption may be included in the recorded consumption. As for the beverage-specific categories, beer includes malt beers, wine includes wine made from grapes and vermouth, spirits include all distilled beverages, and other includes one or several other alcoholic beverages, such as fermented beverages made from sorghum, maize, millet, rice, or cider, fruit wine, fortified wine, etc. For unrecorded APC, the first priority in the decision tree is given to nationally representative empirical data; these are often general population surveys in countries where alcohol is legal. Second are specific other empirical investigations, and third is expert opinion supported by periodic survey of experts at country level using modified Delphi-technique. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For recorded APC, if beverage volumes are not available in litres of pure alcohol, they are transformed into litres of pure alcohol. The alcohol content (% alcohol by volume) is considered to be as follows: beer (barley beer 5%), wine (grape wine 12%; must of grape 9%, vermouth 16%), spirits (distilled spirits 40%; spirit-like 30%), and other (sorghum, millet, maize beers 5%; cider 5%; fortified wine 17% and 18%; fermented wheat and fermented rice 9%; other fermented beverages 9%).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unrecorded APC is estimated using a regression analysis. Fractional response random intercepts regression models, which account for clustering of data points within countries, are used to estimate what percentage of total APC is due to unrecorded APC. Univariate models are fitted for alcohol consumption statistics and other predictors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The litres of alcohol consumed by tourists (15 years of age and older) in a country are based on the number of tourists who visited a country, the average amount of time they spent in the country, and how much these people drink on average in their countries of origin (estimated based on per capita consumption of recorded and unrecorded alcohol). Furthermore, tourist alcohol consumption also accounts for the inhabitants of a country consuming alcohol while visiting other countries (based on the average time spent outside of their country (for all people 15 years and older) and the amount of alcohol consumed in their country of origin). These estimations assume the following: (1) that people drink the same amounts of alcohol when they are tourists as they do in their home countries, and (2) that global tourist consumption is equal to 0 (and thus tourist consumption can be either net negative or positive). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uso nocivo del alcohol, definido según el contexto nacional como el consumo per cápita de alcohol (mayores de 15 años) dentro de un año natural en litros de alcohol puro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El consumo total per cápita de alcohol (CPA) se define como la cantidad total (suma del promedio trienal de CPA registrado y del CPA no registrado como proporción del total) de alcohol consumido por adulto (mayor de 15 años) durante un año civil, en litros de alcohol puro, ajustado por el consumo turístico. El consumo de alcohol registrado se refiere a las estadísticas oficiales a nivel de país (datos de producción, importación, exportación y ventas o impuestos), mientras que el consumo de alcohol no registrado se refiere al alcohol que no se grava y que está fuera del sistema habitual de control gubernamental, como el alcohol de producción casera o informal (legal o ilegal), el alcohol de contrabando, el alcohol de sustitución (que es el alcohol no destinado al consumo humano) o el alcohol obtenido a través de compras transfronterizas (que se registra en una jurisdicción diferente). El consumo turístico tiene en cuenta a los turistas que visitan el país y a los habitantes que visitan otros países. Las cifras positivas indican que el consumo de alcohol de los turistas salientes es mayor que el de los entrantes, y las negativas, lo contrario. El consumo turístico se basa en las estadísticas de la ONU, y los datos son proporcionados por el Instituto de Métricas y Evaluación de la Salud (IHME, por sus siglas en inglés).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concept0s:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El consumo per cápita de alcohol puro registrado (mayores de 15 años) se calcula como la suma del consumo específico de alcohol puro (cerveza, vino, licores, otros) de diferentes fuentes. La primera prioridad en el árbol de decisión son las estadísticas nacionales de los gobiernos; la segunda son las estadísticas de la industria del alcohol específicas de cada país que son de dominio público y se basan en entrevistas o trabajo de campo (GlobalData (antes Canadean), International Wine and Spirit Research (IWSR), Instituto del Vino; históricamente World Drink Trends) o datos de la Organización Internacional de la Viña y el Vino (OIV); la tercera es la base de datos estadísticos de la Organización de las Naciones Unidas para la Agricultura y la Alimentación (FAOSTAT), y la cuarta son los datos de las estadísticas de la industria del alcohol que son de dominio público y se basan en un estudio documental. En el caso de los países cuya fuente de datos es FAOSTAT, el consumo no registrado puede incluirse en el consumo registrado. A partir de la introducción de la categoría específica de &amp;quot;Otras&amp;quot; bebidas, la cerveza incluye las cervezas de malta, el vino incluye el vino hecho de uvas, las bebidas espirituosas incluyen todas las bebidas destiladas y otras incluyen una o varias otras bebidas alcohólicas, como las bebidas fermentadas hechas de sorgo, maíz, mijo, arroz o sidra, vino de frutas, vino fortificado, etc. En el caso del CPA no registrado, la primera prioridad en el árbol de decisión son los datos empíricos representativos a nivel nacional; suelen ser encuestas generales de población en países donde el alcohol es legal. En segundo lugar, se encuentran otras investigaciones empíricas específicas, y en tercer lugar, la opinión de los expertos apoyada por una encuesta periódica de expertos a nivel nacional (50 países con estimaciones significativas de consumo de alcohol no registrado) utilizando la técnica Delphi modificada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En el caso del CPA registrado, para hacer la conversión en litros de alcohol puro, se considera que el contenido de alcohol (% de alcohol por volumen) es el siguiente Cerveza (cerveza de cebada 5%), Vino (vino de uva 12%; mosto de uva 9%, vermut 16%), Bebidas espirituosas (bebidas espirituosas destiladas 40%; bebidas espirituosas 30%), y Otras (cervezas de sorgo, mijo, maíz 5%; sidra 5%; vino fortificado 17% y 18%; trigo fermentado y arroz fermentado 9%; otras bebidas fermentadas 9%). Las preguntas de la encuesta sobre el consumo de alcohol no registrado se convierten en estimaciones por año de CPA no registrado. En algunos países, el alcohol no registrado se estima sobre la base del alcohol confiscado por las aduanas o la policía.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los litros de alcohol consumidos por los turistas (mayores de 15 años) en un país se basaron en el número de turistas que visitaron un país, la cantidad promedio de tiempo que pasaron en el país y cuánto beben estas personas en promedio en sus países de origen (estimado en base al consumo per cápita de alcohol registrado y no registrado). Además, el consumo de alcohol por parte de los turistas también tiene en cuenta a los habitantes de un país que consumían alcohol mientras visitaban otros países (basándose en el tiempo medio que pasaban fuera de su país (para todas las personas de 15 años o más) y la cantidad de alcohol que consumían en su país de origen). Estas estimaciones suponen lo siguiente (1) que las personas beben las mismas cantidades de alcohol cuando son turistas que en sus países de origen, y (2) que el consumo global de los turistas es igual a 0 (y, por tanto, el consumo de los turistas puede ser negativo o positivo en términos netos).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définitions :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usage nocif de l’alcool, défini selon le contexte national comme la consommation d’alcool par habitant (âgé de 15 ans ou plus) au cours d’une année civile en litres d’alcool pur. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La consommation totale d’alcool par habitant (15 ans ou plus) est définie comme la quantité totale (somme de la moyenne sur trois ans de la CAH enregistrés et de la CAH non enregistrée ajustée pour la consommation touristique) de l’alcool pur consommée par adulte (15 ans out plus), au cours d’une année civile, en litres d’alcool pur. La consommation d’alcool enregistrée se réfère aux statistiques officielles au niveau des pays (données de production, d’importation, d’exportation et de vente ou de taxation), tandis que la consommation d’alcool non enregistrée se réfère à l’alcool qui n’est pas taxé et qui est en dehors du système habituel de contrôle gouvernemental, comme l’alcool domestique ou produit de manière informelle (légal ou illégal), l’alcool de contrebande, l’alcool de substitution (qui est de l’alcool non destiné à la consommation humaine), ou l’alcool obtenu par le biais d’achats transfrontaliers (qui sont enregistrés dans une juridiction différente). La consommation touristique prend en compte les touristes visitant le pays et les habitants visitant d’autres pays. Les chiffres positifs indiquent que la consommation d’alcool des touristes sortants est supérieure à la consommation d’alcool des touristes entrants, les chiffres négatifs étant le contraire. La consommation touristique est basée sur les statistiques de l’ONU et les données sont fournies par l’institut IHME. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La consommation enregistrée d’alcool pur par habitant (15 ans ou plus) est calculée comme la somme de la consommation d’alcool pur spécifique à une boisson (bière, vin, spiritueux, autres) provenant de différentes sources. La première priorité dans l’arbre de décision est donnée aux statistiques nationales gouvernementales; deuxièmement, les statistiques de l’industrie de l’alcool par pays dans le domaine public basées sur des entretiens ou des travaux sur le terrain (GlobalData (anciennement Canadean), International Wine and Spirit Research (IWSR), Wine Institute historiquement World Drink Trends) ou des données de l’Organisation internationale de la vigne et du vin (OIV); troisièmement, la base de données statistiques de l’Organisation des Nations Unies pour l’alimentation et l’agriculture (FAOSTAT), et quatrièmement, les données des statistiques de l’industrie de l’alcool dans le domaine public basées sur un examen documentaire. Pour les pays dont la source de données est FAOSTAT, la consommation non enregistrée peut être incluse dans la consommation enregistrée. En ce qui concerne les catégories spécifiques aux boissons, la bière comprend les bières de malt, le vin comprend le vin fabriqué à partir de raisins et de vermouth, les spiritueux comprennent toutes les boissons distillées et les autres comprennent une ou plusieurs autres boissons alcoolisées, telles que les boissons fermentées à base de sorgho, de maïs, de millet, de riz ou de cidre, de vin de fruits, de vin fortifié, etc. Pour la CAH non enregistrée, la première priorité dans l’arbre de décision est donnée aux données empiriques représentatives à l’échelle nationale; il s’agit souvent d’enquêtes générales auprès de la population dans les pays où l’alcool est légal. Deuxièmement, il y a d’autres enquêtes empiriques spécifiques, et troisièmement, l’opinion d’experts soutenue par une enquête périodique auprès d’experts au niveau des pays utilisant la technique Delphi modifiée. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour la CAH enregistrée, si les volumes de boissons ne sont pas disponibles en litres d’alcool pur, ils sont transformés en litres d’alcool pur. La teneur en alcool (% alcool par volume) est considérée comme suit : bière (bière d’orge 5%), vin (vin de raisin 12%, moût de raisin 9%, vermouth 16%), spiritueux (spiritueux distillés 40%, spiritueux 30%) et autres (sorgho, millet, bières de maïs 5%; cidre 5%; vin fortifié 17% et 18%; blé fermenté et riz fermenté 9%; autres boissons fermentées 9%). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La CAH non enregistrée est estimée à l’aide d’une analyse de régression. Les modèles de régression à réponse fractionnée avec origines aléatoires, qui tiennent compte du regroupement des points de données dans les pays, sont utilisés pour estimer le pourcentage du TOTAL de la CAH qui est due à la CAH non enregistrée. Des modèles univariés sont adaptés aux statistiques de consommation d’alcool et à d’autres prédicteurs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les litres d’alcool consommés par les touristes (âgés de 15 ans ou plus) dans un pays sont basés sur le nombre de touristes qui ont visité un pays, le temps moyen qu’ils ont passé dans le pays et la quantité moyenne que ces personnes boivent dans leur pays d’origine (estimée sur la base de la consommation d&apos;alcool par habitant enregistrée et non enregistrée). En outre, la consommation d’alcool des touristes représente également les habitants d’un pays consommant de l’alcool lors de leur visite dans d’autres pays (sur la base du temps moyen passé à l’extérieur de leur pays (pour toutes les personnes de 15 ans ou plus) et de la quantité d’alcool consommée dans leur pays d’origine). Ces estimations supposent ce qui suit : (1) que les gens boivent les mêmes quantités d’alcool lorsqu’ils sont touristes que dans leur pays d’origine, et (2) que la consommation touristique mondiale est égale à 0 (et donc la consommation touristique nette peut être négative ou positive). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Злоупотребление алкоголем, определяемое в соответствии с национальными особенностями как употребление алкоголя на душу населения (в возрасте 15 лет и старше) в литрах чистого спирта в течение календарного года &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Общее потребление алкоголя на душу населения (ПAДН) определяется как общее количество алкоголя (сумма учтенного среднего за три года потребления алкоголя на душу населения и неучтенного потребления алкоголя на душу населения как доля общего потребления), потребляемого на одного взрослого (15 лет и старше) за календарный год в литрах чистого алкоголя с поправкой на туристическое потребление. Учтенное потребление алкоголя относится к данным официальной статистики на страновом уровне (данные по производству, импорту, экспорту, продажам или налогообложению), в то время как неучтенное потребление алкоголя относится к алкоголю, который не облагается налогами и выходит за рамки обычной системы государственного контроля, такой как произведенный в домашних условиях или неофициально произведенный алкоголь (законный или незаконный), контрабандный алкоголь, суррогатный алкоголь (который является алкоголем, не предназначенным для употребления человеком) или алкоголь, полученный в результате трансграничных покупок (что относится к другой сфере полномочий). Институт измерения и оценки здоровья (ИПОЗ) учитывает туристов, посещающих страну, и местных жителей, посещающих другие страны. Положительные цифры означают, что потребление алкоголя выезжающими туристами превышает потребление алкоголя въезжающими туристами, отрицательные цифры - наоборот. Туристическое потребление основано на статистике ООН, а данные предоставлены Институтом измерения и оценки здоровья. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Учтенное потребление чистого алкоголя на душу населения (15 лет и старше) рассчитывается как сумма потребления алкогольсодержащих напитков в пересчете на чистый алкоголь (пиво, вино, крепкие спиртные напитки и другие напитки) из различных источников. Первым приоритетом в дереве решений является государственная национальная статистика; на втором месте - статистика алкогольной промышленности по конкретной стране, имеющаяся в открытом доступе и основанная на интервью или полевых исследованиях (GlobalData (ранее Канадское), Международное исследование по вину и крепким спиртным напиткам (IWSR), Институт вина; Исторические мировые тенденции в потреблении алкоголя) или данные Международной организации виноградарства и виноделия (OIV); на третьем месте - статистическая база данных (FAOSTAT) Продовольственной и сельскохозяйственной организации Объединенных Наций, а на четвертом месте располагаются данные статистики алкогольной промышленности, имеющиеся в открытом доступе и основанные на теоретических исследованиях. В странах, для которых источником данных является FAOSTAT, неучтенное потребление может быть включено в учтенное потребление. Что касается введения категории &quot;других&quot; алкогольсодержащих напитков, то пиво включает солодовое пиво, вино включает вино, изготовленное из винограда, спиртные напитки включают все напитки, полученные перегонкой, а другие включают один или несколько иных алкогольных напитков, таких как ферментированные напитки, приготовленные из сорго, кукурузы, проса, риса или сидра, фруктовое вино, крепленое вино и т. д. Для неучтенного потребления алкоголя на душу населения первый приоритет в дереве решений отдается национально репрезентативным эмпирическим данным; часто они получаются в результате обследования населения в странах, где употребление алкоголя разрешено. На втором месте - другие специфические эмпирические исследования, а на третьем месте - заключения экспертов, подкрепленные периодическим опросом специалистов на страновом уровне (50 стран со значительными оценками неучтенного потребления алкоголя) с использованием модифицированного метода &quot;Дельфи&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для учтенного потребления алкоголя на душу населения, чтобы преобразовать количество в литры чистого алкоголя, содержание алкоголя (% алкоголя по объему) считается равным: пиво (ячменное пиво 5%), вино (виноградное вино 12%; виноградное сусло 9%, вермут 16%), спиртные напитки (напитки, полученные перегонкой 40%; спиртосодержащие напитки 30%) и прочие (пиво из сорго, проса, кукурузы 5%; сидр 5%; крепленое вино 17% и 18%; ферментированная пшеница и ферментированные рис 9%; прочие ферментированные напитки 9%). Вопросы обследования по потреблению неучтенного алкоголя конвертируются в оценки неучтенного потребления алкоголя на душу населения за год. В некоторых странах количество неучтенного алкоголя оценивается на основе алкоголя, конфискованного таможней или полицией.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Расчет количества алкоголя, потребляемого туристами (в возрасте 15 лет и старше) в стране, основывается на количестве туристов, посетивших страну, среднем количестве времени, которое они провели в стране, и на данных о том, сколько эти люди выпивают в среднем в стране их происхождения (оценка основана на потреблении учтенного и неучтенного алкоголя на душу населения). Кроме того, потребление алкоголя туристами также учитывается для жителей страны, потребляющих алкоголь во время посещения других стран (на основе среднего времени, проведенного за пределами своей страны (для всех лиц в возрасте 15 лет и старше), и количества алкоголя, потребляемого в стране их происхождения. ). Эти оценки предполагают следующее: (1) люди пьют такое же количество алкоголя, когда они являются туристами, как и в своих странах, и (2) что глобальное туристское потребление равно 0 (и, таким образом, туристское потребление может быть либо отрицательным чистым, либо положительным чистым).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
