<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 15-4-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;Land cover maps developed by relevant national authorities will generally provide the most relevant data source to compute this indicator. However, in certain cases, such data may not be available. In those cases, various regional or global products provide a viable alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The global default source of land cover data for this indicator is the European Space Agency Climate Change Initiative (ESA-CCI) Land Cover product (ESA, 2017). The ESA-CCI product consists of a series of annual Land Cover maps at 300 m resolution, providing 22 land cover classes based on 300m MERIS, 1km SPOT &amp;#x2013;VEGETATION, 1km PROBA &amp;#x2013;V and 1km AVHRR. The ESA CCI adheres to the Cover Classification System of the United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization (UN FAO) (Santoro &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt;. 2015). Annual updates are currently available from 1992 to 2020. Additional years will be made available by the European Space Agency. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A global mountain area map sub-divided by bioclimatic belts has been developed by FAO and made available to national authorities to facilitate the compute this indicator. This map is the result of combining a global mountain area map developed from the Global Multi-Resolution Terrain Elevation Data (GMTED2010), following the UNEP-WCMC methodology (Ravilious &lt;em&gt;et al. &lt;/em&gt;2021) and a mountain bioclimatic belt map created by the Global Mountain Biodiversity Assessment&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-4&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-4&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-4&quot;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; https://ilias.unibe.ch/goto.php?target=file_2171234 &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-4&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</data>
</root>
