<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 11-1-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;As seen in Table 1, most of the criteria for defining slums, informal settlements and inadequate housing overlap. The three criteria of informal settlements are essentially captured in the definition of slums, which sustains the combination of both (slums/informal settlements). Both aspects of slums and informal settlements are therefore combined into one component of the indicator, providing some continuity with what was captured under MDG 7. At a later stage, a composite index will be developed that will incorporate all measures (combining slum/informal settlements and inadequate housing) and provide one estimate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second component of the indicator is on inadequate housing. From the seven criteria of adequate housing, the three that are not covered by slums / informal settlements are &lt;em&gt;affordability&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;accessibility&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;cultural adequacy&lt;/em&gt;. However, affordability is the most relevant and easier to measure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this regard, &lt;em&gt;housing affordability&lt;/em&gt; is not only a key housing adequacy criterion, but is a suitable means of measuring inadequate housing in a more encompassing manner, as it remains a global challenge across different countries and income levels, with strong negative impact on urban inequality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The underlying principle is that household financial costs associated with housing should not threaten or compromise the attainment and satisfaction of other basic needs such as, food, education, access to health care, transport, etc. Based on the existing method and data of UN-Habitat&amp;#x2019;s Urban Indicators Program (1996-2006), unaffordability is currently measured as the net monthly expenditure on housing cost that exceeds 30% of the total monthly income of the household.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table 2 details the proposed definition of Slum/Informal Settlements and Inadequate Housing as well as the respective measurements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table 2 &amp;#x2013; Definition and measurement criteria for slums, informal settlements and inadequate housing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slums / Informal Settlements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DEFINITION:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;As adopted in the MDG, slum households are households whose members suffer one or more of the following &amp;#x2018;household deprivations&amp;#x2019;: 1) Lack of access to improved water source, 2) Lack of access to improved sanitation facilities, 3) Lack of sufficient living area, 4) Lack of housing durability and, 5) Lack of security of tenure.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEASUREMENT&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-13&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-13&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Security of Tenure:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Proportion of households with formal title deeds to both land and residence.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Proportion of households with formal title deeds to either one of land or residence.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Proportion of households with agreements or any document as a proof of a tenure arrangement.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Access to improved water sources:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Proportion of households whose members have access to improved drinking water sources (i.e. piped in water into dwelling, plot or yard; public tap/stand pipe service; protected spring; rain water collection; bottled water if secondary source is also improved; bore hole/tube well; and protected dug well). &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Access to improved sanitation facilities:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Proportion of households whose members have access to improved sanitation facilities (i.e. pour-flush toilets or latrines connected to a sewer, septic tank or pit; ventilated improved pit latrine; pit latrine with a slab or platform that covers the pit entirely; composting toilets/latrines).&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Structural quality of Housing and location:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Proportion of households residing on or near a hazardous site. The following locations should be considered:&lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;housing in geologically hazardous zones (landslide/earthquake and flood areas);&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;housing on or under garbage mountains;&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;housing around high-industrial pollution areas;&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;housing around other unprotected high-risk zones (e.g. railroads, airports, energy transmission lines).&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Structural quality of the housing and permanency of the structure:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Proportion of households living in temporary and/or dilapidated structures. The following factors should be considered when placing a housing unit in these categories: &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;quality of construction (e.g. materials used for wall, floor and roof);&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;compliance with local building codes, standards and bylaws.&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sufficient living area: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Proportion of households in which not more than three people share the same habitable room.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inadequate housing &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DEFINITION: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Proposed to complement the slums/informal settlements measuring affordability of housing at the global level. A housing is considered inadequate if it is not affordable to the household, i.e. the net monthly expenditure on its cost exceeds 30% of the total monthly income of the household.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEASUREMENT: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inadequate housing: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Proportion of households with net monthly expenditure on housing exceeding 30% of the total monthly income of the household&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-14&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-14&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-13&quot;&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Measurements based on those in the (2003) UN-Habitat Challenge of Slums, p.12. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-13&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-14&quot;&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; To note, housing affordability can also be measured using house price-to-income ratio (HPIR) and the house rent-to-income ratio (HRIR). Housing is considered affordable when the house-price-to-annual household income ratio (HPIR) is 3.0 or less and the rent-to-monthly household income ratio (RIR) is 25% or less. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-14&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</data>
</root>
