<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The QUALITY_ASSURE field for indicator 6-a-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Data are collected using a converged reporting system whereby bilateral and multilateral providers of development co-operation use a single file format (Creditor Reporting System &amp;#x2013; CRS) to report at item level on all flows of resources to developing countries. Item-level reporting is validated against key aggregates also reported by donors and then serves as the basis for producing various other aggregate statistics. For further details, see: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A statistical reporter is responsible for the collection of DAC statistics in each providing country/agency. This reporter is usually located in the national aid agency, Ministry of Foreign Affairs or Finance etc.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Garantía de calidad:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos se recogen mediante un sistema de información convergente en el que los proveedores bilaterales y multilaterales de cooperación al desarrollo utilizan un único formato de archivo (Sistema de Notificación de los Países Acreedores &amp;#x2013; CRS) para informar a nivel de partida de todos los flujos de recursos destinados a los países en desarrollo. Los informes a nivel de partida se validan con los agregados clave que también comunican los donantes y luego sirven de base para elaborar otras estadísticas agregadas. Para más detalles, véase: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Un informante estadístico es responsable de la recopilación de las estadísticas del CAD en cada país/organismo proveedor. Este informante suele estar ubicado en la agencia nacional de ayuda, el Ministerio de Asuntos Exteriores o de Finanzas, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Assurance de la qualité : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont collectées au moyen d&apos;un système de notification convergent dans lequel les fournisseurs bilatéraux et multilatéraux de la coopération au développement utilisent un format de fichier unique (Système de notification des créanciers &amp;#x2013; CRS) pour rendre compte au niveau des postes de tous les flux de ressources vers les pays en développement. La déclaration au niveau des postes est validée par rapport aux principaux agrégats également communiqués par les donateurs et sert ensuite de base à la production de diverses autres statistiques agrégées. Pour plus de détails, voir : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Un déclarant statistique est responsable de la collecte des statistiques du CAD dans chaque pays/organisme fournisseur. Ce déclarant se trouve généralement dans l&apos;organisme d&apos;aide national, le ministère des affaires étrangères ou des finances, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Обеспечение качества: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные собираются с использованием конвергентной системы отчетности, при которой двусторонние и многосторонние поставщики помощи в целях развития используюFт единый формат файла (Система отчетности кредиторов - СОК) для отчетности на уровне отдельных элементов обо всех потоках ресурсов в развивающиеся страны. Отчетность на уровне элементов проверяется по ключевым агрегированным показателям, также представленной донорами, и затем служит основой для получения различных других агрегированных статистических данных. Для получения дополнительной информации см. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt; http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Составитель статистики отвечает за сбор статистических данных Комитета содействия развитию (КСР) в каждой стране / агентстве-поставщике. Этот составитель обычно находится в национальном агентстве по оказанию помощи, Министерстве иностранных дел или финансов и т. д. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
