<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 6-a-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Comments and limitations:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data on water and sanitation-related ODA included in the government budget will be available by end-2016 with the current cycle of UN-Water Global Analysis and Assessment of Sanitation and Drinking-Water (GLAAS) data. Until then, total water and sanitation-related ODA (denominator) will be reported. Total water and sanitation-related ODA will continue to be reported as an additional indicator going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the proportion of ODA channelled through the government treasury will be reported as an additional indicator. ODA channelled through treasury indicates a high level of cooperation and alignment between donors and national government in which the donors channel funds through the national budget process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OECD Creditor Reporting System (CRS) currently disaggregates ODA for the water and sanitation among several categories including: sector policy and administration, water resources protection, large and basic water and sanitation systems, river basin infrastructure, waste management, agricultural water resources, and education and training. While these categories do not align directly with the target areas of SDG 6 individually, which limits the disaggregation of ODA among the SDG target areas, the combined ODA from these categories does align with a majority of the reported ODA to the water sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the numerator and denominator come from different sources, there is the possibility of different underlying assumptions regarding what should be included/excluded in the ODA figures. This could lead to situations in which the proportion of ODA included in government budget is greater than 1 (100%) if total ODA reported to OECD is lower than ODA reported to be included the budget. To guard against this possibility, the OECD will supply GLAAS with the reported ODA figures, broken down to the project level, so that respondents can match these with their on-budget project data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ODA represents only one aspect of international cooperation. To capture other dimensions, additional supporting indicators are available, including indicators for the Collaborative Behaviours identified by the Sanitation and Water for All (SWA) partnership. Each behaviour has one or two key indicators for governments and for development partners. If the behaviours are jointly adapted by governments and development partners, long-term sector performance and sustainability would improve. For additional information on the Collaborative Behaviours see: &lt;a href=&quot;http://sanitationandwaterforall.org/about/the-four-swa-collaborative-behaviours/&quot;&gt;http://sanitationandwaterforall.org/about/the-four-swa-collaborative-behaviours/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires et limitations : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sur l&apos;APD liée à l&apos;eau et à l&apos;assainissement incluses dans le budget du gouvernement seront disponibles d&apos;ici la fin de l&apos;année 2016 avec le cycle actuel des données de l&apos;analyse et de l&apos;évaluation mondiales de l&apos;assainissement et de l&apos;eau potable (GLAAS) d&apos;ONU-Eau. D&apos;ici là, le total de l&apos;APD liée à l&apos;eau et à l&apos;assainissement (dénominateur) sera communiqué. L&apos;APD totale liée à l&apos;eau et à l&apos;assainissement continuera d&apos;être rapportée en tant qu&apos;indicateur supplémentaire à l&apos;avenir.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En outre, la proportion de l&apos;APD acheminée par le Trésor public sera indiquée comme un indicateur supplémentaire&lt;p&gt;. L&apos;APD acheminée par le Trésor public indique un niveau élevé de coopération et d&apos;alignement entre les donateurs et le gouvernement national, les donateurs acheminant les fonds par le biais du processus budgétaire national. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le système de notification des pays créanciers de l&apos;OCDE (SNPC) ventile actuellement l&apos;APD pour l&apos;eau et l&apos;assainissement en plusieurs catégories, notamment : la politique et l&apos;administration sectorielles, la protection des ressources en eau, les systèmes d&apos;eau et d&apos;assainissement de base et de grande envergure, l&apos;infrastructure des bassins fluviaux, la gestion des déchets, les ressources en eau agricole, et l&apos;éducation et la formation. Bien que ces catégories ne s&apos;alignent pas directement sur les domaines cibles du SDG 6 pris individuellement, ce qui limite la ventilation de l&apos;APD entre les domaines cibles du SDG, l&apos;APD combinée de ces catégories s&apos;aligne sur la majorité de l&apos;APD déclarée au secteur de l&apos;eau.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comme le numérateur et le dénominateur proviennent de sources différentes, il est possible que les hypothèses sous-jacentes concernant les éléments à inclure/exclure dans les chiffres de l&apos;APD soient différentes. Cela pourrait conduire à des situations dans lesquelles la proportion de l&apos;APD incluse dans le budget du gouvernement est supérieure à 1 (100%) si l&apos;APD totale déclarée à l&apos;OCDE est inférieure à l&apos;APD déclarée pour être incluse dans le budget. Pour éviter cette éventualité, l&apos;OCDE fournira à GLAAS les chiffres de l&apos;APD déclarés, ventilés au niveau des projets, afin que les répondants puissent les faire correspondre aux données de leurs projets inscrits au budget. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L&apos;APD ne représente qu&apos;un aspect de la coopération internationale. Pour saisir d&apos;autres dimensions, des indicateurs de soutien supplémentaires sont disponibles, y compris des indicateurs pour les comportements de collaboration identifiés par le partenariat Assainissement et eau pour tous (SWA). Chaque comportement comporte un ou deux indicateurs clés pour les gouvernements et les partenaires du développement. Si les comportements sont adaptés conjointement par les gouvernements et les partenaires de développement, la performance et la durabilité à long terme du secteur s&apos;en trouveront améliorées. Pour plus d&apos;informations sur les comportements de collaboration, voir &lt;a href=&quot;http://sanitationandwaterforall.org/about/the-four-swa-collaborative-behaviours/&quot;&gt;http://sanitationandwaterforall.org/about/the-four-swa-collaborative-behaviours/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
