<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REG_AGG field for indicator 6-a-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Regional aggregates:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global and regional aggregates for ODA are derived based on summation of recipient country ODA disbursement for the water sector (purpose codes 14000- series) and agricultural water resources (purpose code 31140) from the OECD Creditor Reporting System. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global and regional proportions of ODA disbursements as part of a government budget are derived for countries based on a summation of ODA for the water sector that is included in the budget divided by a summation of total ODA for water sector. The calculation of global and regional aggregates would only be performed for those countries reporting the amount of ODA for the water sector that is included in the budget. If no data is provided for the amount of ODA in the budget, then the country is excluded from the regional and/or global analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Agrégats régionaux : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les agrégats mondiaux et régionaux de l&apos;APD sont calculés sur la base de la somme des décaissements d&apos;APD des pays bénéficiaires pour le secteur de l&apos;eau (codes d&apos;objectif 14000) et les ressources en eau agricoles (code d&apos;objectif 31140) du système de notification des pays créanciers de l&apos;OCDE. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les proportions mondiales et régionales des décaissements d&apos;APD dans le cadre d&apos;un budget gouvernemental sont calculées pour les pays sur la base d&apos;une somme d&apos;APD pour le secteur de l&apos;eau qui est incluse dans le budget, divisée par une somme d&apos;APD totale pour le secteur de l&apos;eau. Le calcul des agrégats mondiaux et régionaux ne serait effectué que pour les pays qui déclarent le montant de l&apos;APD pour le secteur de l&apos;eau qui est inclus dans le budget. Si aucune donnée n&apos;est fournie pour le montant de l&apos;APD dans le budget, le pays est alors exclu de l&apos;analyse régionale et/ou mondiale. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
