<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DOC_METHOD field for indicator 5-1-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; Methodology used by countries for the compilation of the data at the national level: The questionnaires provided to countries include guidance, definitions and instructions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; International recommendations and guidelines: The areas of law and questions are drawn from the international legal and policy framework on gender equality, in particular the Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Discrimination against Women (CEDAW), which has 189 States parties, (http://www.ohchr.org/EN/HRBodies/CEDAW/Pages/CEDAWIndex.aspx), and the Beijing Platform for Action (http://www.unwomen.org/en/how-we-work/intergovernmental-support/world-conferences-on-women). The attached Methodological Note sets out the international standards supporting the areas of law and questions and also attaches the background paper for the expert workshop which provides a useful summary of the international legal and policy framework on equality and non-discrimination on the basis of sex and the relevance for SDG indicator 5.1.1.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt; &amp;#x2022; Méthodologie utilisée par les pays pour la compilation des données au niveau national : Les questionnaires fournis aux pays comprennent des orientations, des définitions et des instructions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &amp;#x2022; Recommandations et directives internationales : Les domaines du droit et des questions sont tirés du cadre juridique et politique international sur l’égalité des sexes, en particulier la Convention sur l’élimination de toutes les formes de discrimination à l’égard des femmes (CEDEF), qui compte 189 États parties ((en anglais) http://www.ohchr.org/EN/HRBodies/CEDAW/Pages/CEDAWIndex.aspx), et le Programme d’action de Beijing (https://www.unwomen.org/fr/how-we-work/intergovernmental-support/world-conferences-on-women). La note méthodologique ci-jointe expose les normes internationales à l’appui des domaines du droit et des questions et joint également le document d’information pour l’atelier d’experts qui fournit un résumé utile du cadre juridique et politique international sur l’égalité et la non-discrimination basée sur le sexe et de la pertinence pour l’indicateur 5.1.1 des ODD. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
