<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 5-1-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Definitions:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator 5.1.1 measures Government efforts to put in place legal frameworks that promote, enforce and monitor gender equality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is based on an assessment of legal frameworks that promote, enforce and monitor gender equality. The assessment is carried out by national counterparts, including National Statistical Offices (NSOs) and/or National Women&amp;#x2019;s Machinery (NWMs), and legal practitioners/researchers on gender equality, using a questionnaire comprising 42 yes/no questions under four areas of law: (i) overarching legal frameworks and public life; (ii) violence against women; (iii) employment and economic benefits; and (iv) marriage and family&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The areas of law and questions are drawn from the international legal and policy framework on gender equality, in particular the Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Discrimination against Women (CEDAW), which has 189 States parties, and the Beijing Platform for Action. As such, no new internationally agreed standard on equality and non-discrimination on the basis of sex was needed. The primary sources of information relevant for indicator 5.1.1 are legislation and policy/action plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 42 questions in the questionnaire are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Area 1: Overarching legal frameworks and public life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Promote&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If customary law is a valid source of law under the constitution, is it invalid if it violates constitutional provisions on equality or nondiscrimination? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If personal law is a valid source of law under the constitution, is it invalid if it violates constitutional provisions on equality or nondiscrimination? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is there a discrimination law that prohibits both direct and indirect discrimination against women? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do women and men enjoy equal rights and access to hold public and political office (legislature, executive, judiciary)? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are there quotas for women (reserved seats) in, or quotas for women in candidate lists for, national parliament?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do women and men have equal rights to confer citizenship to their spouses and their children?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enforce and monitor &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the law establish a specialized independent body tasked with receiving complaints of discrimination based on gender (e.g., national human rights institution, women&amp;#x2019;s commission, ombudsperson)? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is legal aid mandated in criminal matters? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is legal aid mandated in civil/family matters?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does a woman&amp;#x2019;s testimony carry the same evidentiary weight in court as a man&amp;#x2019;s? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are there laws that explicitly require the production and/or dissemination of gender statistics?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are there sanctions for noncompliance with mandated candidate list quotas, or incentives for political parties to field women candidates in national parliamentary elections? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Area 2: Violence against women&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Promote&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is there legislation specifically addressing domestic violence ?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have provisions exempting perpetrators from facing charges for rape if the perpetrator marries the victim after the crime been removed, or never existed in legislation? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have provisions reducing penalties in cases of so-called honour crimes been removed, or never existed in legislation?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are laws on rape based on lack of consent, without requiring proof of physical force or penetration? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does legislation explicitly criminalize marital rape or does legislation entitle a woman to file a complaint for rape against her husband or partner?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is there legislation that specifically addresses sexual harassment? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enforce and monitor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are there budgetary commitments provided for by government entities for the implementation of legislation addressing violence against women by creating an obligation on government to provide budget or allocation of funding for the implementation of relevant programmes or activities? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are there budgetary commitments provided for by government entities for the implementation of legislation addressing violence against women by allocating a specific budget, funding and/or incentives to support non-governmental organizations for activities to address violence against women? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is there is a national action plan or policy to address violence against women that is overseen by a national mechanism with the mandate to monitor and review implementation? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Area 3: Employment and economic benefits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Promote&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the law mandate nondiscrimination on the basis of gender in employment?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the law mandate equal remuneration for work of equal value? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can women work in jobs deemed hazardous, arduous or morally inappropriate in the same way as men?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are women able to work in the same industries as men?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are women able to perform the same tasks as men?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the law allow women to work the same night hours as men? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the law provide for maternity or parental leave available to mothers in accordance with the ILO standards? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the law provide for paid paternity or parental leave available to fathers or partners?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enforce and monitor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is there a public entity that can receive complaints on gender discrimination in employment? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is childcare publicly provided or subsidized?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Area 4: Marriage and family&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Promote&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the minimum age of marriage at least 18, with no legal exceptions, for both women and men?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do women and men have equal rights to enter marriage (i.e., consent) and initiate divorce? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do women and men have equal rights to be the legal guardian of their children during and after marriage? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do women and men have equal rights to be recognized as head of household or head of family?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do women and men have equal rights to choose where to live? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do women and men have equal rights to choose a profession?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do women and men have equal rights to obtain an identity card?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do women and men have equal rights to apply for passports? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do women and men have equal rights to own, access and control marital property including upon divorce?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enforce and monitor &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is marriage under the legal age void or voidable?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are there dedicated and specialized family courts? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Article 1 of CEDAW provides a comprehensive definition of discrimination against women covering direct and indirect discrimination and article 2 sets out general obligations for States, in particular on required legal frameworks, to eliminate discrimination against women. Article 1 of CEDAW states: &amp;#x201C;&amp;#x2026; the term &amp;quot;discrimination against women&amp;quot; shall mean any distinction, exclusion or restriction made on the basis of sex which has the effect or purpose of impairing or nullifying the recognition, enjoyment or exercise by women, irrespective of their marital status, on a basis of equality of men and women, of human rights and fundamental freedoms in the political, economic, social, cultural, civil or any other field&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;#x201C;legal frameworks&amp;#x201D; is defined broadly to encompass laws, mechanisms and policies/plans to &amp;#x2018;promote, enforce and monitor&amp;#x2019; gender equality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legal frameworks that &amp;#x201C;promote&amp;#x201D; are those that establish women&amp;#x2019;s equal rights with men and enshrine non-discrimination on the basis of sex. Legal frameworks that &amp;#x201C;enforce and monitor&amp;#x2019; are directed to the realization of equality and non-discrimination and implementation of laws, such as policies/plans, establishment of enforcement and monitoring mechanisms, and allocation of financial resources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; The areas of law were agreed at the expert workshop, held on 14 and 15 June 2016, to discuss the methodological development of SDG indicator 5.1.1. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Définitions :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur 5.1.1 mesure les efforts du gouvernement pour mettre en place des cadres juridiques qui favorisent, appliquent et surveillent l&apos;égalité des sexes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur est basé sur une évaluation des cadres juridiques qui favorisent, appliquent et surveillent l&apos;égalité des sexes. L&apos;évaluation est effectuée par des homologues nationaux, y compris les bureaux nationaux de statistique et/ou les mécanismes nationaux de la femme, et des praticiens/chercheurs juridiques sur l&apos;égalité des sexes, à l&apos;aide d&apos;un questionnaire comprenant 42 questions oui/non dans quatre domaines du droit : (i) cadres juridiques généraux et vie publique; (ii) violence à l&apos;égard des femmes; (iii) emploi et avantages économiques; et (iv) mariage et famille&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Les domaines de droit et les questions sont tirés du cadre juridique et politique international sur l&apos;égalité des sexes, en particulier la Convention sur l&apos;élimination de toutes les formes de discrimination à l&apos;égard des femmes (CEDEF), qui compte 189 États parties, et le Programme d&apos;action de Beijing. Il n&apos;est donc pas nécessaire d&apos;adopter une nouvelle norme internationale sur l&apos;égalité et la non-discrimination fondée sur le sexe. Les principales sources d&apos;information pertinentes pour l&apos;indicateur 5.1.1 sont la législation et les politiques/plans d&apos;action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les 42 questions du questionnaire sont :&lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;h2&gt;Domaine 1 : Cadres juridiques généraux et vie publique&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Promouvoir&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Si le droit coutumier est une source de droit valide en vertu de la constitution, est-il invalide s&apos;il viole les dispositions constitutionnelles sur l&apos;égalité ou la non-discrimination ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Si le droit personnel est une source de droit valide en vertu de la constitution, est-il invalide s&apos;il viole les dispositions constitutionnelles sur l&apos;égalité ou la non-discrimination ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Existe-t-il une loi sur la discrimination qui interdit la discrimination directe et indirecte à l&apos;égard des femmes ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les femmes et les hommes bénéficient-ils des mêmes droits et de l&apos;égalité d&apos;accès aux fonctions publiques et politiques (législatif, exécutif, judiciaire) ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Est-il prévu des quotas pour les femmes (sièges réservés) au sein du parlement national ou des quotas pour les femmes sur les listes de candidats à ce parlement ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les femmes et les hommes ont-ils les mêmes droits de conférer la citoyenneté à leur conjoint et à leurs enfants ? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Appliquer et surveiller &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La loi établit-elle un organisme indépendant spécialisé chargé de recevoir les plaintes pour discrimination fondée sur le sexe (p. ex., institution nationale des droits de l&apos;homme, commission des femmes, médiateur(trice)) ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;L&apos;aide judiciaire est-elle mandatée en matière pénale ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;L&apos;aide judiciaire est-elle obligatoire en matière civile/familiale ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Le témoignage d&apos;une femme a-t-il la même force probante au tribunal que celui d&apos;un homme ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Y a-t-il des lois qui exigent explicitement la production et/ou la diffusion de statistiques sur le genre ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Est-il prévu des sanctions en cas de non-respect des quotas obligatoires sur les listes de candidats, ou des incitations pour les partis politiques à présenter des candidates aux élections parlementaires nationales ? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Domaine 2 : Violence à l&apos;égard des femmes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Promouvoir&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Est-ce qu&apos;il existe une législation traitant spécifiquement de la violence domestique ?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les dispositions exemptant les auteurs de violences de faire face à des accusations de viol si l&apos;auteur épouse la victime après le crime ont-elles été supprimées, ou n&apos;ont-elles jamais existé dans la législation ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les dispositions réduisant les peines en cas de crimes dits d&apos;honneur ont-elles été supprimées, ou n&apos;ont-elles jamais existé dans la législation ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les lois sur le viol sont-elles fondées sur l&apos;absence de consentement, sans exiger la preuve de la force physique ou de la pénétration ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La législation criminalise-t-elle explicitement le viol conjugal ou permet-elle à une femme de porter plainte pour viol contre son mari ou son partenaire ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Y a-t-il une législation qui traite spécifiquement du harcèlement sexuel ? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Appliquer et surveiller&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Y a-t-il des engagements budgétaires prévus par les entités gouvernementales pour la mise en œuvre de la législation traitant de la violence à l&apos;égard des femmes en créant une obligation pour le gouvernement de fournir un budget ou une allocation de fonds pour la mise en œuvre de programmes ou d&apos;activités pertinents ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Des engagements budgétaires sont-ils prévus par les entités gouvernementales pour la mise en œuvre de la législation traitant de la violence à l&apos;égard des femmes en allouant un budget spécifique, un financement et/ou des incitations pour soutenir les organisations non gouvernementales pour des activités visant à lutter contre la violence à l&apos;égard des femmes ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Existe-t-il un plan d&apos;action ou une politique nationale pour lutter contre la violence à l&apos;égard des femmes qui est supervisé par un mécanisme national ayant pour mandat de surveiller et d&apos;examiner sa mise en œuvre ? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Domaine 3 : Emploi et avantages économiques&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Promouvoir&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La loi impose-t-elle la non-discrimination sur la base du sexe dans l&apos;emploi ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La loi impose-t-elle une rémunération égale pour un travail de valeur égale ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les femmes peuvent-elles travailler dans des emplois jugés dangereux, pénibles ou moralement inappropriés au même titre que les hommes ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les femmes peuvent-elles travailler dans les mêmes industries que les hommes ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les femmes sont-elles capables d&apos;effectuer les mêmes tâches que les hommes ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La loi permet-elle aux femmes de travailler les mêmes heures de nuit que les hommes ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La loi prévoit-elle un congé de maternité ou parental accessible aux mères conformément aux normes de l&apos;OIT ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La loi prévoit-elle un congé de paternité ou parental rémunéré à la disposition des pères ou des partenaires ? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Appliquer et surveiller&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Est-ce qu&apos;il existe une entité publique qui peut recevoir des plaintes pour discrimination sexuelle dans l&apos;emploi ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les services de garde d&apos;enfants sont-ils fournis ou subventionnés par l&apos;État ? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Domaine 4 : Mariage et famille&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Promouvoir&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;L&apos;âge minimum du mariage est-il d&apos;au moins 18 ans, sans exception légale, pour les femmes comme pour les hommes ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les femmes et les hommes ont-ils les mêmes droits de contracter un mariage (c&apos;est-à-dire de consentir) et de demander le divorce ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les femmes et les hommes ont-ils les mêmes droits d&apos;être le tuteur légal de leurs enfants pendant et après le mariage ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les femmes et les hommes ont-ils des droits égaux à être reconnus comme chef de famille ou chef de ménage ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les femmes et les hommes ont-ils les mêmes droits pour choisir leur lieu de vie ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les femmes et les hommes ont-ils les mêmes droits pour choisir une profession ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les femmes et les hommes ont-ils les mêmes droits pour obtenir une carte d&apos;identité ?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les femmes et les hommes ont-ils les mêmes droits pour demander un passeport ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les femmes et les hommes ont-ils des droits égaux en matière de propriété, d&apos;accès et de contrôle des biens matrimoniaux, y compris en cas de divorce ? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Appliquer et surveiller &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Le mariage avant l&apos;âge légal est-il nul ou annulable ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Est-ce qu&apos;il existe des tribunaux de la famille dédiés et spécialisés ? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;article 1 de la CEDEF donne une définition complète de la discrimination à l&apos;égard des femmes couvrant la discrimination directe et indirecte et l&apos;article 2 énonce les obligations générales des États, en particulier sur les cadres juridiques requis, pour éliminer la discrimination à l&apos;égard des femmes. L&apos;article 1 de la CEDEF stipule : &quot; ... le terme « discrimination à l&apos;égard des femmes » désigne toute distinction, exclusion ou restriction fondée sur le sexe qui a pour effet ou pour but de compromettre ou de détruire la reconnaissance, jouissance ou l&apos;exercice par les femmes, quel que soit leur état matrimonial, sur la base de l&apos;égalité de l&apos;homme et de la femme, des droits de l&apos;homme et des libertés fondamentales dans les domaines politique, économique, social, culturel et civil ou dans tout autre domaine&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le terme « cadres juridiques » est défini de manière large pour englober les lois, les mécanismes et les politiques/plans visant à « promouvoir, appliquer et surveiller » l&apos;égalité des sexes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les cadres juridiques qui « promeuvent » sont ceux qui établissent l&apos;égalité des droits des femmes avec les hommes et consacrent la non-discrimination sur la base du sexe. Les cadres juridiques qui « appliquent et surveillent » sont orientés vers la réalisation de l&apos;égalité et de la non-discrimination et l&apos;application des lois, comme les politiques/plans, la mise en place de mécanismes d&apos;application et de surveillance, et l&apos;allocation de ressources financières.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Les domaines du droit ont été convenus lors de l&apos;atelier d&apos;experts, qui s&apos;est tenu les 14 et 15 juin 2016, pour discuter de l&apos;élaboration méthodologique de l&apos;indicateur 5.1.1 des ODD. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
