<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 5-a-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;For the purpose of the official reporting at the global level, ONLY the proxies localized in the primary and/or secondary law will be reported because of their binding nature. The only exception to this rule is Proxy D where also national wide programs are considered for the purpose of the assessment. However, for the meaningfulness of the assessment, relevant policies are considered for the analysis because they represent the foundations of the law setting out the principles that indicate the direction towards which the country aims to move and very often suggest reforms that need to be adopted in the legal framework. In this sense, if the proxies are present in these types of instruments they constitute an important step towards a more gender sensitive legal framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data are extracted directly from the laws in force at the moment when the assessment is carried out. Data collection/provision entails the assessment of the relevant laws to determine if the six proxies are present or not in the legal framework. Data will be compiled in an electronic questionnaire organized as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Section 1: General Instructions &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022;. Respondant Information&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; Instructions for filling the questionnaire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Section 2: Legal Assessment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022;. Checklist of policy and legal instruments relevant for the assessment in order to guide the expert in the identification of the proxies in the policy and legal framework of the country analysed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022;. Form 1 &amp;#x201C;Policy and legal instruments, including provisions for Proxy (x)&amp;#x201D;. This form composed of a set of questions to be answered (YES or No) to determine if the proxy is present. The details of the instruments containing the Proxy are to be provided in this form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022;. Form 2 &amp;#x201C;results of Assessment &amp;#x2013; Proxy (x)&amp;#x201D;. This form summarizes the results of the assessment for each proxy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Section 3: Summary of the Assessment (Country Results)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To complete the indicator 5.a.2 assessment, national legal experts must examine the national legal and policy framework and complete the electronic questionnaire following the methodological guidelines. This involves three steps that must be repeated for each proxy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Collect all the relevant policy and legal documents, using the checklist contained in the electronic questionnaire as a guide as to the instruments to check for the concerned proxy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Using the detailed methodological guidelines, determine whether the proxy exists in the legal and policy framework and in which instruments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Complete the questionnaire for each proxy, citing the instrument and the relevant provisions where the proxy was located as well as any further relevant information or exception. Include a hyperlink to the text of the legal and policy instrument. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After these three steps have been undertaken for all six proxies the national responsible institution will identify the level of protection to women&amp;#x2019;s land rights present in the legal framework according to the number of proxies located. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The filled questionnaire will be communicated to FAO for the quality control and global reporting to the UN SDGs Secretariat.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Aux fins de l’établissement de rapports officiels au niveau mondial, SEULS les items retrouvés dans le droit primaire et/ou secondaire seront déclarés en raison de leur caractère contraignant. La seule exception à cette règle est l&apos;item D où des programmes à l’échelle nationale sont également pris en compte aux fins de l’évaluation. Cependant, pour la pertinence de l’évaluation, les politiques pertinentes sont prises en compte pour l’analyse parce qu’elles représentent les fondements de la loi établissant les principes qui indiquent la direction vers laquelle le pays vise à aller et suggèrent très souvent des réformes qui doivent être adoptées dans le cadre juridique. En ce sens, si les items sont présents dans ces types d’instruments, ils constituent une étape importante vers un cadre juridique plus sensible au genre. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont extraites directement des lois en vigueur au moment où l’évaluation est effectuée. La collecte/déclaration de données implique l’évaluation des lois pertinentes pour déterminer si les six items sont présents ou non dans le cadre juridique. Les données seront compilées dans un questionnaire électronique organisé comme suit :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Section 1 : Instructions générales &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; Informations sur le répondant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; Instructions pour remplir le questionnaire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Section 2 : Évaluation juridique&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; Liste de contrôle des instruments politiques et juridiques pertinents pour l’évaluation afin de guider l’expert dans l’identification des items dans le cadre politique et juridique du pays analysé. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; Formulaire 1 « Politique et instruments juridiques, y compris les dispositions relatives à l&apos;item (x) ». Ce formulaire est composé d’un ensemble de questions auxquelles il faut répondre (OUI ou NON) pour déterminer si l&apos;item est présent. Les détails des instruments contenant l&apos;item doivent être fournis dans ce formulaire. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; Formulaire 2 « Résultats de l’évaluation – Item (x) ». Ce formulaire résume les résultats de l’évaluation pour chaque item. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Section 3 : Résumé de l’évaluation (résultats par pays)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour compléter l’évaluation de l’indicateur 5.a.2, les experts juridiques nationaux doivent examiner le cadre juridique et politique national et remplir le questionnaire électronique en suivant les lignes directrices méthodologiques. Cela implique trois étapes qui doivent être répétées pour chaque item. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Rassembler tous les documents politiques et juridiques pertinents, en utilisant la liste de contrôle contenue dans le questionnaire électronique comme guide quant aux instruments pour vérifier l&apos;item concerné. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. À l’aide des lignes directrices méthodologiques détaillées, déterminer si l&apos;item existe dans le cadre juridique et politique et dans quels instruments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Remplir le questionnaire pour chaque item, en citant l’instrument et les dispositions pertinentes où l&apos;item était situé, ainsi que toute autre information ou exception pertinente. Inclure un lien hypertexte vers le texte de l’instrument juridique et politique. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Une fois ces trois étapes franchies pour les six items, l’institution nationale responsable identifiera le niveau de protection des droits fonciers des femmes présents dans le cadre juridique en fonction du nombre d&apos;items localisés. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le questionnaire rempli sera envoyé à la FAO pour le contrôle de la qualité et le rapport mondial au Secrétariat des ODD de l’ONU. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
