<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 5-a-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The qualitative and legal nature of this indicator required the development of a nuanced and articulated methodology that could be feasible, universally relevant and meaningful. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The computation of results under Indicator 5.a.2 involves two steps: (1) classification of the country according to the number of proxies located &lt;strong&gt;in primary or primary and secondary legislation&lt;/strong&gt; and (2) consolidation of all country results for global reporting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Step 1: Classification categories of country &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The country will be classified according to the total number of proxies found in &lt;u&gt;primary legislation&lt;/u&gt; or &lt;u&gt;primary and secondary legislation&lt;/u&gt;. Given that &lt;strong&gt;not all countries&lt;/strong&gt; recognize customary land tenure or customary law (related to proxy E), a dual approach for computing national results has been developed: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For countries where customary land tenure is &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; recognized in the legal framework (either via statute or the constitution), regardless of whether it exists &lt;em&gt;de facto &lt;/em&gt;or not, Proxy E is marked &lt;strong&gt;non-applicable&lt;/strong&gt; and the country will be assessed out of the five remaining proxies. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For countries where customary land tenure is recognized in the legal framework, the country will be assessed against all six proxies,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The table below describes the dual approach for computing results and the classification bands. As is shown below, in countries where customary law is applicable (Proxy E) the presence of five or six proxies are included in the same band (band 6 - very high levels of guarantees). This is due to the necessity of making universal the calculation of the component of customary law, which is not universal and not always formalized in the legal system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table 1: Classification Band System&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result of assessment &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where Proxy E is &lt;u&gt;applicable&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result of assessment &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where Proxy E is &lt;u&gt;not&lt;/u&gt; applicable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Classification &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;None of the six proxies&lt;/u&gt; are present in the primary or primary and secondary legislation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;None of the five proxies&lt;/u&gt; are present in the primary or primary and secondary legislation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Band 1:&lt;/u&gt; No evidence of guarantees of gender equality in the land ownership and/or control in the legal framework.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;One&lt;/u&gt; of the proxies present in primary or primary and secondary legislation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;One of the proxies&lt;/u&gt; present in primary or primary and secondary legislation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Band 2:&lt;/u&gt; Very low levels of guarantees of gender equality in land ownership and/or control in the legal framework.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Two&lt;/u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt; &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;the proxies&lt;/u&gt; present in primary or primary and secondary legislation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Two of the proxies&lt;/u&gt; present in primary and secondary legislation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Band 3:&lt;/u&gt; Low levels of guarantees of gender equality in land ownership and/or control in the legal framework.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Three of the proxies&lt;/u&gt; are present in primary legislation or primary and secondary legislation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Three of the proxies&lt;/u&gt; are present in primary legislation or primary and secondary legislation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Band 4:&lt;/u&gt; Medium levels of guarantees of gender equality in land ownership and/or control in the legal framework.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Four of the proxies &lt;/u&gt;are present in primary legislation or primary and secondary legislation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Four of the proxies&lt;/u&gt; are present in primary legislation or primary and secondary legislation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Band 5:&lt;/u&gt; High levels of guarantees of gender equality in land ownership and/or control in the legal framework.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Five or six proxies&lt;/u&gt; are present in primary legislation or primary and secondary legislation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;All five proxies&lt;/u&gt; are present in primary legislation or primary and secondary legislation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Band 6:&lt;/u&gt; Very high levels of guarantees of gender equality in land ownership and/or control in the legal framework.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the methodology all proxies have an equal weight. This implies that no dimension is more important than another in terms of supporting gender equality in land ownership and/or control.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;La nature qualitative et juridique de cet indicateur exigeait l’élaboration d’une méthodologie nuancée et articulée qui pourrait être réalisable, universellement pertinente et significative. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le calcul des résultats au titre de l’indicateur 5.a.2 comporte deux étapes : (1) classification du pays en fonction du nombre d&apos;items retrouvés dans la &lt;strong&gt;législation primaire&lt;/strong&gt; ou dans la &lt;strong&gt; législation primaire et secondaire&lt;/strong&gt; et (2) consolidation de tous les résultats par pays pour la déclaration mondiale. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Étape 1 : Catégories de classification des pays &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le pays sera classé en fonction du nombre total d&apos;items retrouvés dans la &lt;u&gt;législation primaire&lt;/u&gt; ou dans la &lt;u&gt;législation primaire et secondaire&lt;/u&gt;. Étant donné que &lt;strong&gt;tous les pays ne reconnaissent pas&lt;/strong&gt; le régime foncier coutumier ou le droit coutumier (lié à l&apos;item E), une double approche pour le calcul des résultats nationaux a été développée : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pour les pays où le régime foncier coutumier n’est &lt;strong&gt;PAS&lt;/strong&gt; reconnu dans le cadre juridique (soit par la loi ou la constitution), qu’il existe &lt;em&gt;de facto&lt;/em&gt; ou non, l&apos;item E est marqué &lt;strong&gt;sans objet&lt;/strong&gt; et le pays sera évalué parmi les cinq items restants. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pour les pays où le régime foncier coutumier est reconnu dans le cadre juridique, le pays sera évalué par rapport aux six items.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le tableau ci-dessous décrit la double approche pour le calcul des résultats et les groupes de classification. Comme indiqué ci-dessous, dans les pays où le droit coutumier s&apos;applique (item E), la présence de cinq ou six items est incluse dans le même groupe (groupe 6 - niveaux de garanties très élevés). Cela est dû à la nécessité de rendre universel le calcul de la composante du droit coutumier qui n’est pas universelle et n&apos;est pas toujours reconnue dans le système juridique. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tableau 1 : Système de classification en groupes (bandes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Résultat de l’évaluation &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Où l&apos;item E &lt;u&gt;s&apos;applique&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Résultat de l’évaluation &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Où l&apos;item E &lt;u&gt;ne s&apos;applique pas&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Classification &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Aucun des six items&lt;/u&gt; n’est présent dans la législation primaire ou primaire et secondaire&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Aucun des cinq items&lt;/u&gt; n’est présent dans la législation primaire ou primaire et secondaire&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Groupe 1&lt;/u&gt; : Aucune preuve de garanties d’égalité des sexes en matière de propriété foncière et/ou de contrôle dans le cadre juridique. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Un des items&lt;/u&gt; présents dans la législation primaire ou primaire et secondaire&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Un des items&lt;/u&gt; présents dans la législation primaire ou primaire et secondaire&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Groupe 2&lt;/u&gt; : Très faibles niveaux de garanties d’égalité des sexes en matière de propriété foncière et/ou de contrôle dans le cadre juridique. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Deux des items&lt;/u&gt; présents dans la législation primaire ou primaire et secondaire&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Deux des items&lt;/u&gt; présents dans la législation primaire ou primaire et secondaire&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Groupe 3&lt;/u&gt; : Faibles niveaux de garanties d’égalité des sexes en matière de propriété foncière et/ou de contrôle dans le cadre juridique. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Trois des items&lt;/u&gt; sont présents dans la législation primaire ou primaire et secondaire&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Trois des items&lt;/u&gt; sont présents dans la législation primaire ou primaire et secondaire&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Groupe 4&lt;/u&gt; : Niveaux moyens de garanties d’égalité des sexes en matière de propriété foncière et/ou de contrôle dans le cadre juridique. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Quatre des items&lt;/u&gt; sont présents dans la législation primaire ou primaire et secondaire&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Quatre des items&lt;/u&gt; sont présents dans la législation primaire ou primaire et secondaire&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Groupe 5&lt;/u&gt; : Niveaux élevés de garanties d&apos;égalité des sexes en matière de propriété foncière et/ou de contrôle dans le cadre juridique.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
       &lt;td&gt;
         &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Cinq ou six items&lt;/u&gt; sont présents dans la législation primaire ou primaire et secondaire&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;/td&gt;
       &lt;td&gt;
         &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Les cinq items&lt;/u&gt; sont présents dans la législation primaire ou primaire et secondaire&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;/td&gt;
       &lt;td&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Groupe 6&lt;/u&gt; : Niveaux très élevés de garanties d&apos;égalité des sexes en matière de propriété foncière et/ou de contrôle dans le cadre juridique.&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
   &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selon la méthodologie, tous les items ont un poids égal. Cela implique qu&apos;aucune dimension n&apos;est plus importante qu&apos;une autre en termes de soutien à l&apos;égalité des sexes en matière de propriété et/ou de contrôle des terres.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
