<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 5-a-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Customary law. Indicator 5.a.2 entails an important challenge in terms of the assessment and computation of the results due to the reference to customary law in the title of the indicator. Customary law is not a homogenous system of law. Therefore, unless it is recognised by the general legal system, it will be extremely difficult to monitor whether or not customary law guarantees men and women equal rights to land ownership and(/or) control. In order to guarantee feasibility of the assessment, the choice of the methodology has been to monitor customary law to the extent that it has been recognised in the legal framework of a country. This however is a major limitation for the purposes of the SDGs of &amp;#x201C;leaving no one behind&amp;#x2019; as it excludes from the assessment many legal systems where customary practices which have not been endorsed in statutory law which are one of the major factors of discrimination against women. Further, given that customary law does not exist in all countries, it is not universally applicable and computation of the results represents a major challenge. The methodology has addressed this issue by creating a dual system of computation of the results which allows to assess separately those systems where customary law has been recognized, and those where no recognition of customary law is present. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geographical scope. The data collected for the SDG indicators is collected at the national level to ensure that it is representative of the country situation. This means that the 5.a.2 assessment to determine the existence of the proxies should focus on legal and policy instruments that have nationwide authority. In countries where law-making power for land or gender matters are not within the authority of the national government (or are shared between the national government and a sub-national government level), there may be a number of different state/provincial or county laws and policy that can be analysed. Further there may be inconsistencies between these different sub-national laws in terms of the presence of a proxy and the degree of its integration in the legal and policy framework. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where this is the case, the assessment should be conducted in as many states or counties needed to cover at least 50 percent of the total country&amp;#x2019;s population. Therefore, the proxy should be located in all of the legal and policy frameworks relevant to these locations. If it is not the case, the proxy is not present.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Droit coutumier. L’indicateur 5.a.2 comporte un défi important en termes d’évaluation et de calcul des résultats en raison de la référence au droit coutumier dans le titre de l’indicateur. Le droit coutumier n’est pas un système de droit homogène. Par conséquent, à moins qu’il ne soit reconnu par le système juridique général, il sera extrêmement difficile de contrôler si le droit coutumier garantit ou non aux hommes et aux femmes des droits égaux à la propriété foncière et (/ou) au contrôle. Afin de garantir la faisabilité de l’évaluation, le choix de la méthodologie a été de contrôler le droit coutumier dans la mesure où il a été reconnu dans le cadre juridique d’un pays. Il s’agit toutefois d’une limite majeure aux fins des ODD de « ne laisser personne de côté » car elle exclut de l’évaluation de nombreux systèmes juridiques où les pratiques coutumières qui n’ont pas été approuvées dans le droit statutaire sont l’un des principaux facteurs de discrimination à l’égard des femmes. En outre, étant donné que le droit coutumier n’existe pas dans tous les pays, il n’est pas universellement applicable et le calcul des résultats représente un défi majeur. La méthodologie a résolu cette question en créant un double système de calcul des résultats qui permet d’évaluer séparément les systèmes où le droit coutumier a été reconnu et ceux où aucune reconnaissance du droit coutumier n’est présente. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Portée géographique. Les données recueillies pour les indicateurs des ODD sont recueillies au niveau national pour s’assurer qu’elles sont représentatives de la situation du pays. Cela signifie que l’évaluation de 5.a.2 visant à déterminer l’existence des items devrait se concentrer sur les instruments juridiques et politiques qui ont une autorité nationale. Dans les pays où le pouvoir législatif en matière foncière ou de genre ne relève pas de l’autorité du gouvernement national (ou est partagé entre le gouvernement national et un niveau de gouvernement infranational), il peut y avoir un certain nombre de lois et de politiques d’État, provinciales ou de comté différentes qui peuvent être analysées. En outre, il peut y avoir des incohérences entre ces différentes lois infranationales en ce qui concerne la présence d’un item et le degré de son intégration dans le cadre juridique et politique. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lorsque c’est le cas, l’évaluation devrait être menée dans autant d’États ou de comtés nécessaires pour couvrir au moins 50% de la population totale du pays. Par conséquent, l&apos;item doit être situé dans tous les cadres juridiques et stratégiques pertinents pour ces emplacements. Si ce n’est pas le cas, l&apos;item n’est pas présent. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
