<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 14-3-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;Detailed information in &lt;a href=&quot;https://unesdoc.unesco.org/ark:/48223/pf0000265127?3=null&amp;amp;queryId=f3a23122-f713-4f5c-aa88-5e73275ff5f6&quot;&gt;Attachment I IOC/EC-LI/2 Annex 6&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator calls for the collection of multiple observations, in the form of individual data points, to capture the variability in ocean acidity. Individual data points for pH either are measured directly or can be calculated based on data for two of the other carbonate chemistry parameters, these being TA (AT), DIC (CT) and &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;. Calculation tools developed by experts in the field are freely available, and they are introduced and linked in the methodology. Average pH is defined as the annual equally weighed mean of multiple data points at representative sampling stations. The exact number of samples and data points depends on the level of variability of ocean acidity at the site in question. The minimum number of samples should enable the characterisation of a seasonal cycle at the site. Detailed guidelines on the minimum number of observations required are provided in the Methodology (&lt;a href=&quot;https://oa.iode.org&quot;&gt;https://oa.iode.org&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the data value, standard deviation and the total range (minimum and maximum values measured), as well as underlying data used to provide traceability and transparency (metadata information) should be reported. All reported values should have gone through a first level quality control by the data provider. If historical data is available, this should be released to enable calculations about the rate of change and to compare natural variability and anthropogenic effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relevant data from 2010 onwards are accepted.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
