<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 15-9-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sub-indicator (a)&lt;/strong&gt;: Missing values are not imputed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sub-indicator (b)&lt;/strong&gt;: Missing values will occur if a country does not respond to the Global Assessment. If a country does not respond, missing values will be imputed if the custodian agency can find evidence of implementation, such as online publications of SEEA accounts, or based on information gathered from international organizations on the compilation of SEEA accounts. In particular:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; -If a national statistical office or other government institution has published a SEEA account which is easily accessible online, this country will be imputed as compiling the SEEA. Since no assumption can be made that the country regularly compiles and publishes the account, this country would fall under Stage II.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; -If the custodian agency finds that a country compiles SEEA accounts through a project or other implementation programme and verifies this with the international organizations involved, this country will be imputed as compiling the SEEA under Stage I or Stage II as appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all cases, imputation is only be done as a secondary step after first contacting countries. All imputations will be clearly flagged for users as imputations by UNSD. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sub-indicator (a)&lt;/strong&gt;: Missing values are considered to be 0 as this indicator refers to reporting processes. Thus if a country does not report it is assumed that there is no corresponding national target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sub-indicator (b)&lt;/strong&gt;: A simple count of countries will be used.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
