<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 6-2-1a, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JMP method uses a simple regression model to generate time series estimates for all years including for years without data points. The JMP then shares all its estimates using its country consultation mechanism to get consensus from countries before publishing its estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regional and global estimates for safely managed sanitation services are calculated if there are (non-imputed) data on the management of the dominant form of improved sanitation (sewer connections or on-site systems) for at least 30% of the relevant population (i.e. the population using sewer connections or on-site improved sanitation systems) within the region. In order to produce estimates for regional or global levels, imputed estimates are produced for countries lacking data. Imputed country estimates are not published and only used for aggregation. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Au niveau national :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La méthode du JMP utilise un modèle de régression simple pour générer des estimations de séries chronologiques pour toutes les années, y compris pour les années sans points de données. Le JMP partage ensuite toutes ses estimations en utilisant son mécanisme de consultation par pays pour obtenir un consensus des pays avant de publier ses estimations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aux niveaux régional et mondial :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des estimations régionales et mondiales pour les services d’assainissement gérés en toute sécurité sont calculées s’il existe des données (non imputées) sur la gestion de la forme dominante d’assainissement amélioré (raccordements aux égouts ou systèmes sur site) pour au moins 30 % de la population concernée (c.-à-d. la population utilisant des raccordements aux égouts ou des systèmes d’assainissement améliorés sur place) dans la région. Afin de produire des estimations aux niveaux régional ou mondial, des estimations imputées sont produites pour les pays qui ne disposent pas de données. Les estimations nationales imputées ne sont pas publiées et ne sont utilisées qu’à des fins d’agrégation.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
