<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REG_AGG field for indicator 6-2-1a, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;For safely managed sanitation services, the regional population using sewer connections is used to weight estimates of the proportion of wastewater treated, while the population using improved on-site facilities is used to weight estimates of the proportion of the population with excreta disposed in situ. Where data coverage for the nondominant form of sanitation is below 30%, estimates are based only on the dominant form of sanitation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regional and global estimates of the population using safely managed services are then calculated by separately summing the populations with on-site and sewered safely managed services. Where data coverage for the relevant population is above 30% in both rural and urban areas, a weighted average is used to produce total regional and global estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These estimates are calculated separately for urban and rural areas and, where possible, a weighted average is made of rural and urban populations to produce total estimates for the region or world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details on JMP rules and methods: JMP Methodology: 2017 update and SDG baselines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-methodology-2017-update&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-methodology-2017-update&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Pour les services d’assainissement gérés en toute sécurité, la population régionale utilisant des raccordements d’égout est utilisée pour pondérer les estimations de la proportion d’eaux usées traitées, tandis que la population utilisant des installations améliorées sur place est utilisée pour pondérer les estimations de la proportion de la population dont les excréments sont éliminés in situ. Lorsque la couverture des données pour la forme non dominante d’assainissement est inférieure à 30 %, les estimations ne sont basées que sur la forme dominante d’assainissement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les estimations régionales et mondiales de la population utilisant des services gérés en toute sécurité sont ensuite calculées en additionnant séparément les populations avec des services gérés sur site et en toute sécurité. Lorsque la couverture des données pour la population concernée est supérieure à 30 % dans les zones rurales et urbaines, une moyenne pondérée est utilisée pour produire des estimations régionales et mondiales totales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ces estimations sont calculées séparément pour les zones urbaines et rurales et, dans la mesure du possible, une moyenne pondérée est faite des populations rurales et urbaines pour produire des estimations totales pour la région ou le monde. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour plus de détails sur les règles et méthodes du JMP : « JMP Methodology: 2017 update and SDG baselines » :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-methodology-2017-update&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-methodology-2017-update&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
