<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 17-16-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator tracks the number of countries reporting progress in multi-stakeholder monitoring frameworks that track the implementation of development effectiveness commitments supporting the achievement of sustainable development goals (SDGs). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x201C;Multi-stakeholder development effectiveness monitoring frameworks&amp;#x201D; that track effective development cooperation are monitoring frameworks: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; whose indicators have been agreed on a voluntary basis; whose indicators measure the strength of the relationship between development actors; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; where data collection and review are led by the countries themselves; and where participation in data collection and review involves relevant stakeholders representing, at minimum, the public sector, the private sector and civil society organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator takes into account the need to capture the respective roles and responsibilities of all parties involved in multi-stakeholder partnerships for development. It does so by looking at development effectiveness frameworks that are led by countries but include the participation of all relevant development partners. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Global Partnership for Effective Development Cooperation (Global Partnership) monitoring framework is an example of existing development effectiveness monitoring frameworks. There are other complementary efforts, such as the United Nations Economic and Social Council (ECOSOC) Development Cooperation Forum (DCF) mutual accountability survey. Emerging and future monitoring frameworks that fit the above definition, such as recent efforts to track South-South Cooperation by the Ibero-American General Secretariat (SEGIB), could also be considered.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
