<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for the indicator 17-18-3, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;Goal 17: Strengthen the means of implementation and revitalize the Global Partnership for Sustainable Development&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 17.18: By 2020, enhance capacity-building support to developing countries, including for least developed countries and small island developing States, to increase significantly the availability of high-quality, timely and reliable data disaggregated by income, gender, age, race, ethnicity, migratory status, disability, geographic location and other characteristics relevant in national contexts&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 17.18.3: Number of countries with a national statistical plan that is fully funded and under implementation, by source of funding&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last updated: 11 July 2017&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Related indicators as of February 2020&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17.19.1: Dollar value of all resources made available to strengthen statistical capacity in developing countries&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Institutional information&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organization(s):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partnership in Statistics for Development in the 21st Century (PARIS21)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator Number of countries with a national statistical plan that is fully funded and under implementation is based on the annual Status Report on National Strategies for the Development of Statistics (NSDS). In collaboration with its partners, PARIS21 reports on country progress in designing and implementing national statistical plans. The indicator is a count of countries that are either (i) implementing a strategy, (ii) designing one or (iii) awaiting adoption of the strategy in the current year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data is provided by the National Statistical Offices. The information is collected annually and verified by direct email correspondence with the national focal point for the country&amp;apos;s NSDS (National Strategy for Development of Statistics).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;List:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National Statistical Offices&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendar&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Data collection:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jan-17&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Data release:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1-Feb-2017&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data providers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Name:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PARIS21&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data compilers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PARIS21&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computation method:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple count of countries that are either (i) implementing a strategy, (ii) designing one or (iii) awaiting adoption of the strategy in the current year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Regional aggregates:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regional-level aggregates are based on the total count of national strategies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Methods and guidance available to countries for the compilation of the data at the national level:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PARIS21 SDG Survey through online form + PARIS21 annual NSDS status report (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paris21.org/nsds-status&quot;&gt;http://www.paris21.org/nsds-status&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NSDS Guideline (&lt;a href=&quot;http://nsdsguidelines.paris21.org/&quot;&gt;http://nsdsguidelines.paris21.org/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Quality assurance:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consultation with countries to check information available online&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data availability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current time series for 2007-2015 covers 121 developing countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Time series:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2007 to 2015&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator can be disaggregated by geographical area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;www.paris21.org&quot;&gt;www.paris21.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PARIS21 (2016). NSDS Status Report. Available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paris21.org/nsds-status&quot;&gt;http://www.paris21.org/nsds-status&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
