<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 6-5-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before starting the SDG reporting process, data were not included in the National Statistical Systems but the information needed to calculate the indicator is simple, does not require advanced monitoring capacities and is normally available to all countries at the ministries or agencies responsible for water resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data is available for the 153 countries having territorial borders in a number of existing databases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data would be most reliably collected at the national level. Basin level data can also be disaggregated to country level (for national reporting) and aggregated to regional and global level.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos no están incluidos hasta ahora en los Sistemas Estadísticos Nacionales, pero la información necesaria para calcular el indicador es sencilla, no requiere capacidades avanzadas de seguimiento y normalmente está disponible para todos los países en los ministerios u organismos responsables de los recursos hídricos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos de los 154 países con fronteras territoriales están disponibles en varias bases de datos existentes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asia y Pacífico: 39&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;África: 47&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;América Latina y el Caribe: 22 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Europa, América del Norte, Australia, Nueva Zelanda y Japón: 46&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No disponibles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos se recopilarían de forma más fiable a nivel nacional. Los datos a nivel de cuenca también pueden desagregarse a nivel de país (para la elaboración de informes nacionales) y agregarse a nivel regional y mundial.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilité des données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données ne sont pas encore incluses dans les systèmes statistiques nationaux, mais les informations nécessaires pour calculer l&apos;indicateur sont simples, ne nécessitent pas de capacités de suivi avancées et sont normalement disponibles pour tous les pays auprès des ministères ou des agences responsables des ressources en eau.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont disponibles pour les 154 pays ayant des frontières territoriales dans un certain nombre de bases de données existantes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Asie et Pacifique : 39 &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Afrique : 47 &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amérique latine et Caraïbes : 22 &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Europe, Amérique du Nord, Australie, Nouvelle-Zélande et Japon : 46&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Séries chronologiques : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NA &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Désaggrégation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données seraient recueillies de la manière la plus fiable au niveau national&lt;p&gt;. Les données au niveau des bassins peuvent également être désagrégées au niveau des pays (pour les rapports nationaux) et agrégées au niveau régional et mondial. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные пока не включены в национальные статистические системы, но информация, необходимая для расчета показателя, проста и не требует продвинутых возможностей мониторинга и обычно доступна для всех стран в министерствах или ведомствах, ответственных за водные ресурсы. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные доступны по 154 странам, имеющим территориальные границы, в ряде существующих баз данных. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Азиатско-Тихоокеанский регион: 39 &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Африка: 47 &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Латинская Америка и Карибский бассейн: 22 &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Европа, Северная Америка, Австралия, Новая Зеландия и Япония: 46 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Не доступно &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные будут наиболее надежно собираться на национальном уровне. Данные на уровне бассейна также могут быть дезагрегированы на страновом уровне (для национальной отчетности) и агрегированы на региональном и глобальном уровнях. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
