<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_SOURCE field for indicator 6-5-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Data are not so far included in the National Statistical Systems but the information needed to calculate the indicator is simple, does not require advanced monitoring capacities and is normally available to all countries at the ministries or agencies responsible for water resources. Spatial information (&amp;#x201C;transboundary basin area&amp;#x201D;) is normally available in ministries in charge of water resources. The value of this component is relatively fixed although the precision may vary (especially on aquifers), and may require only limited update on the basis of improved knowledge. Regarding operationality of arrangement the data needed for calculating the indicator can be directly obtained from information from administrative records (Member States have records of cooperation arrangements).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos no están incluidos hasta ahora en los Sistemas Estadísticos Nacionales, pero la información necesaria para calcular el indicador es sencilla, no requiere capacidades avanzadas de seguimiento y normalmente está disponible para todos los países en los ministerios u organismos responsables de los recursos hídricos. La información espacial (&amp;#x201C;área de la cuenca transfronteriza&amp;#x201D;) suele estar disponible en los ministerios encargados de los recursos hídricos. El valor de este componente es relativamente fijo, aunque la precisión puede variar (especialmente en lo que respecta a los acuíferos), y puede requerir sólo una actualización limitada en función de la mejora de los conocimientos. En cuanto a la operatividad de los acuerdos, los datos necesarios para calcular el indicador pueden obtenerse directamente de la información de los registros administrativos (los Estados miembros tienen registros de los acuerdos de cooperación).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Fournisseurs de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données ne sont pas encore incluses dans les systèmes statistiques nationaux, mais les informations nécessaires pour calculer l&apos;indicateur sont simples, ne nécessitent pas de capacités de suivi avancées et sont normalement disponibles pour tous les pays auprès des ministères ou des agences responsables des ressources en eau. Les informations spatiales (&amp;#x201C;zone de bassin transfrontalier&amp;#x201D;) sont normalement disponibles dans les ministères chargés des ressources en eau. La valeur de cette composante est relativement fixe bien que la précision puisse varier (en particulier sur les aquifères), et peut ne nécessiter qu&apos;une mise à jour limitée sur la base d&apos;une meilleure connaissance. En ce qui concerne l&apos;opérationnalité de l&apos;accord, les données nécessaires au calcul de l&apos;indicateur peuvent être obtenues directement à partir des informations des dossiers administratifs (les États membres ont des dossiers sur les accords de coopération). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Поставщики данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные пока не включены в национальные статистические системы, но информация, необходимая для расчета показателя, проста и не требует продвинутых возможностей мониторинга и обычно доступна во всех странах в министерствах или ведомствах, ответственных за водные ресурсы. Пространственная информация (&quot;территория трансграничного бассейна&quot;) обычно доступна в министерствах, отвечающих за водные ресурсы. Значение этого компонента относительно постоянно, хотя точность может варьироваться (особенно для водоносных горизонтов) и может потребовать лишь ограниченного обновления на основе улучшенных знаний. Что касается механизма договоренности, то данные, необходимые для расчета показателя, могут быть получены непосредственно из информации из административных источников (в государствах-членах есть отчеты по договоренностям о сотрудничестве). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
