<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 6-5-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the country level, ministries and agencies responsible for surface water and groundwater resources (depends on the country but commonly ministry of the environment, water, natural resources, energy or agriculture; institutes of water resources, hydrology or geology, or geological surveys) typically have the spatial information about the location and extent of the surface water basin boundaries and aquifer delineations (as Geographical Information Systems shapefiles). Information on existing arrangement and their operationality is also commonly available from the same institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Regular reporting contributing to the information collection&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reporting under the Convention on the Protection and Use of Transboundary Watercourses and International Lakes (Water Convention) will also gather the information needed for the calculation of the indicator, especially on the cooperation arrangements, transboundary waters covered by them as well as operationality. The Convention&amp;#x2019;s regular reporting on transboundary water cooperation, involving both Parties and non-Parties to the Convention, will collect this information every 3 years as of 2017. The reporting covers trans-boundary rivers, lakes and ground waters. UNESCO IHP will contribute to the reporting on transboundary aquifers. More than 100 countries participate in the Water Convention&amp;#x2019;s activities. The United Nations Economic Commission for Europe acts as Secretariat for the Water Convention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some countries already report to regional organizations on the advancement of transboundary water cooperation, and similar arrangements could be strengthened and facilitated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the absence of available information at the national level global datasets on transboundary basins as well as about agreements and organizations for transboundary cooperation are available, which could be used in the absence of more detailed information, in the short term in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Delineations of transboundary basins&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In global databases, the most up-to-date delineations are available through the Transboundary Waters Assessment Programme (TWAP). TWAP covered 286 main transboundary rivers, 206 transboundary lakes and reservoirs and 199 transboundary aquifers. Relevant information have also been compiled for 592 transboundary aquifers by the UNESCO ISARM project. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cooperation arrangements&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Existence of treaties is available from the International Freshwater Treaties Database, maintained by Oregon State University (OSU). This was last updated to include all arrangements up to 2008. The treaty database includes in total 686 international freshwater treaties. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Organizations for transboundary water cooperation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International River Basin Organization (RBO) Database detailed information about over 120 international river basin organizations, including bilateral commissions, around the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regional assessments describing and inventorying agreements have been undertaken, contributing to the baseline globally, for example, regional inventories of transboundary aquifers under the UNESCO-IHP ISARM.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A nivel nacional, los ministerios y organismos responsables de los recursos hídricos superficiales y subterráneos (depende del país, pero normalmente son los ministerios de medio ambiente, agua, recursos naturales, energía o agricultura; los institutos de recursos hídricos, hidrología o geología, o los estudios geológicos) suelen disponer de la información espacial sobre la ubicación y la extensión de los límites de las cuencas hídricas superficiales y la delimitación de los acuíferos (en forma de archivos shape del Sistema de Información Geográfica). La información sobre la disposición existente y su operatividad también suele estar disponible en las mismas instituciones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Informes periódicos que contribuyen a la recopilación de información&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La presentación de informes en el marco del Convenio sobre la protección y utilización de los cursos de agua transfronterizos y los lagos internacionales (Convenio del Agua) también recogerá la información necesaria para el cálculo del indicador, especialmente sobre los acuerdos de cooperación, las aguas transfronterizas cubiertas por ellos, así como la operatividad. Los informes periódicos del Convenio sobre la cooperación en materia de aguas transfronterizas, en los que participan tanto las Partes como los países que no son parte del Convenio, recogerán esta información cada tres años a partir de 2017. Los informes abarcan los ríos, lagos y aguas subterráneas transfronterizas. El PHI de la UNESCO contribuirá a la presentación de informes sobre los acuíferos transfronterizos. Más de 100 países participan en las actividades del Convenio del Agua. La Comisión Económica para Europa de las Naciones Unidas actúa como Secretaría del Convenio del Agua.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Algunos países ya informan a las organizaciones regionales sobre el avance de la cooperación en materia de aguas transfronterizas, y se podrían reforzar y facilitar acuerdos similares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A falta de información disponible a nivel nacional, existen conjuntos de datos globales sobre cuencas transfronterizas, así como sobre acuerdos y organizaciones de cooperación transfronteriza, que podrían utilizarse a falta de información más detallada, sobre todo a corto plazo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Delimitaciones de cuencas transfronterizas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En las bases de datos mundiales, las delineaciones más actualizadas están disponibles a través del Programa de Evaluación de las Aguas Transfronterizas (TWAP, por sus siglas en inglés). El TWAP abarca 286 ríos transfronterizos principales, 206 lagos y embalses transfronterizos y 199 acuíferos transfronterizos. El proyecto ISARM de la UNESCO también ha recopilado información relevante sobre 592 acuíferos transfronterizos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Acuerdos de cooperación&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La existencia de tratados está disponible en la Base de Datos de Tratados Internacionales de Agua Dulce, mantenida por la Universidad Estatal de Oregón (OSU, por su sigla en inglés). Se ha actualizado por última vez para incluir todos los acuerdos hasta 2008. La base de datos de tratados incluye en total 686 tratados internacionales de agua dulce. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Organizaciones de cooperación en materia de aguas transfronterizas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organismos internacionales de cuenca fluvial (OCF) Base de datos con información detallada sobre más de 120 organismos internacionales de cuenca fluvial, incluidas las comisiones bilaterales, en todo el mundo. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se han llevado a cabo evaluaciones regionales que describen e inventarían los acuerdos, contribuyendo a la línea de base a nivel mundial, por ejemplo, los inventarios regionales de acuíferos transfronterizos en el marco del ISARM del PHI de la UNESCO.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Sources de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Au niveau national, les ministères et agences responsables des ressources en eau de surface et en eaux souterraines (selon le pays, mais généralement le ministère de l&apos;environnement, de l&apos;eau, des ressources naturelles, de l&apos;énergie ou de l&apos;agriculture, les instituts des ressources en eau, d&apos;hydrologie ou de géologie, ou les services géologiques) disposent généralement d&apos;informations spatiales sur l&apos;emplacement et l&apos;étendue des limites des bassins d&apos;eau de surface et des délimitations des aquifères (sous forme de fichiers de forme des systèmes d&apos;information géographique). Les informations sur les dispositions existantes et leur caractère opérationnel sont également généralement disponibles auprès de ces mêmes institutions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Rapports réguliers contribuant à la collecte d&apos;informations &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La communication d&apos;informations au titre de la Convention sur la protection et l&apos;utilisation des cours d&apos;eau transfrontières et des lacs internationaux (Convention sur l&apos;eau) permettra également de recueillir les informations nécessaires au calcul de l&apos;indicateur, notamment sur les accords de coopération, les eaux transfrontières qu&apos;ils couvrent ainsi que l&apos;opérationnalité. Les rapports réguliers de la Convention &amp;#x2019; sur la coopération en matière d&apos;eaux transfrontalières, impliquant à la fois les Parties et les non-Parties à la Convention, collecteront ces informations tous les 3 ans à partir de 2017. Les rapports couvrent les rivières, les lacs et les eaux souterraines transfrontaliers. Le PHI de l&apos;UNESCO contribuera à l&apos;établissement des rapports sur les aquifères transfrontaliers. Plus de 100 pays participent aux activités de la Convention sur l&apos;eau &amp;#x2019;. La Commission économique des Nations unies pour l&apos;Europe fait office de secrétariat de la Convention sur l&apos;eau. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certains pays font déjà rapport aux organisations régionales sur les progrès de la coopération en matière d&apos;eau transfrontalière, et des arrangements similaires pourraient être renforcés et facilités.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En l&apos;absence d&apos;informations disponibles au niveau national, il existe des ensembles de données mondiales sur les bassins transfrontaliers ainsi que sur les accords et organisations de coopération transfrontalière, qui pourraient être utilisés en l&apos;absence d&apos;informations plus détaillées, notamment à court terme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Délimitation des bassins transfrontaliers &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dans les bases de données mondiales, les délimitations les plus récentes sont disponibles par le biais du Programme d&apos;évaluation des eaux transfrontalières (TWAP). Le TWAP a couvert 286 principaux fleuves transfrontaliers, 206 lacs et réservoirs transfrontaliers et 199 aquifères transfrontaliers. Des informations pertinentes ont également été compilées pour 592 aquifères transfrontaliers par le projet ISARM de l&apos;UNESCO. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cooperation arrangements&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;existence des traités est disponible dans la base de données des traités internationaux sur l&apos;eau douce, gérée par l&apos;Oregon State University (OSU). Cette base de données a été mise à jour pour inclure tous les accords conclus jusqu&apos;en 2008. La base de données des traités comprend au total 686 traités internationaux sur l&apos;eau douce. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Organisations de coopération sur les eaux transfrontalières &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La base de données des organisations internationales de bassins fluviaux (RBO) contient des informations détaillées sur plus de 120 organisations internationales de bassins fluviaux, y compris des commissions bilatérales, dans le monde entier. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des évaluations régionales décrivant et inventoriant les accords ont été entreprises, contribuant à la base de référence mondiale, par exemple, les inventaires régionaux des aquifères transfrontaliers dans le cadre de l&apos;ISARM du PHI de l&apos;UNESCO.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; На страновом уровне министерства и агентства, ответственные за ресурсы поверхностных и подземных вод (в зависимости от страны, но обычно ими являются министерство окружающей среды, водных ресурсов, природных ресурсов, энергетики или сельского хозяйства; институты водных ресурсов, гидрологии или геологии, или геологических исследований) обычно владеют пространственной информацией о местоположении и протяженности границ поверхностных водных бассейнов и границ водоносных горизонтов (в виде шейп-файлов географических информационных систем). Информация о существующих механизмах и их функциональности также обычно доступна в тех же учреждениях. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Регулярные отчеты, способствующие сбору информации &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; С помощью отчетности в соответствии с Конвенцией по охране и использованию трансграничных водотоков и международных озер (Конвенция по трансграничным водам) также будет собираться информация, необходимая для расчета показателя, особенно по договоренностям о сотрудничестве, трансграничных водах, на которые они распространяются, а также об их механизмах. В регулярных отчетах Конвенции, касающихся данных о трансграничном водном сотрудничестве, в которых участвуют как Стороны, так и государства, не являющиеся Сторонами Конвенции, эта информация будет собираться каждые 3 года, начиная с 2017 года. Отчетность охватывает трансграничные реки, озера и грунтовые воды. Программа ЮНЕСКО-МГП будет вносить вклад в отчетность по трансграничным водоносным горизонтам. Более 100 стран участвуют в деятельности Конвенции по трансграничным водам. Европейская экономическая комиссия Организации Объединенных Наций действует в качестве секретариата Конвенции по трансграничным водам. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Некоторые страны уже отчитываются перед региональными организациями о продвижении трансграничного водного сотрудничества и аналогичные договоренности можно было бы укрепить и упростить. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В отсутствие доступной информации на национальном уровне имеются глобальные наборы данных по трансграничным бассейнам, а также информация о соглашениях и организациях, осуществляющих трансграничное сотрудничество, которая может быть использована при отсутствии более подробной информации, в частности, в краткосрочной перспективе. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Оконтуривание трансграничных бассейнов &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В глобальных базах данных самые последние оконтуривания доступны с помощью Программы по оценке трансграничных вод (TWAP). Программа TWAP охватывает 286 основных трансграничных рек, 206 трансграничных озер и водохранилищ и 199 трансграничных водоносных горизонтов. Соответствующая информация была также собрана по 592 трансграничным водоносным горизонтам в рамках проекта ЮНЕСКО- Управление ресурсами водоносных горизонтов, совместно используемых на международном уровне (ИСАРМ ЮНЕСКО). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Договоренности о сотрудничестве &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Сведения о договорах можно найти в базе данных международных договоров о пресной воде, которую ведет Университет штата Орегон (OSU). Последний раз она обновлялась и включала все договоренности, достигнутые до 2008 года. База данных договоров включает в общей сложности 686 международных договоров по пресным водам. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Организации по трансграничному водному сотрудничеству &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; База данных Международной организации речных бассейнов (ОРБ) - подробная информация о более чем 120 международных организациях речных бассейнов, включая двусторонние комиссии, расположенные по всему миру. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Были проведены региональные оценки с описанием и инвентаризацией соглашений, которые вносят вклад в базовый уровень в глобальном масштабе, например, региональные кадастры трансграничных водоносных горизонтов в рамках ИСАРМ ЮНЕСКО-МГП.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
