<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 6-5-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proportion of transboundary basin area with an operational arrangement for water cooperation is defined as the proportion of transboundary basins area within a country with an operational arrangement for water cooperation. It is derived by adding up the surface area in a country of those transboundary surface water catchments and transboundary aquifers (i.e. &amp;#x2018;transboundary&amp;#x2019; basins) that are covered by an operational arrangement and dividing the obtained area by the aggregate total area in a country of all transboundary basins (both catchments and aquifers). The result is multiplied by 100 to obtain it expressed as percentage share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The proposed monitoring has as basis the spatial coverage of transboundary basins shared by each country, and focuses on monitoring whether these are covered by cooperation arrangements that are operational. The criteria needing to be met for the cooperation on a specific basin being considered &amp;#x201C;operational&amp;#x201D; seeks to capture whether the arrangement(s) indeed provide an adequate basis for cooperation in water management. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transboundary basins are basins of transboundary waters, that is, of any surface waters (notably rivers, lakes) or groundwaters which mark, cross or are located on boundaries between by two or more states. For the purpose of the calculation of this indicator, for surface waters, the basin is the extent of the catchment area; for groundwater, the area considered is the extent of the aquifer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrangement for water cooperation: a bilateral or multilateral treaty, convention, agreement or other formal arrangement, such as memorandum of understanding) between riparian countries that provides a framework for cooperation on transboundary water management. Agreements or other kind of formal arrangements may be interstate, intergovernmental, interministerial, interagency or between regional authorities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operational: For an agreement or other kind of formal arrangement (e.g. a memorandum of understanding) for cooperation between the riparian countries to be considered operational, all the following criteria needs to be fulfilled: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is a joint body, joint mechanism or commission (e.g. a river basin organization) for transboundary cooperation &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are regular formal communications between riparian countries in form of meetings &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is a joint or coordinated water management plan(s), or joint objectives have been set&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is a regular exchange of data and information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Définition : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La proportion de la zone de bassin transfrontalier avec un arrangement opérationnel pour la coopération sur l&apos;eau est définie comme la proportion de la zone de bassin transfrontalier dans un pays avec un arrangement opérationnel pour la coopération sur l&apos;eau. Elle est obtenue en additionnant la superficie, dans un pays, des bassins versants et des aquifères transfrontaliers (c&apos;est-à-dire &amp;#x2018; bassins transfrontaliers &amp;#x2019;) qui sont couverts par un accord opérationnel et en divisant la superficie obtenue par la superficie totale globale, dans un pays, de tous les bassins transfrontaliers (à la fois les bassins versants et les aquifères). Le résultat est multiplié par 100 pour obtenir une part exprimée en pourcentage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot; La surveillance proposée se fonde sur la couverture spatiale des bassins transfrontaliers partagés par chaque pays et se concentre sur la surveillance de leur couverture par des accords de coopération opérationnels. Les critères à remplir pour la coopération sur un bassin spécifique considéré &amp;#x201C;&amp;#x201D; visent à déterminer si le ou les accords fournissent effectivement une base adéquate pour la coopération en matière de gestion de l&apos;eau. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les bassins transfrontaliers sont des bassins d&apos;eaux transfrontalières, c&apos;est-à-dire de toutes les eaux de surface (notamment les rivières, les lacs) ou souterraines qui marquent, traversent ou sont situées sur des frontières entre deux ou plusieurs États. Aux fins du calcul de cet indicateur, pour les eaux de surface, le bassin est l&apos;étendue du bassin versant ; pour les eaux souterraines, la zone considérée est l&apos;étendue de l&apos;aquifère. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrangement pour la coopération dans le domaine de l&apos;eau : traité, convention, accord ou autre arrangement formel (tel qu&apos;un protocole d&apos;accord) bilatéral ou multilatéral entre pays riverains qui fournit un cadre de coopération pour la gestion des eaux transfrontalières. Les accords ou autres types d&apos;arrangements formels peuvent être interétatiques, intergouvernementaux, interministériels, interagences ou entre autorités régionales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opérationnel : Pour qu&apos;un accord ou un autre type d&apos;arrangement formel (par exemple un protocole d&apos;accord) de coopération entre les pays riverains soit considéré comme opérationnel, tous les critères suivants doivent être remplis : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Il existe un organe, un mécanisme ou une commission mixte (par exemple un organisme de bassin fluvial) pour la coopération transfrontalière. &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Il existe des communications formelles régulières entre les pays riverains sous forme de réunions. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Il existe un ou plusieurs plans de gestion de l&apos;eau communs ou coordonnés, ou des objectifs communs ont été fixés. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Il existe un échange régulier de données et d&apos;informations. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
