<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 2-c-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;FAO relies on official domestic price data that it compiles in the Food Price Monitoring and Analysis (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/giews/food-prices/tool/public/#/home&quot;&gt;FPMA&lt;/a&gt;) tool to calculate and monitor the indicator. Five cereal products will be monitored: maize &amp;amp; maize products, wheat &amp;amp; wheat flour, rice, sorghum and millet. While diets across the world have become more diversified with increasing incomes, cereals still account for 45 percent of a person&amp;#x2019;s daily caloric intake, making this commodity group the most important in terms of its contribution to caloric intake, particularly for low-income populations (FAOSTAT, 2017). For the purpose of a more comprehensive coverage at the global level, FAO also calculates IFPA on countries&amp;#x2019; officially reported food price indices as reported in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/faostat/en/#data/CP&quot;&gt;FAOSTAT&lt;/a&gt;, which facilitates cross country comparisons as it uses a national level food basket covering all the most important commodities consumed. While the basket differs from country to country, this approach is more reflective of national and global trends as countries have predefined the commodities that have the most impact on local consumers. This approach also facilitates the implementation of the indicator as countries will not be asked to create a new index or modify existing methodologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Food CPI, the FAOSTAT monthly CPI &amp;amp; Food CPI database was based on the ILO CPI data until December 2014. In 2014, IMF-ILO-FAO agreed to transfer global CPI data compilation from ILO to IMF. Upon agreement, CPIs for all items and its subcomponents originates from the International Monetary Fund (IMF), and the UN Statistics Division (UNSD) for countries not covered by the IMF. However, due to a limited time coverage from IMF and UNSD for a number of countries, the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD), the European statistics (EUROSTAT), the Latin America and the Caribbean statistics (CEPALSTAT), Central Bank of Western African States (BCEAO), Eastern Caribbean Central Bank (ECCB) and national statistical office website data are used for missing historical data from IMF and UNSD food CPI. The FAO CPI dataset for all items (or general CPI) and the Food CPI, consists of a complete and consistent set of time series from January 2000 onwards. It further contains regional and global food CPIs compiled by FAO using population weights to aggregate across countries. &lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
