<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 4-1-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Collection process:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data from all publicly available household surveys and censuses with the required information are compiled and used to calculate the completion rate. For international comparability, national data are mapped to the International Standard Classification of Education (ISCED) before indicator calculation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator values intended for dissemination and addition to the global SDG Indicators Database are submitted by the UNESCO Institute for Statistics to National Statistical Offices, Ministries of Education or other relevant agencies in individual countries for their review and feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Processus de collecte : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données de toutes les enquêtes et de tous les recensements des ménages accessibles au public et comportant les informations requises sont compilées et utilisées pour calculer le taux d&apos;achèvement. Pour assurer la comparabilité internationale, les données nationales sont mises en correspondance avec la Classification internationale type de l&apos;éducation (CITE) avant le calcul des indicateurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les valeurs des indicateurs destinées à être diffusées et ajoutées à la base de données mondiale des indicateurs ODD sont soumises par l&apos;Institut de statistique de l&apos;UNESCO aux bureaux nationaux de statistique, aux ministères de l&apos;éducation ou à d&apos;autres organismes compétents dans les différents pays pour qu&apos;ils les examinent et les commentent.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Данные по всем общедоступным обследованиям домашних хозяйств и переписям населения с необходимой информацией собираются и используются для расчета процента завершения. Для достижения международной сопоставимости национальные данные перед расчетом показателя увязываются с Международной стандартной классификацией образования (МСКО). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Значения показателей, предназначенные для распространения и внесения в глобальную базу данных показателей ЦУР, передаются Статистическим институтом ЮНЕСКО в национальные статистические управления, министерства образования или другие соответствующие учреждения в отдельных странах для анализа и получения в ответ от них комментариев и предложений. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
