<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SDG_RELATED_INDICATORS field for indicator 4-1-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Related indicators&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combined with SDG indicator 4.1.1 &amp;#x2013; proportion of children and young people (a) in Grade 2 or 3; (b) at the end of primary education; and (c) at the end of lower secondary education achieving at least a minimum proficiency level in (i) reading and (ii) mathematics &amp;#x2013; the completion rate can provide information on the percentage of children in a given cohort who achieve minimum proficiency in reading and mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Indicadores relacionados&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combinado con el indicador 4.1.1 de los ODS &amp;#x2013; proporción de niños y jóvenes (a) en el segundo o tercer grado; (b) al final de la educación primaria; y (c) al final del primer ciclo de la educación secundaria que alcanzan al menos un nivel mínimo de competencia en (i) lectura y (ii) matemáticas &amp;#x2013; la tasa de finalización puede proporcionar información sobre el porcentaje de niños de una cohorte determinada que alcanzan un nivel mínimo de competencia en lectura y matemáticas.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Indicateurs connexes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combiné à l&apos;indicateur 4.1.1 de l&apos;ODD &amp;#x2013;la proportion d&apos;enfants et de jeunes (a) en deuxième ou troisième année d&apos;études ; (b) à la fin de l&apos;enseignement primaire ; et (c) à la fin du premier cycle de l&apos;enseignement secondaire atteignant au moins un niveau de compétence minimum en (i) lecture et (ii) mathématiques, le taux d&apos;achèvement peut fournir des informations sur le pourcentage d&apos;enfants d&apos;une cohorte donnée qui atteignent une compétence minimum en lecture et en mathématiques. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Связанные индикаторы &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В сочетании с показателем 4.1.1 ЦУР - доля детей и молодежи, приходящаяся на (а) учащихся 2 и 3 классов; (б) выпускников начальной школы; и (c) выпускников неполной средней школы, которые достигли по меньшей мере минимального уровня владения навыками в i) чтении и ii) математике - процент завершения может предоставить информацию о доле детей в данной возрастной группе, которые достигли минимального уровня владения навыками в чтении и математике. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
