<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 8-8-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator measures the level of national compliance with fundamental rights at work (freedom of association and collective bargaining, FACB) for all ILO member states based on six international ILO supervisory body textual sources and also on national legislation. It is based on the coding of textual sources against a list of evaluation criteria and then converting the coding into indicators. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Freedom of association and collective bargaining rights and their supervision&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principles of freedom of association and collective bargaining (FACB) are and have long been at the core of the ILO&amp;#x2019;s normative foundations. These foundations have been established in the ILO&amp;#x2019;s Constitution (1919), the ILO Declaration of Philadelphia (1944), in two key ILO Conventions (namely the &lt;em&gt;Freedom of Association and Protection of the Right to Organise Convention, 1948 (No. 87)&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Right to Organise and Collective Bargaining Convention, 1949 (No. 98)&lt;/em&gt;) and the ILO Declaration on Fundamental Principles and Rights at Work (1998). They are also rights proclaimed in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights (1948) and other international and regional human rights instruments. With the adoption of the 1998 ILO Declaration, the promotion and realization of these fundamental principles and rights also became a constitutional obligation of all ILO member States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FACB rights are considered as &amp;#x2018;enabling rights&amp;#x2019;, the realisation of which is necessary to promote and realise other rights at work. They provide an essential foundation for social dialogue, effective labour market governance and realization of decent work. They are vital in enabling employers and workers to associate and efficiently negotiate work relations, to ensure that both employers and workers have an equal voice in negotiations, and that the outcome is fair and equitable. As such they play a crucial role in the elaboration of economic and social policies that take on board the interests and needs of all actors in the economy. FACB rights are also salient because they are indispensable pillars of democracy as well as the process of democratization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FACB rights, together with other international labour standards, are backed by the ILO&amp;#x2019;s unique supervisory system. The ILO regularly examines the application of standards in member States and highlights areas where those standards are violated and where they could be better applied. The ILO&amp;#x2019;s supervisory system includes two kinds of supervisory mechanisms: the regular system of supervision and the special procedures. The prior entails the examination of periodic reports submitted by member States on the measures taken to implement the provisions of ILO Conventions ratified by them. The special procedures, that is, representations, complaints and the special procedure for complaints regarding freedom of association through the Freedom of Association Committee, allow for the examination of violations on the basis of a submission of a representation or a complaint. &lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
