<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 4-a-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For administrative sources:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UNESCO Institute for Statistics (UIS) produces time series based on data reported by Ministries of Education or National Statistical Offices (NSOs). The data are gathered through the annual Survey of Formal Education (on access to electricity, drinking water, sanitation and handwashing facilities) and through the Survey on ICTs in Education (on access to electricity, Internet and computers). Data on adapted infrastructure are not collected currently. Countries are asked to report data according to the levels of education defined in the International Standard Classification of Education (ISCED) to ensure international comparability of resulting indicators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data received are validated using electronic error detection systems that check for arithmetic errors and inconsistencies and trend analysis for implausible results. Queries are taken up with the country representatives reporting the data so that corrections can be made (of errors) or explanations given (of implausible but correct results). During this process, countries are also encouraged to provide estimates for missing or incomplete data items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, countries also have an opportunity to see and comment on the main indicators the UIS produces in an annual &amp;#x201C;country review&amp;#x201D; of indicators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For cross-national learning assessments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data is acquired from the administrators of cross-national assessment; typically, these are available for download publicly. UIS analyses this data to provide estimates of the indicator. When there is more than one data point available for a given level of schooling, an average is used as the indicator. Annex Table 2 presents the questionnaire used to collect data in the cross-national assessments included. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pour les sources administratives :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’Institut de statistique de l’UNESCO produit des séries chronologiques basées sur les données déclarées par les ministères de l’éducation ou les bureaux nationaux de statistique. Les données sont recueillies dans le cadre de l’Enquête annuelle sur l’éducation formelle (sur l’accès à l’électricité, à l’eau potable, à un système sanitaire et aux installations de lavage de mains) et de l’Enquête sur les TIC dans l’éducation (sur l’accès à l’électricité, à Internet et aux ordinateurs). Les données sur les infrastructures adaptées ne sont pas recueillies actuellement. On invite les pays à déclarer des données en fonction des niveaux d’éducation définis dans la Classification internationale type de l’éducation (CITE) afin d’assurer la comparabilité internationale des indicateurs qui en résultent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données reçues sont validées à l’aide de systèmes électroniques de détection d’erreurs qui vérifient les erreurs et les incohérences arithmétiques et analyse des tendances pour des résultats invraisemblables. Les requêtes sont envoyées aux représentants des pays qui déclarent les données afin que des corrections puissent être apportées (des erreurs) ou des explications données (des résultats invraisemblables mais corrects). Au cours de ce processus, on encourage également les pays à fournir des estimations pour les éléments de données manquants ou incomplets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En outre, les pays ont également la possibilité de voir et de commenter les principaux indicateurs produits par l’ISU dans un « examen annuel » des indicateurs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pour les évaluations d’apprentissage transnationales :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont acquises auprès des administrateurs de l’évaluation transnationale; en règle générale, celles-ci sont disponibles en téléchargement public. L’ISU analyse ces données pour fournir des estimations de l’indicateur. Lorsqu’il y a plus d’un point de données disponible pour un niveau de scolarité donné, une moyenne est utilisée comme indicateur. Le tableau 2 de l’annexe présente le questionnaire utilisé pour recueillir des données dans les évaluations transnationales. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
