<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 3-8-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coverage of essential health services (defined as the average coverage of essential services based on tracer interventions that include reproductive, maternal, newborn and child health, infectious diseases, non-communicable diseases and service capacity and access, among the general and the most disadvantaged population).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is an index reported on a unitless scale of 0 to 100, which is computed as the geometric mean of 14 tracer indicators of health service coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The index of health service coverage is computed as the geometric means of 14 tracer indicators. The 14 indicators are listed below and detailed metadata for each of the components are given online (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/UHC_Tracer_Indicators_Metadata.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/UHC_Tracer_Indicators_Metadata.pdf&lt;/a&gt;) and Annex 1. The tracer indicators are as follows, organized by four broad categories of service coverage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I. Reproductive, maternal, newborn and child health&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Family planning&lt;/strong&gt;: Percentage of women of reproductive age (15&amp;#x2212;49 years) who are married or in-union who have their need for family planning satisfied with modern methods &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Pregnancy and delivery care&lt;/strong&gt;: Percentage of women aged 15-49 years with a live birth in a given time period who received antenatal care four or more times&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;Child immunization&lt;/strong&gt;: Percentage of infants receiving three doses of diphtheria-tetanus-pertussis containing vaccine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. &lt;strong&gt;Child treatment&lt;/strong&gt;: Percentage of children under 5 years of age with suspected pneumonia (cough and difficult breathing NOT due to a problem in the chest and a blocked nose) in the two weeks preceding the survey taken to an appropriate health facility or provider&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;II. Infectious diseases&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. &lt;strong&gt;Tuberculosis&lt;/strong&gt;: Percentage of incident TB cases that are detected and successfully treated&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6. &lt;strong&gt;HIV/AIDS&lt;/strong&gt;: Percentage of people living with HIV currently receiving antiretroviral therapy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7. &lt;strong&gt;Malaria&lt;/strong&gt;: Percentage of population in malaria-endemic areas who slept under an insecticide-treated net the previous night [only for countries with high malaria burden]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8. &lt;strong&gt;Water and sanitation&lt;/strong&gt;: Percentage of households using at least basic sanitation facilities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;III. Noncommunicable diseases&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9. &lt;strong&gt;Hypertension&lt;/strong&gt;: Age-standardized prevalence of non-raised blood pressure (systolic blood pressure &amp;lt;140 mm Hg or diastolic blood pressure &amp;lt;90 mm Hg) among adults aged 18 years and older&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10. &lt;strong&gt;Diabetes&lt;/strong&gt;: Age-standardized mean fasting plasma glucose (mmol/L) for adults aged 18 years and older&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11. &lt;strong&gt;Tobacco&lt;/strong&gt;: Age-standardized prevalence of adults &amp;gt;=15 years not smoking tobacco in last 30 days (SDG indicator 3.a.1, metadata available &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/sdgs/metadata/files/Metadata-03-0a-01.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;IV. Service capacity and access&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12. &lt;strong&gt;Hospital access&lt;/strong&gt;: Hospital beds per capita, relative to a maximum threshold of 18 per 10,000 population&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13. &lt;strong&gt;Health workforce&lt;/strong&gt;: Health professionals (physicians, psychiatrists, and surgeons) per capita, relative to maximum thresholds for each cadre (partial overlap with SDG indicator 3.c.1, see metadata &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/sdgs/metadata/files/Metadata-03-0C-01.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14. &lt;strong&gt;Health security&lt;/strong&gt;: International Health Regulations (IHR) core capacity index, which is the average percentage of attributes of 13 core capacities that have been attained (SDG indicator 3.d.1, see metadata &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/sdgs/metadata/files/Metadata-03-0D-01.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
