<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 16-5-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportion of firms asked for a gift or informal payment when meeting with tax officials. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In every Enterprise Survey (&lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\jenpa\AppData\Local\Temp\Temp1_Tier%201-Pilot%20Refresh.zip\Tier%201-Pilot%20Refresh\www.enterprisesurveys.org&quot;&gt;www.enterprisesurveys.org&lt;/a&gt;), there is a standard question which asks the survey respondent if they were inspected by or required to meet with tax officials. If the respondent indicates &amp;#x2018;yes&amp;#x2019;, then there is a follow-up question which asks if the respondent was expected to provide a gift or an informal payment during these inspections/meetings. The response options include &amp;#x201C;yes&amp;#x201D;, &amp;#x201C;no&amp;#x201D;, &amp;#x201C;don&amp;#x2019;t know&amp;#x201D;, and &amp;#x201C;refuse&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enterprise Surveys are firm-level surveys conducted in World Bank client countries. The survey focuses on various aspects of the business environment as well as firm&amp;#x2019;s outcome measures such as annual sales, productivity, etc. The surveys are conducted via face-to-face interviews with the top manager or business owner. For each country, the survey is conducted approximately every 4-5 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The respondents to the Enterprise Survey are firms- either manufacturing or services establishments. These are registered (formal) firms with 5+ employees. The firms are either fully or partially private (100% state-owned firms are ineligible for the Enterprise Survey). More information on the survey methodology can be found on the Methodology page of the website: &lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\jenpa\AppData\Local\Temp\Temp1_Tier%201-Pilot%20Refresh.zip\Tier%201-Pilot%20Refresh\www.enterprisesurveys.org\methodology&quot;&gt;www.enterprisesurveys.org/methodology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A gift or an informal payment is considered a &amp;#x2018;bribe&amp;#x2019;.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
