<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 2-5-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The indicator is based on the data contained in FAO&amp;#x2019;s Global Databank for Animal Genetic Resources DAD-IS (&lt;a href=&quot;http://dad.fao.org/&quot;&gt;http://dad.fao.org/&lt;/a&gt;). Risk classes are defined based on population sizes of breeds reported to DAD-IS. The risk class is considered to be &amp;#x201C;unknown&amp;#x201D; if (i) no population sizes are reported or (ii) the most recent population size reported refers to a year more than 10- years before the year of calculation (10 year cut off point). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Species are assigned to two groups. The first group comprises species that have high reproductive capacity, such as pigs, rabbits, guinea pigs and avian species, and the second comprises species that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;have low reproductive capacity, i.e. those belonging to the taxonomical families Bovidae, Equidae, Camelidae and Cervidae.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The risk status categories are defined as follows (see also FAO. 2013. In vivo conservation of animal genetic resources. FAO Animal Production and Health Guidelines. No. 14. Rome. Accessible at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/docrep/018/i3327e/i3327e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/docrep/018/i3327e/i3327e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;): &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Extinct. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;A breed is categorized as extinct when there are no breeding males or breeding females remaining and any cryoconserved genetic material that may be available is insufficient for breed reconstitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cryoconserved only. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Breeds that have no living male or female animals remaining, but for which there is sufficient cryopreserved material to allow for reconstitution of the breed, are assigned to the category cryoconserved only. The ability to reconstitute an otherwise extinct breed depends on the amount of and type of stored germplasm. Requirements differ greatly according to species. Guidance on what constitutes &amp;#x201C;sufficient cryopreserved material&amp;#x201D; is provided in the FAO guidelines &lt;em&gt;Cryoconservation of animal genetic resources&lt;/em&gt; (FAO, 2012).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Critical. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;A breed is categorized as critical if:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; &lt;/strong&gt;the total number of breeding females is less than or equal to 100 (300 for species with low reproductive capacity); or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; &lt;/strong&gt;the overall population size is less than or equal to 80 (240) and the population trend is increasing and the proportion of females being bred to males of the same breed is greater than 80 percent (i.e. cross-breeding is equal to or less than 20 percent); or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; &lt;/strong&gt;the overall population size is less than or equal to 120 (360) and the population trend is stable or decreasing; or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; &lt;/strong&gt;the total number of breeding males is less than or equal to five (i.e. &lt;em&gt;&amp;#x394;F &lt;/em&gt;is 3 percent or greater).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the population trend is unknown, then it is assumed to be stable. Breeds for which demographic characteristics suggest a critical risk of extinction, but that have active conservation programmes (including cryoconservation) in place, or populations that are maintained by commercial companies or research institutions are considered to be &amp;#x201C;critical-maintained&amp;#x201D; for reporting purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Endangered. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;A breed is categorized as endangered if:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; &lt;/strong&gt;the total number of breeding females is greater than 100 (300 for species with low reproductive capacity) and less than or equal to 1 000 (3 000); or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; &lt;/strong&gt;the overall population size is greater than 80 (240) and less than 800 (2 400) and increasing in size and the percentage of females being bred to males of the same breed is above 80 percent; or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; &lt;/strong&gt;the overall population size is greater than 120 (360) and less than or equal to 1 200 (3 600) and the trend is stable or decreasing; or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; &lt;/strong&gt;the total number of breeding males is less than or equal to 20 and greater than five (i.e. &lt;em&gt;&amp;#x394;F &lt;/em&gt;is between 1 and 3 percent).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, if the population trend is unknown, then it is assumed to be stable. Endangered breeds will be assigned to the subcategory &amp;#x201C;endangered-maintained&amp;#x201D; if active conservation programmes are in place or if their populations are maintained by commercial companies or research institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vulnerable. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;A breed is categorized as vulnerable if:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; &lt;/strong&gt;the total number of breeding females is between 1 000 and 2 000 (3 000 and 6 000 for species with low reproductive capacity); or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; &lt;/strong&gt;the overall population size is greater than 800 (2 400) and less than or equal to 1 600 (4 800) and increasing and the percentage of females being bred to males of the same breed is greater than 80 percent; or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; &lt;/strong&gt;the overall population size is greater than 1 200 (3 600) and less than or equal to 2 400 (7 200) but stable or decreasing; or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; &lt;/strong&gt;the total number of breeding males is between 20 and 35 (i.e. the &lt;em&gt;&amp;#x394;F &lt;/em&gt;is between 0.5 and 1 percent).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unreported population trends are assumed to be stable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Not at risk. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;A breed is categorized as not at risk if the population status is known and the breed does not fall in the critical or endangered categories (including the respective subcategories) or the vulnerable category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unknown. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;This category is self-explanatory and calls for action. A population survey is needed; the breed could be critical, endangered or vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A breed is considered to be at risk if it has been classified as either critical, critical-maintained, endangered, endangered-maintained or vulnerable. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is calculated as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk status of local breeds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;At risk&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
            &lt;msub&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/msub&gt;
          &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Not at risk&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
            &lt;msub&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/msub&gt;
          &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Unknown&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
            &lt;msub&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;U&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/msub&gt;
          &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;All risk classes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;msub&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/msub&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;msub&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/msub&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;msub&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;U&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/msub&gt;
          &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SDG indicator for country i: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;msub&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;bold-italic&quot;&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;bold-italic&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/msub&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;msub&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/msub&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur est basé sur les données contenues dans la Banque de données mondiale des ressources zoogénétiques DAD-IS de la FAO (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fao.org/dad-is/fr/&quot;&gt;https://www.fao.org/dad-is/fr/&lt;/a&gt;). Les classes de risque sont définies sur la base des tailles de population des races rapportées dans le DAD-IS. La classe de risque est considérée comme « inconnue » si (i) aucune taille de population n&apos;est signalée ou (ii) la plus récente taille de population signalée se réfère à une année antérieure de plus de 10 ans à l&apos;année de calcul (seuil de 10 ans). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les espèces sont réparties en deux groupes. Le premier groupe comprend les espèces qui ont une capacité de reproduction élevée, comme les porcs, les lapins, les cobayes et les espèces aviaires, et le second comprend les espèces qui ont une faible capacité de reproduction, c&apos;est-à-dire celles qui appartiennent aux familles taxonomiques Bovidae, Equidae, Camelidae et Cervidae&lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;Les catégories de statut de risque sont définies comme suit (voir également FAO. 2013. « In vivo conservation of animal genetic resources ». Directives FAO: Production et santé animales. Numéro 14. Rome. Accessible (en anglais) à l&apos;adresse &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/docrep/018/i3327e/i3327e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/docrep/018/i3327e/i3327e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;) : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Éteinte : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;une race est catégorisée comme éteinte lorsqu&apos;il n&apos;y a plus de mâles ou de femelles reproducteurs et que le matériel génétique cryoconservé éventuellement disponible est insuffisant pour la reconstitution de la race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cryoconservée seulement : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;les races pour lesquelles il ne reste plus d&apos;animaux mâles ou femelles vivants, mais pour lesquelles il y a suffisamment de matériel cryoconservé pour permettre la reconstitution de la race. La capacité de reconstituer une race autrement éteinte dépend de la quantité et du type de germoplasme stocké. Les exigences diffèrent grandement selon les espèces. Des conseils sur ce qui constitue une « quantité suffisante de matériel cryoconservé » sont fournis dans les directives (en anglais) de la FAO &lt;em&gt;« Cryoconservation of animal genetic resources »&lt;/em&gt; (FAO, 2012).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Critique : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;une race est classée comme critique si :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;le nombre total de femelles reproductrices est inférieur ou égal à 100 (300 pour les espèces à faible capacité de reproduction); ou &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;la taille globale de la population est inférieure ou égale à 80 (240) et la tendance de la population est à la hausse et la proportion de femelles accouplées à des mâles de la même race est supérieure à 80% (c&apos;est-à-dire que le croisement est égal ou inférieur à 20%); ou&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;la taille globale de la population est inférieure ou égale à 120 (360) et la tendance de la population est stable ou à la baisse; ou &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;le nombre total de mâles reproducteurs est inférieur ou égal à cinq (c&apos;est-à-dire que &lt;em&gt;&amp;#x394;F&lt;/em&gt;est de 3% ou plus).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Si la tendance de la population est inconnue, on suppose qu&apos;elle est stable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les races pour lesquelles les caractéristiques démographiques suggèrent un risque critique d&apos;extinction, mais qui ont des programmes de conservation actifs (y compris la cryoconservation) en place, ou les populations qui sont maintenues par des sociétés commerciales ou des instituts de recherche sont considérées comme étant « critiques-maintenues » aux fins de déclaration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;En voie de disparition : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;une race est classée comme étant en voie de disparition si :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;le nombre total de femelles reproductrices est supérieur à 100 (300 pour les espèces à faible capacité de reproduction) et inférieur ou égal à 1 000 (3 000); ou &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;la taille globale de la population est supérieure à 80 (240) et inférieure à 800 (2 400) et la tendance de la population est à la hausse et le pourcentage de femelles accouplées à des mâles de la même race est supérieur à 80%; ou &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;la taille globale de la population est supérieure à 120 (360) et inférieure ou égale à 1 200 (3 600) et la tendance est stable ou à la baisse; ou &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;le nombre total de mâles reproducteurs est inférieur ou égal à 20 et supérieur à cinq (c&apos;est-à-dire que &lt;em&gt;&amp;#x394;F&lt;/em&gt;est compris entre 1% et 3%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Encore une fois, si la tendance de la population est inconnue, on suppose qu&apos;elle est stable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les races menacées d&apos;extinction seront assignées à la sous-catégorie « menacée-maintenue » si des programmes de conservation actifs sont en place ou si leurs populations sont maintenues par des entreprises commerciales ou des instituts de recherche.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vulnérable : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;une race est classée comme vulnérable si :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;le nombre total de femelles reproductrices est compris entre 1 000 et 2 000 (3 000 et 6 000 pour les espèces à faible capacité de reproduction) ; ou &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;la taille globale de la population est supérieure à 800 (2 400) et inférieure ou égale à 1 600 (4 800) et la tendance de la population est à la hausse et le pourcentage de femelles accouplées à des mâles de la même race est supérieur à 80%; ou&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;la taille globale de la population est supérieure à 1 200 (3 600) et inférieure ou égale à 2 400 (7 200) et la tendance est stable ou à la baisse; ou &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;le nombre total de mâles reproducteurs est compris entre 20 et 35 (c&apos;est-à-dire que le &lt;em&gt;&amp;#x394;F &lt;/em&gt;est compris entre 0,5% et 1%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les tendances démographiques non déclarées sont supposées être stables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Non menacée : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;une race est classée comme non menacée si l&apos;état de la population est connu et que la race n&apos;entre pas dans les catégories critique, en voie de disparition (y compris les sous-catégories respectives) ou vulnérable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inconnue : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;cette catégorie est explicite et appelle à l&apos;action. Une enquête sur la population est nécessaire; la race pourrait être critique, en voie de disparition ou vulnérable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Une race est considérée comme étant à risque si elle a été classée soit comme critique, critique-maintenue, en voie de disparition, menacée-maintenue ou vulnérable. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur est calculé comme suit : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statut de risque des races locales&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nombre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;À risque&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
            &lt;msub&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/msub&gt;
          &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Non à risque&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
            &lt;msub&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/msub&gt;
          &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Inconnu&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
            &lt;msub&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;U&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/msub&gt;
          &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tous les types de risque&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;msub&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/msub&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;msub&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/msub&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;msub&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;U&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/msub&gt;
          &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indicateur ODD pour le pays i : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;msub&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;bold-italic&quot;&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;bold-italic&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/msub&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;msub&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/msub&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
