<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 2-5-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;At breed level&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If no population data are provided for a respective year, it is assumed that the risk status remains the same as for the last year for which population data have been reported. In this case the nature of data is considered to be estimated. However, if the most recent reporting refers to a year more than 10- years before, the risk status is considered &amp;#x201C;unknown&amp;#x201D;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; At country level&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Country information is considered to be missing if 100% percent of a country&amp;#x2019;s local breeds do have risk status &amp;#x201C;unknown&amp;#x201D;. If 100% of a country&amp;#x2019;s breed risk status values are estimates (see above), the nature of country data is also considered to be an estimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; At regional and global levels&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See aggregation rules under 4.g&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Au niveau de la race&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Si aucune donnée de population n&apos;est fournie pour une année donnée, il est supposé que le statut de risque reste le même que pour la dernière année pour laquelle des données de population ont été communiquées. Dans ce cas, la nature des données est considérée comme étant estimée. Toutefois, si le rapport le plus récent se réfère à une année antérieure de plus de 10 ans, le statut de risque est considéré comme « inconnu ». &lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;· Au niveau national&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les informations sur le pays sont considérées comme manquantes si 100 % des races locales d&apos;un pays ont un statut de risque « inconnu ». Si 100 % des valeurs du statut de risque des races d&apos;un pays sont des estimations (voir ci-dessus), la nature des données du pays est également considérée comme une estimation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· Aux niveaux régional et mondial&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voir les règles d&apos;agrégation sous 4.g&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
