<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 16-3-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The total number of persons held in detention who have not yet been sentenced, as a percentage of the total number of persons held in detention, on a specified date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2018;Sentenced&amp;#x2019; refers to persons subject to criminal proceedings who have received a decision from a competent authority regarding their conviction or acquittal. For the purposes of the indicator, persons who have received a &amp;#x2018;non-final&amp;#x2019; decision (such as where a conviction is subject to appeal) are considered to be &amp;#x2018;sentenced&amp;#x2019;.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El número total de personas detenidas que aún no han sido condenadas, como porcentaje del número total de personas detenidas, en una fecha determinada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2018;Condenado&amp;#x2019; se refiere a las personas sujetas a un proceso penal que han recibido una decisión de una autoridad competente sobre su condena o absolución. A efectos del indicador, se considera que las personas que han recibido una decisión &amp;#x2018;no definitiva&amp;#x2019; (como cuando una condena está sujeta a apelación) están &amp;#x2018;condenadas&amp;#x2019;.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
 &lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Доля общего количества лиц, задерживаемых до вынесения приговора, в общей численности
заключенных, выраженная в процентах, на определенную дату.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2&gt; Понятия:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Осужденные&quot; относятся к лицам, в отношении которых возбуждено уголовное дело и которые получили решение компетентного органа об их осуждении или оправдании. Для целей данного показателя лица, получившие &quot;не окончательное&quot; решение (например, когда обвинительный приговор может быть обжалован) считаются &quot;осужденными&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
