<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The INST_MANDATE field for indicator 5-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The United Nations Statistics Division is committed to the advancement of the global statistical system. UNSD compiles and disseminates global statistical information, develops standards and norms for statistical activities, and supports countries&amp;apos; efforts to strengthen their national statistical systems. UNSD facilitates the coordination of international statistical activities and support the functioning of the United Nations Statistical Commission as the apex entity of the global statistical system. The Social and Gender Statistics Section of UNSD works on migration statistics, gender statistics, and time use statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Global Gender Statistics Programme is mandated by the United Nations Statistical Commission, implemented by the United Nations Statistics Division (UNSD) and coordinated by the Inter-Agency and Expert Group on Gender Statistics IAEG-GS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Programme encompasses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;improving coherence among existing initiatives on gender statistics through international coordination&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;developing and promoting methodological guidelines in existing domains as well as in emerging areas of gender concern&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;strengthening national statistical and technical capacity for the production, dissemination and use of gender relevant data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;facilitating access to gender relevant data and metadata through a newly developed data portal (forthcoming).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNSD serves as Secretariat of the Inter-Agency and Expert Group on Gender Statistics (IAEG-GS), the coordinating and guiding body of the Global Gender Statistics Programme. The IAEG-GS was first convened in 2006, meets annually and functions through advisory groups. Presently, the main advisory group&amp;apos;s work concentrates on examining emerging and unaddressed key gender issues and related data gap with the aim to develop proposals on how to fill these gaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, UNSD serves as Secretariat of the United Nations Expert Group on Innovative and Effective Ways to Collect Time-Use Statistics, which initiated its work in June 2018 with the overall objective of taking stock and reviewing country practices in time-use surveys and providing technical guidance and recommendations to improve the collection and use of time use data, in line with international standards and in support of SDGs implementation. In particular, the Group was established to develop methodological guidelines on how to operationalize &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/demographic-social/time-use/icatus-2016/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ICATUS 2016&lt;/a&gt; and produce time-use statistics using the latest technologies, as requested by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/statcom/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;United Nations Statistical Commission&lt;/a&gt; at its &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/statcom/48th-session/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;forty-eighth session&lt;/a&gt; in 2017 in its decision &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/statcom/decisions-ref/?code=48/109&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;48/109&lt;/a&gt;. Presently, the TUS-EG together with UNSD is finalizing the reports on the minimum harmonized instrument, data quality in time use statistics, and digitalization of time use data, which will be presented at the Statistical Commission in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">Sans objet
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
