<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 5-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the indicator is to measure the amount of time women and men spend doing unpaid work, to ensure that all work, whether paid or unpaid, is valued. In addition, it also provides an assessment of gender equality, by highlighting discrepancies between how much time women and men spend on unpaid work, like cooking, cleaning or taking care of children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator measures the average amount of time as a proportion in a day, so that if for a given country it is reported that women aged 15+ spend 10% of their day on unpaid domestic chores while men in the same age group spend 1%, it indicates that women spend 2.4 hours (2 hours and 24 minutes), while men spend 14.4 minutes on it a day, on average. As explained further in 4.c, this daily average is obtained from an average taken over a weekly period (or the reference period for the data collection), and thus not mean that women and men spend these given amounts of time every single day. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;L’objectif de l’indicateur est de mesurer le temps que les femmes et les hommes passent à faire un travail non rémunéré, afin de s’assurer que tout le travail, rémunéré ou non, est évalué. En outre, il fournit également une évaluation de l’égalité des sexes, en soulignant les écarts entre le temps que les femmes et les hommes consacrent à des travaux non rémunérés, comme cuisiner, nettoyer ou s’occuper des enfants. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur mesure la quantité moyenne de temps en proportion d’une journée, de sorte que si, pour un pays donné, il est signalé que les femmes âgées de 15 ans ou plus consacrent 10% de leur journée aux tâches domestiques non rémunérées alors que les hommes du même groupe d’âge dépensent 1%, il indique que les femmes passent 2,4 heures (2 heures et 24 minutes), tandis que les hommes y passent 14,4 minutes par jour, en moyenne. Comme expliqué plus en détail dans la section 4.c, cette moyenne quotidienne est obtenue à partir d’une moyenne prise sur une période hebdomadaire (ou la période de référence pour la collecte de données), et ne signifie donc pas que les femmes et les hommes passent ces quantités de temps données chaque jour. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
