<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DOC_METHOD field for indicator 5-5-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Methods and guidance available to countries for the compilation of the data at the national level:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to calculate this indicator, data on employment by sex and occupation is needed, using at least the 2-digit level of the International Standard Classification of Occupations. This data are collected at the national level mainly through labour force surveys (or other types of household surveys with an employment module). For the methodology of each national household survey, one must refer to the most comprehensive survey report or to the methodological publications of the national statistical office in question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ILO Guidebook - Decent Work and the Sustainable Development Goals: A Guidebook on SDG Labour Market Indicators (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ILO Manual &amp;#x2013; Decent Work Indicators, Concepts and Definitions &amp;#x2013; Chapter 8, Equal opportunity and treatment in employment &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/integration/resources/pubs/WCMS_229374/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/integration/resources/pubs/WCMS_229374/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; (second version, page 146)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resolution concerning statistics of work, employment and labour underutilization &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutionsadopted-by-international-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_230304/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutionsadopted-by-international-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_230304/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;International Standard Classification of Occupations 2008 (ISCO-08) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/public/english/bureau/stat/isco/isco08/&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/public/english/bureau/stat/isco/isco08/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ILOSTAT Database (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ILOSTAT&amp;#x2013; Indicator Descriptions (Employment by occupation, at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/resources/methods/description-employment-by-occupation/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/resources/methods/description-employment-by-occupation/&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Métodos y directrices a disposición de los países para la recopilación de los datos a nivel nacional:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para calcular este indicador se necesitan datos sobre el empleo por sexo y ocupación, utilizando al menos el nivel de 2 dígitos de la Clasificación Internacional Uniforme de Ocupaciones. Estos datos se recogen a nivel nacional principalmente a través de las encuestas de población activa (u otros tipos de encuestas de hogares con un módulo de empleo). Para conocer la metodología de cada encuesta nacional de hogares, hay que remitirse al informe más completo de la encuesta o a las publicaciones metodológicas de la oficina nacional de estadística en cuestión.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Guía de la OIT - El trabajo decente y los Objetivos de Desarrollo Sostenible: Una guía sobre los indicadores del mercado laboral de los ODS (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manual de la OIT &amp;#x2013; Indicadores de trabajo decente, conceptos y definiciones &amp;#x2013; Capítulo 8, Igualdad de oportunidades y de trato en el empleo &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/integration/resources/pubs/WCMS_229374/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/integration/resources/pubs/WCMS_229374/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; (segunda versión, página 146)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resolución relativa a las estadísticas del trabajo, el empleo y la subutilización de la mano de obra &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutionsadopted-by-international-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_230304/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutionsadopted-by-international-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_230304/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clasificación Internacional Uniforme de Ocupaciones 2008 (CIUO-08) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/public/english/bureau/stat/isco/isco08/&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/public/english/bureau/stat/isco/isco08/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ILOSTAT Database (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ILOSTAT&amp;#x2013; Descripciones de los indicadores (Empleo por ocupación, en: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/resources/methods/description-employment-by-occupation/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/resources/methods/description-employment-by-occupation/&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt; Méthodes et instructions à la disposition des pays pour la compilation des données au niveau national :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Pour calculer cet indicateur, des données sur l’emploi selon le sexe et la profession sont nécessaires, en utilisant au moins le niveau à deux chiffres de la Classification standard internationale des professions. Ces données sont recueillies au niveau national principalement au moyen d’enquêtes sur la population active (ou d’autres types d’enquêtes auprès des ménages avec un module d’emploi). Pour la méthodologie de chaque enquête nationale auprès des ménages, il faut se référer au rapport d’enquête le plus complet ou aux publications méthodologiques de l’Office national de la statistique en question. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Guide de l’OIT - Travail décent et objectifs de développement durable : Guide
sur les indicateurs du marché du travail des ODD (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Manuel de l’OIT &amp;#x2013; Indicateurs, concepts et définitions du travail
décent &amp;#x2013; Chapitre 8, Égalité des chances et traitement de l’emploi &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/integration/resources/pubs/WCMS_229374/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/integration/resources/pubs/WCMS_229374/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; (deuxième version, page 146)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Résolution concernant les statistiques sur la sous-utilisation du travail,
de l’emploi et du travail &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutionsadopted-by-international-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_230304/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutionsadopted-by-international-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_230304/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Classification standard internationale des professions 2008 (ISCO-08) &lt;a
href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/public/english/bureau/stat/isco/isco08/&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/public/english/bureau/stat/isco/isco08/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Base de données ILOSTAT (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; ILOSTAT&amp;#x2013; Descriptions des indicateurs (Emploi par profession, à :
&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/resources/methods/description-employment-by-occupation/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/resources/methods/description-employment-by-profession/&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Доступные странам методы и руководства для составления данных на национальном уровне: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для расчета этого показателя необходимы данные по занятости с разбивкой по полу и роду занятий, используя как минимум двузначный уровень Международной стандартной классификации занятий. Эти данные собираются на национальном уровне в основном посредством обследований рабочей силы (или других типов обследований домашних хозяйств, имеющих модуль занятости). Чтобы узнать о методологии каждого национального обследования домашних хозяйств, необходимо обратиться к наиболее полному отчету об обследовании или к методическим публикациям соответствующего национального статистического управления. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Руководство МОТ - Достойный труд и цели в области устойчивого развития: Руководство по показателям рынка труда в рамках ЦУР (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Руководство МОТ - Показатели, концепции и определения достойного труда - Глава 8, Равные возможности и обращение в сфере занятости &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/integration/resources/pubs/WCMS_229374/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt; http://www.ilo.org/integration/resources/pubs/WCMS_229374/lang- -en / index.htm &lt;/a&gt; (вторая версия, стр. 146) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Постановление о статистике труда, занятости и недоиспользования рабочей силы &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutionsadopted-by-international-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_230304/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutionsadopted-by-international-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_230304/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Международная стандартная классификация занятий 2008 года (МСКЗ-08) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/public/english/bureau/stat/isco/isco08/&quot;&gt; http://www.ilo.org/public/english/bureau/stat/isco/isco08/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; База данных ILOSTAT (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; ILOSTAT &amp;#x2013; Описание показателей (Занятость в разбивке по роду занятий, доступно по адресу: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/resources/methods/description-employment-by-occupation/&quot;&gt; https://ilostat.ilo.org/resources/methods/description-employment-by-occupation/&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
