<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 5-5-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator refers to the proportion of females in the total number of persons employed in managerial positions. It is recommended to use two different measures jointly for this indicator: the share of females in (total) management and the share of females in senior and middle management (thus excluding junior management). The joint calculation of these two measures provides information on whether women are more represented in junior management than in senior and middle management, thus pointing to an eventual ceiling for women to access higher-level management positions. In these cases, calculating only the share of women in (total) management would be misleading, in that it would suggest that women hold positions with more decision-making power and responsibilities than they actually do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Employment comprises all persons of working age who, during a short reference period (one week), were engaged in any activity to produce goods or provide services for pay or profit. The difference between the 13&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; and 19&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; ICLS series for a given country is the operational criteria used to define employment, with two series based on the statistical standards from the 13th International Conference of Labour Statisticians (ICLS) and the other two series based on 19th ICLS standards. In the 19th ICLS series, employment is defined more narrowly as work done for pay or profit, while activities not done mainly in exchange for remuneration (i.e., own-use production work, volunteer work and unpaid trainee work) are recognized as other forms of work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Employment in management is determined according to the categories of the latest version of the International Standard Classification of Occupations (ISCO-08), which organizes jobs into a clearly defined set of groups based on the tasks and duties undertaken in the job. For the purpose of this indicator, it is preferable to refer separately to senior and middle management only, and to total management (including junior management). The share of women tends to be higher in junior management than in senior and middle management, so limiting the indicator to a measure including junior management may introduce bias. Senior and middle management correspond to sub-major groups 11, 12 and 13 in ISCO-08 and sub-major groups 11 and 12 in ISCO-88. If statistics are not available disaggregated at the sub-major group level (two-digit level of ISCO), then major group 1 of ISCO-88 and ISCO-08 can be used as a proxy and the indicator would then refer only to total management (including junior management).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Este indicador se refiere a la proporción de mujeres en el número total de personas empleadas en puestos directivos. Se recomienda utilizar conjuntamente dos medidas diferentes para este indicador: la proporción de mujeres en la dirección (total) y la proporción de mujeres en la dirección superior e intermedia (excluyendo, por tanto, la dirección inferior). El cálculo conjunto de estas dos medidas proporciona información sobre si las mujeres están más representadas en los puestos de dirección subalternos que en los superiores e intermedios, apuntando así a un posible techo para que las mujeres accedan a puestos de dirección de mayor nivel. En estos casos, calcular sólo el porcentaje de mujeres en la dirección (total) sería engañoso, ya que sugeriría que las mujeres ocupan puestos con más poder de decisión y responsabilidades de los que realmente tienen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;El empleo comprende a todas las personas en edad de trabajar que, durante un breve período de referencia (una semana), realizaron cualquier actividad para producir bienes o prestar servicios a cambio de una remuneración o un beneficio.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;El empleo en la gestión se determina según las categorías de la última versión de la Clasificación Internacional Uniforme de Ocupaciones (CIUO-08), que organiza los empleos en un conjunto de grupos claramente definidos en función de las tareas y funciones realizadas en el trabajo. A los efectos de este indicador, es preferible referirse por separado a los directivos superiores e intermedios únicamente, y a los directivos totales (incluidos los directivos subalternos). La proporción de mujeres tiende a ser mayor en los mandos inferiores que en los superiores e intermedios, por lo que limitar el indicador a una medida que incluya a los mandos inferiores puede introducir un sesgo. Los directivos superiores e intermedios corresponden a los subgrupos 11, 12 y 13 de la CIUO-08 y a los subgrupos 11 y 12 de la CIUO-88. Si no se dispone de estadísticas desglosadas a nivel de subgrupo principal (nivel de dos dígitos de la CIUO), se puede utilizar el grupo principal 1 de la CIUO-88 y la CIUO-08 como aproximación y el indicador se referiría entonces sólo al total de directivos (incluidos los directivos sbalternos).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur fait référence à la proportion de femmes dans le nombre total de personnes employées à des postes de direction. Il est recommandé d’utiliser conjointement deux mesures différentes pour cet indicateur : la part des femmes dans la gestion (totale) et la part des femmes dans les cadres supérieurs et intermédiaires (excluant ainsi la gestion junior (cadres inférieurs). Le calcul conjoint de ces deux mesures fournit des informations pour déterminer si les femmes sont plus représentées dans les postes de cadres inférieurs que dans les postes de cadres supérieurs et intermédiaires, ce qui indique un plafond éventuel pour les femmes d’accéder à des postes de direction de haut niveau. Dans ces cas, calculer seulement la proportion de femmes dans la gestion (totale) serait trompeur, suggérant que les femmes occupent des postes ayant plus de pouvoir de décision et de responsabilités qu’elles ne le font réellement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;L’emploi comprend toutes les personnes en âge de travailler qui, au cours
d’une courte période de référence (une semaine), ont été engagées dans une activité de production de biens ou de services rémunérés ou rentables. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;L’emploi dans la gestion est déterminé selon les catégories de la dernière
version de la Classification internationale type des professions (CITP-08), qui organise les emplois en un ensemble clairement défini de groupes basés sur les tâches et les fonctions entreprises dans le travail. Aux fins de cet indicateur, il est préférable de se référer séparément aux cadres supérieurs et intermédiaires seulement, ainsi qu’à la gestion totale (y compris la gestion junior). La proportion de femmes tend à être plus élevée dans les postes de cadres inférieurs que dans les postes de cadres supérieurs et intermédiaires, de sorte que limiter l’indicateur à une mesure incluant la gestion junior peut introduire des biais. Les cadres supérieurs et intermédiaires correspondent aux sous-grands groupes 11, 12 et 13 de la CITP-08 et aux sous-grands groupes 11 et 12 de la CITP-88. Si les statistiques ventilées au niveau des sous-grands groupes (niveaux à deux chiffres de la CITP) ne sont pas disponibles, alors le groupe principal 1 de la CITP-08 et de la CITP-88 peut être utilisé comme indicateur et celui-ci ne ferait alors référence qu’à la gestion totale (y compris la gestion junior). &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Этот показатель относится к доле женщин в общей численности лиц, занятых на руководящих должностях. Для этого показателя рекомендуется использовать два разных критерия: долю женщин в (общем) руководстве и долю женщин в высшем и среднем руководящем звене (таким образом, исключая младшее руководящее звено). Общий расчет этих двух критериев дает информацию о том, представлено ли женщин больше в низшем руководящем звене, чем в высшем и среднем руководящих звеньях, что указывает на возможный потолок доступа женщин к руководящим должностям более высокого уровня. В этих случаях подсчет доли женщин только в (общем) руководстве может ввести в заблуждение, поскольку это предполагало бы, что женщины занимают должности, наделенные большей властью и ответственностью в принятии решений, чем это происходит на самом деле.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Занятость включает всех лиц трудоспособного возраста, которые в течение короткого отчетного периода (одна неделя) занимались какой-либо деятельностью по производству товаров или оказанию услуг за плату или доход. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Занятость в группе руководителей определяется в соответствии с категориями последней версии Международной стандартной классификации занятий (МСКЗ-08), которая объединяет рабочие места в четко определенный набор групп на основе задач и обязанностей, выполняемых на рабочем месте. Для целей этого показателя предпочтительно обращаться отдельно только к высшему и среднему руководящему звену и к руководству в целом (включая младшее руководящее звено). Доля женщин, как правило, выше в младшем руководящем звене, чем в старшем и среднем руководящих звеньях, поэтому если ограничить показатель оценкой, включающей только младшее руководящее звено, то это может вызвать ошибку. Руководители высшего и среднего звена соответствуют основным подгруппам 11, 12 и 13 в МСКЗ-08 и основным подгруппам 11 и 12 в МСКЗ-88. Если статистические данные с разбивкой на подгруппы отсутствуют (двузначный уровень МСКЗ), тогда основная группа 1 МСКЗ-88 и МСКЗ-08 может использоваться в качестве косвенного показателя, и тогда показатель будет относиться только к общему руководству (включая младшее руководящее звено).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
