<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for the indicator 5-b-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;Goal 5: Achieve gender equality and empower all women and girls&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 5.b: Enhance the use of enabling technology, in particular information and communications technology, to promote the empowerment of women&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 5.b.1: Proportion of individuals who own a mobile telephone, by sex&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Proportion of individuals who own a mobile telephone, by sex (%)&lt;/p&gt;2023-03-31&lt;p&gt;4.4.1, 9.c.1, 17.6.1, 17.8.1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;International Telecommunication Union (ITU)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;International Telecommunication Union (ITU)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proportion of individuals who own a mobile telephone, by sex is defined as the &amp;#x2018;proportion of individuals who own a mobile telephone, by sex&amp;#x2019;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An individual owns a mobile cellular phone if he/she has a mobile cellular phone device with at least one active SIM card for personal use. Mobile cellular phones supplied by employers that can be used for personal reasons (to make personal calls, access the Internet, etc.) are included. Individuals who have only active SIM card(s) and not a mobile phone device are excluded. Individuals who have a mobile phone for personal use that is not registered under his/her name are also included. An active SIM card is a SIM card that has been used in the last three months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mobile (cellular) telephone refers to a portable telephone subscribing to a public mobile telephone service using cellular technology, which provides access to the Public Switched Telephone Network (PSTN). This includes analogue and digital cellular systems and technologies such as IMT-2000 (3G) and IMT-Advanced. Users of both postpaid subscriptions and prepaid accounts are included.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Percent (%) (of individuals)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For countries that collect this data through an official survey, and if data allow breakdown and disaggregation, the indicator can be broken down by region (urban/rural), sex, age group, educational level (International Standard Classification of Education (ISCED) ), by labour force status (International Labour Organization (ILO)), and by occupation (International Standard Classification of Occupation (ISCO)). The International Telecommunication Union (ITU)) collects data for all these breakdowns from countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This indicator is a newly developed International Telecommunication Union (ITU) indicator that was approved by the World Telecommunication/ICT Indicators Symposium (WTIS) in 2014. The indicator&amp;#x2019;s definition and methodology were developed under the coordination of ITU, through its Expert Groups, and following an extensive consultation process with countries. Data for the proportion of individuals owning a mobile phone were first collected in 2015 through an annual questionnaire that ITU sends to National Statistical Offices (NSO). In this questionnaire, through which ITU already collects several ICT indicators, ITU collects absolute values. The percentages are calculated a-posteriori. The survey methodology is verified to ensure that it meets adequate statistical standards. The data are verified to ensure consistency with previous years&amp;#x2019; data and other relevant country-level indicators (ICT and economic).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are usually not adjusted, but discrepancies in the definition, age scope of individuals, reference period, or the break in comparability between years are noted in a data note. For this reason, data are not always strictly comparable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The International Telecommunication Union (ITU) collects data on this indicator through an annual questionnaire that it sends to the heads of the National Statistical Offices (NSO). In this questionnaire, through which ITU already collects several ICT indicators, ITU collects absolute values. The percentages are calculated a-posteriori. The survey methodology is verified to ensure that it meets adequate statistical standards. The data are verified to ensure consistency with previous years&amp;#x2019; data and other relevant country-level indicators (ICT and economic). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The data are collected using the ITU Short and Long ICT Household questionnaires. . Each survey has its own data collection cycle. The International Telecommunication Union (ITU) collects data twice a year from Member States, in Q1 using the short questionnaire and in Q3 using the long questionnaire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data are released twice a year, In July and December, in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.itu.int/en/ITU-D/Statistics/Pages/publications/wtid.aspx&quot;&gt;Wor&amp;#x200B;ld Telecommun&amp;#x200B;ic&amp;#x200B;ation/ICT Indicators Database&amp;#x200B;&lt;/a&gt; (WTID) and in the ITU DataHub&amp;#x200B;, see https://datahub.itu.int/.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National Statistical Offices (NSOs).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;International Telecommunication Union (ITU)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the UN specialized agency for information and communication technologies (ICTs), the International Telecommunication Union (ITU) is the official source for global ICT statistics, collecting ICT data from its Member States. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mobile phone networks have spread rapidly over the last decade and the number of mobile-cellular subscriptions is quasi equal to the number of people living on earth. However, not every person uses or owns a mobile-cellular telephone. Mobile phone ownership, in particular, is important to track gender equality since the mobile phone is a personal device that, if owned and not just shared, provides women with a degree of independence and autonomy, including for professional purposes. Several studies have highlighted the link between mobile phone ownership and empowerment, and productivity growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Existing data on the proportion of women owning a mobile phone suggest that fewer women than men own a mobile phone. This indicator highlights the importance of mobile phone ownership to track and improve gender equality, and monitoring will help design targeted policies to overcome the gender divide. The collection of this indicator was proposed by the Task Group on Gender of the Partnership on Measuring ICT for Development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the data on the &amp;#x2018;proportion of individuals who own a mobile telephone&amp;#x2019; currently only exist for very few countries, ITU is encouraging all countries to collect data on this indicator through national household surveys and the indicator is expected to be added to the Partnership on Measuring ICT for Development&amp;#x2019;s Core List of Indicators. The number of countries with official data for this indicator is expected to increase in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Countries can collect data on this indicator through national household surveys. This indicator is calculated by dividing the total number of in-scope individuals who own a mobile phone by the total number of in-scope individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;[&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;(&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;m&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;b&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;-&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;v&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;w&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;g&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;m&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;b&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;)&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;/&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;(&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;m&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;b&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;-&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;v&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;)&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;]&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;*&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;100&lt;/mn&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data are submitted by Member States to The International Telecommunication Union (ITU). ITU checks and validates the data, in consultation with the Member States. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No adjustments are made to the data submitted by countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Missing values are not estimated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the absence of official household surveys, International Telecommunication Union (ITU) estimates the percentage of individuals owning mobile phones (owners of mobile phones as a percentage of total population) using various techniques, such as hot-deck imputation, regression models and time series forecast, using data such as Internet use, income, education and other ICT indicators.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Country-level data on the percentage of individuals owning mobile phones (owners of mobile phones as a percentage of total population) are first estimated using various techniques, such as hot-deck imputation, regression models and time series forecast. Hot-deck imputation uses data from countries with &amp;#x201C;similar&amp;#x201D; characteristics, such as GNI per capita and geographic location. In cases when it is not possible to find an adequate imputation based on similar cases, regression models are applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the country-level percentages are available for all countries, the number of mobile phone owners are calculated by multiplying the percentages to the population of the country. The regional and world total mobile phone owners were calculated by summing the country-level data. The aggregate percentages were calculated by dividing the regional totals by the population of respective groups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;ITU Manual for Measuring ICT Access and Use by Households and Individuals 2020:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.itu.int/en/ITU-D/Statistics/Pages/publications/manual.aspx&quot;&gt;https://www.itu.int/en/ITU-D/Statistics/Pages/publications/manual.aspx&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data are checked and validated by the ICT Data and Analytics (IDA) Division of the International Telecommunication Union (ITU). Countries are contacted to clarify and correct their submissions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The guidelines of the Manual for Measuring ICT Access and Use by Households and Individuals 2020 are followed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The guidelines of the Manual for Measuring ICT Access and Use by Households and Individuals 2020 are followed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the indicator is available for more than 80 countries at least from one survey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2015 onwards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For countries that collect this indicator through a national household survey, and if data allow breakdown and disaggregation, the indicator can be broken down not only by sex but also by region (urban/rural), age group, educational level, labour force status, and occupation. Estimates of regional aggregates by sex are also calculated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None. The International Telecommunication Union (ITU) uses the data provided by countries, including the in-scope population that is used to calculate the percentages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.itu.int/en/ITU-D/Statistics/Pages/default.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.itu.int/en/ITU-D/Statistics/Pages/default.aspx&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ITU Manual for Measuring ICT Access and Use by Households and Individuals 2020:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.itu.int/en/ITU-D/Statistics/Pages/publications/manual.aspx&quot;&gt;https://www.itu.int/en/ITU-D/Statistics/Pages/publications/manual.aspx&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
