<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COMPILING_ORG field for indicator 17-3-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The government agency in charge of the collection and compilation of the Balance of Payments statistics is the responsible organization for compilation and reporting of the personal remittances data. This information gets reported by the countries&amp;#x2019; government agencies to the International Monetary Fund. The World Bank is the responsible agency for compilation and reporting of the GDP data.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La agencia gubernamental encargada de la recolección y compilación de las estadísticas de la Balanza de Pagos es la organización responsable de la compilación y notificación de los datos sobre remesas personales. Los organismos gubernamentales de los países comunican esta información al Fondo Monetario Internacional. El Banco Mundial es el organismo responsable de la recopilación y notificación de los datos del PIB.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Compilateurs des données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L&apos;organisme gouvernemental chargé de la collecte et de la compilation des statistiques de la balance des paiements est l&apos;organisme responsable de la compilation et de l&apos;acheminement des données sur les envois de fonds des particuliers. Ces informations sont envoyées par les organismes responsables au FMI. La Banque mondiale est l&apos;organisme responsable de la compilation et de la diffusion des données sur le PIB.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Составители данных&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Правительственное учреждение, отвечающее за сбор и составление статистики платежного баланса, является ответственной организацией за составление и представление данных по частным денежным переводам. Эта информация подлежит направлению правительственными органами стран в Международный валютный фонд. Всемирный банк является ответственным учреждением за составление и представление данных по ВВП.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
