<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 17-15-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;To provide a comprehensive measure on the extent of use of country-owned results frameworks and other government-led planning tools, the indicator calculates the degree to which objectives, results, indicators and monitoring frameworks associated with new development interventions are drawn from government sources &amp;#x2013; including national, sector and subnational planning tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each development intervention of significant size (US$ 100,000 and above) approved during the year of reference, the following dimensions are assessed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Q1. Whether objectives are drawn from country-owned results frameworks, plans and strategies 0/1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Q2. Share of results (outcome) indicators that are drawn from country-owned results frameworks, plans and strategies %&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Q3. Share of results (outcome) indicators that will rely on sources of data provided by existing country-led monitoring systems or national statistical services to track project progress %&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global aggregates for the indicator (for partner countries and providers) are obtained by averaging the three dimensions of alignment with country&amp;#x2019;s priorities and goals across all new interventions for the reporting year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aggregated averages per partner country will provide the extent to which CRFs and planning tools are used by providers of development co-operation operating in that specific country in the design and monitoring of new development projects. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All formulas are available at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/sdgs/files/metadata-compilation/Metadata-Goal-17.pdf&quot;&gt;http://unstats.un.org/sdgs/files/metadata-compilation/Metadata-Goal-17.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aggregated averages per development partner will indicate the extent to which that development partner uses CRFs and planning tools in the design and monitoring of new development projects in countries in which it operates. Formulas are available at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/sdgs/files/metadata-compilation/Metadata-Goal-17.pdf&quot;&gt;http://unstats.un.org/sdgs/files/metadata-compilation/Metadata-Goal-17.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When aggregating, the size (budget amount) of the project/ intervention is not considered as weight in order to give the same level of importance to the extent of use of country-owned results frameworks and planning tools in medium-sized vs. larger projects, as the indicator tries to capture the overall behaviour of development partners in designing new interventions in a given country. Weighting by project size would otherwise overrepresent infrastructure projects and underrepresent interventions focused on influencing policies and institutional arrangements. Nevertheless, data on project size is available.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
