<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 3-9-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are available for practically all countries. They are, however, sometimes based on health statistics provided by international agencies as the national data are incomplete. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actual country data for 2010 onwards period &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asia and Pacific - 27% of countries (16 out of 59 countries, including China and India sample systems) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Africa - 6% of countries (3 out of 54 countries) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Latin America and the Caribbean - 56% of countries (19 out of 34 countries) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe, North America, Australia, New Zealand and Japan - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;94% of countries (44 out of 47 countries, missing are mainly very small countries) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the period 2000-2009 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asia and Pacific - 27% of countries (16 out of 59 countries, including China and India sample systems) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Africa - 6% of countries (3 out of 54 countries) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Latin America and the Caribbean - 56% of countries (19 out of 34 countries) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe, North America, Australia, New Zealand and Japan - 94% of countries (44 out of 47 countries, missing are mainly very small countries) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web link to the database: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.home &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator has been established and available for more than a decade. http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.INADEQUATEWSH?lang=en &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/gbd_poor_water/en/ &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHO has been collating country figures and has been using these to produce global and regional estimates against this indicator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limited time series data is available (comparable series for years 2012 and soon 2015; data for 2002 are also available but have more limited comparability) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this indicator is population-based, geographic location is the most natural disaggregation. Data also exists for age group and sex. Similar to JMP&amp;#x2019;s work on disaggregation by income groups (wealth quintile), data can further be disaggregated by wealth quintile. &lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
