<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 3-d-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;AMR is an emerging global threat and risk to public health worldwide. In its early implementation phase of the global antimicrobial resistance surveillance system (GLASS), WHO recognizes various constraints in obtaining unbiased, representative AMR data: number and distribution of surveillance sites and representativeness of surveillance data, sampling bias, poor diagnostic capacity, measurements errors, issues with data management. It is imperative that countries should have a functioning national system to support AMR surveillance and report to GLASS. More detailed GLASS methodology and limitations of data currently submitted by countries can be found in the GLASS report&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-7&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-7&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. AMR surveillance, country preparedness and response are now high priority for WHO and its Member States. In the next five years, WHO aims to provide intensified technical assistance. Experience gained and lessons learnt from the further implementation of the national AMR surveillance systems will increase effectiveness, address limitations, and the make the data more robust. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-7&quot;&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Global antimicrobial resistance surveillance system (GLASS) report: &lt;/strong&gt;Early implementation 2017-2018 (2019). &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/handle/10665/279656/9789241515061-eng.pdf&quot;&gt;https://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/handle/10665/279656/9789241515061-eng.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-7&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;La résistance aux antimicrobiens (RAM) est une menace et un risque mondiaux émergents pour la santé publique dans le monde entier. Dans sa phase initiale de mise en œuvre du système « Global Antimicrobial Resistance and Use Surveillance System » (GLASS), l’OMS reconnaît diverses contraintes pour obtenir des données sur la RAM non biaisées et représentatives : nombre et distribution des sites de surveillance et représentativité des données de surveillance, biais d’échantillonnage, faible capacité de diagnostic, erreurs de mesure et problèmes de gestion des données. Il est impératif que les pays disposent d’un système national opérationnel pour soutenir la surveillance de la RAM et soumettre leurs données dans le système GLASS. La méthodologie plus détaillée et les limites des données actuellement soumises par les pays peuvent être trouvées dans le rapport (en anglais) GLASS&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-7&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-7&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. La surveillance de la résistance aux antimicrobiens, la préparation et la réaction des pays sont désormais une priorité absolue pour l’OMS et ses États embres. Au cours des cinq prochaines années, l’OMS entend intensifier l’assistance technique. L’expérience acquise et les leçons tirées de la poursuite de la mise en œuvre des systèmes nationaux de surveillance de la RAM augmenteront l’efficacité, corrigeront les limites et rendront les données plus robustes. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-7&quot;&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;« Global antimicrobial resistance surveillance system (GLASS) report : &lt;/strong&gt;Early implementation 2017-2018 » (2019). &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/handle/10665/279656/9789241515061-eng.pdf&quot;&gt;https://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/handle/10665/279656/9789241515061-eng.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-7&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
