<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 3-d-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preferred sources:&lt;/strong&gt; National AMR data collected through the national AMR surveillance system and reported to GLASS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GLASS provides a standardised approach to the collection, analysis, and sharing of AMR data by countries, and seeks to document the status of existing or newly developed national AMR surveillance systems. Furthermore, GLASS promotes a shift from surveillance approaches based solely on laboratory data to a system that includes epidemiological, clinical, and population-level data. GLASS also collaborates with regional and national AMR surveillance networks to produce timely and comprehensive data. Collaboration with the UN Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) and the World Organisation for Animal Health (OIE) &amp;#x2013; which together with WHO form the Tripartite Collaboration &amp;#x2013; is ongoing to improve a comprehensive understanding of AMR across sectors and to promote the One Health Approach to AMR control. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GLASS also collects information on the status of national AMR surveillance systems through a short &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;questionnaire completed by AMR national focal points (NFPs) in each country. The questionnaire covers three main areas: 1) overall coordination; 2) surveillance system; and 3) quality control. Each area consists of a set of indicators developed to measure development and strengthening of national AMR surveillance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other possible data sources:&lt;/strong&gt; Published and non-published data from national centres and research/academic institutions and from others regional surveillance networks. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
