<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 6-6-1b, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Treatment of missing values:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At country level:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For countries where no information on wetland inventories was provided to the Ramsar Convention on Wetlands Secretariat as part of their National Reports to COP13 (16% of countries) a report is in preparation by the Ramsar Secretariat using existing information from previous assessments and literature search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At regional and global levels:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As indicated above&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Traitement des valeurs manquantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Au niveau national: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour les pays où aucune information sur les inventaires des zones humides n&apos;a été fournie au Secrétariat de la Convention de Ramsar sur les zones humides dans le cadre de leurs rapports nationaux à la COP13 (16% des pays), un rapport est en cours de préparation par le Secrétariat de Ramsar, qui utilise les informations existantes provenant d&apos;évaluations précédentes et de recherches documentaires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aux niveaux régional et mondial : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Comme indiqué ci-dessus &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для стран, которые не предоставили Секретариату Рамсарской конвенции о водно-болотных угодьях информацию об инвентаризации водно-болотных угодий в рамках их национальных отчетов для COP 13 (16% стран), Секретариат Рамсарской конвенции готовит отчет с использованием существующей информации из предыдущих оценок и материалов литературного поиска. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Как указано выше &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
