<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 6-6-1b, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ramsar Convention on Wetlands is the Intergovernmental treaty that provides the framework for the Conservation and wise use of wetlands and their resources. The Convention was adopted in 1971 and came into force in 1975. Since then 170 Countries, representing almost 90% on UN member states, from all the world&amp;#xB4;s geographic regions have acceded to become Contracting Parties under the Convention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its 52nd meeting, in 2016, the Standing Committee of the Ramsar Convention agreed that Parties would include in their national reports for the 13th meeting of the Conference of the Parties, which have been submitted in January 2018, data on the &amp;#x201C;extent&amp;#x201D; of wetlands. This requirement provides an intergovernmental mechanism to obtain verified data that clearly contribute to Indicator 6.6.1 on wetland extent, but also to collect information for Target 15.1 which consider other types of ecosystems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator provides a measure of the relative extent of inland wetlands in a country. It follows the rationale of the forest indicator (Indicator 15.1.1). The availability of accurate data on a country&amp;apos;s wetland extent based on the country&amp;#xB4;s wetland inventory is crucial for the decision making regarding policies, restoration of critical wetlands or designation under national or international management or protected area categories. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changes in the wetland extent reflect wetland loss and degradation for land use changes or for other uses and may help identify unsustainable practices from different sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Convention de Ramsar sur les zones humides est le traité intergouvernemental qui fournit le cadre pour la conservation et l&apos;utilisation rationnelle des zones humides et de leurs ressources. La Convention a été adoptée en 1971 et est entrée en vigueur en 1975. Depuis lors, 170 pays, représentant près de 90 % des États membres des Nations unies, de toutes les régions géographiques du monde&amp;#xB4; ont adhéré à la Convention pour en devenir parties contractantes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lors de sa 52e réunion, en 2016, le Comité permanent de la Convention de Ramsar a convenu que les Parties incluraient dans leurs rapports nationaux pour la 13e session de la Conférence des Parties, qui ont été soumis en janvier 2018, des données sur l&apos;étendue des zones humides. Cette exigence fournit un mécanisme intergouvernemental pour obtenir des données vérifiées qui contribuent clairement à l&apos;indicateur 6.6.1 sur l&apos;étendue des zones humides, mais aussi pour collecter des informations pour l&apos;objectif 15.1 qui prennent en compte d&apos;autres types d&apos;écosystèmes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur fournit une mesure de l&apos;étendue relative des zones humides intérieures d&apos;un pays. Il suit la logique de l&apos;indicateur forestier (Indicateur 15.1.1). La disponibilité de données précises sur l&apos;étendue des zones humides d&apos;un pays &amp;apos;sur la base de l&apos;inventaire des zones humides du pays &amp;#xB4;est cruciale pour la prise de décision concernant les politiques, la restauration des zones humides critiques ou la désignation dans les catégories de gestion ou d&apos;aires protégées nationales ou internationales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les changements dans l&apos;étendue des zones humides reflètent la perte et la dégradation des zones humides pour des changements d&apos;affectation des terres ou pour d&apos;autres utilisations et peuvent aider à identifier des pratiques non durables dans différents secteurs.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Рамсарская конвенция о водно-болотных угодьях - это межправительственный договор, который обеспечивает основу для сохранения и разумного использования водно-болотных угодий и их ресурсов. Конвенция была принята в 1971 году и вступила в силу в 1975 году. С тех пор 170 стран, представляющих почти 90% государств-членов ООН, из всех географических регионов мира присоединились к ней, чтобы стать Договаривающимися сторонами в рамках Конвенции. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; На своем 52-м заседании в 2016 году Постоянный комитет Рамсарской конвенции согласился с тем, что Стороны включат в свои национальные отчеты к 13-му совещанию Конференции Сторон, представленные в январе 2018 года, данные о &quot;площади&quot; водно-болотных угодий. Это требование обеспечивает межправительственный механизм для получения верифицированных данных, которые явно вносят вклад в показатель 6.6.1 по площади водно-болотных угодий, а также для сбора информации для Целевой задачи 15.1, которая учитывает другие типы экосистем. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель позволяет оценить относительную площадь внутренних водно-болотных угодий в стране. Это соответствует обоснованию показателя лесов (показатель 15.1.1). Наличие точных данных по площади водно-болотных угодий страны, основанных на инвентаризации водно-болотных угодий страны, имеет решающее значение для принятия решений относительно политики, восстановления критических водно-болотных угодий или включения их в национальное или международное управление или категории охраняемых территорий. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Изменения в площади водно-болотных угодий отражают утрату и деградацию водно-болотных угодий в связи с изменениями в землепользовании или для других целей и могут помочь выявить неустойчивые методы в различных секторах. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
