<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 11-a-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Comments and limitations:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UN-Habitat and UNFPA, along with many other partners such as OECD and Cities Alliance are working together to collect updated information from Member States regarding the three qualifiers in addition to other questions pertinent to National Urban Policies and their implementation process. The survey&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-7&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-7&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; results will inform the 2020 Global State of National Urban Policy Report. Many countries have filled in required information based on the specific qualifiers of indicator 11.a.1. which builds upon the 2018 NUP dataset&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-8&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The success of the indicator requires more capacity development and routine follow ups with ministries and NSOs at national levels, but sometimes also going beyond the national levels to ensure good understanding of the 3 sub-components.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-7&quot;&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; See question 27 of Global Survey on National Urban Policies at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1-zn9d85GWJv1Tr039OtmoqPOfpwiowku/view?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1-zn9d85GWJv1Tr039OtmoqPOfpwiowku/view?usp=sharing&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-7&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-8&quot;&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; UN-Habitat and OECD, 2018, Global State of National Urban Policy (&lt;a href=&quot;http://urbanpolicyplatform.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Global-Report-NUP1.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://urbanpolicyplatform.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Global-Report-NUP1.pdf&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)  &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-8&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires et limites : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONU-Habitat et l&apos;UNFPA, ainsi que de nombreux autres partenaires tels que l&apos;OCDE et Cities Alliance travaillent ensemble pour recueillir des informations actualisées auprès des États membres concernant les trois critères de qualification, en plus d&apos;autres questions pertinentes pour les politiques urbaines nationales et leur processus de mise en œuvre. Les résultats de l&apos;enquête &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-7&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-7&quot;&gt; [7] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; alimenteront le rapport mondial 2020 sur l&apos;état des politiques urbaines nationales. De nombreux pays ont rempli les informations requises sur la base des qualificatifs spécifiques de l&apos;indicateur 11.a.1. qui s&apos;appuie sur l&apos;ensemble de données NUP 2018 &lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-8&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-8&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Le succès de l&apos;indicateur nécessite davantage de développement des capacités et un suivi de routine avec les ministères et les OSN aux niveaux nationaux, mais parfois aussi en allant au-delà des niveaux nationaux pour assurer une bonne compréhension des 3 sous-composantes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-7&quot;&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Voir la question 27 de l&apos;Enquête mondiale sur les politiques urbaines nationales à l&apos;adresse : &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1-zn9d85GWJv1Tr039OtmoqPOfpwiowku/view?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1-zn9d85GWJv1Tr039OtmoqPOfpwiowku/view?usp=sharing&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-7&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-8&quot;&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; ONU-Habitat et OCDE, 2018, État mondial des politiques urbaines nationales (&lt;a href=&quot;http://urbanpolicyplatform.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Global-Report-NUP1.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://urbanpolicyplatform.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Global-Report-NUP1.pdf&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).  &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-8&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ООН-Хабитат и ЮНФПА, а также многие другие партнеры, такие как ОЭСР и Альянс городов, совместно работают над сбором обновленной информации от государств-членов относительно трех спецификаторов в дополнение к другим вопросам, относящимся к национальным городским стратегиям и процессу их реализации. Результаты обследования &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-7&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-7&quot;&gt; [7] &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; послужат основой для Глобального доклада о состоянии национальной городской стратегии за 2020 год. Многие страны включили требуемую информацию, основанную на конкретных спецификаторах показателя 11.a.1., который построен на наборе данных национальной городской стратегии 2018 года. &lt;sup&gt; &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-8&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-8&quot;&gt; [8] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; Успех показателя требует большего развития потенциала и регулярной последующей работы с министерствами и национальными статистическими управлениями на национальном уровне, но иногда также требует выходить за рамки национального уровня, чтобы обеспечить хорошее понимание трех подкомпонентов. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-7&quot;&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt;&gt; См. вопрос 27 Глобального обследования национальной городской стратегии по адресу: &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1-zn9d85GWJv1Tr039OtmoqPOfpwiowku/view?usp=sharing&quot;&gt; https://drive.google.com/file/d/1-zn9d85GWJv1Tr039OtmoqPOfpwiowku/view?usp=sharing &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-7&quot;&gt; &amp;#x2191; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-8&quot;&gt; 8 &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p&gt; ООН-Хабитат и ОЭСР, 2018 г., Глобальный доклад о состоянии национальной городской стратегии (&lt;a href=&quot;http://urbanpolicyplatform.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Global-Report-NUP1.pdf&quot;&gt; &lt;u&gt; http : //urbanpolicyplatform.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Global-Report-NUP1.pdf &lt;/u&gt; &lt;/a&gt;) &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-8&quot;&gt; &amp;#x2191; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
