<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The QUALITY_ASSURE field for indicator 4-c-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The indicator should be based on available data on trained teachers for the given level of education, from all types of educational institutions in the country (public and private). The process for quality assurance includes review of survey documentation, review of the indicator values across time, calculation of measures of reliability, examination of consistency of indicator values derived from different sources and, if necessary, consultation with data providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before its annual data release and the addition of any indicators to the global SDG Indicators Database, the UNESCO Institute for Statistics submits all indicator values and notes on methodology to National Statistical Offices, Ministries of Education or other relevant agencies in individual countries for their review and feedback. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;L’indicateur devrait être basé sur les données disponibles sur les enseignants formés pour le niveau d’enseignement donné, de tous les types d’établissements d’enseignement du pays (publics et privés). Le processus d’assurance de la qualité comprend l’examen de la documentation de l’enquête, l’examen des valeurs des indicateurs au fil du temps, le calcul des mesures de fiabilité, l’examen de la cohérence des valeurs des indicateurs provenant de différentes sources et, si nécessaire, la consultation des fournisseurs de données. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avant la publication annuelle des données et l’ajout de tout indicateur à la base de données mondiale sur les indicateurs des ODD, l’Institut de statistique de l’UNESCO soumet toutes les valeurs des indicateurs et les notes méthodologiques aux bureaux nationaux de statistique, aux ministères de l’Éducation ou à d’autres organismes concernés dans les différents pays pour examen et rétroaction. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
