<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 1-a-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 1. End poverty in all its forms everywhere&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 1.a. Ensure significant mobilization of resources from a variety of sources, including through enhanced development cooperation, in order to provide adequate and predictable means for developing countries, in particular least developed countries, to implement programmes and policies to end poverty in all its dimensions&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 1.a.1:&amp;#xA0;Total official development assistance (ODA) grants from all donors that focus on poverty reduction as a share of the recipient country&amp;#x2019;s gross national income&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last updated: 14 April 2020&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Related indicators&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Institutional information&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organization(s):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OECD&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total official development assistance (ODA) grants from all donors that focus on poverty reduction as a share of the recipient country&amp;#x2019;s gross national income. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OECD/Development Assistance Committee (DAC) defines ODA as &amp;#x201C;flows to countries and territories on the DAC List of ODA Recipients and to multilateral institutions which are i) provided by official agencies, including state and local governments, or by their executive agencies; and ii) each transaction is administered with the promotion of the economic development and welfare of developing countries as its main objective; and is concessional in character and conveys a grant element of at least 25 per cent (calculated at a rate of discount of 10 per cent). (See &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poverty reduction items can be defined as ODA to basic social services (basic health, basic education, basic water and sanitation, population programmes and reproductive health) and developmental food aid (see here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/purposecodessectorclassification.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/purposecodessectorclassification.htm&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OECD/Development Assistance Committee (DAC) defines ODA as &amp;#x201C;flows to countries and territories on the DAC List of ODA Recipients and to multilateral institutions which are i) provided by official agencies, including state and local governments, or by their executive agencies; and ii) each transaction is administered with the promotion of the economic development and welfare of developing countries as its main objective; and is concessional in character and conveys a grant element of at least 25 per cent (calculated at a rate of discount of 10 per cent). (See &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic social services and development food aid, which focus on poverty reduction, are defined using the following OECD Creditor Reporting System purpose codes, which identify the sector the activity is intended to target: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Basic Education (CRS codes 112xx)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Basic Health (CRS codes (122xx)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Water Supply and Sanitation (CRS codes 140xx)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multisector aid for basic social services (CRS code 16050)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Development Food Aid (CRS code 52010)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The detailed list of CRS purpose codes and their definitions are available here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/purposecodessectorclassification.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/purposecodessectorclassification.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OECD/DAC has been collecting data on official and private resource flows, from 1960 at an aggregate level, and 1973 at an activity level through the Creditor Reporting System (CRS data are considered complete from 1995 for commitments at an activity level and 2002 for disbursements). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data are reported by donors according to the same standards and methodologies (see here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are reported on an annual calendar year basis by statistical reporters in national administrations (aid agencies, Ministries of Foreign Affairs or Finance, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Collection process:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A statistical reporter is responsible for the collection of DAC statistics in each providing country/agency. This reporter is usually located in the national aid agency, Ministry of Foreign Affairs or Finance etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OECD prepares and sends a questionnaire on aid flows (at an activity level and aggregate level) to the national statistical reporter every year. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendar&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Data collection:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data collection is annual. Detailed 2019 flows will be published in December 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Data release:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detailed 2019 flows will be published in December 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data providers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A statistical reporter is responsible for the collection of DAC statistics in each providing country/agency. This reporter is usually located in the national aid agency, Ministry of Foreign Affairs or Finance etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data compilers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OECD, Development Cooperation Directorate&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Rationale:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total ODA flows to developing countries quantify the public effort (excluding non- concessional flows and export credits), that all donors provide for the economic development and welfare of developing countries. Within ODA, basic social services and development food aid focus on poverty alleviation in developing countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comments and limitations:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data in the Creditor Reporting System (i.e. at an activity level), are available from 1973 onwards. However, the data coverage is considered complete since 1995 for commitments and 2002 for disbursements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computation method:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From a donor country&amp;#x2019;s perspective&lt;/strong&gt;: The sum of bilateral ODA grants by donor that focus on poverty reduction as a share of the donor country&amp;#x2019;s gross national income. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From a recipient country&amp;#x2019;s perspective&lt;/strong&gt;: The sum of total ODA grants from all donors (i.e. DAC donors, multilateral organisations and other bilateral providers of development cooperation) that focus on poverty reduction as a share of the developing country&amp;#x2019;s gross national income. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Treatment of missing values:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At country level:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to high quality of reporting, no estimates are produced for missing data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At regional and global levels:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to high quality of reporting, no estimates are produced for missing data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Regional aggregates:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global, regional and country figures are based on the sum of ODA grant flows for poverty reduction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Methods and guidance available to countries for the compilation of the data at the national level:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DAC statistical Reporting Directives govern the reporting of DAC statistics, and are reviewed and agreed by the DAC Working Party of Development Finance Statistics, see: &lt;a href=&quot;https://one.oecd.org/document/DCD/DAC/STAT(2018)9/FINAL/en/pdf&quot;&gt;https://one.oecd.org/document/DCD/DAC/STAT(2018)9/FINAL/en/pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Quality assurance:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OECD/DAC Secretariat is responsible for verifying and validating data submissions from providers of development cooperation, as well as publishing the data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data availability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are published on an annual basis in December for flows in the previous year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detailed 2019 flows will be published in December 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provisional data classification: Tier I&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Time series:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OECD/DAC has been collecting data on official and private resource flows, from 1960 at an aggregate level, and 1973 at an activity level through the Creditor Reporting System (CRS data are considered complete from 1995 for commitments at an activity level and 2002 for disbursements). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator can be disaggregated by donor, by recipient country, by type of finance, by type of aid, by sub-sector, by policy marker (e.g. gender), etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DAC statistics are standardized on a calendar year basis for all donors and may differ from fiscal year data available in budget documents for some countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See all links here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See all links here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 1: Poner fin a la pobreza en todas sus formas y en todo el mundo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 1.a: Garantizar una movilización significativa de recursos procedentes de diversas fuentes, incluso mediante la mejora de la cooperación para el desarrollo, a fin de proporcionar medios suficientes y previsibles a los países en desarrollo, en particular los países menos adelantados, para que implementen programas y políticas encaminados a poner fin a la pobreza en todas sus dimensiones&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 1.a.1: Total de las subvenciones de asistencia oficial para el desarrollo de todos los donantes que se centran en la reducción de la pobreza como porcentaje del ingreso nacional bruto del país receptor&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Última actualización: 14 de abril de 2020&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicadores relacionados&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Información institucional &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Organización(es): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; OCDE &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El total de la ayuda oficial al desarrollo (AOD) de todos los donantes que se centran en la reducción de la pobreza como porcentaje de la renta nacional bruta del país receptor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El Comité de Ayuda al Desarrollo (CAD) de la OCDE define la AOD como &amp;#x201C;los flujos destinados a los países y territorios que figuran en la lista de beneficiarios de la AOD del CAD y a las instituciones multilaterales que i) son proporcionados por organismos oficiales, incluidos los gobiernos estatales y locales, o por sus organismos ejecutivos; y ii) cada transacción se administra con el objetivo principal de promover el desarrollo económico y el bienestar de los países en desarrollo; y es de carácter concesional y transmite un elemento de subvención de al menos el 25% (calculado con una tasa de descuento del 10%). (Véase &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las partidas de reducción de la pobreza pueden definirse como la AOD destinada a los servicios sociales básicos (salud básica, educación básica, agua y saneamiento básico, programas de población y salud reproductiva) y la ayuda alimentaria al desarrollo (véase aquí: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/purposecodessectorclassification.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/purposecodessectorclassification.htm&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El Comité de Ayuda al Desarrollo (CAD) de la OCDE define la AOD como &amp;#x201C;los flujos destinados a los países y territorios que figuran en la lista de beneficiarios de la AOD del CAD y a las instituciones multilaterales que i) son proporcionados por organismos oficiales, incluidos los gobiernos estatales y locales, o por sus agencias ejecutivas; y ii) cada transacción se administra teniendo como objetivo principal la promoción del desarrollo económico y el bienestar de los países en desarrollo; y es de carácter concesional y conlleva un elemento de subvención de al menos el 25% (calculado con una tasa de descuento del 10%). (Véase &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los servicios sociales básicos y la ayuda alimentaria al desarrollo, que se centran en la reducción de la pobreza, se definen utilizando los siguientes códigos de propósito del Sistema de Notificación de los Países Acreedores (CRS, por sus siglas en inglés) de la OCDE, que identifican el sector al que se dirige la actividad: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Educación básica (códigos 112xx del CRS)&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Salud básica (códigos CRS (122xx)&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Abastecimiento de agua y saneamiento (códigos CRS 140xx)&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Ayuda multisectorial a los servicios sociales básicos (código CRS 16050)&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Ayuda alimentaria al desarrollo (código CRS 52010)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La lista detallada de los códigos de propósito del CRS y sus definiciones están disponibles aquí: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/purposecodessectorclassification.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/purposecodessectorclassification.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El CAD de la OCDE ha venido recopilando datos sobre los flujos de recursos oficiales y privados, desde 1960 a nivel agregado, y desde 1973 a nivel de actividad a través del Sistema de Notificación de los Países Acreedores (CRS, por sus siglas en inglés) (los datos del CRS se consideran completos desde 1995 para los compromisos a nivel de actividad y desde 2002 para los desembolsos). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos son comunicados por los donantes según las mismas normas y metodologías (véase aquí: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos son comunicados por año calendario por los informadores estadísticos de las administraciones nacionales (organismos de ayuda, Ministerios de Asuntos Exteriores o de Hacienda, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Proceso de recolección:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Un informante estadístico es responsable de la recopilación de estadísticas del DAC en cada país/agencia. Este informante se encuentra generalmente en la agencia nacional de cooperación, Ministerio de Relaciones Exteriores o Finanzas, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La OCDE prepara y envía cada año un cuestionario sobre los flujos de ayuda (a nivel de actividad y de nivel agregado) al informante estadístico nacional. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendario&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recolección de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La recolección de datos es anual. Los flujos detallados de 2019 se publicarán en diciembre de 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publicación de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los flujos detallados de 2019 se publicarán en diciembre de 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Un informante estadístico es el responsable de la recogida de las estadísticas del CAD en cada país/agencia proveedora. Este informante suele estar ubicado en la agencia nacional de cooperación, el Ministerio de Asuntos Exteriores o de Finanzas, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; OCDE, Dirección de Cooperación para el Desarrollo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los flujos totales de AOD a los países en desarrollo cuantifican el esfuerzo público (excluyendo los flujos no concesionales y los créditos a la exportación) que todos los donantes aportan para el desarrollo económico y el bienestar de los países en desarrollo. Dentro de la AOD, los servicios sociales básicos y la ayuda alimentaria al desarrollo se centran en el alivio de la pobreza en los países en desarrollo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos del Sistema de Información de los Países Acreedores (a nivel de actividad), están disponibles a partir de 1973. Sin embargo, la cobertura de datos se considera completa desde 1995 para los compromisos y 2002 para los desembolsos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Desde la perspectiva de un país donante&lt;/strong&gt;: La suma de las donaciones bilaterales de AOD por donante que se centran en la reducción de la pobreza como proporción de la renta nacional bruta del país donante. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Desde la perspectiva de un país receptor&lt;/strong&gt;: La suma de las donaciones totales de AOD de todos los donantes (es decir, los donantes del CAD, las organizaciones multilaterales y otros proveedores bilaterales de cooperación al desarrollo) que se centran en la reducción de la pobreza como porcentaje de la renta nacional bruta del país en desarrollo. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel de país:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debido a la alta calidad de los informes, no se elaboran estimaciones para los datos que faltan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel regional y mundial:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Debido a la alta calidad de los informes, no se elaboran estimaciones para los datos que faltan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Agregados regionales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Las cifras mundiales, regionales y de países se basan en la suma de los flujos de donaciones de la AOD para la reducción de la pobreza. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Métodos y directrices a disposición de los países para la compilación de los datos a nivel nacional:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las Directivas de Información Estadística del CAD rigen la presentación de las estadísticas del CAD, y son revisadas y acordadas por el Grupo de Trabajo del CAD sobre Estadísticas de Financiación del Desarrollo, véase: &lt;a href=&quot;https://one.oecd.org/document/DCD/DAC/STAT(2018)9/FINAL/en/pdf&quot;&gt;https://one.oecd.org/document/DCD/DAC/STAT(2018)9/FINAL/es/pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Garantía de calidad:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Secretaría del CAD de la OCDE se encarga de verificar y validar los datos presentados por los proveedores de cooperación al desarrollo, así como de publicarlos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos se publican anualmente en diciembre para los flujos del año anterior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los flujos detallados de 2019 se publicarán en diciembre de 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clasificación provisional de los datos: Nivel I&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El CAD de la OCDE ha venido recopilando datos sobre los flujos de recursos oficiales y privados, desde 1960 a nivel agregado, y desde 1973 a nivel de actividad a través del CRS (los datos del CRS se consideran completos desde 1995 para los compromisos a nivel de actividad y desde 2002 para los desembolsos). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Este indicador puede desglosarse por donante, por país receptor, por tipo de financiación, por tipo de ayuda, por subsector, por marcador de política (por ejemplo, género), etc. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Fuentes de discrepancia:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las estadísticas del CAD están estandarizadas en base al año calendario para todos los donantes y pueden diferir de los datos del año fiscal disponibles en los documentos presupuestarios de algunos países.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ver todos los enlaces aquí: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Referencias: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ver todos los enlaces aquí: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 1 : Éliminer la pauvreté sous toutes ses formes et partout dans le monde&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 1.a : Garantir une mobilisation importante de ressources provenant de sources multiples, y compris par le renforcement de la coopération pour le développement, afin de doter les pays en développement, en particulier les pays les moins avancés, de moyens adéquats et prévisibles de mettre en œuvre des programmes et politiques visant à mettre fin à la pauvreté sous toutes ses formes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 1.a.1 : Total des dons d’aide publique au développement axés sur la réduction de la pauvreté, tous donateurs confondus, exprimé en proportion du revenu national brut du pays bénéficiaire&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dernière mise à jour : 14 avril 2020&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicateurs connexes&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Informations institutionnelles&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Organisation(s) :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; OCDE&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Définition : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total des subventions d&apos;aide publique au développement (APD) de tous les donateurs qui se concentrent sur la réduction de la pauvreté en tant que part du revenu national brut du pays bénéficiaire. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Le Comité d&apos;aide au développement (CAD) de l&apos;OCDE définit l&apos;APD comme « les flux vers les pays et territoires figurant sur la liste du CAD des bénéficiaires de l&apos;APD et institutions multilatérales qui sont i) fournis par des organismes officiels, y compris les gouvernements des États et les collectivités locales, ou par leurs agences exécutives ; et ii) chaque transaction est administrée avec pour principal objectif la promotion du développement économique et du bien-être des pays en développement ; elle est de nature concessionnelle et comporte un élément de don d&apos;au moins 25 % (calculé à un taux d&apos;actualisation de 10 %)». (Voir &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les éléments de réduction de la pauvreté peuvent être définis comme l&apos;APD aux services sociaux de base (santé de base, éducation de base, eau et assainissement de base, programmes de population et santé reproductive) et l&apos;aide alimentaire au développement (voir &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/purposecodessectorclassification.htm&quot;&gt; http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Le Comité d&apos;aide au développement (CAD) de l&apos;OCDE définit l&apos;APD comme «les flux à destination des pays et territoires figurant sur la liste du CAD des bénéficiaires de l&apos;APD et institutions multilatérales qui sont i) fourni par des organismes officiels, y compris les gouvernements des États et les collectivités locales, ou par leurs agences exécutives ; et ii) chaque transaction est administrée avec pour principal objectif la promotion du développement économique et du bien-être des pays en développement ; elle est de nature concessionnelle et comporte un élément de libéralité d&apos;au moins 25 % (calculé à un taux d&apos;actualisation de 10 %)». (Voir &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les services sociaux de base et l&apos;aide alimentaire au développement, qui sont axés sur la réduction de la pauvreté, sont définis à l&apos;aide des codes d&apos;objectif suivants du Système de notification des pays créanciers de l&apos;OCDE, qui identifient le secteur que l&apos;activité est censée cibler : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Éducation de base (codes SNPC 112xx) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Santé de base (codes SNPC 122xx)) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Approvisionnement en eau et assainissement (codes SNPC 140xx) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aide multisectorielle pour les services sociaux de base (code SNPC 16050)
&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aide alimentaire au développement (code SNPC 52010) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La liste détaillée des codes de finalité des SNPC et leurs définitions sont disponibles ici : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/purposecodessectorclassification.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/purposecodessectorclassification.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Sources de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le CAD de l&apos;OCDE collecte des données sur les flux de ressources officielles et privées depuis 1960 au niveau agrégé et depuis 1973 au niveau des activités par le biais du Système de notification des pays créanciers (les données du CRS sont considérées comme complètes à partir de 1995 pour les engagements au niveau des activités et de 2002 pour les décaissements). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont communiquées par les donateurs selon les mêmes normes et méthodologies (voir ici : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont déclarées sur la base d&apos;une année civile annuelle par les déclarants statistiques des administrations nationales (agences d&apos;aide, ministères des affaires étrangères ou des finances, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Processus de collecte:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Un déclarant statistique est responsable de la collecte des statistiques du CAD dans chaque pays ou agence fournisseur d&apos;aide. Ce dernier est généralement situé dans l’agence nationale d’aide, ministère des affaires étrangères ou des finances, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Chaque année, l’OCDE prépare et envoie un questionnaire sur les flux d’aide (au niveau de l’activité et au niveau global) au déclarant statistique national. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendrier&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Collecte de données :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La collecte de données est annuelle. Les flux détaillés de 2019 seront publiés en décembre 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publication des données :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les flux détaillés pour 2019 seront publiés en décembre 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fournisseurs de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Un déclarant statistique est responsable de la collecte des statistiques du CAD dans chaque pays/organisme fournisseur. Ce déclarant se trouve généralement dans l&apos;organisme d&apos;aide national, le ministère des affaires étrangères ou des finances, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compilateurs de données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OCDE, Direction de la coopération pour le développement &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justification :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les flux totaux d&apos;APD aux pays en développement quantifient l&apos;effort public (à l&apos;exclusion des flux non concessionnels et des crédits à l&apos;exportation) que tous les donateurs fournissent pour le développement économique et le bien-être des pays en développement. Dans le cadre de l&apos;APD, les services sociaux de base et l&apos;aide alimentaire au développement sont axés sur la lutte contre la pauvreté dans les pays en développement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires et limites : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les données du Système de notification des pays créanciers (SNPC, c&apos;est-à-dire au niveau des activités) sont disponibles à partir de 1973. Toutefois, la couverture des données est considérée comme complète que depuis 1995 pour les engagements et 2002 pour les décaissements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Méthodologie&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Méthode de calcul :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Du point de vue d&apos;un pays donateur&lt;/strong&gt; : La somme des dons bilatéraux d&apos;APD par donateur qui se concentrent sur la réduction de la pauvreté en tant que part du revenu national brut du pays donateur. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Du point de vue d&apos;un pays bénéficiaire&lt;/strong&gt; : La somme des subventions totales de l&apos;APD de tous les donateurs (c&apos;est-à-dire les donateurs du CAD, les organisations multilatérales et les autres fournisseurs bilatéraux de coopération au développement) qui se concentrent sur la réduction de la pauvreté en tant que part du revenu national brut du pays en développement. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Traitement des valeurs manquantes : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Au niveau national : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; En raison de la qualité élevée des rapports, aucune estimation n&apos;est produite pour les données manquantes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Aux niveaux régional et mondial : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En raison de la grande qualité des rapports, aucune estimation n&apos;est produite pour les données manquantes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agrégats régionaux : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les chiffres mondiaux, régionaux et nationaux sont basés sur la somme des flux de subventions de l&apos;APD pour la réduction de la pauvreté.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Méthodes et instructions mises à la disposition des pays pour la compilation des données au niveau national :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les directives du CAD sur les rapports statistiques régissent la communication des statistiques du CAD, et sont examinées et approuvées par le groupe de travail du CAD sur les statistiques du financement du développement, voir : &lt;a href=&quot;https://one.oecd.org/document/DCD/DAC/STAT(2018)9/FINAL/en/pdf&quot;&gt;https://one.oecd.org/document/DCD/DAC/STAT(2018)9/FINAL/en/pdf &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Assurance de la qualité : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Secrétariat du CAD de l&apos;OCDE est chargé de vérifier et de valider les données transmises par les fournisseurs de la coopération au développement, ainsi que de les publier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilité des données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont publiées sur une base annuelle en décembre pour les flux de l’année précédente. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les flux détaillés pour 2019 seront publiés en décembre 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Classification provisoire des données : niveau I&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Séries chronologiques :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le CAD de l&apos;OCDE recueille des données sur les flux officiels et privés de ressources, à partir de 1960 à un niveau global, et de 1973 au niveau de l’activité par l’intermédiaire du Système de notification des pays créanciers (les données du SNPC sont considérées comme complètes à partir de 1995 pour les engagements au niveau de l’activité et de 2002 pour les décaissements). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Désagrégation :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur peut être désagrégé par donateur, par pays bénéficiaire, par type de financement, par type d’aide, par sous-secteur, par marqueur de politiques (par exemple le sexe), etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sources d’écarts :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les statistiques du DAC sont normalisées sur une base d’année civile pour tous les donateurs et peuvent différer des données de l’exercice disponible dans les documents budgétaires de certains pays. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Références&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voir tous les liens ici : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Références : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voir tous les liens ici : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 1: Повсеместная ликвидация нищеты во всех ее формах&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 1.a: Обеспечить мобилизацию значительных ресурсов из самых разных источников, в том числе на основе активизации сотрудничества в целях развития, с тем чтобы предоставить развивающимся странам, особенно наименее развитым странам, достаточные и предсказуемые средства для осуществления программ и стратегий по ликвидации нищеты во всех ее формах&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 1.a.1: Суммарный объем субсидий на официальную помощь в целях развития, полученных от всех доноров и направляемых на искоренение нищеты, в качестве доли от валового национального дохода страны-получателя&lt;/p&gt;Последнее обновление: 14 апреля 2020 года&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Связанные показатели&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Институциональная информация &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Организация (и): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ОЭСР &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Суммарный объем субсидий на официальную помощь в целях развития (ОПР), полученных от всех доноров и направляемых на искоренение нищеты, в качестве доли от валового национального дохода страны-получателя. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ОЭСР / Комитет содействия развитию (КСР) определяет ОПР как потоки в страны и территории, указанные в Списке получателей официальной помощи в целях развития Комитета содействия развитию, и в многосторонние учреждения, которые i) представлены официальными учреждениями, включая правительства государств и местные органы власти, или их исполнительными агентствами; и ii) каждая трансакция проводится с основной целью содействия экономическому развитию и благосостоянию развивающихся стран; носит концессионный характер и предусматривает безвозмездный элемент в размере не менее 25 процентов (рассчитывается по ставке дисконтирования 10 процентов). (См. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm&quot;&gt; http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm &lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Элементы сокращения бедности можно определить как официальную помощь в целях развития для основных социальных услуг (базовое здравоохранение, базовое образование, базовое водоснабжение и санитария, программы в области народонаселения и репродуктивное здоровье) и продовольственную помощь в целях развития (см. здесь: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/purposecodessectorclassification.htm&quot;&gt; http: // www. oecd.org/dac/stats/purposecodessectorclassification.htm&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ОЭСР / Комитет содействия развитию (КСР) определяет ОПР как потоки в страны и территории, указанные в Списке получателей официальной помощи в целях развития Комитета содействия развитию, и в многосторонние учреждения, которые i) представлены официальными учреждениями, включая правительства государств и местные органы власти, или их исполнительными агентствами; и ii) каждая трансакция проводится с основной целью содействия экономическому развитию и благосостоянию развивающихся стран; носит концессионный характер и предусматривает безвозмездный элемент в размере не менее 25 процентов (рассчитывается по ставке дисконтирования 10 процентов). (См. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm&quot;&gt; http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm &lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Основные социальные услуги и продовольственная помощь в целях развития, которые направлены на сокращение бедности, определяются с использованием следующих целевых кодов Системы отчетности кредиторов (СОК) ОЭСР, которые определяют сектор направления деятельности: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Базовое образование (коды СОК112xx) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Базовое здравоохранение (коды СОК(122xx) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Водоснабжение и санитария (коды СОК 140xx) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Многосекторальная помощь для основных социальных услуг (код СОК 16050) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Продовольственная помощь в целях развития (код СОК 52010) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Подробный список целевых кодов Система отчетности кредиторов и их определения доступны здесь: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/purposecodessectorclassification.htm&quot;&gt; http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/purposecodessectorclassification.htm &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OЭСР / Комитет содействия развитию (КСР) собирает данные по потокам официальных и частных ресурсов с 1960 г. на агрегированном уровне и с 1973 г. на уровне секторов деятельности с помощью Системы отчетности кредиторов (данные СОК считаются полными с 1995 г. по обязательствам на уровне секторов деятельности и с 2002 г. по выплаченным суммам).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Доноры представляют данные в соответствии с теми же стандартами и методологиями (см. здесь: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt; http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm &lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные представляются ежегодно лицами, направляющими статистические отчеты, из национальных администраций (агентства по оказанию помощи, министерства иностранных дел или финансов и т. д.) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Лицо, направляющее статистический отчет, отвечает за сбор статистических данных Комитета содействия развитию (КСР) в каждой отчитывающейся стране / агентстве. Это лицо, направляющее отчет, обычно находится в национальном агентстве по оказанию помощи, Министерстве иностранных дел или финансов и т. д. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ОЭСР ежегодно готовит и отсылает лицу, направляющему национальной статистический отчет, вопросник о потоках помощи (на уровне секторов деятельности и на агрегированном уровне). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Календарь &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Сбор данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Сбор данных осуществляется ежегодно. Подробные сведения о потоках за 2019 год будут опубликованы в декабре 2020 года. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Выпуск данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Подробные данные по потокам за 2019 год будут опубликованы в декабре 2020 года. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Поставщики данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Лицо, направляющее статистические отчеты, отвечает за сбор статистических данных КСР в каждой отчитывающейся стране / агентстве. Это лицо, направляющее отчеты, обычно находится в национальном агентстве по оказанию помощи, Министерстве иностранных дел или финансов и т. д. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Составители данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ОЭСР, Директорат сотрудничества в целях развития &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Общие потоки ОПР в развивающиеся страны количественно определяют государственные усилия (исключая неконцессионные потоки и экспортные кредиты), которые все доноры предоставляют для экономического развития и благосостояния развивающихся стран. В рамках ОПР основные социальные услуги и продовольственная помощь в целях развития направлены на сокращение масштабов нищеты в развивающихся странах. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные в Системе отчетности кредиторов (т. е. на уровне секторов деятельности) доступны начиная с 1973 года. Однако охват данных считается полным с 1995 г. по обязательствам и с 2002 г. по выплаченным суммам. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; С точки зрения страны-донора &lt;/strong&gt;: сумма двусторонних грантов ОПР донора, направленных на сокращение бедности, как доля валового национального дохода страны-донора. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; С точки зрения страны-получателя &lt;/strong&gt;: Сумма общих грантов ОПР от всех доноров (т.е. доноров КСР, многосторонних организаций и других двусторонних поставщиков инструментов сотрудничества в целях развития), которые направлены на сокращение бедности как доля валового национального дохода развивающейся страны. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Благодаря высокому качеству отчетности оценка отсутствующих данных не производится. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Благодаря высокому качеству отчетности оценка отсутствующих данных не производится. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Региональные агрегаты: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Глобальные, региональные и страновые данные основаны на сумме потоков грантов ОПР, направленных на сокращение бедности. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Доступные странам методы и руководства для составления данных на национальном уровне: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Директивы КСР по статистической отчетности регулируют составление отчетов по статистике КСР и рассматриваются и согласовываются Рабочей группой КСР по статистике финансирования развития, см.: &lt;a href=&quot;https://one.oecd.org/document/DCD/DAC/STAT(2018)9/FINAL/en/pdf&quot;&gt; https://one.oecd.org/document/DCD/DAC / STAT (2018) 9 / FINAL / en / pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обеспечение качества: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Секретариат ОЭСР / КСР отвечает за верификацию и подтверждение данных, представленных поставщиками инструментов сотрудничества в целях развития, а также за публикацию данных. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные по потокам публикуются на ежегодной основе в декабре за предыдущий год. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Подробные данные по потокам 2019 года будут опубликованы в декабре 2020 года. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Предварительная классификация данных: Уровень I&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ОЭСР / КСР собирает данные по потокам официальных и частных ресурсов с 1960 г. на агрегированном уровне и с 1973 г. на уровне секторов деятельности с помощью Системы отчетности кредиторов (данные СОК считаются полными с 1995 г. по обязательствам на уровне секторов деятельности и с 2002 г. по выплаченным суммам). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Этот показатель может быть дезагрегирован по донорам, странам-получателям, по типам финансирования, по типам помощи, по подсекторам, по маркерам политики гендерного равенства (например, по полу) и т. д.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Источники расхождений:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Статистика Комитета содействия развитию (КСР) унифицирована на основе календарного года для всех доноров и может отличаться от данных, составленных на основе финансового года, применяющегося в бюджетных документах некоторых стран.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; См. все ссылки здесь: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt; http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Ссылки: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; См. все ссылки здесь: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt; http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
