<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 3-b-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Collection process:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annual data collection through established mechanism. Since 1998, in an effort to strengthen collaboration and minimize the reporting burden, WHO and UNICEF jointly collect information through a standard questionnaire (the Joint Reporting Form) sent to all Member States &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/immunization/monitoring_surveillance/routine/reporting/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/immunization/monitoring_surveillance/routine/reporting/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Proceso de recolección:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recopilación anual de datos a través de un mecanismo establecido. Desde 1998, en un esfuerzo por reforzar la colaboración y minimizar la carga de información, la OMS y UNICEF recopilan conjuntamente la información a través de un cuestionario estándar (el Formulario de Información Conjunta) enviado a todos los Estados miembros &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/immunization/monitoring_surveillance/routine/reporting/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/immunization/monitoring_surveillance/routine/reporting/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Processus de collecte : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collecte annuelle de données par le biais d&apos;un mécanisme établi. Depuis 1998, dans un effort pour renforcer la collaboration et réduire au minimum la charge de travail liée à l&apos;établissement des rapports, l&apos;OMS et l&apos;UNICEF recueillent conjointement des informations au moyen d&apos;un questionnaire standard (le formulaire de rapport conjoint) envoyé à tous les États membres &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/immunization/monitoring_surveillance/routine/reporting/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/immunization/monitoring_surveillance/routine/reporting/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Ежегодный сбор данных с помощью общепринятого механизма. С 1998 года, стремясь укрепить сотрудничество и минимизировать бремя отчетности, ВОЗ и ЮНИСЕФ совместно собирают информацию с помощью стандартного вопросника (Совместная форма отчетности), рассылаемого всем странам-членам &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/immunization/monitoring_surveillance/routine/reporting/en/&quot;&gt; http://www.who.int/immunization/monitoring_surveillance/regular/reporting/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
