<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 17-19-2b, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Proceso de recolección:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las Oficinas Nacionales de Estadística de todos los países y zonas proporcionan el nivel nacional de exhaustividad del registro de nacimientos y defunciones a la División de Estadística de las Naciones Unidas como parte de la recopilación anual de datos para el &lt;em&gt;Anuario Demográfico de las Naciones Unidas&lt;/em&gt;. Esta información se suele comunicar como parte de las hojas de trabajo de metadatos del cuestionario de Estadísticas Vitales. La plantilla de este cuestionario está disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/demographic/products/dyb/dybquest.htm&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/demographic/products/dyb/dybquest.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Информация о национальном уровне полноты регистрации рождений и смертей предоставляются национальными статистическими управлениями всех стран и территорий Статистическому отделу Организации Объединенных Наций в рамках ежегодного сбора данных для &lt;em&gt; Демографического ежегодника Организации Объединенных Наций&lt;/em&gt;. Эта информация обычно включается в таблицы метаданных вопросника по статистике естественного движения населения. Шаблон этого вопросника доступен по адресу: &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/demographic/products/dyb/dybquest.htm&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/demographic/products/dyb/dybquest.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Collection process:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The national level of completeness of birth and death registration is provided by the National Statistical Offices of all countries and areas to the United Nations Statistics Division as part of the annual data collection for the United Nations &lt;em&gt;Demographic Yearbook&lt;/em&gt;. This information is usually reported as part of the metadata worksheets of the Vital Statistics questionnaire. The template of this questionnaire is available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/demographic/products/dyb/dybquest.htm&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/demographic/products/dyb/dybquest.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
