<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 6-5-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Rationale:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator provides a direct progress measurement of the first part of Target 6.5 &amp;#x201C;&amp;#x2026;implement integrated water resources management at all levels &amp;#x2026;&amp;#x201D;. The indicator score provides an easy and understandable way of measuring progress towards the target, with &amp;#x2018;0&amp;#x2019; interpreted as no implementation of IWRM, and &amp;#x2018;100&amp;#x2019; interpreted as IWRM being fully implemented. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To further aid interpretation and comparison, the indicator results can be categorized as follows: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Degree of implementation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Score range&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;General interpretation for overall IWRM score&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Very high&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;91 - 100&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Vast majority of IWRM elements are fully implemented, with objectives consistently achieved, and plans and programmes periodically assessed and revised.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;High&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;71 - 90&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;IWRM objectives of plans and programmes are generally met, and geographic coverage and stakeholder engagement is generally good.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Medium-high&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;51 - 70&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Capacity to implement elements of IWRM is generally adequate, and elements are generally being implemented under long-term programmes.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Medium-low&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;31 - 50&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Elements of IWRM are generally institutionalized, and implementation is underway.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Low&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;11 - 30&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Implementation of elements of IWRM has generally begun, but with limited uptake across the country, and potentially low engagement of stakeholder groups.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Very low&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;0 - 10&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Development of elements of IWRM has generally not begun, or has stalled.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of the survey is that it provides sufficient information to be of real value to the countries in determining their progress towards the target, and through this, various aspects of IWRM. A balance has been sought between providing sufficient information to cover the core principles of IWRM, and thus providing a robust indicator value, and not overburdening countries with unnecessary reporting requirements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Countries are encouraged to provide additional information on each question, which may help to qualify their choice of score, and/or put that score into their national context. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator 6.5.1 is supported by indicator 6.5.2 &amp;#x201C;Proportion of transboundary basin area with an operational arrangement for water cooperation&amp;#x201D;, which directly addresses the portion of Target 6.5 &amp;#x201C;&amp;#x2026;, including through transboundary cooperation as appropriate.&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador proporciona una medición directa del progreso de la primera parte de la Meta 6.5 &amp;#x201C;&amp;#x2026;implementar la gestión integrada de los recursos hídricos en todos los niveles &amp;#x2026;&amp;#x201D;. La puntuación del indicador proporciona una forma fácil y comprensible de medir el progreso hacia la meta, con &amp;#x2018;0&amp;#x2019; interpretado como que no se ha implementado la GIRH, y &amp;#x2018;100&amp;#x2019; interpretado como que la GIRH se ha implementado completamente.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para facilitar la interpretación y la comparación, los resultados de los indicadores pueden clasificarse de la siguiente manera:.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Grado de implementación.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Rango de puntuación.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Interpretación general de la puntuación global de la GIRH.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Muy alta.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;91 - 100.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;La gran mayoría de los elementos de la GIRH se aplican en su totalidad, los objetivos se alcanzan sistemáticamente y los planes y programas se evalúan y revisan periódicamente.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Alta.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;71 - 90.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Los objetivos de la GIRH incluidos en los planes y programas se cumplen en general, y la cobertura geográfica y la participación de las partes interesadas son generalmente buenas.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Media-Alta.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;51 - 70.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;La capacidad para aplicar los elementos de la GIRH es, en general, adecuada, y los elementos se aplican generalmente en el marco de programas a largo plazo&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Media-Baja.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;31 - 50.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Los elementos de la GIRH están generalmente institucionalizados y su aplicación está en marcha.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Baja.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;11 - 30.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;La aplicación de los elementos de la GIRH ha comenzado en general, pero con una aceptación limitada en todo el país y una participación potencialmente escasa de los grupos interesados.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Muy baja.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;0 - 10.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;En general, el desarrollo de los elementos de la GIRH no ha comenzado o se ha estancado.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El concepto de la encuesta es que proporcione suficiente información para que sea realmente valiosa para los países a la hora de determinar su progreso hacia el objetivo, y, a través de esto, a varios aspectos de la GIRH. Se ha buscado un equilibrio entre proporcionar suficiente información para cubrir los principios básicos de la GIRH, y así proporcionar un valor de indicador sólido, y no sobrecargar a los países con requisitos de información innecesarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se anima a los países a que proporcionen información adicional sobre cada pregunta que pueda ayudar a calificar su elección de puntuación, y/o a situar esa puntuación en su contexto nacional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador 6.5.1 está respaldado por el indicador 6.5.2 &amp;#x201C;Proporción de la zona de la cuenca transfronteriza con un acuerdo operativo para la cooperación en materia de agua&amp;#x201D;, que aborda directamente la sección de la Meta 6.5 &amp;#x201C;&amp;#x2026;, incluso a través de la cooperación transfronteriza, según corresponda.&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Raison d&apos;être :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur fournit une mesure directe des progrès réalisés dans la première partie de la cible 6.5 &amp;#x201C;&amp;#x2026; mettre en œuvre une gestion intégrée des ressources en eau à tous les niveaux &amp;#x2026;&amp;#x201D;. Le score de l&apos;indicateur fournit un moyen facile et compréhensible de mesurer les progrès vers la cible, avec &amp;#x2018;0&amp;#x2019; interprété comme une absence de mise en œuvre de la GIRE, et &amp;#x2018;100&amp;#x2019; interprété comme une mise en œuvre complète de la GIRE. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour faciliter l&apos;interprétation et la comparaison, les résultats des indicateurs peuvent être classés comme suit : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Degré de mise en œuvre &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Fourchette de points &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Interprétation générale pour la note globale de la GIRE &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Très élevé &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;91 - 100&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;La grande majorité des éléments de la GIRE sont pleinement mis en œuvre,
les objectifs sont systématiquement atteints et les plans et programmes sont périodiquement évalués et révisés.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Haut &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;71 - 90&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Les objectifs de la GIRE des plans et programmes sont généralement atteints,
et la couverture géographique et l&apos;engagement des parties prenantes sont généralement bons.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Medium-high&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;51 - 70&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;La capacité de mettre en œuvre les éléments de la GIRE est généralement
adéquate, et ces éléments sont généralement mis en œuvre dans le cadre de programmes à long terme.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Medium-low&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;31 - 50&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;Les éléments de la GIRE sont généralement institutionnalisés et leur mise
en œuvre est en cours. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Faible &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;11 - 30&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;La mise en œuvre des éléments de la GIRE a généralement commencé, mais
avec une adoption limitée dans tout le pays et un engagement potentiellement faible des groupes de parties prenantes. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;Très faible &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;0 - 10&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;Le développement des éléments de la GIRE n&apos;a généralement pas commencé,
ou est au point mort.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le concept de l&apos;enquête est qu&apos;elle fournit suffisamment d&apos;informations pour être réellement utile aux pays pour déterminer leurs progrès vers l&apos;objectif, et par ce biais, les différents aspects de la GIRE. Un équilibre a été recherché entre la fourniture d&apos;informations suffisantes pour couvrir les principes de base de la GIRE, et donc fournir une valeur d&apos;indicateur solide, et ne pas surcharger les pays avec des exigences de rapport inutiles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les pays sont encouragés à fournir des informations supplémentaires sur chaque question, qui peuvent aider à qualifier leur choix de score, et/ou à replacer ce score dans leur contexte national. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur 6.5.1 est étayé par l&apos;indicateur 6.5.2 &amp;#x201C;Proportion de la zone du bassin transfrontalier faisant l&apos;objet d&apos;un arrangement opérationnel de coopération dans le domaine de l&apos;eau &amp;#x201D;, qui porte directement sur la partie de la cible 6.5 &amp;#x201C; &amp;#x2026;, y compris par le biais de la coopération transfrontalière, le cas échéant &amp;#x201D;. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель обеспечивает прямую оценку хода выполнения первой части задачи 6.5 «...обеспечить комплексное управление водными ресурсами на всех уровнях...». Балльная оценка показателя обеспечивает простой и понятный способ оценки прогресса в достижении цели, которая при значении &quot;0&quot; интерпретируется как отсутствие реализации КУВР, а при значении &quot;100&quot; интерпретируется как полная реализация КУВР. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для облегчения интерпретации и сравнения результаты разработки показателя можно разделить на следующие категории: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Степень реализации &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Диапазон балльных оценок &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Общая интерпретация полной оценки КУВР &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Очень высокая &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 91 - 100 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Подавляющее большинство элементов КУВР полностью реализовано, цели последовательно достигаются, а планы и программы периодически оцениваются и пересматриваются. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Высокая &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 71–90 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Цели планов и программ КУВР в целом достигаются, а географический охват и взаимодействие с заинтересованными сторонами в основном хорошие.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Средне-высокая &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 51–70 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Потенциал для реализации элементов ИУВР в целом достаточен, и элементы в основном реализуются в рамках долгосрочных программ. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Средне-низкая &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 31–50 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Элементы КУВР в целом институционализированы, и процесс реализации продолжается.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Низкая &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 11–30 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Внедрение элементов КУВР в целом началось, но с ограниченным распространением по стране и потенциально низким вовлечением групп заинтересованных сторон. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Очень низкая &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 0–10 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Разработка элементов КУВР вообще не началась или застопорилась.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Идея обследования заключается в том, что оно предоставляет достаточно информации, которая будет иметь реальную значимость для стран при определении прогресса в достижении цели, а, следовательно, и в различных аспектах КУВР. Был найден баланс между предоставлением информации, достаточной для охвата основных принципов КУВР и, таким образом, предоставляя надежное значение показателя, и отсутствием излишней нагрузки на страны, которая может быть обусловлена ничем не оправданными излишними требованиями к отчетности. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Странам рекомендуется предоставлять дополнительную информацию по каждому вопросу, которая может помочь уточнить их выбор балльной оценки и / или учесть этот балл в контексте своей страны. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель 6.5.1 поддерживается показателем 6.5.2 «Доля трансграничных водных бассейнов, охваченных действующими договоренностями о сотрудничестве в области водопользования», который непосредственно касается части задачи 6.5 &quot;...в том числе, при необходимости, на основе трансграничного сотрудничества&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
