<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 1-a-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Méthodologie&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Méthode de calcul :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Du point de vue d&apos;un pays donateur&lt;/strong&gt; : La somme des dons bilatéraux d&apos;APD par donateur qui se concentrent sur la réduction de la pauvreté en tant que part du revenu national brut du pays donateur. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Du point de vue d&apos;un pays bénéficiaire&lt;/strong&gt; : La somme des subventions totales de l&apos;APD de tous les donateurs (c&apos;est-à-dire les donateurs du CAD, les organisations multilatérales et les autres fournisseurs bilatéraux de coopération au développement) qui se concentrent sur la réduction de la pauvreté en tant que part du revenu national brut du pays en développement. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; С точки зрения страны-донора &lt;/strong&gt;: сумма двусторонних грантов ОПР донора, направленных на сокращение бедности, как доля валового национального дохода страны-донора. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; С точки зрения страны-получателя &lt;/strong&gt;: Сумма общих грантов ОПР от всех доноров (т.е. доноров КСР, многосторонних организаций и других двусторонних поставщиков инструментов сотрудничества в целях развития), которые направлены на сокращение бедности как доля валового национального дохода развивающейся страны. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computation method:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From a donor country&amp;#x2019;s perspective&lt;/strong&gt;: The sum of bilateral ODA grants by donor that focus on poverty reduction as a share of the donor country&amp;#x2019;s gross national income. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From a recipient country&amp;#x2019;s perspective&lt;/strong&gt;: The sum of total ODA grants from all donors (i.e. DAC donors, multilateral organisations and other bilateral providers of development cooperation) that focus on poverty reduction as a share of the developing country&amp;#x2019;s gross national income. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
