<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 3-c-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computation method:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Health worker densities by occupation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figures for number of medical doctors (including generalist and specialist medical practitioners) depending on the nature of the original data source may include practising medical doctors only or all registered medical doctors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figures for number of nursing and midwifery include nursing personnel and midwifery personnel, whenever available. In many countries, nurses trained with midwifery skills are counted and reported as nurses. This makes the distinction between nursing personnel and midwifery personnel difficult to draw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figures for number of dentists include dentists in the given national and/or subnational area. Depending on the nature of the original data source may include practising (active) only or all registered in the health occupation. The ISCO -08 codes included here are 2261.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figures for number of pharmacists include in the given national and/or subnational area. Depending on the nature of the original data source may include practising (active) only or all registered in the health occupation. The ISCO -08 codes that relate to this occupation is 2262.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, the denominator data for workforce density (i.e. national population estimates) are obtained from the United Nations Population Division&amp;apos;s World Population Prospects database. In cases where the official health workforce report provides density indicators instead of counts, estimates of the stock were then calculated using the population estimated from the United Nations Population Division&amp;apos;s World population prospects database (2017). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Health worker distribution by sex:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of male medical doctors as reported by the country is expressed as a percentage of total male and female medical doctors reported by the country&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of female medical doctors as reported by the country is expressed as a percentage of total male and female medical doctors reported by the country&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of male nursing personnel as reported by the country is expressed as a percentage of total male and female nursing personnel reported by the country&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of female nursing personnel as reported by the country is expressed as a percentage of total male and female nursing personnel reported by the country.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Méthodologie&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Méthode de calcul :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Densité de travailleurs de la santé par profession : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les chiffres relatifs au nombre de médecins (y compris les médecins généralistes et spécialistes), selon la nature de la source de données initiale, peuvent inclure uniquement les médecins en exercice ou tous les médecins agréés.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les chiffres relatifs au nombre d&apos;infirmières et de sages-femmes incluent le personnel infirmier et le personnel de sages-femmes, lorsqu&apos;ils sont disponibles. Dans de nombreux pays, les infirmières formées à la profession de sage-femme sont comptées et déclarées comme infirmières. Cela rend la distinction entre le personnel infirmier et le personnel de sage-femme difficile à établir. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les chiffres relatifs au nombre de dentistes incluent les dentistes de la zone nationale et/ou infranationale donnée. Selon la nature de la source de données originale, il peut s&apos;agir uniquement des praticiens (actifs) ou de tous les praticiens inscrits dans la profession de santé. Les codes ISCO -08 inclus ici sont 2261. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les chiffres relatifs au nombre de pharmaciens sont inclus dans la zone nationale et/ou infranationale donnée. Selon la nature de la source de données originale, il peut s&apos;agir de pharmaciens exerçant uniquement (en activité) ou de tous les pharmaciens enregistrés dans la profession de santé. Le code CITP -08 qui se rapporte à cette profession est le 2262. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En général, les données du dénominateur pour la densité de la main-d&apos;œuvre (c&apos;est-à-dire les estimations de la population nationale) sont obtenues à partir de la base de données World Population Prospects de la Division de la population des Nations unies. Dans les cas où le rapport officiel sur le personnel de santé fournit des indicateurs de densité au lieu de chiffres, les estimations du stock ont alors été calculées en utilisant la population estimée à partir de la base de données World Population Prospects (2017) de la Division de la population des Nations Unies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Répartition des travailleurs de la santé par sexe : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le nombre de médecins hommes tel que rapporté par le pays est exprimé en pourcentage du total des médecins hommes et femmes rapporté par le pays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le nombre de femmes médecins tel que rapporté par le pays est exprimé en pourcentage du total des hommes et des femmes médecins rapportés par le pays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le nombre de personnel infirmier masculin tel que rapporté par le pays est exprimé en pourcentage du total du personnel infirmier masculin et féminin rapporté par le pays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le nombre de femmes infirmières tel que rapporté par le pays est exprimé en pourcentage du total du personnel infirmier masculin et féminin rapporté par le pays.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
