<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 3-c-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Health worker densities by occupation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Density of medical doctors:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;The density of medical doctors is defined as the number of medical doctors, including generalists and specialist medical practitioners per 10,000 population in the given national and/or subnational area. The International Standard Classification of Occupations (ISCO) unit group codes included in this category are 221, 2211 and 2212 of ISCO-08.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Density of nursing and midwifery personnel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; The density of nursing and midwifery personnel is defined as the number of nursing and midwifery personnel per 10,000 population in the given national and/or subnational area. The ISCO-08 codes included in this category are 2221, 2222, 3221 and 3222.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Density of dentists&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; The density of dentists is defined as the number of dentists per 10,000 population in the given national and/or subnational area. The ISCO-08 codes included in this category are 2261.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Density of pharmacists:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; The density of pharmacists is defined as the number of pharmacists per 10,000 population in the given national and/or subnational area. The ISCO-08 codes included in this category are 2262.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Health worker distribution by sex&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Percentage of male medical doctors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Male doctors as percentage of all medical doctors at national level. The ISCO-08 codes included in this category are 221, 2211 and 2212.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Percentage of female medical doctors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Female doctors as percentage of all medical doctors at national level. The ISCO-08 codes included in this category are 221, 2211 and 2212.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Percentage of male nursing personnel:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Male nursing personnel as percentage of all nursing personnel at national level. The ISCO-08 codes included in this category are 2221 and 3221.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Percentage of female nursing personnel:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Female nursing personnel as percentage of all nursing personnel at national level. The ISCO-08 codes included in this category are 2221 and 3221.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Densidad de trabajadores de la salud por ocupación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definición:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Densidad de médicos:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;La densidad de médicos se define como el número de médicos, incluidos los generalistas y los médicos especialistas, por cada 10.000 habitantes en un área nacional y/o subnacional determinada. Los códigos de grupos de unidades de la Clasificación Internacional Uniforme de Ocupaciones (CIUO) incluidos en esta categoría son 221, 2211 y 2212 de la CIUO-08.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Densidad de personal de enfermería y partería&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; La densidad de personal de enfermería y partería se define como el número de personal de enfermería y partería por cada 10.000 habitantes en el área nacional y/o subnacional dada. Los códigos CIUO-08 incluidos en esta categoría son 2221, 2222, 3221 y 3222.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Densidad de dentistas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; La densidad de dentistas se define como el número de dentistas por cada 10.000 habitantes en el área nacional y/o subnacional dada. Los códigos CIUO-08 incluidos en esta categoría son 2261.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Densidad de farmacéuticos:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; La densidad de farmacéuticos se define como el número de farmacéuticos por cada 10.000 habitantes en el área nacional y/o subnacional dada. Los códigos CIUO-08 incluidos en esta categoría son 2262.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distribución del personal de salud por sexo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Porcentaje de médicos varones&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Médicos varones como porcentaje del total de médicos a nivel nacional. Los códigos CIUO-08 incluidos en esta categoría son 221, 2211 y 2212.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Porcentaje de mujeres médicas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Médicos mujeres como porcentaje de todos los médicos a nivel nacional. Los códigos CIUO-08 incluidos en esta categoría son 221, 2211 y 2212.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Porcentaje de personal de enfermería masculino:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Personal de enfermería masculino como porcentaje de todo el personal de enfermería a nivel nacional. Los códigos CIUO-08 incluidos en esta categoría son el 2221 y el 3221.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Porcentaje de personal de enfermería femenino:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Personal de enfermería femenino como porcentaje de todo el personal de enfermería a nivel nacional. Los códigos CIUO-08 incluidos en esta categoría son 2221 y 3221.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Densités de travailleurs de la santé par profession :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Densité de médecins :&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;La densité de médecins est définie comme le nombre de médecins, y compris les généralistes et les médecins spécialistes, pour 10 000 habitants dans une zone nationale et/ou sous-nationale donnée. Les codes des groupes d&apos;unités de la Classification internationale type des professions (CITP) inclus dans cette catégorie sont 221, 2211 et 2212 de la CITP-08.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Densité du personnel infirmier et de sages-femmes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; La densité du personnel infirmier et de sages-femmes est définie comme le nombre de personnel infirmier et de sages-femmes pour 10 000 habitants dans la zone nationale et/ou sous-nationale donnée. Les codes CITP-08 inclus dans cette catégorie sont 2221, 2222, 3221 et 3222.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Densité de dentistes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; La densité de dentistes est définie comme le nombre de dentistes pour 10 000 habitants dans la zone nationale et/ou sous-nationale donnée. Les codes CITP-08 inclus dans cette catégorie sont 2261.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Densité de pharmaciens :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; La densité de pharmaciens est définie comme le nombre de pharmaciens pour 10 000 habitants dans la zone nationale et/ou sous-nationale donnée. Les codes CITP-08 inclus dans cette catégorie sont 2262.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Répartition des professionnels de la santé par sexe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pourcentage de médecins masculins&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Médecins masculins en pourcentage de l&apos;ensemble des médecins au niveau national. Les codes ISCO-08 inclus dans cette catégorie sont 221, 2211 et 2212.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pourcentage de femmes médecins&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Pourcentage de femmes médecins par rapport à l&apos;ensemble des médecins au niveau national. Les codes ISCO-08 inclus dans cette catégorie sont 221, 2211 et 2212.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pourcentage du personnel infirmier masculin :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Pourcentage du personnel infirmier masculin par rapport à l&apos;ensemble du personnel infirmier au niveau national. Les codes CITP-08 inclus dans cette catégorie sont 2221 et 3221.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pourcentage du personnel infirmier féminin :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Pourcentage du personnel infirmier féminin par rapport à l&apos;ensemble du personnel infirmier au niveau national. Les codes CITP-08 inclus dans cette catégorie sont 2221 et 3221.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Концепции и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Численность медицинских работников на душу населения по профессиям: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Определение :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong &lt;em&gt; Численность врачей на душу населения: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Численность врачей на душу населения определяется как количество врачей, включая врачей общего профиля и практикующих врачей-специалистов, на 10 000 человек населения на данной национальной и / или субнациональной территории. Коды начальных групп Международной стандартной классификации занятий (МСКЗ), включенные в эту категорию, - 221, 2211 и 2212 МСКЗ-08. &lt;br&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong &lt;em&gt; Численность сестринского и акушерского персонала на душу населения&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Численность сестринского и акушерского персонала на душу населения определяется как количество медсестер и акушерок на 10 000 человек населения на данной национальной и / или субнациональной территории. Коды МСКЗ-08, включенные в эту категорию, - 2221, 2222, 3221 и 3222. &lt;br&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong &lt;em&gt; Численность стоматологов на душу населения&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Численность стоматологов на душу населения определяется как количество стоматологов на 10 000 человек населения на данной национальной и / или субнациональной территории. Коды МСКЗ-08, включенные в эту категорию, - 2261. &lt;br&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Численность фармацевтов на душу населения: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Численность фармацевтов на душу населения определяется как количество фармацевтов на 10 000 человек населения на данной национальной и / или субнациональной территории. Коды МСКЗ-08, включенные в эту категорию, - 2262. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Распределение медицинских работников по полу &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&lt;em&gt; Доля врачей-мужчин &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Доля врачей-мужчин от всех врачей на национальном уровне. Коды МСКЗ-08, включенные в эту категорию, - 221, 2211 и 2212. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&lt;em&gt; Доля врачей-женщин &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Доля врачей-женщин от всех врачей на национальном уровне. Коды МСКЗ-08, включенные в эту категорию, - 221, 2211 и 2212. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&lt;em&gt; Доля среднего медицинского персонала-мужчин: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Доля среднего медперсонала мужского пола от всего среднего медицинского персонала на национальном уровне. Коды МСКЗ-08, включенные в эту категорию, - 2221 и 3221. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong &lt;em&gt; Доля медсестер-женщин: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Доля медсестринского персонала женского пола от всего сестринского персонала на национальном уровне. Коды МСКЗ-08, включенные в эту категорию, - 2221 и 3221. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
