<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 3-c-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Health worker densities by occupation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Density of medical doctors:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;The density of medical doctors is defined as the number of medical doctors, including generalists and specialist medical practitioners per 10,000 population in the given national and/or subnational area. The International Standard Classification of Occupations (ISCO) unit group codes included in this category are 221, 2211 and 2212 of ISCO-08.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Density of nursing and midwifery personnel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; The density of nursing and midwifery personnel is defined as the number of nursing and midwifery personnel per 10,000 population in the given national and/or subnational area. The ISCO-08 codes included in this category are 2221, 2222, 3221 and 3222.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Density of dentists&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; The density of dentists is defined as the number of dentists per 10,000 population in the given national and/or subnational area. The ISCO-08 codes included in this category are 2261.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Density of pharmacists:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; The density of pharmacists is defined as the number of pharmacists per 10,000 population in the given national and/or subnational area. The ISCO-08 codes included in this category are 2262.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Health worker distribution by sex&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Percentage of male medical doctors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Male doctors as percentage of all medical doctors at national level. The ISCO-08 codes included in this category are 221, 2211 and 2212.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Percentage of female medical doctors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Female doctors as percentage of all medical doctors at national level. The ISCO-08 codes included in this category are 221, 2211 and 2212.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Percentage of male nursing personnel:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Male nursing personnel as percentage of all nursing personnel at national level. The ISCO-08 codes included in this category are 2221 and 3221.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Percentage of female nursing personnel:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Female nursing personnel as percentage of all nursing personnel at national level. The ISCO-08 codes included in this category are 2221 and 3221.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Densités de travailleurs de la santé par profession :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Densité de médecins :&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;La densité de médecins est définie comme le nombre de médecins, y compris les généralistes et les médecins spécialistes, pour 10 000 habitants dans une zone nationale et/ou sous-nationale donnée. Les codes des groupes d&apos;unités de la Classification internationale type des professions (CITP) inclus dans cette catégorie sont 221, 2211 et 2212 de la CITP-08.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Densité du personnel infirmier et de sages-femmes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; La densité du personnel infirmier et de sages-femmes est définie comme le nombre de personnel infirmier et de sages-femmes pour 10 000 habitants dans la zone nationale et/ou sous-nationale donnée. Les codes CITP-08 inclus dans cette catégorie sont 2221, 2222, 3221 et 3222.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Densité de dentistes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; La densité de dentistes est définie comme le nombre de dentistes pour 10 000 habitants dans la zone nationale et/ou sous-nationale donnée. Les codes CITP-08 inclus dans cette catégorie sont 2261.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Densité de pharmaciens :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; La densité de pharmaciens est définie comme le nombre de pharmaciens pour 10 000 habitants dans la zone nationale et/ou sous-nationale donnée. Les codes CITP-08 inclus dans cette catégorie sont 2262.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Répartition des professionnels de la santé par sexe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pourcentage de médecins masculins&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Médecins masculins en pourcentage de l&apos;ensemble des médecins au niveau national. Les codes ISCO-08 inclus dans cette catégorie sont 221, 2211 et 2212.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pourcentage de femmes médecins&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Pourcentage de femmes médecins par rapport à l&apos;ensemble des médecins au niveau national. Les codes ISCO-08 inclus dans cette catégorie sont 221, 2211 et 2212.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pourcentage du personnel infirmier masculin :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Pourcentage du personnel infirmier masculin par rapport à l&apos;ensemble du personnel infirmier au niveau national. Les codes CITP-08 inclus dans cette catégorie sont 2221 et 3221.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pourcentage du personnel infirmier féminin :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Pourcentage du personnel infirmier féminin par rapport à l&apos;ensemble du personnel infirmier au niveau national. Les codes CITP-08 inclus dans cette catégorie sont 2221 et 3221.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
