<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COMPARABILITY field for indicator 6-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regional differences, in particular in relation to irrigated agriculture and different climatic conditions (including variability), are to be considered in the interpretation of this indicator, especially in countries with large amounts of available water resources. Also for this reason, coupling this indicator with water stress (6.4.2) is important for the interpretation of the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Obtaining internationally comparable data for global monitoring:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data for this indicator are collected through a questionnaire/calculation sheet that allows countries to identify the needed parameters, and provide some preliminary control checks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data so collected are then reviewed by FAO experts, also through the GEMI team if needed. The finding of the review is then shared with the country, in order to ensure consistency and harmonization of methods, definitions and results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO has prepared a Step-by-step methodological paper, in order to provide a technical guide for the country teams. Moreover, an e-learning tool, in the form of a course on-line, is being prepared and will be ready early in 2018. Finally, an overall manual is being drafted.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt; Sources des écarts: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les différences régionales, en particulier en ce qui concerne l&apos;agriculture irriguée et les différentes conditions climatiques (y compris la variabilité), doivent être prises en compte dans l&apos;interprétation de cet indicateur, en particulier dans les pays disposant de grandes quantités de ressources en eau disponibles. C&apos;est également pour cette raison que le couplage de cet indicateur avec le stress hydrique (6.4.2) est important pour l&apos;interprétation des données. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Obtention de données comparables au niveau international pour la surveillance mondiale: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les données pour cet indicateur sont collectées au moyen d&apos;un questionnaire / feuille de calcul qui permet aux pays d&apos;identifier les paramètres nécessaires et de procéder à des contrôles préliminaires. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les données ainsi collectées sont ensuite examinées par des experts de l&apos;ONUAA, également par l&apos;intermédiaire de l&apos;équipe GEMI si nécessaire. Les conclusions de l&apos;examen sont ensuite communiquées au pays, afin d&apos;assurer la cohérence et l&apos;harmonisation des méthodes, des définitions et des résultats. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L&apos;ONUAA a préparé un document méthodologique étape par étape afin de fournir un guide technique aux équipes de pays. De plus, un outil d&apos;apprentissage en ligne, sous la forme d&apos;un cours en ligne, est en cours de préparation et sera prêt au début de 2018. Enfin, un manuel global est en cours de rédaction. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Региональные различия, в частности, в отношении орошаемого земледелия и различных климатических условий (включая климатическую вариативность), должны учитываться при интерпретации этого показателя, особенно в странах с большими объемами доступных водных ресурсов. Также по этой причине связь этого показателя с нагрузкой на водные ресурсы (6.4.2) важна для интерпретации данных. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Получение международно сопоставимых данных для глобального мониторинга: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные для этого показателя собираются с помощью вопросника / таблицы расчетов, которая позволяет странам определять необходимые параметры и проводить некоторые предварительные контрольные проверки. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Собранные таким образом данные затем анализируются экспертами ФАО, а также, при необходимости, группой GEMI (Глобальная инициатива по управлению окружающей средой). Затем результаты анализа доводятся до сведения страны, чтобы обеспечить согласованность и гармонизацию методов, определений и результатов. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ФАО подготовила пошаговый методологический документ, чтобы предоставить техническое руководство для страновых групп. Кроме того, готовится средство дистанционного обучения в виде онлайн-курса, который будет готов в начале 2018 года. Наконец, готовится проект общего руководства.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
