<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REG_AGG field for indicator 6-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Regional aggregates:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aggregation for global and regional estimations is done by summing up the values of the various parameters constituting the elements of the formula, i.e. value added by sector and water use by sector. The aggregated indicator is then calculated by applying the formula with those aggregated data, as if it were a single country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Excel sheet with the calculations is being prepared, and will be shared with the IAEG if required.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt; Agrégats régionaux:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L’agrégation des estimations mondiales et régionales se fait en résumant les valeurs des différents paramètres constituant les éléments de la formule, c’est-à-dire la valeur ajoutée par secteur et l’utilisation de l’eau par secteur. L’indicateur agrégé est ensuite calculé en appliquant la formule avec ces données agrégées, comme s’il s’agissait d’un seul pays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Une feuille Excel avec les calculs est en cours de préparation et sera partagée avec l’IAEG si nécessaire. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Региональные агрегаты: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Агрегирование глобальных и региональных оценок выполняется путем суммирования значений различных параметров, составляющих элементы формулы, то есть добавленная стоимость по секторам и водопользование по секторам. Затем агрегированный показатель рассчитывается путем применения формулы с этими агрегированными данными, как если бы это была одна страна. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В настоящее время готовится таблица Excel с расчетами, которая при необходимости будет передана в Межучрежденческую группу экспертов (МГЭ). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
