<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 16-6-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommended set of complementary questions to address selection 16.6.2 bias towards &amp;#x2018;&lt;em&gt;users&amp;#x2019;&lt;/em&gt; of public services &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Since SDG 16.6.2 refers to people&amp;#x2019;s &amp;#x2018;last experience&amp;#x2019; with public services, the indicator needs to focus on user experiences rather than on non-user perceptions. The experience of users is important, but it is equally important to understand the experiences and perceptions of those who turn elsewhere for services, or who do not access services altogether. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For each service area, NSOs are therefore strongly encouraged to administer three complementary questions (see Methodology section) &lt;em&gt;prior &lt;/em&gt;to the two &amp;#x2018;priority questions&amp;#x2019; to be used for global 16.6.2 reporting. These additional questions will help capture the experience of &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; users &lt;em&gt;and &lt;/em&gt;non-users of public services. They will help identify which population sub-groups who needed healthcare, education and government services did &lt;em&gt;not &lt;/em&gt;access the services they needed, and what barriers prevented them from doing so. While the information generated by these additional questions is critical for policymakers to design service provision programmes that &amp;#x2018;leave no one behind&amp;#x2019;, it is left to the discretion of each country to integrate them or not, as some may already be collecting similar information through existing surveys.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, the selection bias inherent in SDG 16.6.2, with its focus on users, can result in mismeasurement due to underlying inequalities in the propensity of various groups to interact with state institutions. In other words, a focus on &amp;#x2018;the last experience with public services&amp;#x2019; implicitly means that this indicator includes only those respondents who were privileged enough to access public services in the past year. This means that those (such as ethnic minorities, migrants, the elderly, undocumented workers) who have &lt;em&gt;not &lt;/em&gt;been able &amp;#x2013; or willing &amp;#x2013; to access the healthcare, education or government services they needed in the past 12 months, often as a consequence of multiple social and economic barriers arising from overlapping forms of marginalization will be undercounted by this indicator. There is a risk therefore that overall satisfaction levels reported on 16.6.2 will over-represent the experience of more privileged groups for whom access to public services is easier, because they have the financial, logistical and intellectual means to do so, and they trust that it is in their interest to do so.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
