<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 16-7-1a, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;The concept of representation&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are different approaches to the concept of representation in parliament, with two of the most widely-known being descriptive and substantive representation (Bird, 2003; Floor Eelbode, 2010). Descriptive representation is concerned with the extent to which the composition of parliament mirrors the various socio-demographic groups in the national population. Substantive representation, meanwhile, is concerned with the extent to which parliament acts in the interest of certain population groups (irrespective of whether or not members of parliament consider themselves as members of those groups).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator 16.7.1 focuses on descriptive representation. The underlying assumption is that when parliament reflects the social diversity of a nation, this may lead to greater legitimacy of the parliament in the eyes of the electorate, as members resemble the people they represent in respect to gender, age, ethnicity and disability. Descriptive representation has been found to be associated with higher levels of trust in public institutions, as people feel closer to elected representatives who resemble them and perceive more visibly representative political bodies with better quality and fairness of policy decisions, and with less undue influence of vested interests over decision-making.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-9&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-9&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Such descriptive representation should then enhance the substantive influence of population groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The methodology for this indicator measures representation in parliamentary decision-making with respect to the sex and age of members of parliament. It identifies the extent to which the proportion of women members of parliament, and the proportion of young members of parliament, corresponds to the proportion of these groups in society as a whole. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A different approach is taken with regard to disability and population group status, which focuses on electoral and constitutional provisions guaranteeing the representation of persons with disabilities and various population groups in national parliaments (see &amp;#x2018;Comments and limitations&amp;#x2019;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&amp;#x2018;Decision-making positions&amp;#x2019; in national parliaments&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Target 16.7 focuses on &amp;#x2018;decision-making&amp;#x2019; and the extent to which it is responsive, inclusive, participatory and representative. For the purpose of this indicator, three positions were identified for their importance in decision-making and leadership: Members of parliament, the Speaker of parliament and permanent committee Chairs. Broadly speaking, the decision-making power of individuals holding these positions can be described as follows: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Members of parliament&lt;/em&gt; play important roles in public decision-making by voting on laws and holding the government to account. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Speaker&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;of a legislature presides over the proceedings of parliament and typically plays a significant role in setting the parliamentary agenda and organizing the business of parliament. The Speaker is responsible for ensuring parliamentary business is conducted fairly and effectively, and for protecting the autonomy of the legislature in relation to the other branches of government. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Committee Chairs&lt;/em&gt; preside over the work of parliamentary committees, and typically have great influence over the committee agenda and business, including the legislative and oversight work carried out. In addition, committee Chairs often participate in the management boards or bureau that guide the overall work of parliament. As the number and mandates of permanent committees vary between parliaments, for the sake of better-quality data and greater comparability, this indicator only considers five Permanent Committees : Foreign Affairs, Defence, Finance, Human Rights and Gender Equality (see &amp;#x2018;Comments and limitations&amp;#x2019;). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Political representation and disaggregation dimensions&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator calls for disaggregation of positions by age, sex, contextually relevant population groups and disability status. The following international human rights instruments contain provisions on enhancing opportunities for political participation by individuals and groups holding such characteristics: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The right and opportunity to participate in public affairs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Article 25 of the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights (ICCPR) recognizes &amp;#x201C;the right and opportunity, without distinction of any kind such as race, color, sex, language, religion, political or other opinion, national or social origin, property, birth or other status to take part in the conduct of public affairs, directly or through freely chosen representatives&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Age&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2015 Security Council Resolution 2250 urges Member States to consider ways to increase inclusive representation of youth in decision-making at all levels in local, national, regional and international institutions and mechanisms to prevent and resolve conflict and counter violent extremism. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sex&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2000 Security Council Resolution 1325 and the six supporting resolutions between 2000-2013 on Women, Peace and Security urge member states to increase the numbers of women at all levels of decision-making institutions. The 1979 Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Discrimination against Women (CEDAW) provides the basis for realizing equality between women and men through ensuring women&amp;apos;s equal access to, and equal opportunities in, political and public life, including the right to vote and to stand for election, as well as to hold public office at all levels of government (Article 7). States parties agree to take all appropriate measures to overcome historical discrimination against women and obstacles to women&amp;#x2019;s participation in decision-making processes (Article 8), including legislation and temporary special measures (Article 4). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ethnic or minority status&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Declaration on the Rights of Persons belonging to National or Ethnic, Religious and Linguistic Minorities (1992) and the Declaration on the Rights of Indigenous Peoples (2007) provide that persons belonging to minorities and indigenous peoples have the right to participate in the political, economic, social and cultural life of the State. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disability status&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United Nations Convention on the Rights of Persons with Disabilities (2006) calls upon State Parties to ensure that persons with disabilities can effectively and fully participate in political and public life on an equal basis with others, directly or through freely chosen representatives, including the right and opportunity for persons with disabilities to vote and be elected. Resolution 2155 (2017) of the Parliamentary Assembly of the Council of Europe (PACE) on the political rights of persons with disabilities recommends for countries to consider the establishment of quotas for the participation of persons with disabilities in parliamentary and local elections, with a view to increasing participation and representation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-9&quot;&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; See OECD (2017) &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-9&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</data>
</root>
