<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 7-3-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IEA and UN Energy Balances combined provide total energy supply data for all countries on an annual basis. GDP data are available for most countries on an annual basis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2000 &amp;#x2013; present &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disaggregation of energy intensity, e.g. by final consumption sectors or end-uses, could provide further insights into progress towards energy efficiency. At present it is only feasible to calculate such sector disaggregation for the following sectors &amp;#x2013; industry, residential, transport, agriculture, households &amp;#x2013; as reported in the Tracking SDG7: The Energy Progress Report (formerly Sustainable Energy for All Global Tracking Framework). It would be desirable, over time, to develop more refined sectoral level energy intensity indicators that make it possible to look at energy intensity by industry (e.g. cement, steel) or by type of vehicle (e.g. cars, trucks), for example. Doing so will not be possible without further statistical data collection, also including collaboration with relevant institutions and energy consumers. Full methodological explanations are provided in the IEA &lt;em&gt;Energy Efficiency Indicators: Fundamentals on Statistics &lt;/em&gt;manual available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iea.org/reports/energy-efficiency-indicators-fundamentals-on-statistics&quot;&gt;iea.org/reports/energy-efficiency-indicators-fundamentals-on-statistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decomposition analysis of energy intensity trends seeks to filter out factors that affect energy demand, such as economy wide scale and structural shifts, from more narrowly defined energy intensity shifts. This analysis is also reported in the &lt;em&gt;Tracking SDG7: The Energy Progress Report&lt;/em&gt; or in the &lt;em&gt;IEA Energy Efficiency Indicators Highlights&lt;/em&gt; available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iea.org/reports/energy-efficiency-indicators-fundamentals-on-statistics&quot;&gt;iea.org/reports/energy-efficiency-indicators&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
