<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 16-10-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computation method:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The method of computation is both quantitative and qualitative, with data generated from a global review of existing surveys (e.g. UNESCO&amp;apos;s World Trends in Freedom of Expression &amp;amp; Media Development reports, etc.), administrative records, expert assessments (e.g. World Justice Open Government Index), etc. More specifically, the following key variables will be assessed: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does a country have constitutional, statutory and/or policy guarantees for public access to information?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do those constitutional, statutory and/or policy guarantees reflect known international agreements (e.g. the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights, etc.)?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What implementation mechanisms are in place to ensure that such guarantees work optimally?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address these questions, the following will serve as performance sub-indicators:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;National law or constitutional guarantee on the right to information&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Country has signed and ratified relevant treaty obligations, with no significant exemptions, and these are reflected, to the extent possible, in domestic FOI legislation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Public is aware of and exercises right to access official information&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Public bodies release information both pro-actively and on demand&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Effective and efficient appeals mechanism via independent administrative body e.g. information commissioner or ombudsman&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Any restriction on grounds of protection of personal privacy is narrowly defined so as to exclude information in which there is no justifiable public interest. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The means of verification will include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Any law or policy on right to information that accords with international standards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reports from credible agencies/experts about right to information guarantees and the extent to which they reflect international standards/agreements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Policies of public bodies concerning release of information (which ensure readily, freely available public access to information, including online)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evidence of state commitment to open government e.g. publication and dissemination of laws, court decisions, parliamentary proceedings, spending programmes (vis-&amp;#xE0;-vis SDG undertakings)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Statistical information about public requests for official information and their fulfilment or rejection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Statistical information about appeals or complaints over information requests that have been refused&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</data>
</root>
