<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 6-2-1b, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;The production of estimates follows a consistent series of steps, which are explained in this and following sections: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Identification of appropriate national datasets &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Extraction of data from national datasets into harmonized tables of data inputs &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Use of the data inputs to model country estimates &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. Consultation with countries to review the estimates &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. Aggregation of country estimates to create regional and global estimates&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Household surveys and censuses provide data on the presence of handwashing facilities and soap and water in the home. The JMP uses data from household surveys in which the enumerator observes the handwashing facility and confirms the presence or absence of soap and water at the facility. Datasets that include availability of soap in the household (i.e. not at the handwashing facility), or self-reported availability of handwashing facilities, soap and water may be included in the JMP database and country files, but in most cases are not used for making estimates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some parts of the world, households sometimes do not give permission for survey enumerators to enter the premises and observe handwashing facilities. These households are excluded from calculations of the proportion of households having handwashing facilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JMP uses original microdata to produce its own tabulations and estimates by using populations weights (or household weights multiplied by de jure household size), where possible. However, in many cases microdata are not readily accessible so relevant data are transcribed from reports available in various formats (PDFs, Word files, Excel spreadsheets, etc.) if data are tabulated for the proportion of the population, or household/dwelling. National data from each country, area, or territory are recorded in the JMP country files, with water, sanitation, and hygiene data recorded on separate sheets. Country files can be downloaded from the JMP website: https://washdata.org/data/downloads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JMP estimates the proportion of population with a basic handwashing facility with soap and water on premises by fitting a regression model to all available and validated data points within the reference period, starting from year 2000. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details on JMP rules and methods on how data on the type of sanitation facility used and the disposal and treatment of excreta are combined to compute the safely managed sanitation services indicator, please refer to recent JMP progress reports and &amp;#x201C;JMP Methodology: 2017 update and SDG baselines&amp;#x201D;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/sites/default/files/documents/reports/2018-04/JMP-2017-update-methodology.pdf&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/sites/default/files/documents/reports/2018-04/JMP-2017-update-methodology.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
