<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 11-1-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data on slums is available for all developing countries, as it has been reported yearly by UN-Habitat in the MDGs&amp;#x2019; reports. Recently, UN-Habitat has disaggregated information on this indicator at city level, increasing its suitability for SDG 11. The people living in slums&amp;#x2019; indicator is currently measured in more than 320 cities across the world as part of UN-Habitat City Prosperity Initiative. UN-Habitat and World Bank computed this indicator for many years (1996-2006) as part of the Urban Indicators Programme. Data on inadequate housing, measured through housing affordability, is available for all OECED countries as well as in UN Global Sample of Cities covering 200 cities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data on inadequate housing, measured through housing affordability, is available in many countries. UN-Habitat and World Bank computed this indicator for many years (1996-2006) as part of the Urban Indicators Programme. Recently, the Global Housing Indicators Working Group, a collaborative effort of Cities Alliance, Habitat for Humanity International, the Inter-American Development Bank, UN-Habitat proposed the collection of data on this indicator worldwide. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Available data cover the period 1990-2018. Because the efforts and capacity of collecting and analysing survey data are different for each country, the length of the time series for each country varies greatly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Potential Disaggregation:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Disaggregation by location (intra-urban)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Disaggregation by income group&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Disaggregation by sex, race, ethnicity, religion, migration status (head of household)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Disaggregation by age (household members)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Disaggregation by disability status (household members)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quantifiable Derivatives:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proportion of households with durable housing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proportion of households with improved water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proportion of households with improved sanitation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proportion of households with sufficient living space&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proportion of households with security of tenure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proportion of households with one (1) housing deprivation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proportion of households with multiple (2 or more) housing deprivations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proportion of households with approved municipal permit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proportion of households with (in) adequate housing (affordability)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</data>
</root>
