<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 4-7-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator 4.7.1/12.8.1/13.3.1 measures the extent to which countries mainstream Global Citizenship Education (GCED) and Education for Sustainable Development (ESD) in their education systems. This is an indicator of characteristics of different aspects of education systems: education policies, curricula, teacher training and student assessment as reported by government officials, ideally following consultation with other government ministries, national human rights institutes, the education sector and civil society organizations. It measures what governments intend and not what is implemented in practice in schools and classrooms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each of the four components of the indicator (policies, curricula, teacher education, and student assessment), a number of criteria are measured, which are then combined to give a single score between zero and one for each component. (See methodology section for full details).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator and its methodology have been reviewed and endorsed by UNESCO&amp;#x2019;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://tcg.uis.unesco.org/&quot;&gt;Technical Cooperation Group on the Indicators for SDG 4-Education 2030&lt;/a&gt; (TCG), which is responsible for the development and maintenance of the thematic indicator framework for the follow-up and review of SDG 4. The TCG also has an interest in education-related indicators in other SDGs, including global indicators 12.8.1 and 13.3.1. The TCG is composed of 38 regionally representative experts from UNESCO Member States (nominated by the respective geographic groups of UNESCO), as well as international partners, civil society, and the Co-Chair of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://sdg4education2030.org/who-we-are&quot;&gt;Education 2030 Steering Committee&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://uis.unesco.org/&quot;&gt;UNESCO Institute for Statistics&lt;/a&gt; acts as the Secretariat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Global Citizenship Education (GCED) &lt;/em&gt;and&lt;em&gt; Education for Sustainable Development (ESD)&lt;/em&gt; nurture respect for all, build a sense of belonging to a common humanity, foster responsibility for a shared planet, and help learners become responsible and active global citizens and proactive contributors to a more peaceful, tolerant, inclusive, secure and sustainable world. They aim to empower learners of all ages to face and resolve local and global challenges and to take informed decisions and actions for environmental integrity, economic viability and a just society for present and future generations, while respecting cultural diversity.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
