<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 14-2-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;A full methodology for this indicator is available in the document entitled, &amp;#x201C;Global Manual on Ocean Statistics for Measuring SDG 14.1.1, 14.2.1 and 14.5.1&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regional Seas Coordinated Indicator 22 &amp;#x2018;Integrated Coastal Zone Management (ICZM) is proposed as the primary indicator. For countries with Marine/Maritime Spatial Planning (MSP) in place, these plans can be helpful to assess ICZM. For other countries, it is important to identify ways to measure existing plans and to build capacity for integrated planning. All data for this indicator will be based on country submissions to the Regional Seas Programme. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator will measure the number of countries using ecosystem-based approaches to manage marine areas (measured through ICZM (Integrated Coastal Zone Management), marine spatial plan or other area-based, integrated planning and management in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step one &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify national authorities/agencies/organisations responsible for coastal and marine/maritime planning and management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step two &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify and spatially map the boundaries of ICZM plans or other plans at national, sub-national and local level. Coordinate with the national authorities/agencies/organisations responsible for coastal and marine/maritime planning and management to complete a questionnaire on the ICZM plans (Shipman and Petit 2014)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step three&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Determine the status of implementation of each plan, and categorise the spatial map according to implementation stages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Initial plan preparation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) Plan development&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3) Plan adoption/designation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4) Implementation and adaptive management&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collect the questionnaire responses and document the answers is recommended. The spatial map showing the boundaries of relevant plans (produced in step two) could also be used to calculate the proportion of national waters, or national exclusive economic zone, covered by relevant plans. This can be done by overlaying the spatial layer of relevant plans with a spatial layer of national waters, or of the exclusive economic zone, to identify where the two layers coincide. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All countries should report on if a plan is in place. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
