<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for the indicator 14-2-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;Goal 14: Conserve and sustainably use the oceans, seas and marine resources for sustainable development&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 14.2: By 2020, sustainably manage and protect marine and coastal ecosystems to avoid significant adverse impacts, including by strengthening their resilience, and take action for their restoration in order to achieve healthy and productive oceans&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 14.2.1: Number of countries using ecosystem-based approaches to managing marine areas&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2021-02-08&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;N/A&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;United Nations Environment Programme (UNEP)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;United Nations Environment Programme (UNEP)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regional Seas Coordinated Indicator 22 &amp;#x2018;Integrated Coastal Zone Management (ICZM) is proposed as the primary indicator. For countries with Marine/Maritime Spatial Planning (MSP) in place, these plans can be helpful to assess ICZM. For other countries, it is important to identify ways to measure existing plans and to build capacity for integrated planning. All data for this indicator will be based on country submissions to the Regional Seas Programme. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to promote the use of the Regional Seas as part of the follow-up and review mechanism for the Regional Seas, UNEP drafted report on how Regional Seas data could be directly used for the SDGs (see https://wedocs.unep.org/bitstream/handle/20.500.11822/27295/ocean_SDG.pdf?sequence=1&amp;amp;isAllowed=y).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A full methodology for this indicator is available in the document entitled, &amp;#x201C;Global Manual on Ocean Statistics for Measuring SDG 14.1.1, 14.2.1 and 14.5.1&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICZM &amp;#x2013; An Integrated Coastal Zone Management (ICZM) plan covers the entire coastal zone. Marine and terrestrial areas are managed together. Plans are developed through coordination across different marine and terrestrial institutions and agencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marine Spatial Planning (MSP) &amp;#x2013; Marine Spatial Planning is focused on the EEZ. It the integrates the needs and policies of multiple marine sectors in one coherent planning framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EEZ - national Exclusive Economic Zone (EEZ) (200 nautical miles from the coast) as outlined by the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Number&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data provided by national governments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The custodian agencies propose to collect national data through the Regional Seas Programmes in order to reduce the reporting burden on countries. For countries that are not included in a Regional Seas Programme then UNEP will reach out directly. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. First data collection: Data is already being collected by the Regional Seas&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. First reporting cycle: 2021&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National Statistical Systems, through the Regional Seas. The Regional Seas Programmes include the CPPS: Permanent Commission for the South Pacific (Southeast Pacific); EU MSFD: European Union Marine Strategy Framework Directive; EU WFD: European Union Water Framework Directive; GEF-TWAP: Global Environment Facility Transboundary Waters Assessment Programme; HELCOM: Helsinki Commission (Baltic Sea); Nairobi Convention (Western Indian Ocean); NOAA: National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; NOWPAP: Northwest Pacific Action Plan (Northwest Pacific); OSPAR: Oslo-Paris Convention (Northeast Atlantic); ROMPE: Regional organization for the Protection of the Marine Environment (ROMPE sea area); UNEP-MAP: UN Environment Mediterranean Action Plan (Mediterranean Sea)). For more information on the Regional Seas see: https://www.unenvironment.org/explore-topics/oceans-seas/what-we-do/working-regional-seas. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. UN Environment (United Nations Environment Programme), in collaboration with partners mentioned in the other sections of this metadata&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From an ecological perspective, ecosystem approaches consider the connections between the living organisms, habitats, physical and chemical conditions within an ecosystem, focusing on the importance of ecological integrity, biodiversity and overall ecosystem health. From a management perspective, ecosystem-based approaches refer to integrated management strategies for socio-ecological systems that consider ecological, social and economic factors and apply principles of sustainable development. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A marine or coastal area-based (or spatial) management promotes better management of EEZs. Many countries use Marine Spatial Planning (MSP) and Integrated Coastal Zone Management (ICZM) as their approach for ensuring appropriate ecosystem-based management, including issues that are cross-sectoral and wider scale in nature.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Indicator only measures the policy formulation and not policy implementation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A full methodology for this indicator is available in the document entitled, &amp;#x201C;Global Manual on Ocean Statistics for Measuring SDG 14.1.1, 14.2.1 and 14.5.1&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regional Seas Coordinated Indicator 22 &amp;#x2018;Integrated Coastal Zone Management (ICZM) is proposed as the primary indicator. For countries with Marine/Maritime Spatial Planning (MSP) in place, these plans can be helpful to assess ICZM. For other countries, it is important to identify ways to measure existing plans and to build capacity for integrated planning. All data for this indicator will be based on country submissions to the Regional Seas Programme. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator will measure the number of countries using ecosystem-based approaches to manage marine areas (measured through ICZM (Integrated Coastal Zone Management), marine spatial plan or other area-based, integrated planning and management in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step one &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify national authorities/agencies/organisations responsible for coastal and marine/maritime planning and management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step two &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify and spatially map the boundaries of ICZM plans or other plans at national, sub-national and local level. Coordinate with the national authorities/agencies/organisations responsible for coastal and marine/maritime planning and management to complete a questionnaire on the ICZM plans (Shipman and Petit 2014)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step three&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Determine the status of implementation of each plan, and categorise the spatial map according to implementation stages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Initial plan preparation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) Plan development&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3) Plan adoption/designation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4) Implementation and adaptive management&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collect the questionnaire responses and document the answers is recommended. The spatial map showing the boundaries of relevant plans (produced in step two) could also be used to calculate the proportion of national waters, or national exclusive economic zone, covered by relevant plans. This can be done by overlaying the spatial layer of relevant plans with a spatial layer of national waters, or of the exclusive economic zone, to identify where the two layers coincide. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All countries should report on if a plan is in place. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Missing values are not imputed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The data will be aggregated at the sub-regional, regional and global levels by counting the number of countries with a plan for each group.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data will be made available for all member states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National data collection through the Regional Seas already exists for many Regional Seas, this data will be compiled for SDG reporting in 2020. Reporting will be every 5 years &amp;#x2013; as policy development takes time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; A geospatial map of areas covered by a plan is recommended for national level decision making.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NA&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regional Seas website: https://www.unenvironment.org/explore-topics/oceans-seas/what-we-do/working-regional-seas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNEP Global Manual on Ocean Statistics for Measuring SDG 14.1.1, 14.2.1 and 14.5.1 (forthcoming)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICZM (and Marine Spatial Planning (MSP)) for monitoring SDG 14.1.1: https://wedocs.unep.org/bitstream/handle/20.500.11822/26440/MSP_ICZM_Guidelines.pdf?sequence=1&amp;amp;isAllowed=y&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
