<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 4-1-1a, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computation method:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of children and/or young people at the relevant stage of education n in year t achieving or exceeding the pre-defined proficiency level in subject s expressed as a percentage of the number of children and/or young people at stage of education n, in year t, in any proficiency level in subject s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MPL&lt;sub&gt;t,n,s,&lt;/sub&gt; = MP&lt;sub&gt;t,n,s&lt;/sub&gt; / P&lt;sub&gt;t,n&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MP&lt;sub&gt;t,n,s&lt;/sub&gt; = the number of children and young people at stage of education n, in year t, who have achieved or exceeded the minimum proficiency level in subject s. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P&lt;sub&gt;t,n &lt;/sub&gt;= the number of children and young people at stage of education n, in year t, in any proficiency level in subject s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;n = the stage of education that was assessed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;s = the subject that was assessed (reading or mathematics).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Harmonize various data sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address the challenges posed by the limited capacity of some countries to implement cross-national, regional, and national assessments, actions have been taken by the UIS and its partners. The strategies are used according to its level of precision and following a &lt;a href=&quot;http://gaml.uis.unesco.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2019/05/GAML6-WD-2-Protocol-for-reporting-4.1.1_v1.pdf&quot;&gt;reporting protocol&lt;/a&gt; that includes the national assessments under specific circumstances. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Out-of-school children &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, 263 million children, adolescents and youth were out of school, representing nearly one-fifth of the global population of this age group. 63 million, or 24% of the total, are children of primary school age (typically 6 to 11 years old); 61 million, or 23% of the total, are adolescents of lower secondary school age (typically 12 to 14 years old); and 139 million, or 53% of the total, are youth of upper secondary school age (about 15 to 17 years old). Not all these kids will be permanently outside school, some will re-join the educational system and, eventually, complete late, while some of them will enter late. The quantity varies per country and region and demands some adjustment in the estimate of Indicator 4.1.1. There is currently a discussion on how to implement these adjustments to reflect all the population. In 2017, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://uis.unesco.org/en/blog/helping-countries-improve-their-data-out-school-children&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;UIS proposed to make adjustments using the out-of-school children (OOSC)&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and the completion rates. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; UIS (2017a). More than one-half of children and adolescents are not learning worldwide. Montreal and UIS (2017b). Counting the number of children not learning: Methodology for a global composite indicator for education. Montreal. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</data>
</root>
