<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 3-a-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is defined as the percentage of the population aged 15 years and over who currently use any tobacco product (smoked and/or smokeless tobacco) on a daily or non-daily basis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tobacco use means use of smoked and/or smokeless tobacco products. &amp;#x201C;Current use&amp;#x201D; means use within the previous 30 days at the time of the survey, whether daily or non-daily use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tobacco products means products entirely or partly made of the leaf tobacco as raw material intended for human consumption through smoking, sucking, chewing or sniffing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x201C;Smoked tobacco products&amp;#x201D; include cigarettes, cigarillos, cigars, cheroots, bidis, pipes, shisha (water pipes), roll-your-own tobacco, kretek, heated tobacco products and any other form of tobacco that is consumed by smoking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Smokeless tobacco product&amp;quot; includes moist snuff, creamy snuff, dry snuff, plug, dissolvables, gul, loose leaf, red tooth powder, snus, chimo, gutkha, khaini, gudakhu, zarda, quiwam, dohra, tuibur, nasway, naas, naswar, shammah, toombak, paan (betel quid with tobacco), iq&amp;#x2019;mik, mishri, tapkeer, tombol and any other tobacco product that consumed by sniffing, holding in the mouth or chewing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prevalence estimates have been &amp;#x201C;age-standardized&amp;#x201D; to make them comparable across all countries no matter the demographic profile of the country. This is done by applying each country&amp;#x2019;s age-and-sex specific prevalence rates to the WHO Standard Population. The resulting rates are hypothetical numbers which are only meaningful when comparing rates obtained for one country &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;with those obtained for another country. &lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
