<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 16-10-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNESCO and World Bank reports&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other UN bodies, such as UNDP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National bodies such as commissioners responsible for right to information implementation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Media regulators &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Academic and research institutions &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Media support NGOs (national and international)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods used for data collection for this data are varied, drawing upon both quantitative and qualitative ones, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Qualitative expert assessments (World Justice Open Government Index, launched in 2015 and covering 102 countries); &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Administrative records (e.g. number of requests for information; number of requests process in the last 12 months; number of women who submit such requests, etc.) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Surveys (e.g. UNESCO World Trends in Freedom of Expression &amp;amp; Media Development and Media Development Indicators (MDI) reports; Open Society Foundation&amp;#x2019;s series of surveys on &amp;#x2018;access to information laws and practices&amp;#x2019;; the World Values Survey [www.worldvaluessurvey.org]; IPU data on access-to-information legislation and constitutional guarantees of access to information; World Values Survey on trust of news media]; etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UN or relevant regional bodies that carry details of each treaty, including countries that have signed, ratified or registered any exemptions to their obligations, together with the treaty bodies&amp;#x2019; general comments on implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various international and regional rapporteurs on freedom of expression issue country-specific reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For data on national laws and constitutional guarantees, sources include: national libraries, law commissions, official records of parliament and government records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;List:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNESCO and World Bank reports; Other UN bodies; National bodies; World Justice Open Government Index, Administrative records, World Justice Open Government Index, UNESCO World Trends in Freedom of Expression &amp;amp; Media Development and Media Development Indicators (MDI) reports; Open Society Foundation&amp;#x2019;s, World Values Survey [&lt;a href=&quot;www.worldvaluessurvey.org&quot;&gt;www.worldvaluessurvey.org&lt;/a&gt;]; IPU data on access-to-information legislation and constitutional guarantees of access to information; World Values Survey on trust of news media]; etc.)&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
