<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 15-5-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;There are four main sources of uncertainty associated with Red List Index values and trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inadequate, incomplete or inaccurate knowledge of a species&amp;#x2019; status. This uncertainty is minimized by assigning estimates of extinction risk to categories that are broad in magnitude and timing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delays in knowledge about a species becoming available for assessment. Such delays apply to a small (and diminishing) proportion of status changes, and can be overcome in the Red List Index through back-casting (Butchart et al. 2007).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inconsistency between species assessments. These can be minimized by the requirement to provide supporting documentation detailing the best available data, with justifications, sources, and estimates of uncertainty and data quality, which are checked and standardized by IUCN through Red List Authorities, a Red List Technical Working Group and an independent Standards and Petitions Sub-committee. Further, detailed Guidelines on the Application of the Categories and Criteria are maintained (IUCN SPSC 2019), as is an online training course (in English, Spanish and French).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Species that are too poorly known for the Red List Criteria to be applied are assigned to the Data Deficient category. For birds, only 0.8% of extant species are evaluated as Data Deficient, compared with 24% of amphibians. If Data Deficient species differ in the rate at which their extinction risk is changing, the Red List Index may give a biased picture of the changing extinction risk of the overall set of species. The degree of uncertainty this introduces is estimated through a bootstrapping procedure that randomly assigns each Data Deficient species a category based on the numbers of non-Data Deficient species in each Red List category for the set of species under consideration, and repeats this for 1,000 iterations, plotting the 2.5 and 97.5 percentiles as lower and upper confidence intervals for the median.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main limitation of the Red List Index is related to the fact that the Red List Categories are relatively broad measures of status, and thus the Red List Index for any individual taxonomic group can practically be updated at intervals of at least four years. However, as the overall index is aggregated across multiple taxonomic groups, with groups reassessed asynchronously, it can be updated annually. A further limitation is that the Red List Index does not reflect particularly well the deteriorating status of common species that remain abundant and widespread but are declining slowly.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
