<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 11-3-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definitions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is defined as the ratio of land consumption rate to population growth rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator requires defining the two components of population growth and land consumption rate. Computing the population growth rate is more straightforward and more readily available, while land consumption rate is slightly challenging, and requires the use of new techniques. In estimating the land consumption rate, one needs to define what constitutes &amp;#x201C;consumption&amp;#x201D; of land since this may cover aspects of &amp;#x201C;consumed&amp;#x201D; or &amp;#x201C;preserved&amp;#x201D; or available for &amp;#x201C;development&amp;#x201D; for cases such as land occupied by wetlands. Secondly, there is not one unequivocal measure of whether land that is being developed is truly &amp;#x201C;newly-developed&amp;#x201D; (or vacant) land, or if it is at least partially &amp;#x201C;redeveloped&amp;#x201D;. As a result, the percentage of current total urban land that was newly developed (consumed) will be used as a measure of the land consumption rate. The fully developed area is also sometimes referred to as built up area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;City or urban area&lt;/strong&gt;: Since 2016 UN-Habitat and partners organized global consultations and discussions to narrow down the set of meaningful definitions that would be helpful for the global monitoring and reporting process. Following consultations with 86 member states, the United Nations Statistical Commission, in its 51st Session (March 2020) endorsed the Degree of Urbanisation (DEGURBA) as a workable method to delineate cities, urban and rural areas for international statistical comparisons.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;This definition combines population size and population density thresholds to classify the entire territory of a country along the urban-rural continuum, and captures the full extent of a city, including the dense neighbourhoods beyond the boundary of the central municipality. DEGURBA is applied in a two-step process: First, 1 km2 grid cells are classified based on population density, contiguity and population size. Subsequently, local units are classified as urban or rural based on the type of grid cells in which majority of their population resides. For the computation of indicator 11.3.1, countries are encouraged to adopt the degree of urbanisation to define the analysis area (city or urban area).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Population growth rate (PGR)&lt;/strong&gt; is the change of a population in a defined area (country, city, etc) during a period, usually one year, expressed as a percentage of the population at the start of that period. It reflects the number of births and deaths during a period and the number of people migrating to and from the focus area. In SDG 11.3.1, this is computed at the area defined as urban/city. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Land consumption&lt;/strong&gt; within the context of indicator 11.3.1 is defined as the uptake of land by urbanized land uses, which often involves conversion of land from non-urban to urban functions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Land consumption rate&lt;/strong&gt; is the rate at which urbanized land or land occupied by a city/urban area changes during a period of time (usually one year), expressed as a percentage of the land occupied by the city/urban area at the start of that time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Built up area &lt;/strong&gt;within the context of indicator 11.3.1 is defined as all areas occupied by buildings. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; A recommendation on the method to delineate cities, urban and rural areas for international statistical comparisons. &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/statcom/51st-session/documents/BG-Item3j-Recommendation-E.pdf&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/statcom/51st-session/documents/BG-Item3j-Recommendation-E.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</data>
</root>
