<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 5-3-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nationally representative prevalence data are currently available for 30 low- and middle-income countries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the country level, the latest available data for indicator 5.3.2 are published. At the regional level, time series estimates for indicator 5.3.2 (as measured among adolescent girls aged 15-19 years) are published for 5-year intervals beginning from 2000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Age (15-49 years at the national level, 15-19 years at the regional level)&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt; Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Actualmente se dispone de datos de prevalencia representativos a nivel nacional para 30 países de ingresos bajos y medianos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Edad, ingresos, lugar de residencia, ubicación geográfica, etnia, educación&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disponibilité des données :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des données de prévalence représentatives à l’échelle nationale sont actuellement disponibles pour 30 pays à faible ou à moyen revenu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Séries chronologiques :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Au niveau national, les dernières données disponibles pour l’indicateur 5.3.2 sont publiées. Au niveau régional, les estimations des séries chronologiques pour l’indicateur 5.3.2 (mesurées chez les adolescentes âgées de 15 à 19 ans) sont publiées pour des intervalles de 5 ans à partir de 2000. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Désagrégation :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Âge (15-49 ans au niveau national, 15-19 ans au niveau régional).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Репрезентативные на национальном уровне данные по распространенности явления в настоящее время доступны по 30 странам с низким и средним уровнем доходов &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Возможно по возрасту, доходу, месту жительства, географическому положению, этнической принадлежности, образованию &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
