<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 5-3-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Rationale:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FGM/C is a violation of girls&amp;#x2019; and women&amp;#x2019;s human rights. There is a large body of literature documenting the adverse health consequences of FGM/C over both the short and long term. The practice of FGM/C is a direct manifestation of gender inequality &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FGM/C is condemned by a number of international treaties and conventions. Since FGM/C is regarded as a traditional practice prejudicial to the health of children and is, in most cases, performed on minors, it violates the Convention on the Rights of the Child. Existing national legislation in many countries also include explicit bans against FGM/C.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La MGF es una violación de los derechos humanos de las niñas y las mujeres. Existe una gran cantidad de literatura que documenta las consecuencias adversas para la salud de la MGF tanto a corto como a largo plazo. La práctica de la MGF es una manifestación directa de la desigualdad de género &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La MGF está condenada por varios tratados y convenciones internacionales. Dado que la MGF se considera una práctica tradicional perjudicial para la salud de los niños y que, en la mayoría de los casos, se realiza en menores, viola la Convención sobre los Derechos del Niño. La legislación nacional existente en muchos países también incluye prohibiciones explícitas contra la MGF.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt; Justification:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les MGF/E sont une violation des droits fondamentaux des filles&amp;#x2019; et des femmes&amp;#x2019;. Il existe un grand nombre de documents documentant les conséquences néfastes des MGF/E sur la santé à court et à long terme. La pratique des MGF/E est une manifestation directe de l’inégalité entre les sexes &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les MGF/E sont condamnées par un certain nombre de traités et de conventions internationaux. Étant donné que les MGF/E sont considérées comme une pratique traditionnelle préjudiciable à la santé des enfants et qu’elles sont, dans la plupart des cas, pratiquées sur des mineurs, elles violent la Convention relative aux droits de l’enfant. La législation nationale existante dans de nombreux pays prévoit également des interdictions explicites contre les MGF/E.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
