<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 15-1-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;This indicator is calculated from data derived from a spatial overlap between digital polygons for protected areas from the World Database on Protected Areas (UNEP-WCMC &amp;amp; IUCN 2020), digital polygons for Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures from the World Database on OECMs and digital polygons for terrestrial and freshwater Key Biodiversity Areas (from the World Database of Key Biodiversity Areas, including Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas, Alliance for Zero Extinction sites, and other Key Biodiversity Areas). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sites were classified as terrestrial Key Biodiversity Areas by undertaking a spatial overlap between the Key Biodiversity Area polygons and an ocean raster layer (produced from the &amp;#x2018;adm0&amp;#x2019; layer from the database of Global Administrative Areas (GADM 2019)), classifying any Key Biodiversity Area as a terrestrial Key Biodiversity Area where it had &amp;#x2264;95% overlap with the ocean layer (hence some sites were classified as both terrestrial and marine). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sites were classified as freshwater Key Biodiversity Areas if the resident species for which they were identified were documented in the IUCN Red List as dependent on &amp;#x2018;Inland Water&amp;#x2019; systems. For non-resident or migrant species, or species that shift habitats during the annual cycle, the site was tagged as freshwater if the species occurred at the site in the appropriate season of water-dependence (e.g. some species are only dependent on water during the breeding season). Sites were then screened (using the satellite imagery base layer within ArcGIS) as to whether they lay wholly in the Coastal Zone (defined here as within 10 km of the coast), and these sites were then untagged as Freshwater and instead tagged as Marine if the wetland habitats present at the site fell purely within the IUCN Habitat Classification Scheme class &amp;#x2018;Marine Supratidal&amp;#x2019; (i.e. estuaries, lagoons, etc.). If the site was within the Coastal Zone, but contained a mixture of Marine Supratidal and Inland Water classes, then it was tagged as both Freshwater and Marine. Each site was then manually cross-checked against other (less comprehensively available) site attributes, such as the habitat preferences of its trigger species, the site&amp;#x2019;s name (Delta, River, Humedal, etc.), its areal coverage by different habitat types, its overlap with Ramsar Sites, and its &amp;#x2018;shadow&amp;#x2019; Ramsar status, so as to confirm or remove the Freshwater tag appropriately. The value of the indicator at a given point in time, based on data on the year of protected area establishment recorded in the World Database on Protected Areas, is computed as the mean percentage of each Key Biodiversity Area currently recognised that is covered by protected areas and/or Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protected areas lacking digital boundaries in the World Database of Protected Areas, and those sites with a status of &amp;#x2018;proposed&amp;#x2019; or &amp;#x2018;not reported&amp;#x2019; are omitted. Degazetted sites are not kept in the WDPA and are also not included. Man and Biosphere Reserves are also excluded as these often contain potentially unprotected areas. Year of protected area establishment is unknown for ~12% of protected areas in the World Database on Protected Areas, generating uncertainty around changing protected area coverage over time. To reflect this uncertainty, a year was randomly assigned from another protected area within the same country, and then this procedure repeated 1,000 times, with the median plotted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to 2017, the indicator was presented as the percentage of Key Biodiversity Areas completely covered by protected areas. However, it is now presented as the mean % of each Key Biodiversity Area that is covered by protected areas in order to better reflect trends in protected area coverage for countries or regions with few or no Key Biodiversity Areas that are completely covered.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
