<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 3-b-3, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;Measurement and monitoring of access to essential medicines are of high priority for the global development agenda given access is an integral part of the Universal Health Coverage movement and an indispensable element of the delivery of quality health care. Access to medicines is a composite multidimensional concept that is composed of the availability of medicines and the affordability of their prices. Information on these two dimensions has been collected and analysed since the 54&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; World Health Assembly in 2001, when Member States adopted the WHO Medicines Strategy (resolution WHA54.11). This resolution led to the launch of the joint project on Medicine Prices and Availability by WHO and the international non-governmental organization Health Action International (HAI/WHO), as well as a proposed HAI/WHO methodology for collecting data and measuring components of access to medicines. To this day, this methodology has been widely implemented to produce useful analyses of availability and affordability of medicines, however the two dimensions have been evaluated separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the above approach has provided an overview of the countries&amp;#x2019; performance and progress on improving the affordability and availability of medicines, it has not allowed evaluation of overall access to medicines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This evaluation is in turn essential as country&amp;#x2019;s success in ensuring one of the dimensions (e.g. availability) does not necessarily indicate the realization of the other (e.g. affordability) and vice versa. For example, a country may focus its policy efforts on ensuring the availability of a core set of essential medicines in the event of low capacity of local production and/or challenges associated with geographic location. As a result of the proposed policies, medicines may become available but their prices may not be affordable. The opposite situation is also possible, as lowering prices of medicines to increase affordability may be too restrictive for some pharmaceutical producers and lead to a decreased supply. Therefore, given the multidimensionality of access to medicines, it is necessary to evaluate both affordability and availability of medicines at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposed methodology for indicator 3.b.3 allows the combination of both dimensions into a single indicator to evaluate the availability and affordability of medicines simultaneously. This methodology also allows for disaggregation so that each dimension can be analysed separately and the main driver of poor performance of the overall index can be properly identified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monitoring the core set of relevant essential medicines is based on the WHO Model List of Essential Medicines (EML). The 2017 WHO EML contains 433 medications deemed essential for addressing the most important public health needs globally. The current index is computed based on a subset of 32 tracer essential medicines for the treatment, prevention and management of acute and chronic, communicable and non-communicable diseases in a primary health care setting.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
