<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 2-2-2a, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Child growth is an internationally accepted outcome area reflecting child nutritional status. Child overweight refers to a child who is too heavy for his or her height. This form of malnutrition results from expending too few calories for the amount of food consumed and increases the risk of noncommunicable diseases later in life. Child overweight is one of the World Health Assembly nutrition target indicators.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El crecimiento infantil es un área de resultados aceptada internacionalmente que refleja el estado nutricional del niño. El sobrepeso infantil se refiere a un niño que pesa demasiado para su estatura. Esta forma de malnutrición es el resultado de gastar muy pocas calorías para la cantidad de alimentos consumidos y aumenta el riesgo de padecer enfermedades no transmisibles más adelante en la vida. El sobrepeso infantil es uno de los indicadores objetivo de nutrición de la Asamblea Mundial de la Salud.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;La croissance de l’enfant est un domaine de résultats internationalement accepté reflétant l’état nutritionnel de l’enfant. Le surpoids chez l’enfant fait référence à un enfant qui est trop lourd pour sa taille. Cette forme de malnutrition résulte de dépenser trop peu de calories pour la quantité de nourriture consommée et augmente le risque de maladies non transmissibles plus tard dans la vie. Le surpoids chez les enfants est l’un des indicateurs cibles nutritionnels de l’Assemblée mondiale de la Santé.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Рост ребенка - это международно-признанный показатель, отражающий состояние питания ребенка. Ребенок с избыточным весом - это ребенок, который слишком тяжел для своего роста. Эта форма неправильного питания возникает из-за того, что расходуется слишком мало калорий по сравнению с количеством потребляемой пищи, и это увеличивает риск неинфекционных заболеваний в более позднем возрасте. Избыточный вес детей является одним из целевых показателей Всемирной ассамблеи здравоохранения в области питания.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
