<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 2-2-2a, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Survey estimates come have uncertainty due to both sampling error and non-sampling error (e.g., measurement technical error, recording error etc.,). The JME modelled estimates for overweight take into account estimates of sampling error around survey estimates. While non-sampling error cannot be accounted for or reviewed in full, when available, a data quality review of weight, height and age data from household surveys supports compilation of a time series that is comparable across countries and over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of particular concern for overweight is the fact that data for high-income countries are scarce yet the prevalence is generally higher among the high-income countries with data. The JME group are working closely with countries in the European region to increase coverage, as well as to apply age adjustments for data covering only partially the age interval 0 to 59 months. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JME working group carefully utilizes all available national data sources, and documents all the steps taken to infer about country trends based on the national data sources. The estimation method (McClain et al 2018) is based on and closely aligned to country data. The approach smooths and fits a trend line across the national data points. The basis of the estimates are nationally representative household surveys. However, as surveys are conducted infrequently (e.g., less frequently than every 3 years) in some countries, models produce a complete time series with estimates available in the same years for all countries. This allows for comparable assessment of progress; for example, all countries can be assessed using the same baseline year. For any individual country, an increase in the availability of primary data points can result in more robust and accurate modelled estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las estimaciones de las encuestas conllevan niveles de incertidumbre debidos tanto a errores de muestreo como a errores ajenos al muestreo (por ejemplo, errores técnicos de medición, errores de registro, etc.). Ninguna de las dos fuentes de error se ha tenido plenamente en cuenta para obtener estimaciones ni a nivel nacional ni a nivel regional y mundial. Es especialmente preocupante el hecho de que los datos de los países de renta alta son escasos y, sin embargo, las tasas son generalmente más altas entre los países de renta alta con datos, por lo que la falta de representación de los países de renta alta puede afectar a las tasas mundiales e incluso regionales.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Les estimations de l’enquête comportent des niveaux d’incertitude dus à la fois à l’erreur d’échantillonnage et à l’erreur non due à l’échantillonnage (p. ex., erreur technique de mesure, erreur d’enregistrement, etc.). Aucune des deux sources d’erreurs n’a été pleinement prise en compte pour établir des estimations ni au niveau national, ni aux niveaux régional et mondial. Le surpoids est particulièrement préoccupant car les données pour les pays à revenu élevé sont rares, alors que les taux sont généralement plus élevés parmi les pays à revenu élevé disposant de données, de sorte que le manque de représentation des pays à revenu élevé peut affecter les taux mondiaux et même régionaux. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Оценки обследования имеют уровни неопределённости, возникающие как из-за ошибок выборки, так и ошибок, не связанных с выборкой (например, техническая ошибка проведения замеров, ошибка в составлении отчетов и т. д.). Ни один из двух источников ошибок не был полностью принят во внимание при получении оценок ни на страновом, ни на региональном, ни на глобальном уровнях. Особую озабоченность по поводу избыточного веса вызывает тот факт, что данных по странам с высоким уровнем дохода мало, однако те данные, которые имеются в наличии, фиксируют, что, как правило, их показатели выше, и поэтому недостаточная представленность стран с высоким уровнем дохода может повлиять на глобальные и даже региональные показатели. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
