<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The QUALITY_MGMNT field for indicator 11-2-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;To ensure consistency in data production across countries, UN-Habitat has developed detailed step-by-step tutorials on the computation of indicator 11.2.1, which further explain the steps presented in this metadata. The detailed tutorials, which will be continuously updated are available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://unhabitat.org/knowledge/data-and-analytics&quot;&gt;https://unhabitat.org/knowledge/data-and-analytics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.urbanagendaplatform.org/learning&quot;&gt;https://www.urbanagendaplatform.org/learning&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.unhabitat.org/&quot;&gt;https://data.unhabitat.org/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within its Data and Analytics Section which is responsible for the indicator data compilation, UN-Habitat has a team of spatial data experts who check all submitted data and provide direct support to countries in the indicator computation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of its global custodianship of indicator 11.2.1, UN-Habitat has also established partnerships with major institutions and organizations involved in production of baseline data relevant for the indicator computation. The main aim of this is to create a common understanding on the approach for the indicator computation, and to encourage continuous production of high-quality global data that responds to the indicator computation needs. Examples of some ongoing initiatives with partners to manage quality of products and processes include, among others providing support to apply the Degree of Urbanisation at the local level for the indicator computation (in partnership with the European Commission), development of an Earth Observation Toolkit for SDG 11 (in partnership with EO4SDG and GEO), and continuous feedback to global products produced by partners such as ITDP, UITP, the German Aerospace Center (DLR) and the European Commission, among others. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
