<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The OTHER_DOC field for indicator 6-6-1a, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sdg6monitoring.org/indicators/target-66/indicators661/&quot;&gt;http://www.sdg6monitoring.org/indicators/target-66/indicators661/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Additional information&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The methodology was tested in two pilot phases. The first of these involved designing the methodology in consultation with countries resulting in a first draft of the methodology which was reviewed and strengthened by the Target Team. In early 2016, the draft methodology was pilot tested in five countries between April and November 2016 through workshops: Jordan, the Netherlands, Peru, Senegal, and Uganda. In each of these countries, various participants from national entities and government sectors were engaged to obtain wide feedback on the technical feasibility of the draft methodology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the 2016 country pilots of the draft methodology, the NSO from each of the 5 countries was consulted and engaged in the process. During the 2017 pilot methodology data drive, the initial request for data was communicated to all NSOs. In addition, in October 2017 national data on spatial extent of open water (derived from earth observations) was shared with 188 countries, directly via their NSOs (see further details above).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Références&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sdg6monitoring.org/indicators/target-66/indicators661/&quot;&gt;http://www.sdg6monitoring.org/indicators/target-66/indicators661/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Information supplémentaire&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La méthodologie a été testée en deux phases pilotes. La première consistait à concevoir la méthodologie en consultation avec les pays, ce qui a donné lieu à une première ébauche de la méthodologie qui a été revue et renforcée par l&apos;équipe cible. Au début de 2016, le projet de méthodologie a été testé dans cinq pays entre avril et novembre 2016 dans le cadre d&apos;ateliers : Jordanie, Pays-Bas, Pérou, Sénégal et Ouganda. Dans chacun de ces pays, divers participants des entités nationales et des secteurs gouvernementaux ont été engagés pour obtenir un large retour d&apos;information sur la faisabilité technique du projet de méthodologie. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lors des essais pilotes de 2016 du projet de méthodologie, l&apos;INS de chacun des 5 pays a été consulté et a participé au processus. Lors de la campagne de collecte de données de la méthodologie pilote de 2017, la demande initiale de données a été communiquée à toutes les OSN. De plus, en octobre 2017, les données nationales sur l&apos;étendue spatiale des eaux libres (dérivées des observations de la terre) ont été partagées avec 188 pays, directement via leurs OSN (voir plus de détails ci-dessus). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sdg6monitoring.org/indicators/target-66/indicators661/&quot;&gt; http://www.sdg6monitoring.org/indicators/target-66/indicators661/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt; Дополнительная информация &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Методология была протестирована на двух пилотных этапах. Первый из них включал разработку методологии при участии стран, в результате чего был разработан первый проект методологии, который был рассмотрен и доработан целевой группой. В начале 2016 года проект методологии был апробирован в пяти странах в период с апреля по ноябрь 2016 года на семинарах в Иордании, Нидерландах, Перу, Сенегале и Уганде. В каждой из этих стран были задействованы различные участники из национальных организаций и государственных секторов для организации широкой обратной связи по обсуждению технической осуществимости проекта методологии. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В ходе пилотных страновых проверок методологии в 2016 году с НСУ каждой из 5 стран проводились консультации, и они участвовали в процессе. Во время сбора пилотных методологических данных в 2017 году первоначальный запрос данных был передан всем НСУ. Кроме того, в октябре 2017 года национальные данные по пространственной протяженности открытой воды (полученные на основе наблюдений за Землей) были предоставлены 188 странам напрямую через их НСУ (см. дополнительную информацию выше). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
