<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 6-6-1a, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator 6.6.1 tracks the extent to which different types of water-related ecosystems are changing in extent over time. The indicator is multifaceted capturing data on different types of freshwater ecosystems and to measure extent change the indicator considers spatial area changes, water quality and water quantity changes. The indicator uses satellite-based Earth observations to globally monitor different freshwater ecosystems types. Earth observation data series on surface area are available on permanent water, seasonal water, reservoirs, wetlands, mangroves; as well as generating data on water quality, using trophic state and turbidity of water bodies. Satellite images can be represented as numerical data, which in turn are aggregated into meaningful statistics of ecosystem change attributed to administrative areas such as national, sub-national (e.g. regions and provinces) and river basin boundaries. Global data products for river flows and groundwater level have not yet been produced at useful spatial and temporal resolutions to be incorporated into this SDG 6.6.1 methodology. Currently, these data should continue to be provided from modelling or from ground-based measurements and required from the countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table 1: SDG indicator 6.6.1 data derived from Earth observations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unit &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Features &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lakes &amp;amp; Rivers (permanent water area)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;surface area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;annual and multi-annual changes in &lt;strong&gt;permanent water area&lt;/strong&gt; (1984-present)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;statistics for new and lost permanent water (2000-2020)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;statistics aggregated at national, sub-national &amp;amp; basin scales&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lakes &amp;amp; Rivers (seasonal water area)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;surface area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;annual and multi-annual changes in &lt;strong&gt;seasonal water area&lt;/strong&gt; (1984-present)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;statistics for new and lost seasonal water (2000-2020)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;annual seasonality statistics for periods: 0-1, 3-6, 7-11 months&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;statistics aggregated at national, sub-national &amp;amp; basin scales&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reservoirs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;surface area&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;water quality&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;annual and multi-annual changes in reservoir surface area (1984-present)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;statistics for new and lost reservoir area (2000-2020)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;statistics aggregated at national, sub-national &amp;amp; basin scales&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Monthly, annual and multi-annual measurements of trophic state and turbidity for 4,200 lakes and reservoirs globally (at 300m resolution)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mangroves&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;surface area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;annual and multi-annual changes in mangrove area (2000-2016)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;statistics aggregated at national, sub-national &amp;amp; basin scales&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wetlands&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;surface area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;wetlands area (baseline area comprised of data btw 2016-2018)&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;statistics aggregated at national, sub-national &amp;amp; basin scales&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;wetlands area changes will be included starting in 2021/22&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lakes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;water quality&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Monthly, annual and multi-annual measurements of trophic state and turbidity for 4,200 lakes and reservoirs globally (at 300m resolution)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SDG indicator 6.6.1 data derived from national in-situ measurements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unit &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Features &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rivers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;flow &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;modelled natural runoff/streamflow, and/or&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;in-situ stream/river flow measurements, aggregated over time, of all major rivers&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Groundwater&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;level&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Changes to volume measurements, over time, of all major groundwater aquifers&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concepts and definitions used in the methodology have been based on existing international frameworks and glossaries unless where indicated otherwise below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water-related ecosystems&lt;/strong&gt; are a sub-set of all ecosystems. They contain the world&amp;#x2019;s freshwater resources and can be defined as &amp;#x201C;a dynamic complex of plant, animal, and micro-organism communities and the non-living environment dominated by the presence of flowing or still water, interacting as a functional unit.&amp;#x201D; (MEA, 2005; Dickens et al, 2019). The indicator is framed around the monitoring of different types of water-related ecosystems including lakes, rivers, wetlands, groundwater and artificial waterbodies such as reservoirs. These water-related ecosystems contain freshwater, except for mangroves which contain brackish water (i.e. a combination of fresh and saltwater), however, mangroves are still included within indicator 6.6.1. Reservoirs are also included as a category of water-related ecosystem within the indicator methodology; while it is recognized that reservoirs are not traditional water ecosystems which should necessarily warrant protection and restoration, in many countries they hold a noteworthy amount of freshwater and have thus been included. By including data on reservoirs, it is intended that countries can better understand changes occurring to artificial water bodies in conjunction with changes occurring to natural water bodies. Ecosystems that are not included under indicator 6.6.1 are: coral reefs and sea grass which are covered within Goal 14 (Oceans); and mountains, forests, and drylands which are covered within Goal 15 (Land). The extent to which each of the water-related ecosystems included under indicator 6.6.1 can be measured, uses one or more of the following physical parameters of change: spatial area, quantity (or volume) of water, and water quality. The full monitoring methodology for indicator 6.6.1 is available here. The extent to which each of the water-related ecosystems included under indicator 6.6.1 can be measured, uses one or more of the following physical parameters of change: spatial area, quantity (or volume) of water, and water quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inland vegetated wetlands&lt;/strong&gt; include areas of marshes, peatlands, swamps, bogs and fens, the vegetated parts of floodplains as well as rice paddies and flood recession agriculture. Inland vegetated wetlands do not include coastal mangroves. Data on mangroves which are produced separately to inland wetlands. This SDG indicator methodology is used for official reporting of SDG indicator 6.6.1 statistics. The SDG indicator 6.6.1 methodology does not apply the definition of wetlands defined by the Ramsar Convention on Wetlands, which is: &amp;#x201C;areas of marsh, fen, peatland or water, whether natural or artificial, permanent or temporary, with water that is static or flowing, fresh, brackish or salt, including areas of marine water the depth of which at low tide does not exceed six meters&amp;#x201D;. The Ramsar definition of wetlands may be interpreted to mean all water within a country including the marine environment. The SDG indicator 6.6.1 definition refers to only a specific group of inland vegetated wetlands typologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Permanent and seasonal water. A permanent water surface is underwater throughout the year whilst a seasonal water surface is underwater for less than 12 months of the year. Some locations don&amp;#x2019;t have observations for all 12 months of the year (for reasons such as polar night). In these cases, water is considered as seasonal if the number of months where water is present is less than the number of months where valid observations were acquired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second consideration is lakes and rivers that freeze for part of the year. During the frozen period water is still present under the ice (true both for rivers/lakes and the sea). If water is present throughout the observation period (i.e. unfrozen period), the water body is considered as a permanent water surface. If the area of the water body contracts during the unfrozen period, then the pixels along the borders of the lake or river are no longer water, and those pixels will be considered as a seasonal water surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reservoirs&lt;/strong&gt; are artificial (or human-made) bodies of freshwater, as opposed to lakes which are naturally occurring. The reservoirs dataset represents surface area data on artificial water bodies including reservoirs formed by dams, flooded areas such as opencast mines and quarries, flood irrigation areas, and water bodies created by hydro-engineering projects such as waterway and harbour construction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turbidity&lt;/strong&gt; is an indicator of water clarity, quantifying the haziness of the water and acting as an indicator of underwater light availability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trophic State&lt;/strong&gt; refers to the degree at which organic matter accumulates in the water body and is most commonly used in relation to monitoring eutrophication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surface Water refers to any area of surface water unobstructed by aquatic vegetation. This includes the following 3 water-related ecosystem categories: rivers and estuaries, lakes, and artificial waterbodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extent &amp;#x2013; has been expanded beyond spatial extent to capture additional basic parameters needed for the protection and restoration of water-related ecosystems. Extent includes three components: the spatial extent or surface area, the quality, and the quantity of water-related ecosystems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change means a shift from one condition of extent to another over time within a water-related ecosystem, measured against a point of reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Permanent and seasonal water concept definitions and data resolution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data on the spatial and temporal dynamics of naturally occurring surface water has been generated for the entire globe. A Global Surface Water dataset (Pekel et al., 2016) has been produced by the European Commission&amp;apos;s Joint Research Centre. The dataset documents different facets of the long term (since 1984 onward) water dynamics at 30x30 meter pixel resolution. The dataset documents permanent and seasonal surface water surfaces. All naturally occurring surface water larger in area than 30x30 meters has been mapped and at this 30-meter grid/pixel spatial resolution satellite imagery is predominantly capturing areas of lakes and wide rivers (ie.. rivers over 30meters wide). The data include land areas that are temporarily inundated. Smaller rivers and waterbodies are not captured as they are too narrow to detect or are masked by forest canopy. The data include individual full-resolution images acquired by the Landsat 5, 7 and 8 and Sentinel 1 satellites. These satellites capture images which are distributed publicly by the United States Geological Survey and by the European Union&amp;#x2019;s Copernicus space programme. Together they provide multispectral imagery at 30x30 meter resolution in six visible, near and shortwave infrared channels, plus thermal imagery at 60x60 meters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data includes land surfaces that are under water (e.g. a permanent water area) for all twelve months of a year. It also accounts for seasonal and climactic fluctuations of water, meaning lakes and rivers which freeze for part of the year are captured. Areas of permanent ice, such as glaciers and ice caps as well as permanently snow-covered land areas are not included. Areas of consistent cloud cover inhibit the observation of water surfaces in some areas and in these limited locations optical observations may not be available. A global shoreline mask has been applied to the data to prevent ocean water being included in the freshwater statistics and the methodology for this shoreline mask is published in the journal of operational oceanography, available here (Sayer et al. 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The accuracy of the Global Surface Water map was determined using over 40,000 control points from around the world and across the 36 years. The full validation methodology and results have been published in the scientific journal Nature, available here, (Pekel et al., 2016). The validation results show that the water detection expert system produced less than 1% of false water detections, and that less than 5% of water surfaces were missed. The provided maps are derived from the analysis of over four million images collected over 36 years which have been individually processed using an accurate expert system classifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SDG 6.6.1 data portal (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sdg661.app&quot;&gt;www.sdg661.app&lt;/a&gt;) documents various water transitions relating to permanent and seasonal surface water - these are changes in water state between two points in time (e.g. 2000 - 2019). Data is available for various transitions including new permanent water surfaces (i.e. conversion of a no water place into a permanent water place.); lost permanent water surfaces (i.e. conversion of a permanent water place into a no water place) as well as new and lost seasonal water. These allow monthly water presence or absence data to be captured. It is possible to identify specific months/years in which conditions changed, e.g. the date of filing of a new dam, or the month/year in which a lake disappeared. In addition, data on seasonality are provided, capturing changes resulting from intra and inter-annual variability or resulting from appearance or disappearance of seasonal or permanent water surfaces. The data separates &amp;apos;permanent&amp;apos; water bodies (those that are present throughout the period of observation) [nominally a year] from &amp;apos;seasonal&amp;apos; (those that are present for only part of the year).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador incluye cinco categorías: 1) humedales con vegetación, 2) ríos y estuarios, 3) lagos, 4) acuíferos y 5) masas de agua artificiales. A efectos de esta metodología, el texto se refiere únicamente a estas cinco categorías de ecosistemas. Para abordar su complejidad, el indicador 6.6.1 se ha dividido en 5 sub-indicadores para captar las diversas fuentes de datos y metodologías necesarias para el seguimiento de los componentes del indicador. Las fuentes de datos proceden de una combinación de muestreo en tierra y observaciones terrestres. Dependiendo del tipo de ecosistema y del tipo de extensión que se mida, la metodología de recopilación de datos también puede ser muy diferente. Se propone un enfoque de seguimiento progresivo con dos niveles:.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nivel 1: 2 sub-indicadores basados en datos disponibles a nivel mundial procedentes de observaciones terrestres que serán validados por los países con sus propias metodologías y conjuntos de datos:.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub-indicador 1 &amp;#x2013; extensión espacial de los ecosistemas relacionados con el agua &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub-indicador 2 &amp;#x2013; calidad del agua de los lagos y masas de agua artificiales&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nivel 2: Datos recopilados por los países a través de 3 sub-indicadores:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub-indicador 3 &amp;#x2013; cantidad de agua (descarga) en ríos y estuarios&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub-indicador 4 &amp;#x2013; calidad del agua importado del indicador 6.3.2 de los ODS &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub-indicador 5 &amp;#x2013; cantidad de agua subterránea en los acuíferos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Una metodología completa para este indicador está disponible en el documento titulado, &amp;#x201C;Metodología de seguimiento del indicador 6.6.1 de los ODS&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Los conceptos y definiciones utilizados en la metodología se han basado en los marcos y glosarios internacionales existentes, a menos que se indique lo contrario a continuación.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ecosistemas relacionados con el agua&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#x2013; incluye cinco categorías 1) humedales con vegetación, 2) ríos y estuarios, 3) lagos, 4) acuíferos y 5) masas de agua artificiales. A efectos de esta metodología, el texto se refiere únicamente a estas cinco categorías de ecosistemas. La mayoría de los tipos de ecosistemas relacionados con el agua que se monitorean en el Indicador 6.6.1 contienen agua dulce, con la excepción de los manglares y los estuarios que contienen aguas salobres y se incluyen en el Indicador 6.6.1. No se incluyen los ecosistemas que contienen o están dentro de aguas saladas, ya que están cubiertos por otros indicadores de los ODS (Objetivo 14). Otras categorías de humedales que se ajustan a las definiciones de la Convención de Ramsar se incluyen en la categoría de ecosistema de &amp;#x2018;humedales con vegetación&amp;#x2019;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humedales con vegetación &amp;#x2013; la categoría de ecosistema relacionado con el agua de los humedales con vegetación incluye pantanos, turberas, marismas, arrozales y manglares. Esta definición está estrechamente relacionada con la definición de humedales de la Convención de Ramsar, que es: &amp;#x201C;extensiones de marismas, pantanos y turberas, o superficies cubiertas de aguas, sean éstas de régimen natural o artificial, permanentes o temporales, estancadas o corrientes, dulces, salobres o saladas, incluidas las extensiones de agua marina cuya profundidad en marea baja no exceda de seis metros&amp;#x201D;, con la salvedad que las aguas saladas no están incluidas en el Indicador 6.6.1 (ya que están cubiertas por el ODS 14) y con la excepción que los humedales con vegetación son distintos de las otras categorías de ecosistemas de lagos, ríos y estuarios, acuíferos y cuerpos de agua artificiales. Los humedales con vegetación se han separado como una categoría de ecosistema propia debido a su importancia para la consecución de los objetivos y porque la metodología para monitorearlos con observaciones terrestres es única respecto a otras aguas abiertas. Los datos generados por la aplicación de esta metodología también generarán los datos requeridos por los países para informar a la Convención de Ramsar relativa a los humedales de importancia internacional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cuerpos de agua artificiales&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#x2013; la categoría de ecosistemas relacionados con el agua de los cuerpos de agua artificiales incluye cuerpos de agua abiertos creados por los seres humanos, como embalses, canales, puertos, minas y canteras. Aunque se reconoce que no son ecosistemas acuáticos tradicionales que deban ser protegidos y restaurados, en algunos países albergan una cantidad notable de agua dulce y por ello se han incluido.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aguas abiertas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#x2013; como cualquier área de agua superficial no obstruida por la vegetación acuática. Esto incluye las siguientes 3 categorías de ecosistemas relacionados con el agua: ríos y estuarios, lagos y cuerpos de agua artificiales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Extensión&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#x2013; se ha ampliado más allá de la extensión espacial para capturar parámetros básicos adicionales necesarios para la protección y restauración de los ecosistemas relacionados con el agua. La extensión incluye tres componentes: la extensión espacial o superficie, la calidad y la cantidad de los ecosistemas relacionados con el agua.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cambio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#x2013; un cambio de una condición de extensión a otra a lo largo del tiempo dentro de un ecosistema relacionado con el agua, medido con respecto a un punto de referencia.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Définition : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur comprend cinq catégories : 1) zones humides végétalisées, 2) rivières et estuaires, 3) lacs, 4) aquifères, et 5) masses d&apos;eau artificielles. Pour les besoins de cette méthodologie, le texte se réfère uniquement à ces cinq catégories d&apos;écosystèmes. Pour faire face à sa complexité, l&apos;Indicateur 6.6.1 a été divisé en 5 sous-indicateurs afin de saisir les différentes sources de données et méthodologies nécessaires à la surveillance des composantes de l&apos;Indicateur. Les sources de données proviennent d&apos;une combinaison d&apos;échantillonnage et d&apos;observation de la terre. Selon le type d&apos;écosystème et le type d&apos;étendue mesurée, la méthodologie de collecte des données peut également être très différente. Une approche de surveillance progressive à deux niveaux est proposée : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Niveau 1 : 2 sous-indicateurs basés sur les données d&apos;observation de la Terre disponibles au niveau mondial, qui seront validées par les pays par rapport à leurs propres méthodologies et ensembles de données : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sous-indicateur 1 &amp;#x2013; étendue spatiale des écosystèmes liés à l&apos;eau &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sous-indicateur 2 &amp;#x2013; qualité de l&apos;eau des lacs et des masses d&apos;eau artificielles
&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Niveau 2 : Données collectées par les pays au moyen de 3 sous-indicateurs
: &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sous-indicateur 3 &amp;#x2013; quantité d&apos;eau (débit) dans les rivières et les
estuaires &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sous-indicateur 4 &amp;#x2013; qualité de l&apos;eau importée de SDG Indicateur 6.3.2
&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sous-indicateur 5 &amp;#x2013; quantité d&apos;eau souterraine dans les aquifères &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
]&lt;p&gt;Une méthodologie complète pour cet indicateur est disponible dans le document intitulé &amp;#x201C;Méthodologie de surveillance de l&apos;indicateur 6.6.1 du ODD &amp;#x201D;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les concepts et définitions utilisés dans la méthodologie ont été basés sur les cadres et glossaires internationaux existants, sauf indication contraire ci-dessous. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Les écosystèmes liés à l&apos;eau &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#x2013; comprennent cinq catégories : 1) zones humides végétalisées, 2) rivières et estuaires, 3) lacs, 4) aquifères, et 5) plans d&apos;eau artificiels. Pour les besoins de cette méthodologie, le texte se réfère uniquement à ces cinq terminologies de catégories d&apos;écosystèmes. La majorité des types d&apos;écosystèmes liés à l&apos;eau surveillés dans l&apos;Indicateur 6.6.1 contiennent de l&apos;eau douce, à l&apos;exception des mangroves et des estuaires qui contiennent des eaux saumâtres et sont inclus dans l&apos;Indicateur 6.6.1. Les écosystèmes contenant ou se trouvant dans des eaux salées ne sont pas inclus, car ils sont couverts par d&apos;autres indicateurs ODD (objectif 14). D&apos;autres catégories de zones humides conformes aux définitions de la Convention de Ramsar sont comprises dans la catégorie d&apos;écosystème des &amp;#x2018; zones humides végétalisées &amp;#x2019;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zones humides végétalisées &amp;#x2013; La catégorie des écosystèmes aquatiques des zones humides végétalisées comprend les marais, les fagnes, les tourbières, les marécages, les rizières et les mangroves. Cette définition est étroitement liée à la définition des zones humides de la Convention de Ramsar sur les zones humides, qui est zones de marais, de fagnes, de tourbières ou d&apos;eaux, naturelles ou artificielles, permanentes ou temporaires, dont l&apos;eau est stagnante ou courante, douce, saumâtre ou salée, y compris les zones d&apos;eau marine dont la profondeur à marée basse ne dépasse pas six mètres&amp;#x201D;, à l&apos;exception des eaux salées qui ne sont pas incluses dans les rapports de l&apos;Indicateur 6.6.1 (car elles sont couvertes par le ODD 14) et à l&apos;exception des zones humides avec végétation qui sont distinctes des autres catégories d&apos;écosystèmes que sont les lacs, les rivières et les estuaires, les aquifères et les plans d&apos;eau artificiels. Les zones humides végétalisées ont été séparées en tant que catégorie d&apos;écosystème à part entière en raison de leur importance pour la réalisation des objectifs et parce que la méthodologie de surveillance de ces zones par l&apos;observation de la terre est unique par rapport aux autres eaux libres. Les données générées par l&apos;application de cette méthodologie généreront également les données requises par les pays pour faire rapport à la Convention de Ramsar sur les zones humides. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Masses d&apos;eau artificielles &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#x2013; La catégorie des écosystèmes liés à l&apos;eau des masses d&apos;eau artificielles comprend les masses d&apos;eau ouvertes créées par l&apos;homme telles que les réservoirs, les canaux, les ports, les mines et les carrières. Bien qu&apos;il soit reconnu qu&apos;il ne s&apos;agit pas d&apos;écosystèmes aquatiques traditionnels qui devraient être protégés et restaurés, dans certains pays, ils contiennent une quantité d&apos;eau douce notable et ont donc été inclus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Eau libre &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#x2013; comme toute zone d&apos;eau de surface non obstruée par une végétation aquatique. Cela comprend les 3 catégories d&apos;écosystèmes liés à l&apos;eau suivantes : rivières et estuaires, lacs et plans d&apos;eau artificiels. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;L&apos;étendue &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#x2013; a été élargie au-delà de l&apos;étendue spatiale pour englober des paramètres de base supplémentaires nécessaires à la protection et à la restauration des écosystèmes liés à l&apos;eau. L&apos;étendue comprend trois composantes : l&apos;étendue spatiale ou la surface, la qualité et la quantité des écosystèmes liés à l&apos;eau. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Changement &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#x2013; : passage d&apos;une condition d&apos;étendue à une autre au fil du temps au sein d&apos;un écosystème lié à l&apos;eau, mesuré par rapport à un point de référence. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель включает пять категорий: 1) заболоченные территории с растительностью, 2) реки и эстуарии, 3) озера, 4) водоносные горизонты и 5) искусственные водные объекты. Для целей данной методологии текст относится только к терминологии этих пяти категорий экосистем. Чтобы решить эту проблему, показатель 6.6.1 был разделен на 5 субпоказателей, чтобы охватить различные источники данных и методологии, необходимые для мониторинга компонентов показателя. Источники данных берутся из комбинации наземных обследований и наблюдений за землей. В зависимости от типа экосистемы и от степени распространения измерений, методология сбора данных также может сильно различаться. Предлагается двухуровневый прогрессивный подход в мониторинге: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Уровень 1: 2 субпоказателя, основанных на глобально доступных данных наблюдений за землей, которые будут подтверждены странами на основе их собственных методологий и наборов данных: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Субпоказатель 1 &amp;#x2013; пространственная протяженность связанных с водой экосистем &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Субпоказатель 2 &amp;#x2013; качество воды озер и искусственных водоемов &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Уровень 2: данные, собираемые странами с использованием 3 субпоказателей: &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Субпоказатель 3 &amp;#x2013; количество воды (сток) в реках и эстуариях &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Субпоказатель 4 &amp;#x2013; качество воды, взятое из показателя 6.3.2 ЦУР &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Субпоказатель 5 &amp;#x2013; количество грунтовых вод в водоносных горизонтах&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Полное описание методологии для этого показателя доступно в документе, озаглавленном «Методология мониторинга для показателя 6.6.1 ЦУР». &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Понятия и определения, используемые в методологии, основаны на существующих международных системах и глоссариях, если иное не указано ниже. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Экосистемы, связанные с водой &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#x2013; включают пять категорий: 1) водно-болотные угодья, покрытые растительностью, 2) реки и эстуарии, 3) озера, 4) водоносные горизонты и 5) искусственные водные объекты. Для целей данной методологии текст относится только к терминологии этих пяти категорий экосистем. Большинство связанных с водой типов экосистем, отслеживаемых в показателе 6.6.1, содержат пресную воду, за исключением мангровых зарослей и эстуариев, которые содержат солоноватую воду и включены в показатель 6.6.1. Экосистемы, содержащие солоноватую воду или находящиеся в пределах солоноватых вод, сюда не включены, поскольку они включены в другие показатели ЦУР (цель 14). Другие категории заболоченных угодий, соответствующие определениям Рамсарской конвенции, включены в категорию экосистемы «водно-болотные угодья, покрытые растительностью».&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Водно-болотные угодья, покрытые растительностью &amp;#x2013; категория водно-болотных угодий, покрытых растительностью, связанных с водными экосистемами, включает болота, фены, торфяники, мочаги, рисовые поля и мангровые заросли. Это определение тесно связано с определением водно-болотных угодий в Рамсарской конвенции о водно-болотных угодьях, а именно: &quot;участки болот, фенов, торфяных угодий или водоемов — естественных или искусственных, постоянных или временных, стоячих или проточных, пресных, солоноватых или соленых, включая морские акватории, глубина которых при отливе не превышает шести метров&quot;, за исключением того, что соленые воды не включены в отчетность по показателю 6.6.1 (поскольку они включены в ЦУР 14), и за исключением того, что водно-болотные угодья, покрытые растительностью, отличаются от других категорий экосистем, таких как озера, реки и эстуарии, водоносные горизонты и искусственные водоемы. Водно-болотные угодья, покрытые растительностью, были выделены в отдельную категорию экосистем из-за их важности для достижения целей и из-за того, что методология их мониторинга с помощью наблюдений за землей отличается от других открытых водоемов. Данные, полученные с применением этой методологии, также будут создавать данные, необходимые странам для представления отчетности по Рамсарской конвенции о водно-болотных угодьях.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Искусственные водоемы &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#x2013; Категория искусственных водоемов, связанных с водными экосистемами, включает открытые водоемы, созданные человеком, такие как водохранилища, каналы, гавани, шахты и карьеры. Хотя признано, что это нетрадиционные водные экосистемы, которые следует защищать и восстанавливать, в некоторых странах они содержат значительное количество пресной воды и поэтому были сюда включены. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Открытая вода &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#x2013; как и любой участок поверхностных вод, свободный от водной растительности. Сюда входят следующие 3 категории экосистем, связанных с водой: реки и эстуарии, озера и искусственные водные объекты. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Протяжённость&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#x2013; это понятие было расширено за пределы пространственной протяженности, чтобы охватить дополнительные основные параметры, необходимые для защиты и восстановления связанных с водой экосистем. Протяжённость включает три компонента: пространственную протяженность или площадь поверхности, качество и количество связанных с водой экосистем. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Изменение&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#x2013; переход от одного состояния протяженности к другому с течением времени в экосистеме, связанной с водой, измеренный относительно точки отсчета. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
