<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 14-6-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The indicator is based upon responses by States to a certain sections of the questionnaire for monitoring the implementation of the Code of Conduct for Responsible Fisheries and related instruments (CCRF). These are sections covering the implementation of different international instruments used to combat IUU fishing. The responses will be converted using an algorithm to obtain a score for the indicator. Each instrument will be covered within a given variable, as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variable 1&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(V1)&lt;/strong&gt; - Adherence and implementation of the 1982 United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variable 2&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(V2)&lt;/strong&gt; - Adherence and implementation of the 1995 United Nations Fish Stocks Agreement &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variable 3 (V3)&lt;/strong&gt; - Development and implementation of a national plan of action (NPOA) to combat IUU fishing in line with the IPOA-IUU &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variable 4 (V4)&lt;/strong&gt; - Adherence and implementation of the 2009 FAO Agreement on Port State Measures (PSMA) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variable 5 (V5)&lt;/strong&gt; - Implementation of Flag State Responsibilities in the context of the 1993 FAO Compliance Agreement and FAO Voluntary Guidelines for Flag State Performance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on responses by FAO Members on the adherence and implementation of the above-mentioned instruments, States will score an indicator value between 0 and 1. Each variable is given a weighting, which takes into consideration the importance of the instrument in combating IUU fishing as well as the overlap between the instruments. The variable weightings are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weighting*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;V1&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;10%&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;V2&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;10%&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;V3&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;30%&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;V4&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;30%&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;V5&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;20%&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(*) item on &amp;#x201C;Applicability of instruments&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For binding agreements, States will still be able to score points if they are not party to the agreement but are implementing its provisions. States will also score points if they have initiated the process to becoming party to an agreement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator is automatically computed within the web-application on which the countries will be responding to the questionnaire. Once the questionnaire is completed the respondent will be presented with a report of the indicator, describing the methodology and the score attained. The user will then be able to give a final confirmation of the indicator. The final scores from all the respondents will automatically be collected onto a database. This web-application will also allow the user to access in any the following languages: English, French, Spanish, Chinese, Arabic and Russian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Choice of weighting per variable:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weightings for each variable have been carefully selected. These have been determined based upon their importance of their role in combatting IUU fishing as well as in consideration of the overlap present in between the different instruments. It is also for this consideration of overlap that the VG-FSP and the Compliance Agreement have been combined into Variable 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Applicability of instruments:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A set of questions will be present to determine certain characteristics of States (coastal, port, flag and land-locked). This will ensure that the indicator scoring for a country is not negatively affected if an instrument is not applicable to them. &lt;u&gt;In such case, the weighing of the variable that is not applicable is redistributed into the remaining variables&lt;/u&gt;. In cases where none of the instruments is applicable, the country will get an indicator score of &amp;#x201C;N/A&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cases in which Instruments are not applicable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The only case where this instrument becomes not applicable, is when the State is landlocked and they are not a flag state. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Is not applicable if the country is land-locked and not a flag State or a coastal State but is not a flag State or Port State.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Same as Variable 2.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Same as Variable 2.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Is not applicable if the country is not a flag State.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details regarding the list of question, scoring and applicability, please refer to Appendix 1 and 2.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador se basa en las respuestas de los Estados a determinadas secciones del cuestionario de seguimiento de la aplicación del Código de Conducta para la Pesca Responsable e instrumentos conexos (CCRF). Se trata de secciones que cubren la aplicación de diferentes instrumentos internacionales utilizados para combatir la pesca INDNR. Las respuestas se convertirán mediante un algoritmo para obtener una puntuación para el indicador. Cada instrumento se cubrirá dentro de una variable determinada, como sigue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variable 1&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(V1)&lt;/strong&gt; - Adhesión y aplicación de la Convención de las Naciones Unidas sobre el Derecho del Mar de 1982&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variable 2&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(V2)&lt;/strong&gt; - Adhesión y aplicación del Acuerdo de las Naciones Unidas sobre las poblaciones de peces de 1995 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variable 3 (V3)&lt;/strong&gt; - Elaboración y aplicación de un plan de acción nacional (PAN) de lucha contra la pesca INDNR en consonancia con el PAI-INDNR &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variable 4 (V4)&lt;/strong&gt; - Adhesión y aplicación del Acuerdo de la FAO sobre las medidas del Estado rector del puerto (PSMA) de 2009 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variable 5 (V5)&lt;/strong&gt; - Aplicación de las responsabilidades del Estado de abanderamiento en el contexto del Acuerdo de Cumplimiento de la FAO de 1993 y de las Directrices voluntarias de la FAO sobre la actuación del Estado de abanderamiento&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En función de las respuestas de los miembros de la FAO sobre la adhesión y la aplicación de los instrumentos mencionados, los Estados obtendrán un valor indicador entre 0 y 1. A cada variable se le asigna una ponderación, que tiene en cuenta la importancia del instrumento en la lucha contra la pesca INDNR, así como el solapamiento entre los instrumentos. Las ponderaciones de las variables son las siguientes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ponderación*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;V1&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;10%&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;V2&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;10%&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;V3&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;30%&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;V4&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;30%&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;V5&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;20%&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(*) punto sobre &amp;#x201C;Aplicabilidad de los instrumentos&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En el caso de los acuerdos vinculantes, los Estados podrán seguir sumando puntos si no son parte del acuerdo pero están aplicando sus disposiciones. Los Estados también sumarán puntos si han iniciado el proceso para convertirse en parte de un acuerdo. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Este indicador se calcula automáticamente en la aplicación web en la que los países responden al cuestionario. Una vez completado el cuestionario, el encuestado recibirá un informe del indicador que describe la metodología y la puntuación obtenida. El usuario podrá entonces dar una confirmación final del indicador. Las puntuaciones finales de todos los encuestados se recopilarán automáticamente en una base de datos. Esta aplicación web también permitirá al usuario acceder en cualquiera de los siguientes idiomas: inglés, francés, español, chino, árabe y ruso.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Elección de la ponderación por variable:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las ponderaciones de cada variable se han seleccionado cuidadosamente. Se han determinado en función de la importancia de su papel en la lucha contra la pesca INDNR, así como teniendo en cuenta el solapamiento existente entre los distintos instrumentos. Es también por esta consideración de solapamiento que el VG-FSP y el Acuerdo de Cumplimiento se han combinado en la Variable 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aplicabilidad de los instrumentos:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habrá un conjunto de preguntas para determinar ciertas características de los Estados (costeros, portuarios, de pabellón y sin litoral). Esto garantizará que la puntuación del indicador para un país no se vea afectada negativamente si un instrumento no le es aplicable. En tal caso, la ponderación de la variable que no es aplicable se redistribuye en las restantes variables. En los casos en que ninguno de los instrumentos sea aplicable, el país obtendrá una puntuación del indicador de &amp;#x201C;N/A&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Casos en los que los instrumentos no son aplicables&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;El único caso en el que este instrumento no es aplicable es cuando el Estado no tiene salida al mar y no es un Estado de abanderamiento. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;No es aplicable si el país no tiene salida al mar y no es un Estado de abanderamiento o un Estado costero pero no es un Estado de abanderamiento o un Estado portuario.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Igual que la variable 2.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Igual que la variable 2.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;No es aplicable si el país no es un Estado de abanderamiento&lt;/p&gt;.
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para más detalles sobre la lista de preguntas, la puntuación y la aplicabilidad, consulte los Apéndices 1 y 2.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Méthodologie &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Méthode de calcul : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur est basé sur les réponses des États à certaines sections du questionnaire de suivi de l&apos;application du Code de conduite pour une pêche responsable et des instruments connexes (CCRF). Il s&apos;agit de sections couvrant la mise en œuvre de différents instruments internationaux utilisés pour lutter contre la pêche INN. Les réponses seront converties à l&apos;aide d&apos;un algorithme afin d&apos;obtenir un score pour l&apos;indicateur. Chaque instrument sera couvert par une variable donnée, comme suit :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variable 1&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(V1)&lt;/strong&gt; - Adhésion et mise en œuvre de la Convention des Nations Unies sur le droit de la mer de 1982&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variable 2 &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(V2)&lt;/strong&gt; - Adhésion à l&apos;Accord des Nations Unies sur les stocks de poissons de 1995 et mise en oeuvre de cet accord &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variable 3 (V3)&lt;/strong&gt; - Elaboration et mise en oeuvre d&apos;un plan d&apos;action national (PAN) pour lutter contre la pêche INN conformément au PAI-INN &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Variable 4 (V4) &lt;/strong&gt; - Adhésion et mise en œuvre de l&apos;accord de la FAO de 2009 sur les mesures du ressort de l&apos;État du port (PSMA) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Variable 5 (V5) &lt;/strong&gt; - Mise en œuvre des responsabilités de l&apos;État du pavillon dans le contexte de l&apos;Accord de conformité de la FAO de 1993 et des Directives volontaires de la FAO sur la performance des États du pavillon &lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;En fonction des réponses des membres de la FAO sur l&apos;adhésion et la mise en œuvre des instruments susmentionnés, les États obtiendront une valeur d&apos;indicateur comprise entre 0 et 1. Chaque variable reçoit une pondération, qui tient compte de l&apos;importance de l&apos;instrument dans la lutte contre la pêche INN ainsi que du chevauchement entre les instruments. Les pondérations des variables sont les suivantes : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weighting*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;V1&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;10%&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;V2&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;10%&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;V3&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;30%&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;V4&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;30%&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;V5&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;20%&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(*) point sur &amp;#x201C;Applicabilité des instruments&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour les accords contraignants, les États pourront toujours marquer des points s&apos;ils ne sont pas parties à l&apos;accord mais en appliquent les dispositions. Les États marqueront également des points s&apos;ils ont entamé le processus pour devenir partie à un accord. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur est automatiquement calculé dans l&apos;application web sur laquelle les pays répondront au questionnaire. Une fois le questionnaire rempli, le répondant recevra un rapport sur l&apos;indicateur, décrivant la méthodologie et le score obtenu. L&apos;utilisateur pourra alors donner une confirmation finale de l&apos;indicateur. Les scores finaux de tous les répondants seront automatiquement collectés dans une base de données. Cette application web permettra également à l&apos;utilisateur d&apos;accéder à l&apos;une des langues suivantes : Anglais, français, espagnol, chinois, arabe et russe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Choix de la pondération par variable :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les pondérations de chaque variable ont été soigneusement sélectionnées. Elles ont été déterminées en fonction de l&apos;importance de leur rôle dans la lutte contre la pêche INN et en tenant compte des chevauchements entre les différents instruments. C&apos;est également pour cette considération de chevauchement que le VG-FSP et l&apos;accord de conformité ont été combinés dans la variable 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Applicability of instruments:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Une série de questions sera présente pour déterminer certaines caractéristiques des Etats (côtiers, portuaires, du pavillon et enclavés). Cela permettra de s&apos;assurer que la notation de l&apos;indicateur pour un pays n&apos;est pas affectée négativement si un instrument ne lui est pas applicable. Dans ce cas, la pondération de la variable qui n&apos;est pas applicable est redistribuée dans les variables restantes. Si aucun des instruments n&apos;est applicable, le pays obtiendra un score d&apos;indicateur de &amp;#x201C;N/A&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Cas dans lesquels les Instruments ne sont pas applicables &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;Le seul cas où cet instrument n&apos;est pas applicable est celui où l&apos;État est enclavé et n&apos;est pas un État du pavillon. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Ne s&apos;applique pas si le pays est enclavé et n&apos;est pas un État du pavillon ou un État côtier mais n&apos;est pas un État du pavillon ou un État du port.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Identique à la variable 2. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Identique à la variable 2. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Ne s&apos;applique pas si le pays n&apos;est pas un État du pavillon&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour plus de détails concernant la liste des questions, la notation et l&apos;applicabilité, veuillez vous référer aux Annexes 1 et 2.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель основан на ответах государств на определенные разделы вопросника для мониторинга соблюдения Кодекса по ведению ответственного рыболовства и связанных с ним документов (КВОР). Это разделы, посвященные реализации различных международных документов, используемых для борьбы с ННН-промыслом. Ответы будут преобразованы с использованием алгоритма для получения баллов по показателю. Каждый документ будет охвачен данной переменной следующим образом: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Переменная 1 &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; (V1) &lt;/strong&gt; - Присоединение и соблюдение Конвенции Организации Объединенных Наций 1982 года по морскому праву &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Переменная 2 &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; (V2) &lt;/strong&gt; - Присоединение и соблюдение Соглашения Организации Объединенных Наций 1995 года по рыбным запасам &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Переменная 3 (V3) &lt;/strong&gt; - Разработка и соблюдение национального плана действий (НПД) по борьбе с ННН-промыслом в соответствии с МПД-ННН &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Переменная 4 (V4) &lt;/strong&gt; - Присоединение и соблюдение Соглашения ФАО 2009 года о мерах государства порта (СМГП) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Переменная 5 (V5) &lt;/strong&gt; - Соблюдение обязанностей государства флага в контексте Соглашения ФАО1993 года о содействии соблюдению и Добровольных руководящих принципов ФАО в отношении действий государства флага&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;В зависимости от ответов членов ФАО о присоединении и соблюдении вышеупомянутых документов государства будут получать оценочное значение показателя от 0 до 1. Каждой переменной присваивается вес, который учитывает важность документа в борьбе с ННН-промыслом, а также взаимное перекрытие документов. Переменные имеют следующие веса: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Переменная &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Вес* &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; V1 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 10% &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; V2 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 10% &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; V3 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 30% &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; V4 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 30% &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; V5 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 20% &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt; (*) пункт &amp;#x201C; Применимость инструментов &amp;#x201D; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В случае соглашений, имеющих обязательную силу, государства также смогут набирать баллы, даже если они не являются участниками соглашения, но соблюдают его положения. Государства также будут набирать баллы, если они начали процесс присоединения к соглашению. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Этот показатель автоматически рассчитывается в веб-приложении, в котором страны будут отвечать на вопросник. После заполнения вопросника респонденту будет представлен отчет по показателю с описанием методологии и набранных баллов. После этого пользователь сможет окончательно подтвердить показатель. Окончательные баллы всех респондентов будут автоматически занесены в базу данных. Это веб-приложение также позволит пользователю получить доступ к вопроснику на любом из следующих языков: английском, французском, испанском, китайском, арабском и русском. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Выбор веса для каждой переменной: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Веса для каждой переменной были тщательно подобраны. Они были определены на основе важности их роли в борьбе с ННН-промыслом, а также с учетом взаимного перекрытия между различными документами. Именно с учетом взаимного перекрытия Добровольные руководящие принципы ФАО в отношении действий государства флага (ДРП-ДГФ) и Соглашение о содействии соблюдению были объединены в переменную 5. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Применимость инструментов: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Будет представлен набор вопросов для определения некоторых характеристик государств (прибрежные, портовые, государства флага и государства, не имеющие выхода к морю). Этот подход даст гарантию, что на оценку показателя страны не будет оказываться отрицательное влияние в том случае, если документ не применим к ней. В таком случае взвешивание переменной, которая к данной стране не применима, перераспределяется на остальные переменные. В случаях, когда ни один из документов не применим, страна получит балльную оценку показателя &amp;#x201C; Не применимо &amp;#x201D;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Переменная &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Случаи, когда документы не применимы &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; V1 &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Единственный случай, когда этот документ становится неприменимым, -
это когда государство не имеет выхода к морю и не является государством флага. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; V2 &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Не применяется, если страна не имеет выхода к морю и не является государством
флага или является прибрежным государством, но не является государством флага или государством порта. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; V3 &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; То же, что и переменная 2. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; V4 &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; То же, что и переменная 2. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; V5 &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Неприменимо, если страна не является государством флага. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для получения более подробной информации относительно списка вопросов, балльных оценок и применимости см. Приложения 1 и 2. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
