<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DOC_METHOD field for indicator 14-6-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Methods and guidance available to countries for the compilation of the data at the national level:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the countries receive the questionnaire, they will have access to a manual that will guide the user along the best process for completing the questionnaire. Due to the various themes that are covered within the questionnaire, it is essential that the focal point or user gather the responses using a well-coordinated process involving all the relevant staff that are in charge of the work within the various themes contained within the questionnaire, such as the focal point for the indicator. Additionally, the manual will also have a section describing the methodology of the indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the questionnaire application, the user will be able to find pop up guides embedded in the application describing technical aspects or terms encountered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;URL to the authenticated CCRF questionnaire application: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/fishery/code/codequest/?locale=en&amp;amp;lang=en&quot;&gt;FAO Questionnaire for Monitoring the Implementation of the Code of Conduct for Responsible Fisheries&lt;/a&gt; and Related Instruments&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Méthodes et instructions à la disposition des pays pour la compilation des données au niveau national : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Une fois que les pays auront reçu le questionnaire, ils auront accès à un manuel qui guidera l&apos;utilisateur dans la meilleure façon de remplir le questionnaire. En raison des différents thèmes couverts par le questionnaire, il est essentiel que le point focal ou l&apos;utilisateur recueille les réponses en utilisant un processus bien coordonné impliquant tout le personnel en charge du travail sur les différents thèmes contenus dans le questionnaire, comme le point focal pour l&apos;indicateur. En outre, le manuel comportera également une section décrivant la méthodologie de l&apos;indicateur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dans l&apos;application du questionnaire, l&apos;utilisateur pourra trouver des guides contextuels intégrés à l&apos;application décrivant les aspects techniques ou les termes rencontrés.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;URL de l&apos;application questionnaire CCRF authentifiée : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/fishery/code/codequest/?locale=en&amp;amp;lang=en&quot;&gt;Questionnaire de la FAO pour le suivi de l&apos;application du Code de conduite pour une pêche responsable&lt;/a&gt; et des instruments connexes.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Доступные странам методы и руководства для составления данных на национальном уровне: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;После того, как страны получат вопросник, они получат доступ к руководству, которое продемонстрирует пользователю наиболее оптимальный процесс заполнения вопросника. Из-за различных тем, затронутых в вопроснике, важно, чтобы координатор или пользователь собирали ответы, используя хорошо скоординированный процесс с участием всего соответствующего персонала, который отвечает за работу по различным темам, содержащимся в вопроснике, например, координатор показателя. Кроме того, в руководстве будет также раздел, описывающий методологию показателя. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В приложении вопросника пользователь сможет найти всплывающие подсказки, встроенные в приложение, с описанием технических аспектов или встречающихся терминов. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; URL-адрес подлинного приложения вопросника Кодекс ФАО по ведению ответственного рыболовства: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/fishery/code/codequest/?locale=en&amp;amp;lang=en&quot;&gt;FAO Questionnaire for Monitoring the Implementation of the Code of Conduct for Responsible Fisheries&lt;/a&gt; и связанных с ним документов&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
