<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The CLASS_SYSTEM field for indicator 3-8-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="en">## Concepts

Indicator 3.8.2 is defined as the “Proportion of the population with large household expenditure on health as a share of total household expenditure or income”. In effect it is based on a ratio exceeding a threshold. The two main concepts of interest behind this ratio are household expenditure on health (numerator) and total household consumption expenditure or, when unavailable, income (denominator).

### Numerator

Household expenditure on health is defined as any expenditure incurred at the time of service use to get any type of care (promotive, preventive, curative, rehabilitative, palliative or long-term care) including all medicines, vaccines and other pharmaceutical preparations as well as all health products, *from any type of provider and for all members of the household.* These health expenditures are characterized by a direct payments that are financed by a household’s income (including remittances), savings or loans  **but do not include any third-party payer reimbursement**. As such they only grant access to the health services and health products individuals can pay for, without any solidarity between the healthy and the sick beyond the household [^1] and solely based on the willingness and ability of the household to pay. Direct health care payments are labelled Out-Of-Pocket (OOP) payments in the classification of health care financing schemes (HF) of the international Classification for Health Accounts (ICHA). OOP health expenditures are the most unequitable source of funding for the health system.

The components of a household’s health care consumption expenditure so defined should be consistent with division 06 on health of the UN Classification of Individual Consumption According to Purpose (COICOP) which currently  includes expenditures on medicines and medical products (06.1), outpatient care services (06.2) and inpatient care services (06.3) but is being expanded. [^2]

Further information on definitions and classifications (for example by provider, by beneficiary characteristics) of health expenditures should be consistent with the [international classification for health accounts](http://www.who.int/health-accounts/methodology/en/) and its family of classifications. ICHA results from collaboration between OECD, Eurostat and the World Health Organization.

### Denominator

Expenditure on household consumption and household income are both monetary welfare measures. Household consumption is a function of permanent income, which is a measure of a household’s long-term economic resources that determine living standards. Consumption is generally defined as the sum of the monetary values of all items (goods and services) consumed by the household on domestic account during a reference period. It includes the imputed values of goods and services that are not purchased but procured otherwise for consumption. Information on household consumption is usually collected in household surveys that may use different approaches to measure ‘consumption’ depending on whether items refer to durable or non-durable goods and/or are directly produced by households.

The most relevant measure of income is disposable income as it is close to the maximum available to the household for consumption expenditure during the accounting period. Disposable income is defined as total income less direct taxes (net of refunds), compulsory fees and fines. Total income is generally composed of income from employment, property income, income from household production of services for own consumption, transfers received in cash and goods, transfers received as services. [^3]

Income is more difficult to measure accurately due to its greater variability over time. Consumption is less variable over time and easier to measure. It is therefore recommended that whenever there is information on both household consumption and income the former is used (see the “comments and limitations” section to learn more about the sensitivity of 3.8.2 to the income/expenditure choice in the denominator). Statistics on 3.8.2 currently produced by WHO and the World Bank predominantly rely on consumption (see section on data sources).

### Thresholds

It is recommended to use two thresholds for global reporting to identify large household expenditure on health as share of total household consumption or income: **a lower threshold of 10% (3.8.2_10) and a higher threshold of 25% (3.8.2_25)**. With these two thresholds the indicator measures financial hardship (see section on comments and limitations).
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">## Понятия

Показатель 3.8.2 определяется как &quot;Доля населения с большими расходами домашних хозяйств на здравоохранение в общих расходах домашних хозяйств или доходах&quot;. По сути, он основан на соотношении, превышающем пороговое значение. За этим показателем стоят два основных элемента: расходы домашних хозяйств на здравоохранение (числитель) и общие расходы домашних хозяйств на потребление или, если таковые отсутствуют, то доходы (знаменатель).

### Числитель

Расходы домохозяйства на здравоохранение определяются как любые расходы, понесенные во время пользования услугами для получения любого вида ухода (промотерного, профилактического, лечебного, реабилитационного, паллиативного или долгосрочного), включая все лекарства, вакцины и другие фармацевтические препараты, а также все товары медицинского назначения * от любого поставщика медицинских услуг и для всех членов домохозяйства*. Эти расходы на здравоохранение представляют собой прямые расходы, которые оплачиваются из дохода домохозяйства (включая денежные переводы), сбережений или займов **, но не включают какие-либо платежи сторонних плательщиков Как таковые, они обеспечивают доступ только к медицинским услугам и товарам медицинского назначения, за которые отдельные лица могут платить, без каких-либо совместных действий, предпринимаемых здоровыми и больными людьми, не входящими в состав домашнего хозяйства [^1] и исключительно на основе желания и способности домашнего хозяйства оплачивать расходы. Прямые платежи за медицинское обслуживание обозначаются как наличные расходы (НР) в классификации схем финансирования здравоохранения (СФЗ) международной Классификации счетов здравоохранения (ICHA). Наличные расходы на здравоохранение НР являются наиболее неравномерно поступающим источником финансирования системы здравоохранения.

Определенные таким образом компоненты расходов на здравоохранение должны соответствовать разделу 06 &quot;Здравоохранение&quot; Классификации индивидуального потребления по целям (КИПЦ), которая в настоящее время включает расходы на лекарства и медицинские товары (06.1), услуги амбулаторного лечения (06.2) и услуги стационарной помощи (06.3), но в настоящее время расширяется. [^2]

Дополнительная информация об определениях и классификациях (например, по поставщикам услуг, по характеристикам бенефициаров) расходов на здравоохранение должна согласовываться с Международной классификацией счетов здравоохранения (МКСЗ) (http://www.who.int/health-accounts/methodology/en/) и ее семейством классификаций. МКСЗ является результатом сотрудничества между ОЭСР, Евростатом и Всемирной организацией здравоохранения.

### Знаменатель

Расходы на потребление домашних хозяйств и доходы домашних хозяйств являются показателями денежного благосостояния. Потребление домохозяйств является функцией постоянного дохода, который является показателем долгосрочных экономических ресурсов домохозяйства, определяющих уровень жизни. Потребление обычно определяется как выраженная в денежной форме суммарная стоимость всех отечественных предметов (товаров и услуг), потребленных домашним хозяйством в течение отчетного периода. Она включает в себя вмененную стоимость товаров и услуг, которые не были приобретены, но были получены иным путем для потребления. Информация о потреблении домашних хозяйств обычно собирается в ходе обследований домашних хозяйств, которые могут использовать различные подходы к измерению &quot;потребления&quot; в зависимости от того, относятся ли предметы к товарам длительного или недлительного пользования и/или производятся непосредственно домашними хозяйствами.

Наиболее значимым показателем дохода является располагаемый доход, так как он близок к максимальному уровню, доступному домохозяйству для покрытия потребительских расходов в течение отчетного периода. Располагаемый доход определяется как общий доход за вычетом прямых налогов (компенсационных выплат), обязательных платежей и штрафов. Общие доходы, как правило, состоят из доходов от занятости, доходов от собственности, доходов от производства услуг для собственного потребления домашними хозяйствами, трансфертов, полученных в виде денежных средств и товаров, трансфертов, полученных в виде услуг. [^3]

Доходы труднее точно измерить из-за их большей вариабельности с течением времени. Потребление менее изменчиво с течением времени и легче поддается измерению. Поэтому во всех случаях, когда имеется информация как о потреблении домохозяйств, так и о доходах, рекомендуется использовать первый показатель (см. раздел &quot;комментарии и ограничения&quot;, чтобы больше узнать об отношении показателя 3.8.2 к выбору дохода/расхода в знаменателе). Статистические данные по показателю 3.8.2, которые в настоящее время публикуются ВОЗ и Всемирным банком, в основном основаны на данных о потреблении (см. раздел об источниках данных).

### Пороговые значения

Рекомендуется использовать два пороговых значения для международной отчетности, чтобы определить долю домашних хозяйств с крупными расходами  на здравоохранение в общем потреблении или доходе домашних хозяйств: **нижний порог составляет 10% (3.8.2_10) и верхний порог - 25% (3.8.2_25)**. С помощью этих двух пороговых значений показатель определяет финансовые трудности (см. раздел, посвященный комментариям и ограничениям).
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
