<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COMPARABILITY field for indicator 3-8-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Country level estimates are all based on nationally representative surveys with information on both household total expenditure or income and household expenditure on health (see data sources). In most cases such data come from non-standard household surveys and ex-post standardization processes can be designed to increase the degree of comparability across countries. For instance, regional teams from the World Bank produce standardized versions of raw datasets following common regional procedures: the ECAPOV harmonized datasets are based on the Living Standards Measurement Study datasets &amp;#x2013; LSMS&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-15&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-15&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; or household budget surveys (HBS) collected in the World Bank&amp;#x2019;s Europe and Central Asia region; the SHIP collection results from a poverty program on harmonized household surveys in the World Bank&amp;#x2019;s African region, while the SHES collection was developed by the World Bank for the international comparison program&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-16&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-16&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The Luxembourg income study (LIS) datasets results from effort to harmonize datasets from many high and middle-income countries&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-17&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-17&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases the raw data is accessible to produce country level estimates. In some countries in addition to the raw data a standardized version of it is available and in other countries only the standardized version is. When multiple versions of the same survey are available the best performing in terms of a series of quality assurance tests is retained (see collection process). When a standardized version of a nationally designed survey instruments is chosen there are differences between expenditure variables generated using the raw data, and the expenditure variables generated using the harmonization procedures which might result in different estimated incidence of the population with large household expenditure on health as a share of household total expenditure or income.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-15&quot;&gt;14&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; http://econ.worldbank.org/WBSITE/EXTERNAL/EXTDEC/EXTRESEARCH/EXTLSMS/0,,contentMDK:21610833~pagePK:64168427~piPK:64168435~theSitePK:3358997,00.html &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-15&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-16&quot;&gt;15&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; A detailed documentation describing the harmonization procedures is available from the accompanying pdf documents &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-16&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-17&quot;&gt;16&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; http://www.lisdatacenter.org/ &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-17&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Fuentes de discrepancias:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las estimaciones a nivel de país se basan todas en encuestas representativas a nivel nacional con información tanto sobre el gasto o los ingresos totales de los hogares como sobre el gasto de los hogares en salud (ver fuentes de datos). En la mayoría de los casos, estos datos proceden de encuestas a hogares no normalizadas y pueden diseñarse procesos de normalización a posteriori para aumentar el grado de comparabilidad entre países. Por ejemplo, los equipos regionales del Banco Mundial producen versiones estandarizadas de conjuntos de datos brutos siguiendo procedimientos regionales comunes: los conjuntos de datos armonizados de ECAPOV (por su sigla en inglés) se basan en los conjuntos de datos del Estudio de Medición de los Niveles de Vida &amp;#x2013; LSMS (por su sigla en inglés) &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-14&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; o en las encuestas de presupuestos familiares (EPF) recopiladas en la región de Europa y Asia Central del Banco Mundial&amp;#x2019;; la colección SHIP (por su sigla en inglés) es el resultado de un programa de pobreza sobre encuestas a hogares armonizadas en la región africana del Banco Mundial&amp;#x2019;, mientras que la colección SHES (por su sigla en inglés) fue desarrollada por el Banco Mundial para el programa de comparación internacional&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-15&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-15&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Los conjuntos de datos del estudio de ingresos de Luxemburgo (LIS, por su sigla en inglés) son el resultado del esfuerzo por armonizar los conjuntos de datos de muchos países de ingresos altos y medios&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-16&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-16&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En algunos casos, los datos brutos son accesibles para producir estimaciones a nivel de país. En algunos países, además de los datos brutos, se dispone de una versión estandarizada de los mismos y en otros países sólo de la versión estandarizada. Cuando se dispone de varias versiones de la misma encuesta, se retiene la de mejor rendimiento en términos de una serie de pruebas de garantía de calidad (véase el proceso de recolección). Cuando se opta por una versión estandarizada de los instrumentos de una encuesta diseñada a nivel nacional, existen diferencias entre las variables de gasto generadas utilizando los datos brutos y las variables de gasto generadas utilizando los procedimientos de armonización, lo que podría dar lugar a una incidencia estimada diferente de la población con un gran gasto de los hogares en salud como proporción del gasto o los ingresos totales de los hogares.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-14&quot;&gt;14&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt;http://econ.worldbank.org/WBSITE/EXTERNAL/EXTDEC/EXTRESEARCH/EXTLSMS/0,,contentMDK:21610833~pagePK:64168427~piPK:64168435~theSitePK:3358997,00.html &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-14&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-15&quot;&gt;15&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;p&gt; Una documentación detallada que describe los procedimientos de armonización está disponible en los documentos pdf adjuntos &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-15&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-16&quot;&gt;16&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;p&gt; http://www.lisdatacenter.org/ &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-16&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Sources des divergences :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les estimations au niveau des pays sont toutes fondées sur des enquêtes représentatives au niveau national avec des informations sur les dépenses ou les revenus totaux des ménages et sur les dépenses de santé des ménages (voir la section « Sources de données »). Dans la plupart des cas, ces données proviennent d’enquêtes non standard auprès des ménages et les processus de normalisation ex post peuvent être conçus pour accroître le degré de comparabilité entre les pays. Par exemple, les équipes régionales de la Banque mondiale produisent des versions normalisées des ensembles de données brutes selon des procédures régionales communes : les ensembles de données harmonisés de l’ECAPOV sont basés sur les ensembles de données de l’Étude sur la mesure du niveau de vie – LSMS&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-15&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-15&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; ou sur les enquêtes sur les dépenses des ménages (EDM) recueillies dans la région Europe et Asie centrale de la Banque mondiale; la collecte du SHIP résulte d’un programme de lutte contre la pauvreté sur les enquêtes harmonisées auprès des ménages dans la région africaine de la Banque mondiale, tandis que la collecte du SHES a été développée par la Banque mondiale pour le programme de comparaison internationale&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-16&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-16&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. La base de données du « Luxembourg Income Study » (LIS) résulte des efforts visant à harmoniser les ensembles de données de nombreux pays à revenu élevé et moyen&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-17&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-17&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dans certains cas, les données brutes sont accessibles pour produire des estimations au niveau des pays. Dans certains pays, en plus des données brutes, une version normalisée de celles-ci est disponible et dans d’autres pays, seule la version normalisée l’est. Lorsque plusieurs versions d’une même enquête sont disponibles, les plus performantes en termes de série de tests d’assurance de la qualité sont conservées (voir processus de collecte). Lorsqu’une version normalisée d’un instrument d’enquête conçu à l’échelle nationale est choisie, il existe des différences entre les variables de dépenses générées à l’aide des données brutes et les variables de dépenses générées à l’aide des procédures d’harmonisation, ce qui pourrait entraîner une incidence estimée différente de la population dont le ménage consacre une part importante de ses dépenses totales ou de son revenu total aux dépenses de santé. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-15&quot;&gt;14&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; (en anglais) http://econ.worldbank.org/WBSITE/EXTERNAL/EXTDEC/EXTRESEARCH/EXTLSMS/0,,contentMDK:21610833~pagePK:64168427~piPK:64168435~theSitePK:3358997,00.html &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-15&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-16&quot;&gt;15&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Une documentation détaillée décrivant les procédures d’harmonisation est disponible dans les documents PDF ci-joints &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-16&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-17&quot;&gt;16&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; (en anglais) http://www.lisdatacenter.org/ &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-17&quot;&gt; &amp;#x2191; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt;Источники расхождений:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Все оценки на страновом уровне основаны на репрезентативных на национальном уровне обследованиях, включающих информацию как об общих расходах или доходах домохозяйств, так и о расходах домохозяйств на здравоохранение (см. Источники данных). В большинстве случаев такие данные поступают из нестандартизированных обследований домашних хозяйств, а процессы последующей стандартизации могут быть разработаны для повышения степени сопоставимости между странами. Например, группы Всемирного банка, ответственные за региональные показатели, создают стандартизированные версии наборов первичных данных на основе общих региональных процедур: гармонизированные наборы данных ECAPOV основаны на наборах данных исследования по измерению уровня жизни (LSMS) &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-14&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-14&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; или обследования бюджетов домашних хозяйств (ОБДХ), собранных в регионе Европы и Центральной Азии, который курирует Всемирный банк; набор данных SHIP является результатом реализации программы борьбы с бедностью в рамках согласованных обследований домашних хозяйств в африканском регионе, который курирует Всемирный банк, в то время как процедура сбора данных SHES была разработана Всемирным банком для международной программы сопоставлений. &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-15&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-15&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;Наборы данных Люксембургского исследования доходов (LIS) являются результатом усилий по гармонизации наборов данных из многих стран с высоким и средним уровнем дохода. &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-16&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-16&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;В некоторых случаях первичные данные доступны для получения оценок на страновом уровне. В некоторых странах в дополнение к первичным данным имеется стандартизированная версия первичных данных, а в других странах имеется только стандартизированная версия. Когда доступны комплексные версии одного и того же обследования, сохраняется наилучшая из реализованных версий с точки зрения проведенной серии проверок на обеспечение качества (см. Процесс сбора). При выборе стандартизированной версии инструментариев обследования, разработанных на национальном уровне, существуют различия между переменными расходов, произведенных с использованием первичных данных, и переменными расходов, произведенных с использованием процедур гармонизации, которые могут привести к различиям в оценке доли населения с большим удельным весом семейных расходов на медицинскую помощь в общем объеме расходов или доходов домохозяйств.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup&gt;14&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt;http://econ.worldbank.org/WBSITE/EXTERNAL/EXTDEC/EXTRESEARCH/EXTLSMS/0,,contentMDK:21610833~pagePK:64168427~piPK:64168435~theSitePK:3358997,00.html

&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-14&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup&gt;15&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Подробная документация, описывающая процедуры гармонизации, доступна в сопроводительных документах в формате pdf &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-15&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup&gt;16&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; http://www.lisdatacenter.org/ &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-16&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
