<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 3-8-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the country level, no imputation is attempted to produce estimates. The proportion of the population with large household expenditure on health as a share of total household expenditure or income is estimated for all years for which a nationally representative survey on the household budget, household income and expenditure, socio-economic conditions or living standards is available with information on both total household expenditure or income and total household expenditure on health. When there are multiple surveys over time for the same country from different collections, a preference is given to estimates produced based on the same type of survey. A series of tests is performed to retain the best performing series (see 4.k).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At regional levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because surveys are not conducted yearly in most countries, SDG 3.8.2 estimates across countries are computed for different years. To compute regional and global aggregates for a common reference year (i.e. every five years between 2000 and 2015; every two years from 2015.), survey-based country estimates are &amp;#x201C;lined-up&amp;#x201D; using one of the following different methods depending upon the availability of information for that country around or at the reference year (T*): In countries for which there is an observed incidence rate of the SDG indicator 3.8.2 in the reference year T*, this point is used. When there are at least two observed incidence rates of the SDG indicator 3.8.2 around the reference over a 5-year window around the reference year [T*&amp;#x2013;5; T*+5], linear interpolation is used to project the value of SDG indicator 3.8.2 in the reference year. If these conditions are not met but there are at least two observed incidences rates of the SDG indicator 3.8.2, a multilevel model is estimated using the aggregate share of out-of-pocket health spending over total consumption expenditure as the explanatory variable if that information is available. If such information is not available or there aren&amp;#x2019;t two incidence rates of the SDG indicator 3.8.2, the incidence rate is imputed in the reference year with the median incidence in that year among countries within the same income group (low, lower-middle, upper-middle, or high) as classified by the World Bank. If such classification is missing, the regional median value of the SDG indicator 3.8.2 at the 10% threshold is used. The regional classification used for the imputation is M49 level 1. The country estimates for the reference year are then aggregated up to the regional and global levels to compute the &amp;#x201C;Total population with household expenditures on health greater than 10% of total household income or expenditure&amp;#x201D; in millions. The proportion of the total population at the global and regional levels is then calculated by expressing these numbers as a share of the relevant population, equivalent to taking a population-weighted average of the relevant country rates. For more information, pleas consult the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/data/gho/indicator-metadata-registry/imr-details/4844&quot;&gt;WHO Global Health Observatory metadata registry (https://www.who.int/data/gho/indicator-metadata-registry/imr-details/4844).&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aggregate proportion of the population with large household expenditure on health as a share of total household expenditure or income for a region corresponds to the total number of people across all the countries in that region with such large expenditures divided by the total number of people in that region. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A nivel de país no se intenta la imputación para producir estimaciones. La proporción de la población con un gran gasto del hogar en salud como proporción del gasto o los ingresos totales del hogar se estima para todos los años para los que se dispone de una encuesta nacional representativa sobre el presupuesto del hogar, los ingresos y gastos del hogar, las condiciones socio-económicas o el nivel de vida con información tanto sobre el gasto o los ingresos totales del hogar como sobre el gasto total del hogar en salud. Cuando existen múltiples encuestas a lo largo del tiempo para un mismo país, se da preferencia a las estimaciones elaboradas a partir de la misma encuesta. Se realiza una serie de pruebas para retener las series con mejores resultados (véase el Proceso de recolección).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Au niveau national :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Au niveau national, aucune imputation n’est tentée pour produire des estimations. La proportion de la population dont le ménage consacre une part importante de ses dépenses totales ou de son revenu total aux dépenses de santé est estimée pour toutes les années pour lesquelles une enquête représentative à l’échelle nationale sur le budget des ménages, le revenu et les dépenses des ménages, les conditions socioéconomiques ou le niveau de vie est disponible avec des informations sur les dépenses ou les revenus totaux des ménages et sur les dépenses totales des ménages en matière de santé. Lorsqu’il y a plusieurs enquêtes au fil du temps pour le même pays, une préférence est donnée aux estimations produites sur la base de la même enquête. Une série de tests est effectuée pour conserver la série la plus performante (consulter la section 4.k). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aux niveaux régional et mondial :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Étant donné que les enquêtes ne sont pas menées chaque année dans la plupart des pays, les estimations de l’indicateur 3.8.2 dans tous les pays sont calculées pour différentes années. Pour calculer les agrégats régionaux et mondiaux pour une année de référence commune (p. ex. 2000, 2005, 2010, 2015, etc.), les estimations par pays fondées sur l’enquête sont d’abord « alignées » à l’aide d’une combinaison d’interpolation et d’extrapolation (lorsqu’au moins deux estimations fondées sur l’enquête sont disponibles autour de l’année de référence); d&apos;une modélisation économétrique (une estimation fondée sur une enquête disponible autour de l’année de référence); et d’une imputation fondée sur les médianes régionales (aucune estimation fondée sur l’enquête n’est disponible autour de l’année de référence). Pour plus d’informations, consulter Wagstaff et collab., 2018 et le chapitre 2 du Rapport mondial de suivi 2017 : la couverture-santé universelle de l&apos;OMS et la Banque internationale pour la reconstruction et le développement/ La Banque mondiale. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La proportion agrégée de la population dont le ménage consacre une part importante de ses dépenses totales ou de son revenu total aux dépenses de santé pour une région correspond au nombre total de personnes dans tous les pays de cette région où les dépenses sont importantes, divisé par le nombre total de personnes dans cette région. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt;Обработка отсутствующих значений:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;На страновом уровне не делается никаких попыток произвести оценку. Доля населения с большим удельным весом семейных расходов на здравоохранение в общем объеме расходов или доходов домохозяйств оценивается за все годы, для которых имеются данные репрезентативного на национальном уровне обследования бюджета, доходов и расходов домохозяйств, социально-экономических условий или уровня жизни с информацией, отражающей как общие расходы или доходы домохозяйства, так и общие расходы домохозяйства на здравоохранение. Если для одной и той же страны с течением времени осуществляются комплексные обследования, предпочтение отдается оценкам, составленным на основе аналогичного обследования. Для сохранения наиболее представительных временных рядов проводится серия тестов (см. Процесс сбора).
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
