<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 4-5-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parity indices require data for the specific groups of interest. They represent the ratio of the indicator value for one group to that of the other. Typically, the likely more disadvantaged group is placed in the numerator. A value of exactly 1 indicates parity between the two groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See metadata for relevant underlying indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt; Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Definición:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Los índices de paridad requieren datos para los grupos específicos de interés. Representan la relación entre el valor del indicador de un grupo y el del otro. Normalmente, el grupo probablemente más desfavorecido se coloca en el numerador. Un valor de exactamente 1 indica la paridad entre los dos grupos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Conceptos:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Consulte los metadatos del indicador subyacente relevante. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les indices de parité nécessitent des données pour les groupes d&apos;intérêt spécifiques. Ils représentent le rapport entre la valeur de l&apos;indicateur pour un groupe et celle de l&apos;autre. Généralement, le groupe le plus défavorisé est placé dans le numérateur. Une valeur de 1 exactement indique la parité entre les deux groupes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voir les métadonnées pour l&apos;indicateur sous-jacent pertinent. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Определение: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Для расчета индексов равенства требуются данные конкретных исследуемых групп. Индексы равенства представляют собой отношение величины показателя одной группы к величине показателя другой группы. Обычно в числитель помещается наиболее обездоленная группа. Значение индекса, ровное 1, указывает на равенство между двумя группами. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Понятия: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; См. метаданные для соответствующего базового показателя. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
