<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 5-5-1b, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;h2&gt;Comments and limitations:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator 5.5.1(b) refers to the representation of women among elected positions of legislative/deliberative bodies of local government. This is a strength, because it ensures comparability across countries, at low cost, and mirrors the SDG indicator measuring women&amp;#x2019;s representation at national level, in parliament. This is also a limitation in that the indicator does not consider other positions in local government. Local government officials holding executive positions who are not simultaneously holding a position within the legislative/deliberative body, or who are appointed and not elected, are not considered in this indicator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is recommended that women&amp;#x2019;s representation in executive positions, particularly at the level of the head of the executive (such as mayor), is monitored separately at national and global levels, but not as a headline SDG indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importantly, the indicator refers to representation among members of local government and not the quality of their participation. Countries may therefore consider assessing political participation through national or subnational studies involving qualitative and/or quantitative methods of research. Additional indicators of political participation may also be monitored at national level, such as women&amp;#x2019;s share among voters and candidates in local elections, to monitor the closing of other gaps on women&amp;#x2019;s political participation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, aspects of local governance beyond the formal institutions of local government, such as public administration staff, are not included in the indicator 5.5.1(b), and may be covered by other indicators in the SDG framework, particularly within the Goal 16 on inclusive societies.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
