<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 16-a-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Rationale:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator measures the global continual efforts of countries in setting up independent national institutions, through international cooperation, to promote inclusive, peaceful and accountable societies. The creation and fosterage of a NHRI indicates a State&amp;#x2019;s commitment to promote and protect the human rights provided in international human rights instruments. Compliance with the Paris Principles vest NHRIs with a broad mandate, competence and power to investigate, report on the national human rights situation, and publicize human rights through information and education. While NHRIs are essentially state funded, they are to maintain independence and pluralism. When vested with a quasi-judicial competence, NHRIs handle complaints and assist victims in taking their cases to courts making them an essential component in the national human rights protection system. These fundamental functions that NHRIs play and their increasing participation in the international human rights fora make them important actors in the improvement of the human rights situation, including the elimination of discriminatory laws and the promotion and enforcement of non-discriminatory laws. At the national level reporting, the better the accreditation classification of the NHRI reflects that it is credible, legitimate, relevant and effective in promoting human rights at the national level.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Este indicador mide los esfuerzos continuos globales de los países en la creación de instituciones nacionales independientes, a través de la cooperación internacional, para promover sociedades inclusivas, pacíficas y responsables. La creación y fomento de una INDH indica el compromiso de un Estado con la promoción y protección de los derechos humanos previstos en los instrumentos internacionales de derechos humanos. El cumplimiento de los Principios de París confiere a las INDH un amplio mandato, competencia y poder para investigar, informar sobre la situación nacional de los derechos humanos y dar a conocer los derechos humanos a través de la información y la educación. Aunque las INDH están financiadas esencialmente por el Estado, deben mantener la independencia y el pluralismo. Al estar dotadas de una competencia cuasi judicial, las INDH tramitan las denuncias y ayudan a las víctimas a llevar sus casos a los tribunales, lo que las convierte en un componente esencial del sistema nacional de protección de los derechos humanos. Estas funciones fundamentales que desempeñan las INDH y su creciente participación en los foros internacionales de derechos humanos las convierten en actores importantes en la mejora de la situación de los derechos humanos, incluyendo la eliminación de leyes discriminatorias y la promoción y aplicación de leyes no discriminatorias. En la presentación de informes a nivel nacional, la mejor clasificación de acreditación de la INDH refleja que es creíble, legítima, pertinente y eficaz en la promoción de los derechos humanos a nivel nacional.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Этот показатель отражает глобальные постоянные усилия стран по созданию независимых национальных институтов посредством международного сотрудничества для развития инклюзивных, мирных и ответственных сообществ. Создание и развитие национального правозащитного учреждения свидетельствует о приверженности государства делу поощрения и защиты прав человека, закрепленных в международных документах по правам человека. Соблюдение Парижских принципов наделяет НПЗУ широким кругом обязанностей, полномочиями и компетенцией проводить расследования, сообщать о ситуации с правами человека в стране и пропагандировать права человека с помощью информации и учебных материалов. Хотя НПЗУ в основном финансируются государством, они должны придерживаться принципов независимости и плюрализма. Обладая квазисудебной компетенцией, национальные правозащитные учреждения рассматривают жалобы и помогают жертвам обращаться с заявлениями в суд, что делает их важным компонентом национальной системы защиты прав человека. Эти фундаментальные функции, которые исполняют национальные правозащитные учреждения, и их растущее участие в международных форумах по правам человека, делают их важными участниками процесса улучшения положения в области прав человека, включая отмену дискриминационных законов и продвижение и обеспечение соблюдения недискриминационных законов. Что касается отчетности на национальном уровне, то более высокая классификация аккредитации национального правозащитного учреждения отражает его надежность, законность, актуальность и эффективность в продвижении прав человека на национальном уровне. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
