<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 9-c-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportion of population covered by a mobile network, broken down by technology, refers to the percentage of inhabitants living within range of a mobile-cellular signal, irrespective of whether or not they are mobile phone subscribers or users. This is calculated by dividing the number of inhabitants within range of a mobile-cellular signal by the total population and multiplying by 100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is based on where the population lives, and not where they work or go to school, etc. When there are multiple operators offering the service, the maximum population number covered should be reported. Coverage should refer to LTE, broadband (3G) and narrowband (2G) mobile-cellular technologies and include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2G mobile population coverage&lt;/strong&gt;: Mobile networks with access to data communications (e.g. Internet) at downstream speeds below 256 Kbit/s. This includes mobile-cellular technologies such as GPRS, CDMA2000 1x and most EDGE implementations. The indicator refers to the theoretical ability of subscribers to use non-broadband speed mobile data services, rather than the number of active users of such services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3G population coverage&lt;/strong&gt;: refers to the percentage of inhabitants that are within range of at least a 3G mobile-cellular signal, irrespective of whether or not they are subscribers. This is calculated by dividing the number of inhabitants that are covered by at least a 3G mobile-cellular signal by the total population and multiplying by 100. It excludes people covered only by GPRS, EDGE or CDMA 1xRTT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LTE population coverage&lt;/strong&gt;: Refers to the percentage of inhabitants that live within range of LTE/LTE-Advanced, mobile WiMAX/WirelessMAN or other more advanced mobile-cellular networks, irrespective of whether or not they are subscribers. This is calculated by dividing the number of inhabitants that are covered by the previously mentioned mobile-cellular technologies by the total population and multiplying by 100. It excludes people covered only by HSPA, UMTS, EV-DO and previous 3G technologies, and also excludes fixed WiMAX coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As technologies evolve and as more and more countries will deploy and commercialize more advanced mobile-broadband networks (5G etc.), the indicator will include further breakdowns.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
