<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 12-1-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Mainstreaming sustainable consumption and production in decision-making at all levels is a core function of the 10-Year Framework, which is expected to &lt;em&gt;&amp;#x201C;support the integration of sustainable consumption and production into sustainable development policies, programmes and strategies, as appropriate, including, where applicable, into poverty reduction strategies&amp;#x201D; (Rio+20 Outcome Document &amp;#x2013; A/CONF.216/5)&lt;/em&gt;. The purpose of this indicator is to help assess the volume and geographical repartition of governments progressing on sustainable consumption and production. In addition, further information is being collected on the types, focus and orientation of the policy instruments that are being developed and used, to monitor their progression over time as well as their contribution to other Sustainable Development Goals. This should support evaluation of how much / how fast governments progress in the development and application of policies addressing sustainable consumption and production, whether at cross-cutting or sectoral level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is also considering both binding (laws and regulations) and non-binding policy instruments. The first category is essential to the shift, as binding instruments provide the legal ground for sustainable consumption and production, and can be used for enforcement or to provide incentives. The ability to develop, pass and implement legislation is an indication of jurisdictions&amp;#x2019; engagement in the shift towards sustainable consumption and production. This indicator can also help monitor the evolution of the global legislative landscape. The second category is also essential to ensure institutional engagement, commitment and ownership. In some cases, non-binding policy instruments can lead to the creation of new legal ones. The development and implementation of non-binding instruments across sectors also provides information on engagement of partners and other stakeholders in sustainable consumption and production.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
