<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 14-1-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator 14.1.1 includes two sub-indicators:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;14.1.1a Index of coastal eutrophication (ICEP), and &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;14.1.1b Plastic debris density. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator 14.1.1a &amp;#x201C;Index of coastal eutrophication&amp;#x201D; (ICEP) is based on loads and ratios of nitrogen, phosphorous and silica delivered by rivers to coastal waters (Garnier et al. 2010) which contribute to the ICEP. This indicator assumes that excess nitrogen or phosphorus relative to silica will result in increased growth of potentially harmful algae (ICEP&amp;gt;0).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator 14.1.1b &amp;#x201C;Plastic debris density&amp;quot; includes potential measurement of plastics washed onto beaches or shorelines, floating on the water or in the water column, deposited on the seafloor/seabed, as well as ingested by biota; however, it is also important to note the importance of monitoring information on waste management and the sources of plastic pollution for understanding plastic pollution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across the 14.1.1a and 14.1.1b, two mandatory levels are proposed: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Level 1: Global Data Products (globally available data from earth observations and modelling), &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Level 2: National Data, which are collected from countries (through the relevant Regional Seas Programme for countries that are member of a Regional Seas Programme, or directly by UNEP).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tables 1 and 2 demonstrate the proposed parameters for sub-indicators 14.1.1a and 14.1.1b.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Table 1: Monitoring parameters for eutrophication to track progress against SDG Indicator 14.1.1a.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Monitoring parameters&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Level 1&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Level 2&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indicator for Coastal Eutrophication Potential (N and P loading)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;X&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Chlorophyll-a deviations (remote sensing)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;X&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Chlorophyll-a concentration (&lt;em&gt;remote sensing and in situ&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;X&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;National modelling of indicator for Coastal Eutrophication Potential (ICEP) &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;X&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Total Nitrogen &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;X&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Total Phosphorus &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;X&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Total Silica &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;X&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Table 2: Monitoring parameters for marine plastic litter to track progress against SDG Indicator 14.1.1b.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Monitoring parameters (and methods)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Level 1&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Level 2&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Plastic patches greater than 10 meters*&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;X&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Beach litter originating from national land-based sources&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;X&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Beach litter (beach surveys)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;X&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Floating plastics (visual observation, manta trawls)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;X&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Water column plastics (demersal trawls)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;X&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Seafloor litter (benthic trawls (e.g. fish survey trawls), divers, video/camera tows, submersibles, remotely operated vehicles)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;X&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the largest pressures on &lt;strong&gt;coastal environments is eutrophication&lt;/strong&gt;, resulting primarily from land-based nutrient input from agricultural runoff and domestic wastewater discharge. Coastal eutrophication can lead to serious damage to marine ecosystems, vital sea habitats, and can cause the spread of harmful algal blooms. SDG Indicator 14.1.1a aims to measure the contribution to coastal eutrophication from countries and the state of coastal eutrophication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eutrophication is an excess nutrient loading into coastal environments from anthropogenic sources, resulting in excessive growth of plants, algae and phytoplankton. The basis for these loads is collected from land-based assessments of land use including fertilizer use, population density, socioeconomic factors and other contributors to nutrient pollution runoff. Given the land-based nature of the indicator, it provides a modelled number indicating the risk of coastal eutrophication at a specific river mouth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more important characteristic is Chlorophyll-a deviation. Chlorophyll-a concentrations for this indicator are obtained from the global ocean, 4 km spatial resolution per pixel monthly mean product of the OC-CCI project product for each pixel within the country&amp;#x2019;s territorial sea and exclusive economic zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Territorial sea is a belt of coastal waters extending at most 12 nautical miles from the baseline of a coastal state, as outlined by the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Exclusive Economic Zone (EEZ) is an area beyond and adjacent to the territorial sea. The EEZ shall not extend beyond 200 nautical miles from the baselines from which the breadth of the territorial sea is measured, as outlined by the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the existing internationally agreed &lt;a href=&quot;https://wedocs.unep.org/handle/20.500.11822/30009&quot;&gt;Group of Experts on the Scientific Aspects of Marine Environmental Protection (GESAMP) guidelines&lt;/a&gt; and the existing national data collections, it is recommended that the SDG reporting includes sub-indicators related to beach litter, floating plastic and plastic in the sea column, plastic on the sea floor and additional option indicators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plastic litter is most obvious on shorelines, where litter accumulates due to current, wave and wind action, river outflows and by direct littering at the coast. However, plastic litter occurs on the ocean surface, suspended in the water column, on the seabed and in association with biota, due to entanglement or ingestion (GESAMP, 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marine litter - any persistent, manufactured or processed solid material which is lost or discarded and ends up in the marine and coastal environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full methodology for this indicator is available in the document entitled &amp;#x201C;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wedocs.unep.org/handle/20.500.11822/35086&quot;&gt;Understanding the State of the Ocean: A Global Manual on Measuring SDG 14.1.1, SDG 14.2.1 and SDG 14.5.1&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#x201D; (UNEP, 2021). &lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
