<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 9-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computation method:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions from fuel combustion are estimated based on energy consumption and on the IPCC Guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The total intensity of the economy is defined as the ratio of total CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions from fuel combustion and GDP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sectoral intensity is defined as CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emission from manufacturing (in physical measurement unit such as tonnes) divided by manufacturing value added (MVA) in constant 2015 USD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CO2 emission per unit of value added &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;= CO2 emission from manufacturing (in kg)/MVA (constant USD)&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Méthodologie &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Méthode de calcul :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les émissions de CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; provenant de la combustion de combustibles sont estimées sur la base de la consommation d&apos;énergie et des lignes directrices du GIEC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;intensité totale de l&apos;économie est définie comme le rapport entre les émissions totales de CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; provenant de la combustion de combustibles et le PIB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;intensité sectorielle est définie comme l&apos;émission de CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; provenant de l&apos;industrie manufacturière (en unité de mesure physique telle que les tonnes) divisée par la valeur ajoutée manufacturière (VAM) en dollars constants de 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Émissions de CO2 par unité de valeur ajoutée&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;= émission de CO2 provenant de l&apos;industrie manufacturière (en kg)/VAM (USD constant)&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
