<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The QUALITY_ASSURE field for indicator 9-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The IEA has extensive data quality checks on the energy data submissions (around 30 statisticians working on it), and iterates with countries on data issues and how to address them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IEA also works in cooperation with the IPCC and the UNFCCC to ensure the highest consistency between international methodologies and those adopted at the IEA; the IEA validates energy data submitted to the UNFCCC by countries within their inventories. The IEA convenes international workshops among partner Agencies working on energy data to ensure that consistency between energy data at global level is enhanced continuously, and methodologies are harmonised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/unsystem/Documents/QAF-UNIDO.pdf&quot;&gt;The UNIDO Quality Assurance Framework&lt;/a&gt; is followed to ensure that the statistical activities of UNIDO are relevant and the data compiled and disseminated are accurate, complete within the defined scope and coverage, timely, comparable in terms of internationally recommended methods and classification standards and internally coherent to variables included in the datasets. While these generally accepted, broad dimensions of quality of statistical data may be defined in each NSO&amp;apos;s own quality assurance framework. UNIDO makes maximum effort that data produced from the statistical operation undertaken with the UNIDO technical cooperation are accurate, internationally comparable and coherent.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Aseguramiento de calidad:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La AIE realiza amplios controles de calidad de los datos energéticos presentados (alrededor de 30 estadísticos trabajan en ello), e itera con los países sobre los problemas con los datos y la forma de abordarlos. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iea.org/statistics/resources/questionnaires/annual/&quot;&gt;http://www.iea.org/statistics/resources/questionnaires/annual/&lt;/a&gt;. La AIE también trabaja en cooperación con el IPCC y la CMNUCC para garantizar la máxima coherencia entre las metodologías internacionales y las adoptadas en la AIE. La AIE valida los datos energéticos presentados a la CMNUCC por los países dentro de sus inventarios. La AIE convoca talleres internacionales entre las Agencias asociadas que trabajan con datos energéticos para garantizar que la coherencia entre los datos energéticos a nivel mundial se mejore continuamente, y que las metodologías se armonicen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La AIE cuenta con un amplio proceso de aseguramiento de la calidad de los datos y de validación mediante el intercambio con los proveedores de datos nacionales de todo el mundo. También convoca una reunión de su Grupo de Desarrollo de Estadísticas Energéticas para debatir con sus miembros la evolución de las estadísticas energéticas, y coopera con socios de todo el mundo para asegurar la coherencia de los datos y los métodos.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Assurance qualité : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;AIE procède à des contrôles approfondis de la qualité des données sur les soumissions de données sur l&apos;énergie (environ 30 statisticiens y travaillent), et itère avec les pays sur les problèmes de données et la manière de les résoudre. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iea.org/statistics/resources/questionnaires/annual/&quot;&gt;http://www.iea.org/statistics/resources/questionnaires/annual/ &lt;/a&gt;. L&apos;AIE travaille également en coopération avec le GIEC et la CCNUCC pour assurer la plus grande cohérence entre les méthodologies internationales et les méthodologies adoptées à l&apos;AIE ; l&apos;AIE valide les données énergétiques soumises à la CCNUCC par les pays dans le cadre de leurs inventaires. L&apos;AIE organise des ateliers internationaux entre les agences partenaires qui travaillent sur les données énergétiques afin de garantir que la cohérence entre les données énergétiques au niveau mondial est continuellement améliorée et que les méthodologies sont harmonisées.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;AIE dispose d&apos;un processus étendu d&apos;assurance qualité et de validation des données par le biais d&apos;échanges avec les fournisseurs de données nationaux du monde entier. Elle convoque également la réunion de son groupe de développement des statistiques de l&apos;énergie pour discuter des développements des statistiques de l&apos;énergie avec ses membres, et coopère avec des partenaires du monde entier pour assurer la cohérence des données et des méthodes.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Обеспечение качества: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; МЭА проводит обширную проверку качества данных в представленных данных по энергетике (над ними работают около 30 статистиков) и обращается к странам по вопросам данных и способам их решения. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iea.org/statistics/resources/questionnaires/annual/&quot;&gt; http://www.iea.org/statistics/resources/questionnaires/annual/ &lt;/a&gt;. МЭА также работает в сотрудничестве с МГЭИК и РКИК ООН для обеспечения максимальной согласованности между международными методологиями и методологиями, принятыми в МЭА; МЭА проводит валидацию данных по энергетике, представленные в РКИК ООН странами в их кадастрах. МЭА созывает международные семинары среди партнерских агентств, работающих с данными по энергетике, чтобы обеспечить постоянное повышение согласованности между данными по энергетике на глобальном уровне и гармонизацию методологий. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; МЭА организует обширный процесс обеспечения качества и валидации данных посредством информационного обмена с национальными поставщиками данных по всему миру. МЭА также созывает совещания Группы по развитию статистики энергетики для обсуждения вопросов развития статистики энергетики со своими членами и сотрудничает с партнерами во всем мире для обеспечения согласованности данных и методов. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
