<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 9-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data on total CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions from fuel combustion, also disaggregated by sector, are taken from the International Energy Agency (IEA) database (IEA CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Emissions from Fuel Combustion: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iea.org/reports/co2-emissions-from-fuel-combustion-2019&quot;&gt;https://www.iea.org/reports/co2-emissions-from-fuel-combustion-2019&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IEA produces the indicator on total CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions/GDP, based on secondary sources for GDP (OECD National Accounts and World Bank Development indicators).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNIDO maintains MVA database. Figures for updates are obtained from national account estimates produced by UN Statistics Division (UNSD).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Sources de données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sur les émissions totales de CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; dues à la combustion de combustibles, également ventilées par secteur, proviennent de la base de données de l&apos;Agence internationale de l&apos;énergie (AIE) (IEA CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Emissions from Fuel Combustion : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iea.org/reports/co2-emissions-from-fuel-combustion-2019&quot;&gt;https://www.iea.org/reports/co2-emissions-from-fuel-combustion-2019&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;AIE produit l&apos;indicateur sur les émissions totales de CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; / PIB, basé sur des sources secondaires pour le PIB (comptes nationaux de l&apos;OCDE et indicateurs de développement de la Banque mondiale).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;ONUDI tient à jour la base de données MVA. Les chiffres pour les mises à jour sont obtenus à partir des estimations des comptes nationaux produites par la Division des statistiques de l&apos;ONU (UNSD).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные по общим выбросам CO &lt;sub&gt; 2 &lt;/sub&gt; от сжигания топлива, также с разбивкой по секторам, взяты из базы данных Международного энергетического агентства (МЭА) (МЭА Выбросы CO &lt;sub&gt; 2 &lt;/sub&gt; от сжигания топлива: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iea.org/reports/co2-emissions-from-fuel-combustion-2019&quot;&gt; https://www.iea.org/reports/co2-emissions-from-fuel-combustion-2019 &lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; МЭА составляет показатель общих выбросов CO &lt;sub&gt; 2 &lt;/sub&gt; / ВВП на основе вторичных источников ВВП (национальные счета ОЭСР и показатели развития Всемирного банка). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ЮНИДО ведет базу данных ДСОП. Обновленные данные получаются с использованием оценок национальных счетов, подготовленных Статистическим отделом ООН (СОООН). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
