<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 16-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data collection has not yet started. It is expected that the number of countries for which this indicator is available will gradually start increasing over time. According to inventories, over 60 per cent of countries globally already collect some data that can be used in the estimation of IFFs. However, notably efforts are planned to support countries in building their capacity to measure Indicator 16.4.1. Currently, pioneering countries are pilot testing the indicator compilation. Estimates will also be prepared in countries participating in UNCTAD and UNODC capacity building projects, carried out currently jointly with ESCAP and ECA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Availability of time series would be useful for the analysis of development over time. Feasibility of constructing historical time series data will be reviewed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to Eurostat&amp;#x2019;s recommendations on measuring illegal economic activities, a disaggregated measurement approach is proposed. As a minimum, disaggregation of the index by relevant types of IFFs, should be published separately for the main elements, depending on data availability: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; IFFs from illicit tax and commercial practices, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; IFFs from corruption, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; IFFs from exploitation-type and financing of crime and terrorism, and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; IFFs from illegal markets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, member states may decide to disaggregate the IFF indicator, where relevant, by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; payment method (cash / trade flows / crypto currencies)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; resulting assets (offshore wealth / real estate etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; actors (characters of individuals / types of businesses etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; industries, commodities or service categories.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
