<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 2-5-1b, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conservation of plant and animal genetic resources for food and agriculture (GRFA) in medium or long term conservation facilities (&lt;em&gt;ex situ&lt;/em&gt;, in genebanks) represents the most trusted means of conserving genetic resources worldwide. Plant and animal GRFA conserved in these facilities can be easily used in breeding programmes as well, even directly on-farm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The measure of trends in &lt;em&gt;ex situ&lt;/em&gt; conserved materials provides an overall assessment of the extent to which we are managing to maintain and/or increase the total genetic diversity available for future use and thus protected from any permanent loss of genetic diversity which may occur in the natural habitat, i.e. &lt;em&gt;in situ&lt;/em&gt;, or on-farm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two components of the indicator 2.5.1, plant (a) and animal (b) GRFA, are separately counted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Animal genetic resources&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The animal component is calculated as the number of local breeds (i.e. being reported to exist only in one country) stored within a genebank collection with an amount of genetic material stored which is required to reconstitute the breed in case of extinction (further information on &amp;#x201C;sufficient material stored to reconstitute a breed&amp;#x201D; can be found in the Guidelines on Cryconservation of Animal Genetic Resources, FAO, 2012, accessible at http://www.fao.org/docrep/016/i3017e/i3017e00.htm). The guidelines have been endorsed by the FAO Commission on Genetic Resources for Food and Agriculture at its Thirteenth Regular Session (http://www.fao.org/docrep/meeting/024/mc192e.pdf).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Animal genetic resources&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breed: A breed is either a sub-specific group of domestic livestock with definable and identifiable external characteristics that enable it to be separated by visual appraisal from other similarly defined groups within the same species, or a group for which geographical and/or cultural separation from phenotypically similar groups has led to acceptance of its separate identity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medium or long term conservation facilities: Biological diversity is often conserved &lt;em&gt;ex situ&lt;/em&gt;, outside its natural habitat, in facilities called genebanks. In the case of domestic animal diversity, &lt;em&gt;ex situ&lt;/em&gt; conservation includes both the maintenance of live animals (&lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;) and cryoconservation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cryoconservation is the collection and deep-freezing of semen, ova, embryos or tissues for potential future use in breeding or regenerating animals.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
