<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 3-2-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Data availability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator is available for all countries from 1990 (or earlier) to 2018, depending on availability of empirical data for each country before 1990.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The common disaggregation for mortality indicators includes disaggregation by sex, age (neonatal, infant, child), wealth quintile, residence, and mother&amp;#x2019;s education. Disaggregated data are not always available. Disaggregation by geographic location is usually at the regional level, or the minimum provincial level for survey or census data. Data from well-functioning vital registration systems can provide further geographical breakdowns.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador está disponible para todos los países desde 1990 (o antes) hasta 2018, dependiendo de la disponibilidad de datos empíricos para cada país antes de 1990.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La desagregación común para los indicadores de mortalidad incluye la desagregación por sexo, edad (neonatal, infantil, niño), quintil de riqueza, residencia y educación de la madre. Los datos desagregados no siempre están disponibles. El desglose por ubicación geográfica suele hacerse a nivel regional o, como mínimo, a nivel provincial en el caso de los datos de encuestas o censos. Los datos de los sistemas de registro civil que funcionan bien pueden proporcionar más desgloses geográficos.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilité des données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’indicateur est disponible pour tous les pays de 1990 (ou avant) à 2018, selon la disponibilité des données empiriques pour chaque pays avant 1990. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Désagrégation :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La désagrégation commune des indicateurs de mortalité comprend une ventilation par sexe, âge (néonatal, nourrisson, enfant), quintile de richesse, résidence et éducation de la mère. Les données ventilées ne sont pas toujours disponibles. La désagrégation par emplacement géographique se fait habituellement au niveau régional, ou au minimum au niveau provincial pour les données d’enquête ou de recensement. Les données provenant de systèmes de l&apos;état civil qui fonctionnent bien peuvent fournir d’autres ventilations géographiques. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные по показателю имеются для всех стран в период с 1990 (или ранее) по 2018 год, в зависимости от наличия эмпирических данных по каждой стране до 1990 года.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Дезагрегирование:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Общее дезагрегирование показателей смертности включает дезагрегирование по полу, возрасту (новорожденный, младенец, ребенок), квинтилю благосостояния, месту жительства и образованию матери. Дезагрегированные данные не всегда доступны. Дезагрегирование по географическому местонахождению обычно осуществляется на региональном или минимальном муниципальном уровне для данных обследования или переписи населения. Данные из хорошо функционирующих систем регистрации актов гражданского состояния могут обеспечить получение дальнейших географических разрезностей.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
