<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 3-2-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At country level &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations Inter-agency Group for Child Mortality Estimation (UN IGME) estimates are based on underlying empirical data. If the empirical data refer to an earlier reference period than the end year of the period the estimates are reported, the UN IGME extrapolates the estimates to the common end year. The UN IGME does not use any covariates to derive the estimates (except in the case of neonatal mortality estimation, which incorporates the relatively more data-rich under-five mortality rate estimates in the modelling). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At regional and global levels &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To construct aggregate estimates of neonatal mortality before 1990, regional averages of mortality rates were used for country-years with missing information and weighted by the respective population in the country-year. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel de país:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las estimaciones del IGME de la ONU se basan en datos empíricos subyacentes. Si los datos empíricos se refieren a un periodo de referencia anterior al año final del periodo del que se informan las estimaciones, la UN-IGME extrapola las estimaciones al año final común. El UN-IGME no utiliza ninguna covariable para derivar las estimaciones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel regional y mundial:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para construir estimaciones agregadas de la mortalidad neonatal antes de 1990, se utilizaron los promedios regionales de las tasas de mortalidad para los países-año con información faltante y se ponderaron por la población respectiva en el país-año.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Au niveau national :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les estimations de l&apos;IGME sont basées sur des données empiriques sous-jacentes. Si les données empiriques se réfèrent à une période de référence antérieure à celle pour laquelle les estimations doivent être produites, l&apos;IGME extrapolera les estimations. L&apos;IGME n&apos;utilise aucune covariable pour calculer les estimations (sauf dans le cas de l’estimation de la mortalité néonatale, qui intègre les estimations relativement plus riches en données du taux de mortalité des moins de cinq ans dans la modélisation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aux niveaux régional et mondial :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour construire des estimations globales de la mortalité néonatale avant 1990, des moyennes régionales des taux de mortalité ont été utilisées pour les années-pays pour lesquelles des informations manquaient, et ont été pondérées par la population respective de l&apos;année-pays.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Оценки UN IGME основаны на исходных эмпирических данных. Если эмпирические данные относятся к более раннему отчетному периоду, чем год окончания периода, за который представлены оценки, Межучрежденческая группа ООН по оценке детской смертности экстраполирует оценки на конец общего года. UN IGME не использует никакие ковариаты для получения оценок. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для построения совокупных оценок неонатальной смертности до 1990 года использовались средние региональные коэффициенты смертности для стран-лет с отсутствующей информацией и взвешенные на соответствующее население в стране-годе. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
