<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 3-8-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;WHO and the World Bank contact Ministries of Health and/or National statistical offices for two purposes: a) request access to the household survey microdata in order to produce SDG indicator 3.8.2; b) request estimates produced by the country itself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A) The first type of request is done by each organization separately. WHO obtains access to the household survey microdata from national statistical offices through its regional offices or country offices. Access request is often part of technical assistance programs on health financing issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The World Bank also typically receives data from National Statistical Offices (NSOs) directly. In other cases, it uses NSO data received indirectly. For example, it receives data from Eurostat and from LIS (Luxembourg Income Study), who provide the World Bank NSO data in its original form or harmonized for comparability. The Universidad Nacional de La Plata, Argentina and the World Bank jointly maintain the SEDLAC (Socio-Economic Database for Latin American and Caribbean) database that includes harmonized statistics on poverty and other distributional and social variables from 24 Latin American and Caribbean countries, based on microdata from household surveys conducted by NSOs. Data is obtained through country specific programs, including technical assistance programs and joint analytical and capacity building activities. The World Bank has relationships with NSOs on work programs involving statistical systems and data analysis. Poverty economists from the World Bank typically engage with NSOs broadly on poverty measurement and analysis as part of technical assistance activities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The World Health Organization and the World Bank regularly undertake training events on the measurement of lack of financial protection coverage to produce SDG 3.8.2 indicator. This type of activity involves participants from the Ministry of Health as well as from the National Statistical Office. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the country-year estimates produced by both organizations are assembled in a joint database following a quality assessment process (see section 4.j). Such estimates are included in a country consultation conducted to give an opportunity to i) review the estimates, the data sources and the methods used for computation; ii) provide information about additional data sources; iii) build mutual understanding of the strengths and weaknesses of available data and ensure broad ownership of the results; and iv) request estimates produced by the country as further explained hereafter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B) Estimates produced by each country are requested through a country consultation conducted by the World Health Organization. Following the WHO Executive Board resolution (EB107.R8), this process starts with WHO sending a formal request to ministries of health to nominate a focal point for the consultation. WHO sends draft estimates and methodological descriptions to them, copying countries&amp;#x2019; focal point for SDG reporting where nominated at the request of UNSD. STATA codes are available to reproduce the estimates shared. The focal points then send to WHO their comments, often including new data or revised country estimates that are used to update the country estimates. Estimates produced by the countries are subject to the same quality assessment process and included in the joint database if they are not flagged in consumption or in the health budget share (see section 4.j).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
