<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 3-2-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Mortality rates among young children are a key output indicator for child health and well-being, and, more broadly, for social and economic development. It is a closely watched public health indicator because it reflects the access of children and communities to basic health interventions such as vaccination, medical treatment of infectious diseases and adequate nutrition. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las tasas de mortalidad entre los niños pequeños son un indicador clave de los resultados de la salud y el bienestar infantil y, en general, del desarrollo social y económico. Es un indicador de salud pública muy vigilado porque refleja el acceso de los niños y las comunidades a intervenciones sanitarias básicas como la vacunación, el tratamiento médico de las enfermedades infecciosas y una nutrición adecuada.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Justification :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le taux de mortalité des jeunes enfants est un indicateur clé de la santé et du bien-être des enfants et, plus largement, du développement social et économique. Il s&apos;agit d&apos;un indicateur de santé publique étroitement surveillé, car il reflète l&apos;accès des enfants et des communautés aux interventions sanitaires de base telles que la vaccination, le traitement médical des maladies infectieuses et une nutrition adéquate.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt;Обоснование:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Коэффициенты смертности среди детей младшего возраста являются ключевым показателем здоровья и благополучия детей и, в более широком смысле, социально-экономического развития. Этот показатель здравоохранения очень внимательно отслеживается, поскольку он отражает доступ детей и сообщества к основным медико-санитарным мероприятиям, таким как вакцинация, лечение инфекционных заболеваний и адекватное питание.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
