<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COMPARABILITY field for indicator 2-1-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the few cases where indicators of food insecurity based on experience-based food security scales have been reported by countries (U.S., Canada, Mexico, Guatemala and Brazil), these have been based on nationally set thresholds that do not correspond to the international thresholds proposed by the FIES. See Annex I and Table A3 in http://www.fao.org/3/i4830e.pdf for a description of the differences. In the future, it is desirable that country would start reporting prevalence estimates using also the internationally set thresholds for moderate or severe and severe levels, in addition to those based on national thresholds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO is ready to provide assistance on the analytic methods needed to estimate prevalence based on the FIES global reference thresholds.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Fuentes de discrepancias:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En los pocos casos en los que los países han notificado indicadores de inseguridad alimentaria basados en escalas de seguridad alimentaria basadas en la experiencia (Estados Unidos, Canadá, México, Guatemala y Brasil), éstos se han basado en umbrales fijados a nivel nacional que no se corresponden con los umbrales internacionales propuestos por la FIES. Véase el anexo I y el cuadro A3 en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/i4830e.pdf%20&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/i4830e.pdf&lt;/a&gt; para una descripción de las diferencias. En el futuro, es deseable que los países empiecen a informar de las estimaciones de prevalencia utilizando también los umbrales establecidos internacionalmente para los niveles moderado o grave y severo, además de los basados en los umbrales nacionales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La FAO está dispuesta a proporcionar asistencia sobre los métodos analíticos necesarios para estimar la prevalencia basándose en los umbrales de referencia mundiales de la FIES.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Sources des divergences : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dans les quelques cas où des indicateurs d&apos;insécurité alimentaire basés sur des échelles de sécurité alimentaire fondées sur l&apos;expérience ont été signalés par les pays (États-Unis, Canada, Mexique, Guatemala et Brésil), ceux-ci ont été basés sur des seuils fixés au niveau national qui ne correspondent pas aux seuils internationaux proposés par la FIES. Voir l&apos;annexe I et le tableau A3 dans https://www.fao.org/3/i4830f/i4830f.pdf pour une description des différences. À l&apos;avenir, il est souhaitable que les pays commencent à déclarer des estimations de la prévalence en utilisant également les seuils internationaux pour les niveaux modérés ou graves et sévères, en plus de ceux basés sur les seuils nationaux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La FAO est prête à fournir une assistance sur les méthodes analytiques nécessaires pour estimer la prévalence sur la base des seuils de référence mondiaux de la FIES.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В тех немногих случаях, когда страны (США, Канада, Мексика, Гватемала и Бразилия) представляли показатели отсутствия продовольственной безопасности, основанные на шкалах продовольственной безопасности на основе восприятия, они основывались на установленных на национальном уровне пороговых значениях, которые не соответствуют международным пороговым значениям, предложенным ШОПБ. См. Приложение I и Таблицу A3 в &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/i4830e.pdf%20&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/i4830e.pdf&lt;/a&gt; для описания различий. В будущем желательно, чтобы страна начала представлять оценки распространенности, используя также установленные на международном уровне пороговые значения для умеренных или острых и острых уровней в дополнение к пороговым значениям, основанным на национальных пороговых значениях. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ФАО готова предоставить помощь по аналитическим методам, необходимым для оценки распространенности на основе глобальных контрольных пороговых значений ШОПБ. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
