<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 2-1-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Définition : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur mesure le pourcentage d&apos;individus dans la population qui ont connu une insécurité alimentaire modérée ou grave au cours de la période de référence. La gravité de l&apos;insécurité alimentaire, définie comme un trait latent, est mesurée sur l&apos;Echelle de l&apos;échelle d&apos;expérience de l&apos;insécurité alimentaire mondiale, une norme de mesure établie par la FAO grâce à l&apos;application de cette mesure dans plus de 140 pays à travers le monde, à partir de 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель отражает процент людей в населении, которые столкнулись с проблемой отсутствия продовольственной безопасности на умеренном или остром уровне в течение отчетного периода. Серьезность отсутствия продовольственной безопасности, определяемая как скрытая особенность, оценивается с помощью Шкалы восприятия отсутствия продовольственной безопасности, стандартной меры, установленной ФАО посредством применения Шкалы восприятия отсутствия продовольственной безопасности в более чем 140 странах мира, начиная с 2014 года.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator measures the percentage of individuals in the population who have experienced food insecurity at moderate or severe levels during the reference period. The severity of food insecurity, defined as a latent trait, is measured on the Food Insecurity Experience Scale global reference scale, a measurement standard established by FAO through the application of the Food Insecurity Experience Scale in more than 140 countries worldwide, starting in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
