<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 11-3-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;Option 1: To measure the level of direct participation structures of civil society in urban planning and management at the city level, a scorecard approach will be used to evaluate the available structures for civil society participation in urban planning and management, as evaluated by five (5) local experts including those from academia, Urban Planning Experts, City Leaders and officials from Local Government Authorities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the monitoring and reporting on SDG 11, UN-Habitat developed an online questionnaire until Kobo toolbox (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ee.humanitarianresponse.info/x/sh3jEDMr&quot;&gt;https://ee.humanitarianresponse.info/x/sh3jEDMr&lt;/a&gt;) that NSOs can administer to stakeholders on public participation in urban planning and management to evaluate public participation in urban planning programs in their cities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To note, the selection of cities in which the evaluation will be conducted may be determined using the National Sample of Cities approach (&lt;a href=&quot;https://unhabitat.org/sites/default/files/2020/06/national_sample_of_cities_english.pdf&quot;&gt;https://unhabitat.org/sites/default/files/2020/06/national_sample_of_cities_english.pdf&lt;/a&gt;). The approach will help draw a sample of cities using sound statistical and scientific methodologies based on several relevant city-specific criteria/characteristics that capture the specific contexts of countries, ensuring that the sample is representative of a given country&amp;#x2019;s territory, geography, size, history, etc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Option 2: To measure the level of direct participation structures of civil society in urban planning and management at the city level and aggregate national level performances, evaluators will first confirm that there is an established legal requirement that civil society must be involved in urban planning and management of cities or municipalities, if its yes, then evaluators will assess whether this is being practiced in al cities and all municipalities in the country, if its yes, national level coverage can be considered as 100%, otherwise if its partial coverage then the true average coverage has to be estimated.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
