<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COMPARABILITY field for indicator 2-2-2a, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the survey estimates included in the JME joint database of primary sources, re-analysis based on standardized methodology using the WHO Child Growth Standards as described in Recommendations for data collection, analysis and reporting on anthropometric indicators in children under 5 years old (&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.unicef.org/resources/data-collection-analysis-reporting-on-anthropometric-indicators-in-children-under-5/&quot;&gt;WHO/UNICEF 2019&lt;/a&gt;) and WHO Anthro Survey Analyser (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/tools/child-growth-standards/software&quot;&gt;WHO, 2019&lt;/a&gt;) is applied whenever microdata are available to enhance comparability across the time series. Country teams are encouraged to use the WHO Anthro Survey Analyser (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/tools/child-growth-standards/software&quot;&gt;WHO, 2019&lt;/a&gt;) to undertake survey analysis and harmonize with the global standard analysis methods. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the inclusion of survey estimates into the JME database, the inter-agency group applies a set of survey quality assessment criteria. When there is insufficient documentation, the survey is not included until information becomes available. Discrepancies between results from standard methodology and those reported may occur for various reasons, for example, the use of different standards for z-score calculations, imputation of the day of birth when missing, the use of rounded age in months, the use of different flagging systems for data exclusion. For surveys based on the previous NCHS/WHO references, and for which raw data are not available, a method for converting the z-scores to be based on the WHO Child Growth Standards is applied (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.biomedcentral.com/1471-2431/8/19&quot;&gt;Yang and de Onis, 2008&lt;/a&gt;). In addition, when surveys do not cover the age interval 0-59 months, or are only representative of the rural areas, an adjustment based on other surveys for the same country, is performed. Any adjustment or conversion is transparently stated in the annotated joint data set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JME country modelled estimates, which are based on smoothing techniques and covariates, as described elsewhere (&lt;a href=&quot;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30430613/&quot;&gt;McLain et al. 2018&lt;/a&gt;), vary from estimates from primary data sources such as household surveys, but in most cases the 95 per cent confidence bounds of the country modelled estimates for a given country in a given year fall within the 95 per cent confidence bounds of the estimate from the primary source for the corresponding country and year(s).&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
