<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 17-1-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Rationale and interpretation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator 17.1.2 Proportion of domestic budgetary central government expenditure funded by taxes supports an understanding of the extent to which countries&amp;#x2019; recurrent and capital outlays are actually covered by domestic revenue mobilization in the form of taxation. The indicator, which can be directly derived from GFS series reported by national authorities to the IMF Statistics Department, will provide analysts with a cross-country comparable dataset that highlights the relationship between the executed national budget and the revenue/tax administration As outlined in the Annex to Chapter 4 of GFSM 2014, a variety of indicators can be observed or derived directly from the GFS framework, while others can be derived using a combination of GFS with other macroeconomic data (i.e., GDP). 17.1.2 will be derived using series that are basic to the GFS reporting framework. This enhances the comparability of data across countries and ensures establishing robust analytical findings to support SDG monitoring using fiscal data. There are also complementarities with Indicator 17.1.1, which facilitates an understanding of the &amp;quot;tax burden&amp;quot;. Both indicators are important in relation to achieving longer-term development objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt;Обоснование и интерпретация:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Показатель 17.1.2 Доля внутренних расходов бюджетных учреждений центрального правительства, финансируемых за счет налогов, помогает понять, в какой степени текущие и капитальные затраты страны фактически покрываются мобилизацией внутренних доходов в форме налогообложения. Показатель, который может быть непосредственно получен из ряда данных СГФ, представленных национальными властями Статистическому управлению МВФ, предоставит аналитикам набор сопоставимых данных по странам, который иллюстрирует взаимосвязь между исполненным национальным бюджетом и администрированием доходов / налогов. Как указано в Приложении к главе 4 РСГФ 2014 года можно исследовать или получать различные показатели непосредственно из структуры СГФ, в то время как другие показатели можно получить с помощью комбинации СГФ с другими макроэкономическими данными (такими как ВВП). Показатель 17.1.2 будет получен с использованием рядов, которые являются базовыми для структуры отчетности СГФ. Это повышает сопоставимость данных по странам и обеспечивает получение надежных аналитических результатов для осуществления мониторинга ЦУР с использованием фискальных данных. С показателем 17.1.1 они взаимодополняемы, что облегчает понимание «налогового бремени». Оба показателя важны для достижения долгосрочных целей развития.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
