<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 17-10-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main information used to calculate indicators 17.10.1 is import tariff data. Information on import tariffs might be retrieved by contacting directly National statistical offices, permanent country missions to the UN, regional organizations or focal points within the customs, ministries in charge of customs revenues (Ministry of economy/finance and related revenue authorities) or, alternatively, the Ministry of trade. Tariff data for the calculation of this indicator are retrieved from ITC (MAcMap) - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macmap.org/&quot;&gt;https://www.macmap.org/&lt;/a&gt;- WTO (IDB) - &lt;a href=&quot;https://tao.wto.org/welcome.aspx?ReturnUrl=%2f&quot;&gt;https://tao.wto.org/welcome.aspx?ReturnUrl=%2f&lt;/a&gt; - and UNCTAD (TRAINS) databases. Import tariff data included in the ITC (MAcMap) database are collected by contacting directly focal points in line national agencies or regional organizations (in the case of custom unions or regional economic communities). When available, data are downloaded from national or regional official websites. In some cases, data are purchased from private companies. Import tariff data included in the WTO (IDB) database are sourced from official notifications of WTO members. Import tariff included in the UNCTAD (TRAINS) database are collected from official sources, including official country or regional organizations websites.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt;Источники данных&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Основная информация, используемая для расчета показателей 17.10.1, - это данные по импортным тарифам. Информацию об импортных тарифах можно получить, связавшись напрямую с национальными статистическими управлениями, постоянными представительствами стран при ООН, региональными организациями или координаторами на таможне, министерствами, отвечающими за таможенные сборы (министерство экономики / финансов и соответствующие налоговые органы) или, в качестве альтернативы, министерством торговли. Данные по тарифам для расчета этого показателя взяты из баз данных МТЦ (MAcMap) - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macmap.org/&quot;&gt; https://www.macmap.org/ &lt;/a&gt; - ВТО ( IDB) - &lt;a href=&quot;https://tao.wto.org/welcome.aspx?ReturnUrl=%2f&quot;&gt; https://tao.wto.org/welcome.aspx?ReturnUrl=%2f &lt;/a&gt; - и ЮНКТАД (TRAINS). Данные по импортным тарифам, включенные в базу данных МТЦ (MAcMap), собираются путем прямого контакта с координаторами в отраслевых национальных агентствах или региональных организациях (в случае таможенных союзов или региональных экономических сообществ). При наличии данные загружаются с национальных или региональных официальных веб-сайтов. В некоторых случаях данные приобретаются у частных компаний. Данные по импортным тарифам, включенные в базу данных ВТО (IDB), получены из официальных уведомлений членов ВТО. Импортные пошлины, включенные в базу данных ЮНКТАД (TRAINS), собираются из официальных источников, включая официальные веб-сайты страновых или региональных организаций.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
