<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 8-1-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Collection process:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each year, the national accounts section of the UNSD sends a pre-filled NAQ to countries or areas to collect the latest data on official annual national accounts in domestic currency. In order to lighten the reporting burden of countries to different international and regional organizations the UNSD receives data from the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD), the United Nations Economic Commission for Europe (ECE) and the Caribbean Community (CARICOM) on behalf of their constituents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The official national accounts data in domestic currency are then validated to check for errors. The validation procedure involves ensuring that aggregates are equal to the sum of their components and that data series which are provided in multiple tables are represented consistently. After that, the current and constant price GDP series are converted into US dollars by applying the corresponding market exchange rates as reported by the International Monetary Fund (IMF). When these conversion rates are not available other IMF rates are used (official rates or principal rates).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For countries whose exchange rates are not reported by the IMF, the annual average of United Nations operational rates of exchange (UNOPs) is applied. The UNOPs are conversion rates that are applied in official transactions of the United Nations with these countries. These exchange rates are based on official, commercial and/or tourist rates of exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In cases where a country experiences considerable distortion in the conversion rates, the UNSD uses price-adjusted rates of exchange (PARE) as an alternative to the exchange rates reported by the IMF or UN operational rates of exchange. The conversion based on PARE corrects the distorting effects of uneven price changes that are not well reflected in the other conversion rates. Consequently, unrealistic levels in GDP and other national accounts aggregates expressed in US Dollars may have been adjusted for certain time periods to improve the economic analysis at national, regional and local levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The estimates derived for each year are compared to previous years to ensure that estimates are prepared consistently from year to year. Additionally, the growth rate from year to year is analysed to identify anomalies in the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The constant-price GDP series for each country is then divided by its population to obtain its real GDP per capita.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information on the methodology to estimate the data is available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/snaama/assets/pdf/methodology.pdf%20&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/snaama/assets/pdf/methodology.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt; Processus de collecte :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Chaque année, la section des comptes nationaux de l’UNSD envoie un NAQ pré-rempli dans les pays ou les régions pour recueillir les dernières données sur les comptes nationaux annuels officiels en monnaie nationale. Afin d’alléger le fardeau de déclaration des pays aux différentes organisations internationales et régionales, l’UNSD reçoit des données de l’Organisation de coopération et de développement économiques (OCDE), de la Commission économique des Nations Unies pour l’Europe (CEE) et de la Communauté des Caraïbes (CARICOM) au nom de leurs mandants. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les données officielles des comptes nationaux en monnaie nationale sont ensuite validées pour vérifier les erreurs. La procédure de validation consiste à s’assurer que les agrégats sont égaux à la somme de leurs composants et que les séries de données fournies dans plusieurs tableaux sont représentées de façon cohérente. Par la suite, la série actuelle et constante du PIB des prix est convertie en dollars américains en appliquant les taux de change correspondants du marché, tel que rapporté par le Fonds monétaire international (FMI). Lorsque ces taux de conversion ne sont pas disponibles, d’autres taux du FMI sont utilisés (taux officiels ou taux directeurs). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Pour les pays dont les taux de change ne sont pas déclarés par le FMI, la moyenne annuelle des taux de change opérationnels des Nations Unies (UNOPs) est appliquée. Les UNOPs sont des taux de conversion qui sont appliqués dans les transactions officielles des Nations Unies avec ces pays. Ces taux de change sont basés sur les taux de change officiels, commerciaux et/ou touristiques. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Dans les cas où un pays connaît une distorsion considérable des taux de conversion, l’UNSD utilise les taux de change ajustés aux prix (PARE) comme alternative aux taux de change déclarés par le FMI ou les taux de change opérationnels de l’ONU. La conversion basée sur le PARE corrige les effets de distorsion des variations de prix inégales qui ne sont pas bien reflétées dans les autres taux de conversion. Par conséquent, des niveaux irréalistes de PIB et d’autres agrégats de comptes nationaux exprimés en dollars américains ont peut-être été ajustés pour certaines périodes afin d’améliorer l’analyse économique aux niveaux national, régional et local. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les estimations tirées pour chaque année sont comparées aux années précédentes pour s’assurer que les estimations sont préparées de façon uniforme d’une année à l’autre. En outre, le taux de croissance d’une année à l’autre est analysé afin d’identifier les anomalies dans les données. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La série de PIB à prix constants pour chaque pays est ensuite divisée par sa population pour obtenir son PIB réel par habitant. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Plus d’informations sur la méthodologie d’estimation des données sont disponibles sur &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/snaama/assets/pdf/methodology.pdf%20&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/snaama/assets/pdf/methodology.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Каждый год секция национальных счетов СОООН рассылает предварительно заполненный ВНС странам или регионам для сбора последних данных по официальным годовым национальным счетам в национальной валюте. Для того, чтобы облегчить бремя отчетности стран перед различными международными и региональными организациями, СОООН получает данные от Организации экономического сотрудничества и развития (ОЭСР), Европейской экономической комиссии Организации Объединенных Наций (ЕЭК) и Карибского сообщества (КАРИКОМ) от имени стран, входящих в их состав. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Официальные данные национальных счетов в национальной валюте затем проверяются на наличие ошибок. Процедура валидации включает в себя обеспечение того, чтобы агрегаты были равны сумме их компонентов, и что ряды данных, представленные в нескольких таблицах, были согласованы. После этого ряды ВВП в текущих и постоянных ценах конвертируются в доллары США с применением соответствующих рыночных обменных курсов, сообщаемых Международным валютным фондом (МВФ). Когда эти курсы конвертации недоступны, используются другие курсы МВФ (официальные курсы или основные курсы). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для стран, обменные курсы которых не предоставляются МВФ, применяется среднегодовой операционный обменный курс Организации Объединенных Наций (ЮНОП). UNOP - это обменные курсы, которые применяются в официальных операциях Организации Объединенных Наций с этими странами. Эти обменные курсы основаны на официальных, коммерческих и / или туристических обменных курсах. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В случаях, когда в стране наблюдается значительное искажение обменных курсов, СОООН использует обменные курсы с поправкой на цену (PARE) в качестве альтернативы обменным курсам, представляемых МВФ или операционными обменными курсами ООН. Преобразование на основе PARE устраняет искажающие эффекты неравномерного изменения цен, которые плохо отражаются в других коэффициентах конверсии. Следовательно, нереалистичные уровни ВВП и других агрегатов национальных счетов, выраженные в долларах США, могли быть скорректированы для определенных периодов времени с целью улучшения экономического анализа на национальном, региональном и местном уровнях.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Оценки, полученные для каждого года, сравниваются с предыдущими годами, чтобы обеспечить согласованность подготовки оценок из года в год. Кроме того, темпы роста от года к году анализируются для выявления аномалий в данных. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Затем ряды ВВП в постоянных ценах для каждой страны делятся на численность ее населения, чтобы получить ее реальный ВВП на душу населения. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Дополнительная информация о методологии оценки данных доступна на &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/snaama/assets/pdf/methodology.pdf%20&quot;&gt; https: // unstats .un.org / unsd / snaama / assets / pdf / methodology.pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
