<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 8-1-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt; Méthodologie &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Méthode de calcul :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Le taux de croissance annuel du produit intérieur brut (PIB) réel par habitant est calculé comme suit :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; a. Convertir le PIB réel annuel en monnaie nationale aux prix de 2015 pour un pays ou une zone en dollars des États-Unis aux prix de 2015 en utilisant les taux de change de 2015. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; b. Divisez le résultat par la population du pays ou de la région pour obtenir le PIB réel annuel par habitant en dollars américains constants aux prix de 2015. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; c. Calculez le taux de croissance annuel du PIB réel par habitant de l&apos;année t + 1 en utilisant la formule suivante : [(G (t + 1) &amp;#x2013 ; G (t)) / G (t)] x 100, où G (t + 1) est le PIB réel par habitant en dollars EU de 2015 l&apos;année t + 1 et G (t) est le PIB réel par habitant en dollars EU de 2015 l&apos;année t. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computation method:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The annual growth rate of real Gross Domestic Product (GDP) per capita is calculated as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. Convert annual real GDP in domestic currency at 2015 prices for a country or area to US dollars at 2015 prices using the 2015 exchange rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Divide the result by the population of the country or area to obtain annual real GDP per capita in constant US dollars at 2015 prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. Calculate the annual growth rate of real GDP per capita in year t+1 using the following formula: [(G(t+1) &amp;#x2013; G(t))/G(t)] x 100, where G(t+1) is real GDP per capita in 2015 US dollars in year t+1 and G(t) is real GDP per capita in 2015 US dollars in year t.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
