<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 1-4-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;The data sources used are census, multi-topic household surveys conducted by national statistical Organizations and, depending on availability, administrative data on land tenure reported by national land institutions (in most cases land registries and cadastres).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Household surveys and census&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Household surveys and census that have been implemented by national statistical agencies, are a key source of information for computing the indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Censuses: &lt;/em&gt;These provide a complete enumeration of all the populations of the country at a specific time. In many recent censuses, questions on household characteristics, including short modules on security of tenure, are collected. So far, 41 countries have carried out a census in which questions on land tenure were included. Options for expanding land-related questions in the upcoming agricultural census are being discussed together with FAO (custodians of 5.a.1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Household-level consumption/expenditure surveys:&lt;/em&gt; To provide aggregate information on levels of consumption, prices and, often, estimates of GDP, many countries conduct this type of survey. As one of the key assets, this often includes questions on how residential land is accessed but rarely goes beyond this in terms of the type of documents held or the gender of rights holders. Elaborated housing modules are often included, and which already contain some questions on tenure status of the dwelling and documentation held. In consultation with the NSO, these modules will be fine-tuned to fully cover the essential land questions identified for 1.4.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Multi-topic household surveys:&lt;/em&gt; Building on the need to generate reliable poverty estimates and understand the factors that lead households to fall into poverty or escape from it in developing countries, these surveys include a roster of household members and, where agriculture is a main source of livelihood, a detailed agricultural module that in many cases obtains information on tenure status, ownership, and production at plot level. The essential questions for 1.4.2 as well as 5.a.1 have been included in the &lt;em&gt;Living Standard Measurement Surveys&lt;/em&gt; approach, which includes individual surveys and puts much emphasis on measuring intra household dynamics through direct reporting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Demographic and Health Surveys (DHS):&lt;/em&gt; Responding to a need for more frequent and reliable information on population and health, especially in developing countries, these types of surveys provide nationally representative data on a wide range of areas including fertility, family planning, maternal and child health, gender, HIV/AIDS, malaria, and nutrition. A standard questionnaire, regularly revised to incorporate newly emerging issues, is administrated at the household and individual level. It is a nationally representative survey. In a majority of DHS surveys, people eligible for individual interviews include women of reproductive age (15-49) and men age 15-49, 15-54, or 15-59.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;The individual questionnaires in the latest version (round 7) includes questions on whether respondents own land, if they have formal ownership documents, and if their name is included on these documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Multiple Indicator Cluster Surveys (MICS):&lt;/em&gt; Surveys implemented by NSOs under the program developed by the United Nations Children&amp;apos;s Fund (UNICEF) to provide internationally comparable, statistically rigorous data on the situation of children and women. They cover topics such as health, education, child protection, and water and sanitation. The survey design follows closely that of DHS questions and modules. This facilitates cross-country comparisons of estimates obtained using DHS data with those obtained using MICS data. In addition to the household questionnaire, there are questionnaires for women of reproductive ages (15-49), men aged between 15 and 49 and children (aged 0-5 and aged 5-17). The household questionnaire includes questions on ownership of land that can be used for agriculture by any member of the household, and on the size of the agricultural land owned by the household members. Also, there are questions about ownership/rental of dwelling where the household lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussions are ongoing with the teams in charge of DHS and MICS, specifically on expanding questions on land in their standardized and nationally representative surveys, in order to cover all data requirements for 1.4.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Urban Inequity Surveys (UIS): &lt;/em&gt;These specialized surveys were designed by UN-Habitat as household surveys to monitor and assess water and sanitation service coverage and other topics on urban inequities, including tenure. More recently, these surveys have been expanded to cover both rural and urban areas. The upcoming UIS surveys will be reviewed to ensure that the data requirements for SDG 1.4.2 are covered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Administrative data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Production of land records and maps is a core function of public land registries, with legally recognized documentation being the output. Reporting on the information contained in these land records ((i) names of people holding rights, (ii) type of rights and (iii) location) is not difficult in principle if records are kept in a computerized format. Using household surveys, this land information can be cross-checked against survey information with respect to quality and coverage. In the case of registered communal or group rights, identifying the group members who gain tenure security through its registration is equally possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The country specific metadata will include a description of the structure of the land information data base, available information and approach for routine SDG reporting.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
