<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 12-6-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The custodian agencies propose to establish a global platform or database which would: &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collate and analyse sustainability reports through advanced analytics to determine coherence with the minimum requirement and advanced level&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide country specific information &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aggregate data at sub-regional, regional and global levels (avoiding double-counting of the same companies)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Disaggregate data (company size, per industry)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Custodian Agencies will mine existing global and national-level report aggregators, to analyse the reports included in their databases. A preliminary list of repositories is included in Annex II.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provision will also be made for manual submission by individual report generators. This is particularly important for small companies whose reports may not be included in the global databases.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Advanced analytics will scan the report content and determine their compliance with the minimum standard or advanced level. They will also assign each company to a country according to the criteria listed above, to determine the number of companies per country publishing sustainability information. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This information will be communicated to each government individually, for their validation. They will also have the opportunity to seek clarification, contest the information, or provide complementary data to the custodian agencies for inclusion in the indicator count.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The platform will also automate the aggregation of data to obtain a global figure as well as data per UN sub-region and region for inclusion in the Global SDGs Database, and as a basis for the analysis of progress carried out annually for the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals Report and Secretary General&amp;#x2019;s Report on Progress towards the Sustainable Development Goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The platform will be online and open access. It will include filters so that governments or other stakeholders will eb able to filter the information themselves, per country, sector, company size or disclosure element, to obtain the desired information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While the platform will provide data for each country, this will be sent to each government for review and verification. Each government will be able to propose amendments to the data should they have further information to complement that provided by the database.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While common definitions of company size, industries (defined below), etc. are required to be used by the custodian agencies for analysis and aggregation at regional and global levels and reporting to the SDGs Report, national governments may choose to use different definitions for their own analysis and reporting, such as for their Voluntary National Reviews (VNRs). Filters will be included on the online platform for the database which will allow governments and other users to filter information according to their own national definitions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
