<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COMPARABILITY field for indicator 3-b-3, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data can be received from three data sources: SARA, HAI/WHO, and the EMP MedMon. These data collection methods demonstrate the following discrepancies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sampling of the facilities to be surveyed,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Size of the sampling of the facilities to be surveyed, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Questions asked at facility level to capture availability (i.e. SARA considers potentially available expired medicines as well).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHO will use any of these three data sources available for the year of calculation as a compromise between the limitations that these discrepancies pose to the proposed methodology and the need to overcome data availability issues in order to start reporting on this critical indicator. In the unlikely case that data is available through more than one data source for a specific country, WHO will rely on the source with a larger sample size and a higher percentage of medicines from the defined core list captured by the survey.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources des divergences :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données peuvent être reçues de trois sources de données : SARA, HAI/OMS et EMP MedMon. Ces méthodes de collecte de données présentent les divergences suivantes :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;échantillonnage des installations à inspecter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;taille de l’échantillonnage des installations à étudier, et&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;questions posées au niveau de l’établissement pour saisir la disponibilité (c.-à-d. SARA tient également compte des médicaments périmés potentiellement disponibles). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’OMS utilisera l’une ou l’autre de ces trois sources de données disponibles pour l’année de calcul comme compromis entre les limites que ces écarts posent à la méthodologie proposée et la nécessité de surmonter les problèmes de disponibilité des données afin de commencer à rendre compte de cet indicateur critique. Dans le cas peu probable où les données sont disponibles via plus d’une source de données pour un pays spécifique, l’OMS s’appuiera sur la source avec un échantillon plus grand et un pourcentage plus élevé de médicaments de la liste de base définie saisie par l’enquête. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
