<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The QUALITY_ASSURE field for indicator 3-b-3, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Quality control can be performed based on the median availability and median consumer price ratio of selected generic medicines listed on the Global Health Observatory (GHO). The quality of the key components of this indicator (i.e. availability, prices, etc.) can be assured for data collected using any of the three mechanisms listed above when cross-referenced with the GHO values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For future data collection, quality will be based on the analysis of the sample size and the number of medicines captured in the basket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Countries will collect and share data with the WHO Secretariat. WHO will subsequently compute the indicator and return to the countries for validation. By request, WHO will also provide all background materials and training for data collection and indicator computation.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Le contrôle de la qualité peut être effectué en fonction de la disponibilité médiane et du ratio médian des prix à la consommation de certains médicaments génériques répertoriés dans l’Observatoire mondial de la santé (GHO). La qualité des composantes clés de cet indicateur (c.-à-d. disponibilité, prix, etc.) peut être assurée pour les données recueillies à l’aide de l’un des trois mécanismes énumérés ci-dessus lorsqu’elles sont croisées avec les valeurs de l’Observatoire mondial de la santé. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour la collecte future de données, la qualité sera basée sur l’analyse de la taille de l’échantillon et du nombre de médicaments saisis dans le panier. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les pays recueilleront et partageront des données avec le Secrétariat de l’OMS. L’OMS calculera ensuite l’indicateur et retournera le faire valider par le pays. Sur demande, l’OMS fournira également tous les documents de base et la formation pour la collecte de données et le calcul des indicateurs. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
