<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 12-1-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 2020, 83 countries and the European Union reported a total of 700 policies and implementation activities for SDG 12.1.1 under the 10-Year Framework of Programmes on Sustainable Consumption and Production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data set covers each nation individually since 2002. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Country (using the official SDG country list provided by UNDESA).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ministry: Ministry of Environment / Sustainable Development / Natural Resources / Energy; Ministry of the Economy / Finance / Treasury; Ministry of Industry / Trade / Commerce / Labour; Ministry of Planning / Development / Infrastructures; Ministry of Foreign Affairs / Regional / International Cooperation; Ministry of Energy / Mineral Development / Power; Ministry of Science / Research / Technology / Innovation; Ministry of Agriculture / Livestock / Fisheries / Forestry / Food Security / Rural Affairs; Ministry of Tourism / Culture / Sports; Ministry of Transports / Roads / Works / Construction / Building; Ministry of Urban Development / Land Management / Housing; Ministry of Education / Higher Education / Youth; Ministry of Poverty Alleviation / Social Welfare / Families / Women.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Type of instrument: national strategy/roadmap/plan; regulatory/legal; economic/financial; voluntary/self-regulatory&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Policy cycle stage: Under development (initial stage); just adopted; under implementation through specific actions; has reached its end date and has been evaluated. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Year of development, adoption, implementation and/or end-date: 2002 to 2022.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Legal status: binding/non-binding.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sectors: Agriculture and fishery; Buildings and construction; Consumer goods; Culture and recreation; Financial sector; Education; Energy, Food &amp;amp; Beverage; Forestry; Environmental protection; Environmental services; Government and Civil Society; Health; Housing; Industrial sector (Including SMEs); Information and Communications Technology (ICT); Plastics; Scientific Research, Development and Innovation; Textiles; Tourism; Transport; Waste (including Chemicals); Water.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Actors involved: national ministries or other specialized national agencies; local authorities; civil society organizations; scientific and technical organizations; United Nations/inter-governmental organizations; business sector. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Support received from non &amp;#x2013; national partner: United Nations/inter-governmental organizations; multilateral financial institutions; bilateral organizations; international non-governmental organizations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Support received from 10YFP: encouraged the development/implementation; technical support; financial support; capacity-building activities; experience and knowledge-sharing tools; no connection to 10YFP.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Link to other SDGs: SDG 1;2;3;4;5;6;7;8;9;10;11;13;14;15;16;17&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Link to other SDG 12 Targets: SDG 12.2; 12.3; 12.4; 12.5; 12.6; 12.7; 12.8; 12.A; 12.B; 12.C&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stages of the value chain being addressed: Finance / investment; Policy / regulation; Product / service design and planning; Research and development / Innovation; Extraction/production of raw materials ; Processing of raw materials and making of product parts &amp;amp; components; Production / manufacturing / construction; Packaging; Transportation; Distribution / retail; Service; Use / consumption; Disposal / treatment of waste / Recycling; Not targeting a specific step of the value chain&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Impact measured: Resource efficiency; environmental impact; human well-being. More detailed impact indicators in the 10YFP Indicators of Success.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Relevant links and attachments including electronic copies of the policies, or their drafts, relevant official reports, summary of consultations and any other relevant associated documents and web links should be attached to the reporting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</data>
</root>
