<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 6-1-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Data sources included in the JMP database are: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Censuses, which in principle collect basic data from all people living within a country and are led by national statistical offices. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Household surveys, which collect data from a subset of households. These may target national, rural, or urban populations, or more limited project or sub-national areas. An appropriate sample design is necessary for survey results to be representative, and surveys are often led by or reviewed and approved by national statistical organizations. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Administrative data, which may consist of information collected by government or non-government entities involved in the delivery or oversight of services. Examples include water and sanitation inventories and databases, and reports of regulators. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Other datasets may be available such as compilations by international or regional initiatives (e.g. Eurostat), studies conducted by research institutes, or technical advice received during country consultations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Access to water, sanitation and hygiene are considered core socio-economic and health indicators, as well as key determinants of child survival, maternal, and children&amp;#x2019;s health, family wellbeing, and economic productivity. Drinking water, sanitation and hygiene facilities are also used in constructing wealth quintiles used by many integrated household surveys to analyse inequalities between rich and poor. Access to drinking water, sanitation and hygiene are therefore core indicators for many household surveys and censuses. In high-income countries where household surveys or censuses do not collect detailed information on the types of facilities used by households, the JMP relies on administrative records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data on availability and quality of drinking water are currently available from both household surveys and from government departments responsible for drinking water supply and regulators. In many low- and middle-income countries, existing water quality data from regulatory authorities is limited, especially for rural areas and populations using non-piped supplies. To complement regulatory data, an increasing number of low- and middle-income countries are collecting nationally representative data on drinking water quality through multi-topic household surveys. Beginning in 2012, a water quality module was developed standardized by the JMP in collaboration with UNICEF&amp;#x2019;s Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) programme. Integration of water quality testing has become a feasible option due to the increased availability of affordable and accurate testing procedures and their adaptation for use by household survey experts. The growing interest in ensuring the implementation of water quality testing in these surveys can, to a large extent, be attributed to the incorporation of drinking water quality in the SDG global indicator for &amp;#x2018;safely managed drinking water services&amp;#x2019;. Data gaps will be reduced even more as regulation becomes more widespread in low- and middle-income countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some datasets available to the JMP are not representative of national, rural or urban populations, or may be representative of only a subset of these populations (e.g. the population using piped water supplies). The JMP enters datasets into the global database when they represent at least 20% of the national, urban or rural populations. However, datasets representing less than 80% of the relevant population, or which are considered unreliable or inconsistent with other datasets covering similar populations, are not used in the production of estimates (see section 2.6, Data Acceptance in JMP Methodology: 2017 update and SDG baselines).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The population data used by the JMP, including the proportion of the population living in urban and rural areas, are those routinely updated by the UN Population Division (World Population Prospects: &lt;a href=&quot;https://population.un.org/wpp/&quot;&gt;https://population.un.org/wpp/&lt;/a&gt;; World Urbanization Projects: &lt;a href=&quot;https://population.un.org/wup&quot;&gt;https://population.un.org/wup&lt;/a&gt;))&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
