<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The OTHER_DOC field for indicator 15-3-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PRAIS 4 portal, data collection tool for SDG 15.3.1: &lt;a href=&quot;https://reporting.unccd.int/&quot;&gt;https://reporting.unccd.int/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trends.Earth, data calculation tool for SDG 15.3.1: &lt;a href=&quot;https://trends.earth/docs/en/&quot;&gt;https://trends.earth/docs/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di Gregorio, A. 2005. Land cover classification system (LCCS): classification concepts and user manual. Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, Rome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European Communities. (2013). Overall Approach to the Classification of Ecological Status and Ecological Potential, Guidance Document No 13. Luxembourg: European Union. &lt;a href=&quot;https://circabc.europa.eu/sd/a/06480e87-27a6-41e6-b165-0581c2b046ad/Guidance%20No%2013%20-%20Classification%20of%20Ecological%20Status%20(WG%20A).pdf&quot;&gt;https://circabc.europa.eu/sd/a/06480e87-27a6-41e6-b165-0581c2b046ad/Guidance%20No%2013%20-%20Classification%20of%20Ecological%20Status%20(WG%20A).pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO-GTOS. 2009. Land Cover: Assessment of the status of the development of the standards for the Terrestrial Essential Climate Variables. Global Terrestrial Observing System, Rome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IPCC. 2006. IPCC Guidelines for National Greenhouse Gas Inventories: Agriculture, Forestry and other Land Use. Prepared by the National Greenhouse Gas Inventories Programme: Eggleston H.S., Buendia L., Miwa K., Ngara T. and Tanabe K. (eds). IGES, Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IPCC. 2019&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;Refinement to the 2006 IPCC Guidelines for National Greenhouse Gas Inventories. In: Buendia&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;E&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;, Tanabe&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; K&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;, Kranjc&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;A&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;, Baasansuren&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;J&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;, Fukuda&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;M&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;, Ngarize&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;S&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;, Osako&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;A&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;, Pyrozhenko&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;Y&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;, Shermanau&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;P&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;, Federici&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;S&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;(eds). Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, Geneva, Switzerland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ivits and Cherlet. 2013. Land-productivity dynamics towards integrated assessment of land degradation at global scales. European Commission JRC Technical Report. &lt;a href=&quot;https://publications.europa.eu/en/publication-detail/-/publication/1e2aceac-b20b-45ab-88d9-b3d187ae6375/language-en/format-PDF/source-49343336&quot;&gt;https://publications.europa.eu/en/publication-detail/-/publication/1e2aceac-b20b-45ab-88d9-b3d187ae6375/language-en/format-PDF/source-49343336&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joint Research Centre of the European Commission. 2017. World Atlas of Desertification, 3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; edition. JRC, Ispra. &lt;a href=&quot;https://wad.jrc.ec.europa.eu/&quot;&gt;https://wad.jrc.ec.europa.eu/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Millennium Ecosystem Assessment. 2005. Ecosystems and human wellbeing: a framework for assessment. Island Press, Washington, DC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Orr, B.J., Cowie, A.L., Castillo Sanchez, V.M., Chasek, P., Crossman, N.D., Erlewein, A., Louwagie, G., Maron, M., Metternicht, G.I., Minelli, S., Tengberg, A.E., Walter, S., Welton, S., 2017. Scientific Conceptual Framework for Land Degradation Neutrality. A Report of the Science Policy Interface. United Nations Convention to Combat Desertification (UNCCD), Bonn, Germany. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unccd.int/publications/scientific-conceptual-framework-land-degradation-neutrality-report-science-policy&quot;&gt;https://www.unccd.int/publications/scientific-conceptual-framework-land-degradation-neutrality-report-science-policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running et al. 1999. MODIS Daily Photosynthesis (PSN) and Annual Net Primary Production (NPP) Product (MOD17): Algorithm Theoretical Basis Document &lt;a href=&quot;https://eospso.gsfc.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/atbd/atbd_mod16.pdf&quot;&gt;https://eospso.gsfc.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/atbd/atbd_mod16.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sims, N.C., Newnham, G.J., England, J.R., Guerschman, J., Cox, S.J.D., Roxburgh, S.H., Viscarra Rossel, R.A., Fritz, S. and Wheeler, I. 2021. Good Practice Guidance. SDG Indicator 15.3.1, Proportion of Land That Is Degraded Over Total Land Area. Version 2.0. United Nations Convention to Combat Desertification, Bonn, Germany. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unccd.int/publications/good-practice-guidance-sdg-indicator-1531-proportion-land-degraded-over-total-land&quot;&gt;https://www.unccd.int/publications/good-practice-guidance-sdg-indicator-1531-proportion-land-degraded-over-total-land&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smith, P., Fang, C., Dawson, J. J., &amp;amp; Moncrieff, J. B. 2008. Impact of global warming on soil organic carbon. Advances in agronomy, 97: 1-43.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations Convention to Combat Desertification. 1994. Convention Text&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.unccd.int/sites/default/files/relevant-links/2017-01/UNCCD_Convention_ENG_0.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www2.unccd.int/sites/default/files/relevant-links/2017-01/UNCCD_Convention_ENG_0.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
