<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 15-9-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The objective of Aichi Biodiversity Target 2 is to ensure that the diverse values of biodiversity and opportunities derived from its conservation and sustainable use are recognized and reflected in all relevant public and private decision-making processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sub-indicator (a)&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;National Biodiversity Strategies and Action Plans are described in Article 6 of the Convention on Biological Diversity on General Measures for Conservation and Sustainable Use. Under this article, it is stated that &amp;#x201C;each Party to the Convention shall, in accordance with its particular conditions and capabilities: (a) Develop national strategies, plans or programmes for the conservation and sustainable use of biological diversity or adapt for this purpose existing strategies, plans or programmes which shall reflect, &lt;em&gt;inter alia&lt;/em&gt;, the measures set out in this Convention relevant to the Contracting Party concerned; and (b) Integrate, as far as possible and as appropriate, the conservation and sustainable use of biological diversity into relevant sectoral or cross-sectoral plans, programmes and policies&amp;#x201D;. Further, under Article 26, it is stated that &amp;#x201C;each Contracting Party shall, at intervals to be determined by the Conference of the Parties, present to the Conference of the Parties, reports on measures which it has taken for the implementation of the provisions of this Convention and their effectiveness in meeting the objectives of this Convention&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sub-indicator (b)&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Integration of biodiversity values into national accounting and reporting systems can be achieved through implementation of the international statistical standard, the System for Environmental-Economic Accounting (SEEA). The SEEA Central Framework (SEEA CF) was adopted by the UN Statistical Commission in 2012 as the first international standard for environmental-economic accounting. In addition, the SEEA Ecosystem Accounting (SEEA EA) was endorsed by the UN Statistical Commission in 2021. Results of the Global Assessment of Environmental-Economic Accounting and Supporting Statistics provide the data needed for Sub-indicator (b) of the indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
