<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 15-9-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator measures the progress towards national targets established in accordance with Aichi Biodiversity Target 2 of the Strategic Plan for Biodiversity 2011-2020: By 2020, at the latest, biodiversity values have been integrated into national and local development and poverty reduction strategies and planning processes and are being incorporated into national accounting, as appropriate, and reporting systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is divided in two sub-indicators: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15.9.1(a): &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Number of countries that established national targets in accordance with Aichi Biodiversity Target 2 of the Strategic Plan for Biodiversity 2011-2020 in their national biodiversity strategy and action plans and the progress reported towards these targets.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15.9.1(b):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Integration of biodiversity into national accounting and reporting systems, defined as implementation of the System of Environmental-Economic Accounting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Biodiversity&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1992 United Nations Earth Summit defined &amp;quot;biological diversity&amp;quot; as &amp;quot;the variability among living organisms from all sources, including, &lt;em&gt;inter alia&lt;/em&gt;, terrestrial, marine and other aquatic ecosystems and the ecological complexes of which they are part: this includes diversity within species, between species and of ecosystems&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Aichi Biodiversity Target 2&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aichi Biodiversity Target 2 is under Strategic Goal A of the Strategic Plan for Biodiversity 2011-2020, which addresses the underlying causes of biodiversity loss by mainstreaming biodiversity across government and society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aichi Biodiversity Target 2: By 2020, at the latest, biodiversity values have been integrated into national and local development and poverty reduction strategies and planning processes and are being incorporated into national accounting, as appropriate,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;and reporting systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;NBSAPs&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In accordance with Article 6 of the Convention on Biological Diversity, Parties are obligated to develop national biodiversity strategies and action plans, and integrate biodiversity considerations into relevant sectoral or cross-sectoral plans, programmes and policies. The National Biodiversity Strategy and Action Plan (NBSAP) is intended to define the current status of biodiversity, the threats leading to its degradation and the strategies and priority actions to ensure its conservation and sustainable use within the framework of the socio-economic development of the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;National Reports&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In accordance with Article 26 of the Convention on Biological Diversity, Parties are obligated to provide information on measures taken towards the implementation of the Convention and its strategic plans, as reflected in the National Biodiversity Strategy and Action Plan (NBSAP), as well as on the effectiveness of these measures. The format for the sixth national reports requested that Parties, among other things, provide an assessment of their progress towards their national targets and/or the Aichi Biodiversity Targets. These national reports are publicly available on the Convention&amp;#x2019;s Clearing-House Mechanism, which is constantly being improved to enhance usability by Parties and better contribute to assessment of the implementation of the Strategic Plan for Biodiversity 2011-2020 and the achievement of the Aichi Biodiversity Targets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The system of environmental-economic accounting&lt;/strong&gt; is presented by two international statistical standards: the System for Environmental-Economic Accounting Central Framework (SEEA-CF), adopted in 2012, and the System for Environmental-Economic Accounting-Ecosystem Accounting (SEEA-EA), adopted in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;SEEA-CF &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The System for Environmental-Economic Accounting Central Framework (SEEA-CF) is an international statistical standard for measuring the environment and its relationship with the economy. It integrates economic and environmental data to provide a more comprehensive and multipurpose view of the interrelationships between the economy and the environment and the stocks and changes in stocks of environmental assets, as they bring benefits to humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;SEEA-EA &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The System for Environmental-Economic Accounting-Ecosystem Accounting (SEEA-EA) is an integrated statistical framework for organizing biophysical data, measuring ecosystem services in physical and monetary terms, tracking changes in the condition and extent of ecosystem assets and linking this information to economic and other human activity. The SEEA-EA takes the perspective of ecosystems and considers how individual environmental assets interact as part of natural processes within a given spatial area. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;The Global Assessment of Environmental-Economic Accounting and Supporting Statistics&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Global Assessment of Environmental-Economic Accounting and Supporting Statistics is a survey administered by the UNSD under the auspices of the UN Committee of Experts on Environmental Economic Accounting (UNCEEA). The aim of the Global Assessment is to assess the progress in reaching the implementation targets of the UNCEEA.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
