<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 17-3-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The indicator is feasible, suitable and relevant. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some providers will be reporting on sub-indicators 17.3.1.a, 17.3.1.b and 17.3.1.c to OECD while some providers will report on these sub-indicators to UNCTAD according to the agreed conceptual framework on South-South cooperation developed by the sub-Group on South-South cooperation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sub-indicator 17.3.1.d (FDI) is reported to UNCTAD by recipients according to the current reporting arrangements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some multilateral and bilateral providers are reporting on sub-indicator 17.3.1.e mobilized private finance to OECD. Mobilized private finance is not part of the conceptual framework of South-South cooperation. Some providers that are engaging in this form of development finance may approach UNCTAD regarding the pilot testing and further development of this indicator for wider and global application. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some countries will report on 17.3.1.f to OECD. Private grants are not part of the conceptual framework of South-South cooperation. Some providers can report on private grants to UNCTAD on a voluntary basis as part of a pilot exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNCTAD and OECD as co-custodians have undertaken to ensure that there are no overlaps in global reporting for this indicator in cases where countries or multilaterals provide their information to both organizations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator does not include debt relief, in-donor refugee costs, administrative costs not allocated to specific development activities, or peace and security expenditures other than those reportable as official development assistance (ODA). Furthermore, it does not include private non-concessional loans; portfolio investment; export credits, whether official, officially-supported, or private; short-term flows with an original maturity of 1 year or less; or any other flows that are not within the scope of the proposed sub-indicators. These exclusions sharpen the focus of the indicator on transfers of new resources to developing countries for sustainable development purposes, while excluding commercially-motivated debt-creating flows. While there was broad support for all exclusions during the discussions of the Working Group and the open consultation, and while there were relatively few objections to specific exclusions, some countries nevertheless believe that all exclusions should be reviewed in the context of the 2025 review.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
