<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 16-1-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a starting point, the indicator will only include documented conflict-related direct deaths. If there are no documented conflict-related direct deaths for a particular situation of armed conflict, no estimate of missing values will be computed. Specific to the nature of this indicator, it is worth noting that depending on the availability and quality of data over the course of the armed conflict, statistical surveys and techniques may be used to estimate undocumented direct conflict-related deaths, adding the statistical estimates to the documented cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National datasets with sufficiently well documented direct deaths constitute an essential source for further statistical analysis and estimations of undocumented direct deaths. As indirect deaths would typically fall outside the scope of common casualty recording practices (that rather focus on direct deaths), they may be captured using additional administrative records and/or statistical surveys allowing the measurement of excess mortality, namely all the deaths (direct and indirect) that would not have occurred in time of peace, as defined and measured by epidemiologists. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The methodology for these estimations will be further developed in collaboration with national statistical offices, national human rights institutions, UN entities and civil society organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same as country level.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
