<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DOC_METHOD field for indicator 17-18-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Methods and guidance available to countries for the compilation of the data at the national level:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methodology used for the compilation of data at national level:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PARIS21 SDG Survey through online form. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;International recommendations and guidelines available to countries: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PARIS21 pre-filled the survey for countries compliant with the European Statistics Code of Practice. The European Statistics Code of Practice is coherent with the Fundamental Principles of Official Statistics. Therefore, compliance with the ESS Code of Practice equates with compliance with all 10 principles.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt;Доступные странам методы и руководства для составления данных на национальном уровне:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Методология, используемая для составления данных на национальном уровне:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Обследование ЦУР PARIS21 с помощью онлайн-формы. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Международные рекомендации и руководства, доступные странам: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Предварительно заполненный вопросник обследования PARIS21 для стран, соответствующих Кодексу норм европейской статистики. Свод правил европейской статистики согласуется с Основными принципами официальной статистики. Таким образом, соблюдение Кодекса норм Европейской статистической системы означает соблюдение всех 10 принципов.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
