<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 15-3-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Data availability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many countries, national data for one or more of the sub-indicators are available. Regional and global data are available for all three sub-indicators and can be disaggregated at the national level for interpretation and validation by national authorities. Communication and coordination with national statistical systems, NSO representatives and UNCCD national focal points in a transparent manner will include an assessment of data needs and capacity building for monitoring and reporting on the indicator when necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Time series:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annual since the year 2000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator can be disaggregated by land cover class or other spatially explicit land unit.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Во многих странах доступны национальные данные по одному или нескольким субпоказателям. Региональные и глобальные данные доступны для всех трех субпоказателей и могут быть дезагрегированы на национальном уровне для интерпретации и валидации национальными властями. Связь и координация с национальными статистическими системами, представителями НСУ и национальными координаторами КБО ООН прозрачным образом будет включать оценку потребностей в данных и наращивание потенциала для проведения мониторинга и подготовки отчетности по показателю, когда это необходимо.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Ежегодно с 2000 года. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель может быть дезагрегирован по классу растительного покрова или другой земельной единице с хорошим пространственным разрешением.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
