<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 15-3-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Data availability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many countries, national data for one or more of the sub-indicators are available. Regional and global data are available for all three sub-indicators and can be disaggregated at the national level for interpretation and validation by national authorities. Communication and coordination with national statistical systems, NSO representatives and UNCCD national focal points in a transparent manner will include an assessment of data needs and capacity building for monitoring and reporting on the indicator when necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Time series:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annual since the year 2000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator can be disaggregated by land cover class or other spatially explicit land unit.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En muchos países se dispone de datos nacionales para uno o más de los sub-indicadores. Los datos regionales y globales están disponibles para los tres sub-indicadores y pueden ser desagregados a nivel nacional para su interpretación y validación por las autoridades nacionales. La comunicación y la coordinación con los sistemas estadísticos nacionales, los representantes de las ONE y los puntos focales nacionales de la CNULD de manera transparente incluirán una evaluación de las necesidades de datos y la creación de capacidades para el seguimiento y la presentación de informes sobre el indicador cuando sea necesario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anual desde el año 2000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador puede desagregarse por clase de cobertura del terreno u otra unidad terrestre espacialmente explícita.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilité des données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dans de nombreux pays, des données nationales sont disponibles pour un ou plusieurs des sous-indicateurs. Les données régionales et mondiales sont disponibles pour les trois sous-indicateurs et peuvent être désagrégées au niveau national pour être interprétées et validées par les autorités nationales. La communication et la coordination avec les systèmes statistiques nationaux, les représentants des services nationaux de statistique et les points focaux nationaux de la CNULCD, de manière transparente, comprendront une évaluation des besoins en données et un renforcement des capacités pour le suivi et le rapportage de l&apos;indicateur si nécessaire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Série chronologique :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annuelle depuis l&apos;année 2000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Désagrégation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur peut être désagrégé par classe d&apos;occupation du sol ou autre unité foncière spatialement explicite.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Во многих странах доступны национальные данные по одному или нескольким субпоказателям. Региональные и глобальные данные доступны для всех трех субпоказателей и могут быть дезагрегированы на национальном уровне для интерпретации и валидации национальными властями. Связь и координация с национальными статистическими системами, представителями НСУ и национальными координаторами КБО ООН прозрачным образом будет включать оценку потребностей в данных и наращивание потенциала для проведения мониторинга и подготовки отчетности по показателю, когда это необходимо.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Ежегодно с 2000 года. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель может быть дезагрегирован по классу растительного покрова или другой земельной единице с хорошим пространственным разрешением.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
