<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 15-3-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Rationale:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last decade, there have been a number of global/regional targets and initiatives to halt and reverse land degradation and restore degraded land. Starting in 2010, these include the Aichi Biodiversity Targets, one of which aims to restore at least 15% of degraded ecosystems; the Bonn Challenge and its regional initiatives to restore more than 150 million hectares; and most recently the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), in particular SDG target 15.3. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each of the sub-indicators, countries can access a wide range of data sources, including Earth observation and geospatial information, while at the same time ensuring national ownership.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-25&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-25&quot;&gt;[25]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The use of the existing national reporting templates of the UNCCD,&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-26&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-26&quot;&gt;[26]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; which include the indicator and sub-indicators, provides a practical and harmonized approach to reporting on this indicator beginning in 2018 and every four years thereafter.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-27&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-27&quot;&gt;[27]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The quantitative assessments and corresponding mapping at the national level, as required by this indicator, would help countries to set policy and planning priorities among diverse land resource areas, in particular:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;to identify hotspots and plan actions of redress, including through the conservation, rehabilitation, restoration and sustainable management of land resources; and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;to address emerging pressures to help avoid future land degradation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-25&quot;&gt;25&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; United Nations General Assembly. 2015. Transforming our world: the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development. Resolution adopted by the General Assembly on 25 September 2015 (A/RES/70/1). &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-25&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-26&quot;&gt;26&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.unccd.int/sites/default/files/relevant-links/2017-12/20171107_Template_Final_EN.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www2.unccd.int/sites/default/files/relevant-links/2017-12/20171107_Template_Final_EN.pdf&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-26&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-27&quot;&gt;27&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.unccd.int/sites/default/files/sessions/documents/2017-09/ICCD_CRIC%2816%29_L.3-1715758E.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www2.unccd.int/sites/default/files/sessions/documents/2017-09/ICCD_CRIC%2816%29_L.3-1715758E.pdf&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-27&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En la última década, ha habido una serie de objetivos e iniciativas globales/regionales para detener e invertir la degradación de la tierra y restaurar las tierras degradadas. A partir de 2010, se incluyen las Metas de Biodiversidad de Aichi, una de las cuales pretende restaurar al menos el 15% de los ecosistemas degradados; el Desafío de Bonn y sus iniciativas regionales para restaurar más de 150 millones de hectáreas; y más recientemente los Objetivos de Desarrollo Sostenible (ODS), en particular la meta 15.3 de los ODS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Para cada uno de los sub-indicadores, los países pueden acceder a una amplia gama de fuentes de datos, incluida la observación de la Tierra y la información geoespacial, al tiempo que garantizan la apropiación nacional&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-25&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-25&quot;&gt;[25]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; El uso de las plantillas existentes de presentación de informes nacionales de la CNULD,&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-26&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-26&quot;&gt;[26]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; que incluyen el indicador y los sub-indicadores, proporciona un enfoque práctico y armonizado para la presentación de informes sobre este indicador a partir de 2018 y cada cuatro años a partir de entonces.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-27&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-27&quot;&gt;[27]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Las evaluaciones cuantitativas y el correspondiente mapeo a nivel nacional, tal como lo requiere este indicador, ayudarían a los países a establecer prioridades de política y planificación entre diversas áreas de recursos de la tierra, en particular:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; para identificar los puntos conflictivos y planificar acciones de reparación, incluso mediante la conservación, rehabilitación, restauración y gestión sostenible de los recursos de la tierra; y&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; para abordar las presiones emergentes y ayudar a evitar la futura degradación de la tierra.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-25&quot;&gt;25&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Asamblea General de las Naciones Unidas. 2015. Transformar nuestro mundo: la Agenda 2030 para el Desarrollo Sostenible. Resolución aprobada por la Asamblea General el 25 de septiembre de 2015 (A/RES/70/1). &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-25&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-26&quot;&gt;26&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.unccd.int/sites/default/files/relevant-links/2017-12/20171107_Template_Final_EN.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www2.unccd.int/sites/default/files/relevant-links/2017-12/20171107_Template_Final_EN.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-26&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-27&quot;&gt;27&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.unccd.int/sites/default/files/sessions/documents/2017-09/ICCD_CRIC%2816%29_L.3-1715758E.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www2.unccd.int/sites/default/files/sessions/documents/2017-09/ICCD_CRIC%2816%29_L.3-1715758E.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-27&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Justification : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Au cours de la dernière décennie, il y a eu un certain nombre d&apos;objectifs et d&apos;initiatives mondiaux/régionaux pour arrêter et inverser la dégradation des terres et restaurer les terres dégradées. Depuis 2010, il s&apos;agit notamment des objectifs d&apos;Aichi en matière de biodiversité, dont l&apos;un vise à restaurer au moins 15 % des écosystèmes dégradés ; du Défi de Bonn et de ses initiatives régionales visant à restaurer plus de 150 millions d&apos;hectares ; et plus récemment des Objectifs de développement durable (ODD), en particulier la cible 15.3 de l&apos;ODD. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour chacun des sous-indicateurs, les pays peuvent accéder à un large éventail de sources de données, y compris l&apos;observation de la Terre et les informations géospatiales, tout en garantissant l&apos;appropriation nationale&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-25&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-25&quot;&gt;[25]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; L&apos;utilisation des modèles de rapports nationaux existants de la CNULD&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-26&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-26&quot;&gt;[26]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; qui incluent l&apos;indicateur et les sous-indicateurs, fournit une approche pratique et harmonisée pour rendre compte de cet indicateur à partir de 2018 et tous les quatre ans par la suite.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-27&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-27&quot;&gt;[27]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Les évaluations quantitatives et la cartographie correspondante au niveau national, telles que requises par cet indicateur, aideraient les pays à établir des priorités en matière de politique et de planification parmi les diverses zones de ressources foncières, en particulier :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pour identifier les points chauds et planifier des actions de redressement, notamment par la conservation, la réhabilitation, la restauration et la gestion durable des ressources foncières ; et &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; pour faire face aux pressions émergentes afin de contribuer à éviter la dégradation future des terres.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-25&quot;&gt;25&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Assemblée générale des Nations Unies. 2015. Transformer notre monde : le Programme 2030 pour le développement durable. Résolution adoptée par l&apos;Assemblée générale le 25 septembre 2015 (A/RES/70/1). &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-25&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-26&quot;&gt;26&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.unccd.int/sites/default/files/relevant-links/2017-12/20171107_Template_Final_EN.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www2.unccd.int/sites/default/files/relevant-links/2017-12/20171107_Template_Final_EN.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-26&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-27&quot;&gt;27&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.unccd.int/sites/default/files/sessions/documents/2017-09/ICCD_CRIC%2816%29_L.3-1715758E.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www2.unccd.int/sites/default/files/sessions/documents/2017-09/ICCD_CRIC%2816%29_L.3-1715758E.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-27&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;В последнее десятилетие был поставлен ряд глобальных / региональных целей и инициатив, призванных остановить и обратить вспять деградацию земель и приступить к восстановлению деградированных земель. Начиная с 2010 года они включают целевые задачи по сохранению биоразнообразия, принятые в Айти, одна из которых направлена на восстановление не менее 15% деградировавших экосистем; Боннский вызов и его региональные инициативы по восстановлению более 150 миллионов гектаров; и совсем недавно принятые Цели устойчивого развития (ЦУР), в частности задачу 15.3 ЦУР.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; По каждому из субпоказателей страны могут получить доступ к широкому спектру источников данных, включая данные наблюдения Земли и геопространственную информацию, при одновременном обеспечении информации национального владения. &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href = &quot;# footnote-25&quot; id = &quot; footnote-ref-25 &quot;&gt; [25] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; Использование существующих шаблонов национальной отчетности КБО ООН, &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href =&quot; # footnote-26 &quot;id =&quot; footnote-ref- 26 &quot;&gt; [26] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;, которые включают показатель и субпоказатели, обеспечивает практический и согласованный подход к отчетности по этому показателю, начиная с 2018 г. и каждые последующие четыре года. &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href = &quot;# footnote-27&quot; id = &quot;footnote-ref-27&quot;&gt; [27] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; Количественные оценки и соответствующее сопоставление на национальном уровне, как того требует этот показатель, помогли бы странам определить стратегические цели и приоритеты планирования в отношении различных областей земельных ресурсов, в частности: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; для выявления горячих точек и планирования действий по исправлению положения,
в том числе посредством сохранения, реабилитации, восстановления и устойчивого управления земельными ресурсами; и &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; для решения возникающих проблем, чтобы помочь избежать деградации земель
в будущем. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-25&quot;&gt; 25 &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p&gt; Генеральная Ассамблея Организации Объединенных Наций. 2015. Преобразование нашего мира: Повестка дня в области устойчивого развития на период до 2030 года. Резолюция принята Генеральной Ассамблеей 25 сентября 2015 года (A / RES / 70/1). &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-25&quot;&gt; &amp;#x2191; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-26&quot;&gt; 26 &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.unccd.int/sites/default/files/relevant-links/2017-12/20171107_Template_Final_EN.pdf&quot;&gt; http://www2.unccd.int/sites/default/files/relevant-links /2017-12/20171107_Template_Final_EN.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-26&quot;&gt; &amp;#x2191; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-27&quot;&gt; 27 &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.unccd.int/sites/default/files/sessions/documents/2017-09/ICCD_CRIC%2816%29_L.3-1715758E.pdf&quot;&gt; http: //www2.unccd. int / sites / default / files / sessions / documents / 2017-09 / ICCD_CRIC% 2816% 29_L.3-1715758E.pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-27&quot;&gt; &amp;#x2191; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
