<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 9-1-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;Aviation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aviation passenger and freight volumes are reported for the air carriers through ICAO Air Transport Reporting Forms and grouped by Member States of ICAO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Road/Rail/Inland waterways/Pipelines&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data for each inland mode are reported to UNECE/ITF/Eurostat by member States, through an annual data collection using the transport statistics web common questionnaire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maritime:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is calculated through a sum of international maritime freight volumes and container port traffic as collected by UNCTAD secretariat from websites and reports by various industry, government and specialised maritime transport data providers and consultancies. Data on international maritime freight excludes transhipments and domestic maritime freight volumes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cargo flows originating in or destined to landlocked countries are attributed to the ports of neighbouring coastal transit countries. The mode of transport &amp;#x201C;maritime&amp;#x201D; is assigned to an international trade transaction when the goods arrived at the country&amp;#x2019;s external border (the seaport) transported by ship. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data on container port traffic include full and empty containers as well as transhipment traffic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data is collected and compiled from various websites and reports, including, by port and industry associations and authorities, national statistics offices, UN Monthly Bulletin of Statistics, governments, specialised agencies such as the International Energy Agency (IEA), the US Energy Information Administration (EIA), the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC), and British Petroleum (BP). Data is also collected from reports issued by maritime specialised sources such as Drewry Maritime Research (DMR), Clarksons Research Services (CRS), Dynamar, and Lloyd&amp;#x2019;s List Intelligence (LLI).&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
