<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 16-7-1b, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The public service is the bedrock of government &amp;#x2013; where the development and implementation of public policies and programmes takes place and where society interacts with the government. In most countries, the public service is also the single largest employer. It is in this context that SDG 16, under its target 16.7, encourages countries to ensure that the public service is representative of the people it serves &amp;#x201C;at all levels&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator 16.7.1 focuses on proportional representation in public institutions; it measures the extent to which a country&amp;#x2019;s public institutions are representative of the general population. Proportional representation (also known as &amp;#x2018;descriptive representation&amp;#x2019;) in the public service is concerned with the extent to which the composition of the public service mirrors the various socio-demographic groups in the national population. The underlying assumption is that when the public service reflects the social diversity of a nation, this may lead to greater legitimacy of the public service in the eyes of citizens, as public servants resemble the people they provide services to. Proportional representation has been found to be associated with higher levels of trust in public institutions, as people perceive more inclusive policymaking processes to improve the quality and fairness of policy decisions, and to help curb the undue influence of vested interests over decision-making.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-13&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-13&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-13&quot;&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; See OECD (2017), &lt;em&gt;Trust and Public Policy: How Better Governance Can Help Rebuild Public Trust.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-13&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
