<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 4-2-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UNICEF undertakes a wide consultative process of compiling and assessing data from national sources for the purposes of updating its global databases on the situation of children. Up until 2017, the mechanism UNICEF used to collaborate with national authorities on ensuring data quality and international comparability on key indicators of relevance to children was known as Country Data Reporting on the Indicators for the Goals (CRING).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of 2018, UNICEF launched a new country consultation process with national authorities on selected child-related global SDG indicators it is custodian or co-custodian to meet emerging standards and guidelines on data flows for global reporting of SDG indicators, which place strong emphasis on technical rigour, country ownership and use of official data and statistics. The consultation process solicited feedback directly from National Statistical Offices, as well as other government agencies responsible for official statistics, on the compilation of the indicators, including the data sources used, and the application of internationally agreed definitions, classification and methodologies to the data from that source. Once reviewed, feedback is made available to countries on whether or not specific data points are accepted, and if not, the reasons why. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;L’UNICEF entreprend un vaste processus consultatif de compilation et d’évaluation des données provenant de sources nationales aux fins de la mise à jour de ses bases de données mondiales sur la situation des enfants. Jusqu’en 2017, le mécanisme utilisé par l’UNICEF pour collaborer avec les autorités nationales afin d’assurer la qualité des données et la comparabilité internationale sur les indicateurs clés pertinents pour les enfants était connu sous le nom de rapport de données par pays sur les indicateurs pour les objectifs (Country Data Reporting on the Indicators for the Goals (CRING)). &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;À partir de 2018, l’UNICEF a lancé un nouveau processus de consultation par pays avec les autorités nationales sur certains indicateurs mondiaux des ODD liés aux enfants, pour lesquels il est gardien ou co-gardien, pour répondre aux normes et directives émergentes sur les flux de données pour la déclaration mondiale des indicateurs des ODD, qui mettent fortement l’accent sur la rigueur technique, l’appropriation par les pays et l’utilisation des données et statistiques officielles. Le processus de consultation a sollicité des commentaires directement des bureaux nationaux de statistique, ainsi que d’autres organismes gouvernementaux responsables des statistiques officielles, sur la compilation des indicateurs, y compris les sources de données utilisées, et l’application des définitions, classifications et méthodologies convenues au niveau international aux données provenant de cette source. Une fois examinés, les pays peuvent faire part de leurs commentaires sur l’acceptation de points de données spécifiques et, dans le cas contraire, sur les raisons pour lesquelles ils ne sont pas acceptés. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
