<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 4-2-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proportion of children aged 24 to 59 months who are developmentally on track in health, learning and psychosocial well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The domains included in the indicator for SDG indicator 4.2.1 include the following concepts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Health&lt;/strong&gt;: gross motor development, fine motor development and self-care.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning&lt;/strong&gt;: expressive language, literacy, numeracy, pre-writing, and executive functioning.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psychosocial well-being: &lt;/strong&gt;emotional skills, social skills, internalizing behavior, and externalizing behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recommended measure for SDG 4.2.1 is the Early Childhood Development Index 2030 (ECDI2030) which is a 20-item instrument to measure developmental outcomes among children aged 24 to 59 months in population-based surveys. The indicator derived from the ECDI2030 is the proportion of children aged 24 to 59 months who have achieved the minimum number of milestones expected for their age group, defined as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Children age 24 to 29 months are classified as developmentally on-track if they have achieved at least 7 milestones;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Children age 30 to 35 months are classified as developmentally on-track if they have achieved at least 9 milestones;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Children age 36 to 41 months are classified as developmentally on-track if they have achieved at least 11 milestones;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Children age 42 to 47 months are classified as developmentally on-track if they have achieved at least 13 milestones;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Children age 48 to 59 months are classified as developmentally on-track if they have achieved at least 15 milestones. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportion d&apos;enfants âgés de 24 à 59 mois dont le développement est sur la bonne voie en matière de santé, d&apos;apprentissage et de bien-être psychosocial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concept :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les domaines inclus dans l&apos;indicateur 4.2.1 des ODD incluent les concepts suivants :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Santé&lt;/strong&gt; : développement de la motricité globale, développement de la motricité fine et soins personnels.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apprentissage&lt;/strong&gt; : langage expressif, littératie, numératie, pré-écriture et fonctionnement exécutif.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bien-être psychosocial : &lt;/strong&gt;compétences émotionnelles, compétences sociales, comportement d&apos;intériorisation et comportement d&apos;extériorisation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La mesure recommandée pour l&apos;indicateur 4.2.1 des ODD est l&apos;Indice de développement de la petite enfance 2030 (ECDI2030), qui est un instrument à 20 éléments permettant de mesurer les résultats développementaux chez les enfants âgés de 24 à 59 mois dans des enquêtes basées sur la population. L&apos;indicateur issu de l&apos;ECDI2030 est la proportion d&apos;enfants âgés de 24 à 59 mois ayant atteint le nombre minimum d&apos;étapes attendues pour leur tranche d&apos;âge, défini comme suit :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les enfants âgés de 24 à 29 mois sont classés comme étant en bonne voie de développement s&apos;ils ont atteint au moins 7 étapes;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les enfants âgés de 30 à 35 mois sont classés comme étant en bonne voie de développement s&apos;ils ont atteint au moins 9 étapes;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les enfants âgés de 36 à 41 mois sont classés comme étant en bonne voie de développement s&apos;ils ont atteint au moins 11 étapes;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les enfants âgés de 42 à 47 mois sont classés comme étant en bonne voie de développement s&apos;ils ont atteint au moins 13 étapes;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les enfants âgés de 48 à 59 mois sont classés comme étant en bonne voie de développement s&apos;ils ont atteint au moins 15 étapes. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
