<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 6-6-1a, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sub-Indicator 1:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Open water spatial extent data, acquired by the Landsat 5, 7 and 8 satellites at a 30 m resolution, has been generated for the entire globe from 2001-2015. From 2016 onwards (up to and including 2030), higher spatial and temporal resolution satellites, including both optical and radar satellites, will be used. For example, 20 m Sentinel 1 (radar) and 10 m Sentinel 2 (optical) satellites, used in combination with Landsat satellites, will allow for a more precise delineation of water bodies both in spatial terms (due to the higher spatial resolution) and in temporal terms (due to the higher revisit time). Additional datasets will be used refine open water spatial extent data, including the Global Reservoir and Dam (GRanD) geospatial database. To generate spatial extent of vegetated wetlands, a combination of imagery from Landsat 8 and Sentinel 1 and 2 will be used. This will be augmented by other existing global datasets such as the Global Mangrove Watch (GMW) annual mangrove maps, as well as the most locally-adapted geospatial datasets capturing topography, hydrography, drainage networks, and soil types. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sub-Indicator 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Chl and TSS lake observations are obtained from combined Landsat and Sentinel satellites paired with instruments like OLCI, MODIS, and VIIRS. The sensor instruments used to detect TSS and Chl determine the spatial resolution of water quality within lakes which can be detected. Some of the more accurate water quality sensors have 250-350 meter resolution, while less accurate sensors can detect TSS and Chl changes to 100 m resolution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sub-Indicator 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: The source of data for monitoring discharge for this Sub-Indicator is primarily from ground in situ measurements within rivers and estuaries, though modelled data is also acceptable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sub-Indicator 4&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: The source of data for monitoring water quality for this Sub-Indicator is from ground in situ measurements within water-related ecosystems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sub-Indicator 5&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: The source of data for monitoring groundwater quantity for this Sub-Indicator is from ground in situ measurements of groundwater level within aquifers, though modelled data is also acceptable. &lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
