<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 1-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Poverty has many dimensions. It is not only a lack of material well-being but also a lack of opportunities to live a tolerable life. The international extreme poverty line was updated in 2015 to 1.90 USD per day using 2011 purchasing power parity (WB 2015). Living under the extreme poverty line often encompasses deprivations of safe drinking water, proper sanitation, access to modern energy, sustainable mobility to economic resources, information technology, healthcare, education, etc. Poverty is also a manifestation of hunger and malnutrition, limited access to education and other basic services, social discrimination and exclusion as well as the lack of participation in decision-making. In other words, poverty is multidimensional and covers many aspects of life ranging from access to opportunities, livelihoods and means of survival. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the different aspects of poverty, this indicator focuses on &amp;#x2018;access to basic services&amp;#x2019;. Providing access to basic services such as safe drinking water, sanitation facilities, sustainable energy and mobility, housing, education, healthcare etc, helps to improve the quality of life of the poor. The lack of basic services provision and the lack of empowerment and involvement of local governments in basic service delivery undermine the economic growth and quality of life in any community. Adequate basic service delivery systems promote socio-economic improvements and help to achieve economic growth, social inclusion, poverty reduction and equality. More specifically, improved basic services can help to raise well-being and productivity of communities, create jobs, save time and human effort in transporting water, support food security, better use of energy, production of essential commodities, improve health (by making medical care, clean water or solid waste collection available) or enhance the level of education. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Quito implementation plan for the New Urban Agenda adopted in Habitat III conference, member states commit to &amp;#x201C;promoting equitable and affordable access to sustainable basic physical and social infrastructure for all, without discrimination, including affordable serviced land, housing, modern and renewable energy, safe drinking water and sanitation, safe, nutritious and adequate food, waste disposal, sustainable mobility, health care and family planning, education, culture, and information and communications technologies&amp;#x201D; . They further commit to &amp;#x201C;ensuring that these services are responsive to the rights and needs of women, children and youth, older persons and persons with disabilities, migrants, indigenous peoples and local communities, as appropriate, and to those of others in vulnerable situations&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic service delivery must move towards a demand-driven approach, which is appropriate for the local needs &amp;#x2013; and hence able to respond to the concept of &amp;#x201C;Access for all&amp;#x201D; &amp;#x2013; as stated in the NUA. Basic services are fundamental to improving living standards. Governments have the responsibility for their provision. This indicator will measure levels of accessibility to basic services and guide the efforts of governments for provision of equitable basic services for all to eradicate poverty.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La pobreza tiene muchas dimensiones. No es solo la falta de bienestar material, sino también la falta de oportunidades para llevar una vida tolerable. La línea internacional de pobreza extrema se actualizó en 2015 a 1,90 USD al día utilizando la paridad de poder adquisitivo de 2011 (BM 2015). Vivir por debajo de la línea de pobreza extrema suele conllevar privaciones de agua potable, saneamiento adecuado, acceso a la energía moderna, movilidad sostenible a los recursos económicos, tecnología de la información, atención sanitaria, educación, etc. La pobreza es también una manifestación del hambre y la malnutrición, el acceso limitado a la educación y otros servicios básicos, la discriminación y la exclusión social, así como la falta de participación en la toma de decisiones. En otras palabras, la pobreza es multidimensional y abarca muchos aspectos de la vida que van desde el acceso a las oportunidades, los medios de vida y los medios de supervivencia. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entre los diferentes aspectos de la pobreza, este indicador se centra en el &amp;#x2018;acceso a los servicios básicos&amp;#x2019;. El acceso a servicios básicos como el agua potable, las instalaciones de saneamiento, la energía y la movilidad sostenibles, la vivienda, la educación, la atención sanitaria, etc., contribuye a mejorar la calidad de vida de los pobres. La falta de prestación de servicios básicos y la falta de capacitación y participación de los gobiernos locales en la prestación de servicios básicos socavan el crecimiento económico y la calidad de vida de cualquier comunidad. Los sistemas adecuados de prestación de servicios básicos promueven mejoras socioeconómicas y ayudan a lograr el crecimiento económico, la inclusión social, la reducción de la pobreza y la igualdad. Más concretamente, la mejora de los servicios básicos puede contribuir a aumentar el bienestar y la productividad de las comunidades, crear puestos de trabajo, ahorrar tiempo y esfuerzo humano en el transporte de agua, apoyar la seguridad alimentaria, un mejor uso de la energía, la producción de productos básicos, mejorar la salud (poniendo a disposición de los ciudadanos atención médica, agua potable o recolección de residuos sólidos) o aumentar el nivel de educación. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En el plan de implementación de Quito para la Nueva Agenda Urbana adoptado en la conferencia Hábitat III, los estados miembros se comprometen a &amp;#x201C;promover el acceso equitativo y asequible a infraestructuras físicas y sociales básicas sostenibles para todos, sin discriminación, incluyendo terrenos con servicios asequibles, vivienda, energía moderna y renovable, agua potable y saneamiento, alimentos seguros, nutritivos y adecuados, eliminación de residuos, movilidad sostenible, atención sanitaria y planificación familiar, educación, cultura y tecnologías de la información y la comunicación&amp;#x201D;. Además, se comprometen a &amp;#x201C;garantizar que estos servicios respondan a los derechos y las necesidades de las mujeres, los niños y los jóvenes, las personas mayores y las personas con discapacidad, los migrantes, los pueblos indígenas y las comunidades locales, según corresponda, y a los de otras personas en situación de vulnerabilidad&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La prestación de servicios básicos debe avanzar hacia un enfoque basado en la demanda, que se adapte a las necesidades locales &amp;#x2013; y, por lo tanto, sea capaz de responder al concepto de &amp;#x201C;Acceso para todos&amp;#x201D; &amp;#x2013;, tal como se establece en la NAU. Los servicios básicos son fundamentales para mejorar el nivel de vida. Los gobiernos tienen la responsabilidad de su prestación. Este indicador medirá los niveles de accesibilidad a los servicios básicos y orientará los esfuerzos de los gobiernos para la prestación de servicios básicos equitativos para todos con el fin de erradicar la pobreza.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;La pauvreté a de nombreuses dimensions. Il ne s&apos;agit pas seulement d&apos;un manque de bien-être matériel, mais aussi d&apos;un manque de possibilités de mener une vie tolérable. Le seuil international d&apos;extrême pauvreté a été mis à jour en 2015 à 1,90 dollar américain par jour en utilisant la parité de pouvoir d&apos;achat de 2011 (Banque Mondiale, 2015). Vivre sous le seuil d&apos;extrême pauvreté implique souvent des privations en fait d&apos;eau potable, d&apos;installations sanitaires adéquates, d&apos;accès à l&apos;énergie moderne, de mobilité durable vers les ressources économiques, des technologies de l&apos;information, des soins de santé, l&apos;éducation, etc. La pauvreté est également une manifestation de la faim et de la malnutrition, d&apos;un accès limité à d&apos;éducation et aux autres services de base, de la discrimination et de l&apos;exclusion sociales ainsi que d&apos;un manque de participation à la prise de décision. En d&apos;autres termes, la pauvreté est multidimensionnelle et couvre de nombreux aspects de la vie, incluant l&apos;accès aux opportunités, aux moyens de subsistance et aux moyens de survie. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parmi les différents aspects de la pauvreté, cet indicateur se concentre sur « l&apos;accès aux services de base ». L&apos;accès aux services de base tels que l&apos;eau potable, les installations sanitaires, l&apos;énergie et la mobilité durables, le logement, l&apos;éducation, les soins de santé, etc. , contribue à améliorer la qualité de vie des pauvres. L&apos;absence de fourniture de services de base et le manque d&apos;autonomisation et d&apos;implication des gouvernements locaux dans la fourniture de services de base sapent la croissance économique et la qualité de vie de toute communauté. Des systèmes adéquats de prestation de services de base favorisent les améliorations socioéconomiques et contribuent à la croissance économique, à l&apos;inclusion sociale, à la réduction de la pauvreté et à l&apos;égalité. Plus précisément, l&apos;amélioration des services de base peut contribuer à accroître le bien-être et la productivité des communautés, à créer des emplois, à économiser du temps et des efforts humains dans le transport de l&apos;eau, à soutenir la sécurité alimentaire, à une meilleure utilisation de l&apos;énergie, à la production de produits de base essentiels, à améliorer la santé (en rendant disponible des soins médicaux, de l&apos;eau propre ou la collecte des déchets solides) ou à relever le niveau d&apos;éducation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dans le cadre du plan de mise en œuvre de Quito pour le nouvel agenda urbain adopté lors de la conférence Habitat III, les États membres s&apos;engagent à « promouvoir un accès équitable et abordable à des infrastructures physiques et sociales de base durables pour tous, sans discrimination, y compris des terrains aménagés à un prix abordable, des logements, des énergies modernes et renouvelables, de l&apos;eau potable et des installations sanitaires, une alimentation sûre, nutritive et adéquate, l&apos;élimination des déchets, la mobilité durable, les soins de santé et la planification familiale, l&apos;éducation, la culture et les technologies de l&apos;information et des communications ». Ils s&apos;engagent en outre à « veiller à ce que ces services répondent aux droits et aux besoins des femmes, des enfants et des jeunes, des personnes âgées et des personnes handicapées, des migrants, des populations autochtones et des communautés locales, selon le cas, et à ceux des autres personnes en situation de vulnérabilité ».&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La fourniture de services de base doit évoluer vers une approche appropriée aux besoins locaux axée sur la demande, et donc capable de répondre au concept d&apos;« accessibllité pour tous » , tel qu&apos;il est énoncé dans le Nouveau programme pour les villes. Les services de base sont essentiels à l&apos;amélioration du niveau de vie. Les gouvernements sont responsables de leur fourniture. Cet indicateur mesurera les niveaux d&apos;accessibilité aux services de base et guidera les efforts des gouvernements pour la fourniture de services de base équitables pour tous afin d&apos;éradiquer la pauvreté. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt;Обоснование:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;У бедности много аспектов. Это не только недостаточное материальное благосостояние, но и отсутствие возможности жить сносной жизнью. В 2015 году международная черта крайней бедности была установлена на уровне 1,90 доллара США в день с использованием паритета покупательной способности 2011 года (ВБ 2015). Жизнь за чертой крайней бедности часто означает отсутствие доступа к безопасной питьевой воде, надлежащей санитарии, современным источникам энергии, устойчивого мобильного доступа к экономическим ресурсам, информационным технологиям, здравоохранению, образованию и т. д. Бедность также является проявлением голода и недоедания, ограниченного доступа к образованию и другим базовым услугам, социальной дискриминации и изоляции, а также недостаточного участия в процессе принятия решений. Другими словами, бедность многомерна и охватывает многие аспекты жизни, начиная от доступа к возможностям, средствам существования и выживания.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Среди различных аспектов бедности этот показатель фокусируется на доступе к основным услугам. Предоставление доступа к основным услугам, таким как безопасная питьевая вода, средства санитарии, устойчивое энергоснабжение и мобильность, жилье, образование, здравоохранение и т. д. помогает улучшить качество жизни бедных. Отсутствие предоставления доступа к базовым услугам и отсутствие полномочий и недостаточное участие местных органов власти в предоставлении базовых услуг подрывают экономический рост и качество жизни в любом сообществе. Адекватные системы предоставления базовых услуг способствуют социально-экономическим улучшениям и помогают достичь экономического роста, социальной интеграции, сокращения бедности и установления равенства. В частности, улучшенные базовые услуги могут помочь повысить благосостояние и продуктивность местного населения, создать рабочие места, сэкономить время и человеческие усилия при доставке воды, поддержать продовольственную безопасность, улучшить использование энергии, обеспечить производство товаров первой необходимости, улучшить здоровье (за счет организации медицинской помощи, доступа к чистой воде или сбора твердых отходов) или повысить уровень образования.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;В Плане Кито по реализации Новой программы развития городов, принятом на конференции Хабитат III, государства-члены обязуются содействовать равноправному и приемлемому по цене доступу к устойчивой базовой материальной и социальной инфраструктуре для всех без дискриминации, включая приемлемую по цене обслуживания землю, жилье, современные и возобновляемые источники энергии, безопасную питьевую воду и санитарию, безопасное, сытное и достаточное питание, удаление отходов, устойчивую мобильность, здравоохранение и планирование семьи, образование, культуру и информационные и коммуникационные технологии. Они также обязуются гарантировать, чтобы эти услуги обеспечивали права и потребности женщин, детей и молодежи, пожилых людей и лиц с ограниченными возможностями, мигрантов, коренных народов и местных сообществ, сообразно обстоятельствам, а также другим лицам, находящимся в уязвимом положении.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;При предоставлении базовых услуг необходимо перейти к подходу, основанному на спросе, который соответствует местным потребностям и, следовательно, может соответствовать понятию Доступ для всех как указано в Новой программе развития городов. Базовые услуги имеют основополагающее значение для повышения уровня жизни. Правительства несут ответственность за их предоставление. Этот показатель будет оценивать уровни доступности основных услуг и направлять усилия правительств на предоставление справедливых базовых услуг для всех в целях искоренения бедности.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
