<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 1-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main source of data for this indicator remains household surveys including DHS, MICS, LSMS, World Bank, UNICEF and UNDP, the censuses and administrative data. These data sources are also described in the various metadata for the constituent SDG indicators. A lot of the pre-processed data is also derived from the SDG indicators that form this indicator. data sources can be other SDG indicators monitoring results as well as additional data from household survey.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La principal fuente de datos para este indicador siguen siendo las encuestas de hogares, incluyendo DHS, MICS, LSMS, Banco Mundial, UNICEF y PNUD, los censos y los datos administrativos. Estas fuentes de datos también se describen en los distintos metadatos de los indicadores de los ODS. Las fuentes de datos pueden ser los resultados del seguimiento de otros indicadores de los ODS, así como datos adicionales de las encuestas de hogares.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Sources de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La principale source de données pour cet indicateur reste les enquêtes sur les ménages, notamment les Enquêtes Démographiques et de Santé (EDS), les Multiple Indicator Cluster Surveys (MICS), les Living Standards Measurement Study (LSMS), la Banque mondiale, l&apos;UNICEF et le PNUD, les recensements et les données administratives. Ces sources de données sont également décrites dans les différentes métadonnées des indicateurs ODD constitutifs. Une grande partie des données prétraitées est également dérivée des indicateurs ODD qui constituent cet indicateur. Les sources de données peuvent être d&apos;autres indicateurs ODD qui suivent les résultats ainsi que des données supplémentaires provenant des enquêtes auprès des ménages. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Основным источником данных для этого показателя остаются обследования домашних хозяйств, включая DHS (Demographic and Health Survey - Обследование демографических характеристик и состояния здоровья), MICS (Multiple indicator cluster survey - Кластерное исследование с множественными показателями), LSMS (Living Standards Measurement Study - Исследование критериев оценки уровня жизни), данные Всемирного банка, ЮНИСЕФ и ПРООН, переписей населения и административные данные. Эти источники данных также описаны в различных метаданных для показателей, составляющих ЦУР. Многие предварительно обработанные данные также получены из показателей ЦУР, которые образуют этот показатель. Источниками данных могут быть результаты мониторинга других показателей ЦУР, а также дополнительные данные обследования домашних хозяйств. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
