<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 14-3-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The official counterparts are the IOC focal points. They, as well as National Oceanographic Data Centres (NODCs), are contacted by IOC to request relevant data from the appropriate national oceanographic data centres and/or relevant scientists, agencies or programmes. An annual data submission request is sent out via IOC Circular Letters directly to the member states asking for the respective data and metadata (through circular letter &lt;a href=&quot;https://oceanexpert.org/document/26312&quot;&gt;2792&lt;/a&gt; in 2019, circular letter &lt;a href=&quot;https://oceanexpert.org/document/27502&quot;&gt;2815&lt;/a&gt; in 2020 and circular letter &lt;a href=&quot;https://unesdoc.unesco.org/ark:/48223/pf0000379637&quot;&gt;2859&lt;/a&gt; in 2021). New updates and the inclusion of new features to the SDG 14.3.1 data portal to be developed in 2022 will facilitate with collaboration with other existing ocean carbon data centres and biogeochemical data platforms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, IOC benefits from direct contributions from ocean acidification scientists organized within the Global Ocean Acidification Observing Network (GOA-ON) to the SDG 14.3.1 data portal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All contributors of data to SDG 14.3.1 are encouraged to read and follow the standard operating procedures provided in Dickson et al. 2007. This document covers ocean carbon chemistry, sample-handling techniques, quality assurance procedures, the use of Certified Reference Materials (CRMs) and Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs) for discrete sampling of pH, &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;, TA, and DIC. Data contributors are also encouraged to read the Guide to Best Practices in Ocean Acidification Research and Data Reporting, which focuses on best practices for laboratory experiments, but also includes background on carbon chemistry (Riebesell et al. 2010). For coastal environments, which can be subject to large variability and a range of influences, such as nutrient and freshwater inputs, guidelines for the measurement of pH and carbonate chemistry can be found here (Pimenta and Grear 2018).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All data submitted to SDG 14.3.1 must include an estimate of measurement uncertainty in the metadata. Autonomous sensors for pH and &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; require calibration and maintenance to validate sensor performance and identify drift or sensor malfunction. Where possible, the analysis of discrete bottle samples analysed for pH, DIC or TA collected next to the sensors can be used to calculate pH and &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All ocean acidity datasets submitted to SDG 14.3.1 must also include associated temperature (in situ [and temperature of measurement if different than in situ]), salinity, and pressure (sampling depth). If submitting pH values, all pH values must be on the total scale (Dickson et al. 2007).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
