<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The QUALITY_ASSURE field for indicator 14-3-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Data quality control and validation processes were developed in close consultation with experts in the field of ocean acidification, amongst them members of the Global Ocean Acidification Observing Network (GOA-ON) and data management experts, like the ones at IODE. Data quality control is a critical component of the data analysis, submission and processing. Scientists and technicians who collected the submitted data will be responsible for the primary quality control of the data and accompanying detailed metadata. The metadata submitted with the data must also describe the quality control standard operating procedures (SOPs) followed for each parameter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Primary quality control by data provider consists of:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quality control that is attached to the methodology (CRMs, tris buffer calibration, SOPs are provided),&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quality control and quality assurance of the actual data (SOPs are provided) and usage of community agreed quality flags,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identifying and flagging of outliers, &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Making determinations regarding validity of those outlying points,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimating uncertainty of the measurement,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identifying all the sources of uncertainty in the measurements,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rolling up the individual uncertainties into overall uncertainty (error propagation).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Secondary quality control by IOC Secretariat and experts:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Harmonization of the data and ensuring metadata completeness,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;External quality control/audit &amp;#x2013; Expert QC Group applying the weather and climate levels as defined by GOA-ON (following the example of SOCAT),&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feedback to data holders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
