<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DOC_METHOD field for indicator 6-5-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;National focal points selected by each country. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;National focal points are responsible for coordinating a national process to engage governmental and non-governmental stakeholders, as appropriate in the context of each country, to develop draft responses and finalise responses. This may be via email, workshops, and online notices. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The following guidance materials are available for national focal points in 7 languages (English, Spanish, French, Arabic, Russian, Chinese, Portuguese), at &lt;a href=&quot;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org/about&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org/about&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&lt;/a&gt;: the survey (MS Word); a detailed monitoring guide; and a PowerPoint presentation and video recording. In addition, focal points may access the following country-level materials at &lt;a href=&quot;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org/countrydatabase&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org/countrydatabase&lt;/a&gt;: the 2017 and 2020 baseline surveys and 2-page results summaries (for 186 countries); and 2017 and 2020 workshop reports (for 36 countries) from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwp.org/en/sdg6support/sdgmap/&quot;&gt;https://www.gwp.org/en/sdg6support/sdgmap/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In addition, an &amp;#x201C;SDG 6.5.1 Facilitator&amp;#x2019;s Training Course&amp;#x201D; is available online via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwp.org/en/sdg6support/consultations/where-we-are/stage-1-activities/&quot;&gt;https://www.gwp.org/en/sdg6support/consultations/where-we-are/stage-1-activities/&lt;/a&gt; , through the SDG 6 IWRM Support Programme. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A more comprehensive &amp;#x201C;IWRM Stage 1 Support Package&amp;#x201D; is available for a limited number of countries (approximately 60 countries in 2020) see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwp.org/en/sdg6support/consultations/where-we-are/stage-1-activities/&quot;&gt;https://www.gwp.org/en/sdg6support/consultations/where-we-are/stage-1-activities/&lt;/a&gt;. The Support Package includes seed funding to engage a Facilitator to support the stakeholder consultation process. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extensive explanations are provided in the monitoring guide and in the survey itself. The survey contains: an overall introduction and explanation; a glossary; an introduction and glossary in each of the four sections; threshold descriptions for six thresholds for each question; and a number of footnotes to explain aspects of questions or threshold descriptions. All materials can be downloaded from &lt;a href=&quot;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&lt;/a&gt;. In addition, a dedicated Help Desk is available to provide assistance at all times. The Help Desk is accessible via email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:iwrmsdg651@un.org&quot;&gt;iwrmsdg651@un.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
