<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 6-3-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;Good ambient water quality is essential for protecting aquatic ecosystems and the services they provide, including: the preservation of biodiversity; the protection of human health during recreational use and through the provision of drinking water; the support of human nutrition through the provision of fish and water for irrigation; the enabling of a variety of economic activities; and the strengthening of the resilience of people against water-related disasters. Good ambient water quality is therefore closely linked to the achievement of many other Sustainable Development Goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Target 6.3 aims at improving water quality and indicator 6.3.2 provides a mechanism for determining whether, and to which extent, water quality management measures are contributing to the improvement of water quality over time. The indicator is also directly linked to indicator 6.3.1 on wastewater treatment because inadequate wastewater treatment leads to degradation in quality of the waters receiving the wastewater effluents. It directly informs progress towards target 6.3 and is strongly linked to target 6.6 on water-related ecosystems, as well as target 14.1 on marine pollution (coastal eutrophication).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The methodology recognises that countries have different capacity levels to monitor water quality, with many developed countries operating extensive and complex programmes that collect and report data to existing reporting frameworks beyond the scope of this methodology. For these countries it is recognised that this methodology will not contribute to improving their water quality; however it must be sufficiently flexible to capture data from existing monitoring frameworks without burdening countries with additional reporting obligations. Conversely, many of the least developed countries currently do not monitor water quality or operate very limited monitoring programmes. The methodology must therefore allow these countries to contribute to the global indicator, according to their national capacity and available resources. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The development of the methodology builds on best practice for water quality monitoring promoted by the UN Environment GEMS/Water programme since 1978 together with testing by several pilot countries during the Integrated Monitoring Initiative Proof of Concept phase of 2016, and external review by experts and international organizations. This led to revision of the original methodology, which was then further tested through the 2017 global data drive. The feedback received has contributed to the present refined methodology.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
