<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The ADJUSTMENT field for indicator 2-3-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The Average income of small-scale food producers in constant PPP 2011 USD is in the dataset in local currency units (LCU). For each country and year, the LCU labour value of production has to be converted into PPP 2011 USD. The process first consists on accounting for inflation in the currency, for which the Consumer Price Index (CPI) of each country is used; once deflated, it is converted into PPP 2011 USD, which allows for a homogenous standard of the indicator. SDG 2.3 not only focuses on small-scale farmers, but also on women and people with indigenous status. The indicator (which is at the household level) is then calculated disaggregated by sex of the household head or producer (depending on whether a household or an agricultural survey was used), that is, whether the household head or producer is female or male headed.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Le revenu moyen des petits producteurs alimentaires en USD 2011 PPA constante se trouve dans l’ensemble de données en unités monétaires locales (UML). Pour chaque pays et chaque année, la valeur de la main-d&apos;oeuvre de production en UML doit être convertie en USD 2011 PPA. Le processus consiste d’abord à comptabiliser l’inflation dans la monnaie, pour laquelle l’indice des prix à la consommation (IPC) de chaque pays est utilisé; une fois déflaté, elle est convertie en USD 2011 PPA, ce qui permet une norme homogène de l’indicateur. L’ODD 2.3 ne se concentre pas seulement sur les petits agriculteurs, mais aussi sur les femmes et les personnes ayant le statut d’autochtone. L’indicateur (qui se situe au niveau du ménage) est ensuite calculé et ventilé par sexe du chef de ménage ou du producteur (selon qu’une enquête auprès du ménage ou une enquête agricole a été utilisée), c’est-à-dire si le chef de ménage ou le producteur est une femme ou un homme. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
