<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 2-3-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Given the approved methodology, the computation of the indicator requires survey microdata collected at the farm level on a wide range of variables &amp;#x2013; including all elements allowing to compute revenues and costs of the enterprise together with labour input and the availability of land and livestock &amp;#x2013; referred to the same production unit. Such type of surveys are seldom collected at the national level. For this reason, the availability of data for the indicator is altogether limited. In some countries, data can be obtained from household surveys reporting details on agricultural production. These data sources have to be considered as second-best solution, given that their sampling is focused on households and not on food production units. While in many countries there is a considerable degree of overlap between the population of food producers and households, this is still a partial overlap, which can undermine the accuracy of the computation. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Compte tenu de la méthodologie approuvée, le calcul de l&apos;indicateur nécessite des microdonnées d&apos;enquête recueillies au niveau de l&apos;exploitation sur un large éventail de variables – y compris tous les éléments permettant de calculer les revenus et les coûts de l&apos;entreprise, ainsi que la main-d&apos;œuvre et la disponibilité des terres et du bétail – pour la même unité de production. Ce type d&apos;enquêtes est rarement fait au niveau national. Pour cette raison, la disponibilité des données pour cet indicateur est tout à fait limitée. Dans certains pays, les données peuvent être obtenues à partir d&apos;enquêtes sur les ménages qui fournissent des détails sur la production agricole. Ces sources de données doivent être considérées comme une solution de second choix, étant donné que leur échantillonnage est axé sur les ménages et non sur les unités de production alimentaire. Bien que dans de nombreux pays, il existe un degré considérable de chevauchement entre la population des producteurs alimentaires et celle des ménages, il s&apos;agit toujours d&apos;un chevauchement partiel, ce qui peut nuire à la précision du calcul. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
