<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_SOURCE field for indicator 12-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Data providers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focal Points and Competent Authorities for the Basel Conventions (185 Parties);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Designated National Authorities and Official contact points for the Rotterdam Convention (180 Parties);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Official contact points and national focal points for Stockholm Convention (156 Parties);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focal points for Montreal Protocol (197 Parties);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focal points for information exchange and national focal points for the Minamata Convention (currently 35 Parties).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Fournisseurs de données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Points focaux et Autorités compétentes pour les Conventions de Bâle (185 Parties) ; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Autorités nationales désignées et points de contact officiels pour la Convention de Rotterdam (180 Parties) ; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Points de contact officiels et points focaux nationaux pour la Convention de Stockholm (156 Parties) ;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Points focaux pour le Protocole de Montréal (197 Parties) ;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Points focaux pour l&apos;échange d&apos;informations et points focaux nationaux pour la Convention de Minamata (actuellement 35 Parties).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Поставщики данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Координаторы и компетентные органы по Базельской конвенции (185 Сторон); &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Назначенные уполномоченные национальные органы и официальные контактные лица по Роттердамской конвенции (180 Сторон); &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Официальные контактные лица и национальные координаторы по Стокгольмской конвенции (156 Сторон); &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Координаторы по Монреальскому протоколу (197 Сторон); &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Координаторы по обмену информацией и национальные координаторы по Минаматской конвенции (в настоящее время 35 Сторон). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
