<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The QUALITY_ASSURE field for indicator 12-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;For the &lt;strong&gt;Basel, Rotterdam and Stockholm Conventions&lt;/strong&gt; the Electronic Reporting System is the tool to be used by Parties to submit their national reports. For guidelines, please see the responses to the question in 4(h).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reporting format for the &lt;strong&gt;Minamata Convention&lt;/strong&gt; has been adopted by the first Conference of the Parties (COP) for the submission of national reports pursuant to Article 21. The Secretariat drafted guidance for the short reports (4 questions) to assist Parties. In decision MC-3/13, on guidance for completing the national reporting format, the COP, recognized the need for a complete and consistent national reporting to provide information for the effectiveness evaluation and for supporting compliance, and requested the secretariat to prepare draft guidance for the full national reporting format to clarify the information being sought. A draft of the Guidance was circulated on 20 May 2021, and has been provisionally used to inform the completion of the first full national reports due by 31 December 2021. The draft guidance is under consideration at the fourth meeting of the COP of the Minamata Convention in March 2022. . An online reporting tool was developed and launched by the Secretariat on 7 September 2021 to assist Parties and facilitate collecting the information for the reports. Under the Minamata Convention, the responsibility for quality assurance of the submitted data and information lies with the Parties. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the &lt;strong&gt;Montreal Protocol&lt;/strong&gt;, the responsibility for quality assurance of the submitted data and information lies with the Parties. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
