<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 12-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The transmission of information as required by the five Conventions follows a different timing. This is the reason why the reporting to this indicator has been scheduled for 5-year cycles, which would allow capturing the compliance of Parties with the transmission of information of all the Conventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please also note that the timing for submission of reporting for the Minamata Convention has been agreed upon under decision MC-1/8, with the deadlines for the short and full reporting: 31 December 2019 as the deadline for the first short national report and 31 December 2021 as the deadline for the first full national report. Based on the prescribed deadlines, it therefore follows that for the first short reports the reporting period covers 16 August 2017 (the date of entry into force of the Convention) to 31 December 2018 (to be submitted by 31 December 2019), and for the first full reports the reporting period covers 16 August 2017 to 31 December 2020 (to be submitted by 31 December 2021). The cycle will then be repeated, with the subsequent short reports covering 1 January 2021 to 31 December 2022 and the subsequent full reports covering 1 January 2021 to 31 December 2024, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La transmisión de información exigida por los cinco Convenios sigue un calendario diferente. Esta es la razón por la que la presentación de informes para este indicador se ha programado para ciclos de 5 años, lo que permitiría captar el cumplimiento de las Partes con la transmisión de información de todos los Convenios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;También hay que tener en cuenta que aún no se ha acordado el calendario de presentación de informes para el Convenio de Minamata. No está claro si se requerirán informes antes de 2020, ni tampoco está claro cuántas veces se requerirán informes antes de 2030. Por lo tanto, el Convenio de Minamata se incluye aquí, pero la presentación de informes está sujeta a nuevas decisiones al respecto.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires et limites : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La transmission d&apos;informations telle que requise par les cinq Conventions suit un calendrier différent. C&apos;est la raison pour laquelle les rapports sur cet indicateur ont été programmés pour des cycles de 5 ans, ce qui permettrait de saisir la conformité des Parties avec la transmission d&apos;informations de toutes les Conventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Veuillez également noter que le calendrier de soumission des rapports pour la Convention de Minamata n&apos;a pas encore été convenu. Il n&apos;est pas clair si des rapports seront exigés avant 2020, ni combien de fois des rapports seront exigés avant 2030. Ainsi, la Convention de Minamata est incluse ici, mais le rapport est soumis à des décisions ultérieures à ce sujet.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Передача информации в соответствии с требованиями пяти конвенций осуществляется в различные сроки. Причина этого в том, что отчетность по этому показателю была запланирована на 5-летние циклы, которые позволили бы фиксировать соблюдение Сторонами передачи информации по всем конвенциям. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Также обратите внимание, что сроки представления отчетности по Минаматской конвенции еще не согласованы. Неясно, потребуется ли какая-либо отчетность до 2020 года, равно как и неясно, сколько раз потребуется представлять отчетность до 2030 года. Таким образом, Минаматская конвенция сюда включена, но вопрос отчетности по ней еще требует принятия решения.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
