<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 9-5-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;The UNESCO Institute for Statistics (UIS) sends out a questionnaire every year to collect research and experimental development (R&amp;amp;D) data from all countries (around 125 countries), which are not covered by the data collections of the other partner organizations such as the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD), Eurostat (Statistical Office of the European Union) and the Network on Science and Technology Indicators &amp;#x2013; Ibero-American and Inter-American (RICYT). In agreement with these three organisations, their data (which were collected from their member states/associated member states &amp;#x2013; around 65 countries-) are directly obtained from the respective databases (in the case of the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development - OECD and Statistical Office of the European Union - Eurostat) or received from the partner (in the case of the Network on Science and Technology Indicators &amp;#x2013; Ibero-American and Inter-American - RICYT). There is also collaboration in Africa with the African Science, Technology and Innovation (STI) Indicators Initiative (ASTII) of the African Union Development Agency-NEPAD (AUDA-NEPAD). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the countries to which the UNESCO Institute for Statistics (UIS) sends a questionnaire, the process is the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A questionnaire is sent to focal points in countries, generally within the Ministry of Science and Technology or the national statistical office.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The UNESCO Institute for Statistics (UIS) processes the questionnaires, communicating with the countries in case of questions, calculates indicators and releases the data and indicators on its website. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Countries are requested to complete the questionnaire using the standard international classifications, therefore adjustments are generally not needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other agencies have similar procedures.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
