<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COMPILING_ORG field for indicator 11-7-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;UN-Habitat is the lead agency on the global reporting for this indicator and as such, has over the last two years coordinated the efforts of various partners, on methodological developments and piloting of data collection. Key among these partners have included National Statistical Offices, New York University, ESRI, FAO, UNGGIM, UCLG, Local government departments, the European Commission, UN regional commissions, KTH University-Sweden, Urban Observatories, etc. Working in partnership with these partners, UN-Habitat has undertaken trainings and capacity development activities in cities, countries and regions, which have contributed to enhanced data collection and setting up of systems to monitor and report on the indicator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, over the last 5 years, UN-Habitat and other partners have held several consultations which have collectively contributed to the refinement of the indicator methodology, and its piloting. Some of the key activities include; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Internal consultations within UN-Habitat and the review of several toolkits of relevance to the subject of public space have provided an initial base of information on concepts and definitions. Lessons learned by UN-Habitat in field projects devoted to public space have proven particularly valuable. &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;A second important source and point of reference has been the Charter of Public Space adopted by the Biennial of Public Space, containing simple and actionable principles for the creation, management and enjoyment of public spaces in cities.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;A third set of sources has been the contributions offered by a team of international experts, both during and immediately following the Expert Group Meeting on Public Space held in Rome in 12-14 January 2014. Additionally, the contributions of over 300 practitioners from over 40 countries during the series of International Conferences on the Future of Places, which developed a set of key messages in advancing the public space agenda at the global level.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;A fourth source has been global consultative meetings organized after the adoption of the 2030 Agenda in line with the SDG requirements for indicator 11.7.1 and global initiatives that have supported the data collection of this indicator. Specifically, these were:&lt;ol&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;The first EGM in October 2016 focused mainly on methodological refinements and on concretising the institutional partnership arrangements for capacity development and data collection. Representatives from the NSOs, Urban Observatories, European Union, World Resources Institute, United Cities and Local Governments, Arab Urban Development Institute, World Health Organization, ESRI, NYU, among others participated in this EGM.&lt;/li&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;The second EGM held in February 2017 focused on the challenges of data collection and review of preliminary data made available through the efforts of collecting city-based monitoring the human settlement data at local levels. &lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ol&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It also focused on the technical aspects of computing the indicator using the proposed methodology. This helped in identifying the challenges and opportunities of improving the methodology as well as strategies to scale up and capacity building for NSOs. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Representatives attended the meeting from Urban Observatories, European Union, World Resources Institute, United Cities and Local Governments, ESRI, Arab Urban Development Institute, UNESCO, Women in Cities (WICI), Universities and private planning firms, senior statisticians from governments, academic institutions, urban planners, etc. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
