<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 11-7-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through a multi-stakeholder collaboration, the major input for this indicator computation &amp;#x2013; a mapping of open public spaces &amp;#x2013; which has been the major gap in its measurement is increasingly being produced at multiple levels. Most of this information is being collated from city land use plans, community mapping activities, volunteered GIS data, as well as through initiatives led by national statistical and mapping agencies as well as UN-Habitat and partners. Detailed data on 712 cities has been produced through multi-stakeholder efforts, and new cities are incrementally being added to a rapidly growing data production system at the local, national, regional and global levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on availability of high-resolution population data, population with access to open public spaces should be disaggregated by age, gender and disability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wherever possible, it would also be useful to have information disaggregated by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Location of public spaces (intra-urban) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quality of the open public space by safety, inclusivity, accessibility, greenness, and comfort &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Type of open space as a share of the city area &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The share of open spaces in public use which are universally accessible, particularly for persons with disabilities. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Type of human settlements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
