<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 11-7-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Satellite imagery (open sources), documentation outlining publicly owned land and community-based maps are the main sources of data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For definition of the city as the unit of analysis, data on the built up areas is required, which can be extracted from existing layers of satellite imagery ranging from open sources such as Google Earth, US Geological Survey/NASA Landsat imagery and Sentinel Imagery to higher resolution land cover data sets and commercial imagery. Images are to be analyzed for the latest available year. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Population data will be sourced from national censuses or other demographic surveys, which can be disaggregated to the smallest units possible through household information aggregation or through population modelling/gridding approaches.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the Inventory of open public space - Information can be obtained from legal documents outlining publicly owned land and well-defined land use plans. In some cases, where this information is lacking, incomplete or outdated, open sources, key informants in the city and community-based maps, which are increasingly recognized as a valid source of information, can be a viable alternative.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The share of land occupied by public open spaces cannot be obtained directly from the use of high-resolution satellite imagery because it is not possible to determine the ownership or use of open spaces through remote sensing. However, fieldwork to validate and verify the open spaces derived from satellite imagery helps to map out land that is for public and non-public use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
