<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COMPARABILITY field for indicator 3-7-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, there is no discrepancy between data presented and data published in survey reports. However, some published national data have been adjusted by the Population Division to improve comparability. Notes are used in the data set to indicate when adjustments were made and where data differed from standard definitions. The global indicator represents all women of reproductive age. Some survey estimates represent women who are married or in a union and this is indicated in a note.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Fuentes de discrepancia:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En general, no hay discrepancias entre los datos presentados y los publicados en los informes de las encuestas. Sin embargo, algunos datos nacionales publicados han sido ajustados por la División de Población para mejorar la comparabilidad. Se utilizan notas en el conjunto de datos para indicar cuándo se hicieron los ajustes y cuándo los datos difieren de las definiciones estándar. El indicador global representa a todas las mujeres en edad reproductiva. Algunas estimaciones de las encuestas representan a las mujeres casadas o en unión libre, lo que se indica en una nota.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Sources des divergences : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En général, il n&apos;y a pas de divergence entre les données présentées et les données publiées dans les rapports d&apos;enquête. Cependant, certaines données nationales publiées ont été ajustées par la Division de la population afin d&apos;améliorer la comparabilité. Des notes sont utilisées dans l&apos;ensemble des données pour indiquer quand les ajustements ont été effectués et quand les données différaient des définitions standards. L&apos;indicateur global représente toutes les femmes en âge de procréer. Certaines estimations de l&apos;enquête représentent les femmes mariées ou en union et ceci est indiqué dans une note.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Как правило, нет никаких расхождений между представленными данными и данными, опубликованными в отчетах об исследованиях. Однако некоторые опубликованные национальные данные были скорректированы Отделом народонаселения для улучшения сопоставимости. Примечания включаются в набор данных, чтобы указать, когда были произведены корректировки и для тех случаев, если данные отличаются от стандартных определений. Глобальный показатель представляет всех женщин репродуктивного возраста. Некоторые оценки обследований относятся к замужним женщинам или женщинам, состоящим в консенсуальном союзе, что и отражено в примечании. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
