<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 12-7-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definitions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator measures the number of countries implementing Sustainable Public Procurement (SPP) policies and action plans, by assessing the degree of implementation through an index. To produce the index, countries self-assess the following main elements: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Public procurement legal and regulatory framework&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Practical support delivered for the implementation of SPP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- SPP priority products&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-3&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and corresponding sustainable procurement criteria &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Existence of SPP monitoring system&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Measurement of actual SPP outcome&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details are provided in the attached &lt;a href=&quot;https://wedocs.unep.org/handle/20.500.11822/37332&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;SPP Index Methodology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (revised February 2021).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainable Public Procurement (SPP): &lt;/em&gt;Sustainable Public Procurement is a &amp;#x201C;A process whereby public organizations meet their needs for goods, services, works and utilities in a way that achieves value for money on a whole life cycle basis in terms of generating benefits not only to the organisation, but also to society and the economy, whilst significantly reducing negative impacts on the environment&amp;#x201D; (Definition updated by the Multistakeholder Advisory Committee of the 10YFP SPP Programme).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sustainable Public Procurement Action Plan:&lt;/em&gt; A Sustainable Public Procurement (SPP) action plan is a policy document articulating the priorities and actions a public authority will adopt to support the implementation of SPP. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plans usually/should address the economic, environmental and social dimensions of SPP, and recognise the potential for SPP to realise SDGs&amp;#x201D;. In some cases a country&amp;#x2019;s action plan may focus on a single aspect of sustainability, being either environmental (e.g. &amp;#x201C;Green&amp;#x201D; public procurement action plan), social (e.g. reference to human rights, fair trade, focus on employment of minorities, etc.), or economic (e.g. promotion of SMEs&amp;#x2019; participation in tenders, focus on employment of minorities, etc.). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best Value for Money:&lt;/em&gt; can be defined as the &amp;#x201C;optimum combination of whole-life cost and quality to meet the end-user&amp;apos;s requirements&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Life-cycle costing (LCC):&lt;/em&gt; is used to evaluate costs which may not be reflected in the purchase price of a product, work or service, and which will be incurred during their lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;MEAT:&lt;/em&gt; The Most Economically Advantageous Tender criterion enables the contracting authority to take account of criteria that reflect qualitative, technical and sustainable aspects of the tender submission as well as price when reaching an award decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More reference about the above and their contextualization can be found in the attached &lt;a href=&quot;https://wedocs.unep.org/handle/20.500.11822/37332&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;SPP Index Methodology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-3&quot;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
