<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 1-1-1a, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="en"># Data sources

## Description

The World Bank typically receives data from National Statistical Offices (NSOs) directly. In other cases it uses NSO data received indirectly. For example, it receives data from Eurostat and from LIS (Luxemburg Income Study), who provide the World Bank NSO data they have received / harmonized.  The Universidad Nacional de La Plata, Argentina and the World Bank jointly maintain the SEDLAC (Socio-Economic Database for Latin American and Caribbean) database that includes harmonized statistics on poverty and other distributional and social variables from 24 Latin American and Caribbean countries, based on microdata from household surveys conducted by NSOs.

Data is obtained through country specific programs, including technical assistance programs and joint analytical and capacity building activities. The World Bank has relationships with NSOs on work programs involving statistical systems and data analysis. Poverty economists from the World Bank typically engage with NSOs broadly on poverty measurement and analysis as part of technical assistance activities.

Within the World Bank, the Global Poverty Working Group (GPWG) is in charge of the collection, validation and estimation of poverty estimates. GPWG archives the datasets obtained from NSOs and then harmonizes them, applying common methodologies. The objective of the GPWG is to ensure that poverty and inequality data generated, curated, and disseminated by the World Bank are up to date, meet high-quality standards, and are well documented and consistent across dissemination channels. Members of GPWG generate and update the estimates for the proportion of population below the international poverty line using raw data typically provided by country governments. The raw data are obtained by poverty economists through their contacts in the NSOs, and checked for quality before being submitted for further analysis. The raw data can be unit-record survey data, or grouped data, depending on the agreements with the country governments. In most cases, the welfare aggregate, the essential element for poverty estimation, is generated by the country governments. Sometimes, the World Bank has to construct the welfare aggregate or adjust the aggregate provided by the country.

## List

Directly from National Statistical Offices (NSOs) or indirectly from others – see section on data sources.
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"># Источники данных

## Описание

Всемирный банк обычно получает данные от национальных статистических управлений (НСУ) напрямую. В других случаях используются данные НСО, полученные косвенно. Например, он получает данные от Евростата и LIS (Luxemburg Income Study - Люксембургское исследование доходов), которые предоставляют данные НСО Всемирного банка, которые они получили / согласовали. Национальный университет штата Ла-Плата, Аргентина и Всемирный банк совместно ведут базу данных SEDLAC (Социально-экономическая база данных для Латинской Америки и Карибского бассейна), которая включает в себя согласованные статистические данныве по бедности и других распространяемые и социальные переменные по 24 странам Латинской Америки и Карибского бассейна, основанную на микроданных из обследований домашних хозяйств, проводимых НСУ.

Данные получают в рамках программ для конкретных стран, включая программы технической помощи и совместные аналитические мероприятия и мероприятия по наращиванию потенциала. Всемирный банк сотрудничает с НСУ по рабочим программам, включающим статистические системы и анализ данных. Экономисты по вопросам бедности из Всемирного банка обычно взаимодействуют с НСУ в вопросах измерения и анализа бедности в рамках деятельности по оказанию технической помощи.

В рамках Всемирного банка Глобальная рабочая группа по бедности (ГРГБ) отвечает за сбор, проверку и оценку оценок бедности. GPWG архивирует наборы данных, полученные от НСУ, а затем согласовывает их, применяя общие методологии. Цель ГРГБ заключается в обеспечении того, чтобы данные о бедности и неравенстве, создаваемые, курируемые и распространяемые Всемирным банком, были актуальными, соответствовали высоким стандартам качества, были хорошо документированы и согласованы по каналам распространения. Члены ГРГБ создают и обновляют оценки доли населения, живущего ниже международной черты бедности, используя исходные данные, обычно предоставляемые правительствами стран. Исходные данные получаются экономистами по бедности через их контакты в НСУ и проверяются по параметрам качества перед отправкой для дальнейшего анализа. Исходные данные могут быть единичными данными обследования или сгруппированными данными, в зависимости от соглашений с правительствами стран. В большинстве случаев агрегаты по благосостоянию, существенный элемент для оценки бедности, создается правительствами стран. Иногда Всемирный банк должен построить агрегаты благосостояния или скорректировать агрегаты, предоставляемые страной.

## Список

Непосредственно из национальных статистических управлений (НСУ) или косвенно от других - см. Раздел об источниках данных.
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
