<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 7-b-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Collection process:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The capacity data is collected as part of IRENA&amp;#x2019;s annual questionnaire cycle. Questionnaires are sent to countries at the start of a year asking for renewable energy data for two years previously (i.e. at the start of 2019, questionnaires ask for data for the year 2017). The data is then validated and checked with countries and published in the IRENA Renewable Energy Statistics Yearbook at the end of June. To minimise reporting burden, the questionnaires for some countries are pre-filled with data collected by other agencies (e.g. Eurostat) and are sent to countries for them to complete any additional details requested by IRENA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time as this, preliminary estimates of capacity for the previous year are also collected from official sources where available (e.g. national statistics, data from electricity grid operators) and from other unofficial sources (mostly industry associations for the different renewable energy sectors). These are published at the end of March. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Population data:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the population part of this indicator, IRENA uses population data from the United Nations World Population Prospects. The population data reflects the residents in a country or area regardless of legal status or citizenship. The values are midyear estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United Nations Department of Economic and Social Affairs published information about their methodology on the link below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://population.un.org/wpp/Methodology/&quot;&gt;https://population.un.org/wpp/Methodology/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные по мощности собираются в рамках ежегодного цикла сбора вопросников IRENA. Вопросники рассылаются странам в начале года с просьбой предоставить данные о возобновляемых источниках энергии за второй год, предыдущий текущему (то есть в начале 2019 года в вопросниках запрашиваются данные за 2017 год). Затем осуществляется валидация и проверка данных со странами и их публикация в конце июня в Статистическом ежегоднике IRENA по возобновляемым источниках энергии. Для того, чтобы свести к минимуму бремя отчетности, вопросники для некоторых стран предварительно заполняются данными, собранными другими агентствами (например, Евростатом), и рассылаются странам, чтобы они могли внести любые дополнительные сведения, запрашиваемые IRENA. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В то же время предварительные оценки мощности за предыдущий год также собираются из официальных источников, где они доступны (например, национальной статистики, данных от операторов электросетей), и из других неофициальных источников (в основном отраслевых ассоциаций различных секторов возобновляемой энергетики). Они публикуются в конце марта. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Данные о населении: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для демографической части этого показателя IRENA использует объединение шести источников Всемирного банка, данные которого доступны через базу данных Всемирного банка Показатели мирового развития. Показатель отражает количество жителей страны или территории независимо от правового статуса или гражданства. Значения являются оценками по состоянию на середину года. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Всемирный банк публикует дополнительную информацию об этом показателе в своих метаданных: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://databank.worldbank.org/reports.aspx?source=2&amp;amp;type=metadata&amp;amp;series=SP.POP.TOTL&quot;&gt; https://databank.worldbank.org/reports.aspx?source=2 &amp;amp; type = metadata &amp;amp; series = SP.POP.TOTL &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
