<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 2-5-1a, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Genetic resources for food and agriculture provide the building blocks of food security and, directly or indirectly, support the livelihoods of every person on earth. As the conservation and accessibility to these resources are of vital importance, medium- or long- term conservation facilities (genebanks) to preserve and make these resources and their associated information accessible for breeding and research have been established at country, regional and global levels. Inventories of genebank holdings provide a dynamic measure of the existing plant and animal diversity and its level of preservation. Data relevant to this indicator facilitate the monitoring of diversity secured and accessible through genebanks and support the development and updating of strategies for the conservation and sustainable use of genetic resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is related to a monitoring framework endorsed by the FAO Commission on Genetic Resources for Food and Agriculture in which the status and trends of plant and animal genetic resources are described through globally agreed indicators and regular country-driven assessments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of materials conserved under medium- or long-term storage conditions provides an indirect measurement of the total genetic diversity, which are managed to secure for future use. Overall, positive variations are therefore approximated to an increase in the agro-biodiversity secured, while negative variations to a loss of it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caution needs to be paid in the reporting and interpretation of the indicator. In the case of plant genetic resources, an uncontrolled addition of accessions that are in fact duplicates of samples already conserved and accounted for, or, &lt;em&gt;vice versa&lt;/em&gt;, the deletion from the reported collections of redundant duplicates may lead to wrong interpretations. In order to avoid duplicate counting at the national level, primarily base collections should be reported. An active collection could be reported, only when, in the absence of a base collection, it also serves the function of the base collection.Another example that needs to be monitored both while reporting and interpreting the results include the grouping or splitting of accessions, as in both cases the variation in the accounted number does not reflect a variation in the genetic diversity conserved and secured. Therefore, it is crucial that reporting countries and regional/international centres together with the accession level information requested explain also the reason for the decrease or increase in the number of accessions, in particular when this does not reflect a real loss or gain in the genetic diversity conserved and secured.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Les ressources génétiques pour l’alimentation et l’agriculture fournissent les éléments constitutifs de la sécurité alimentaire et, directement ou indirectement, soutiennent les moyens de subsistance de chaque personne sur terre. Comme la conservation et l’accessibilité à ces ressources sont d’une importance vitale, des installations de conservation à moyen ou à long terme (banques de gènes) ont été mises en place aux niveaux national, régional et mondial pour préserver et rendre ces ressources et les informations qui leur sont associées accessibles à la sélection et à la recherche. Les inventaires des banques de gènes fournissent une mesure dynamique de la diversité végétale et animale existante et de son niveau de conservation. Les données pertinentes pour cet indicateur facilitent le suivi de la diversité sécurisée et accessible par le biais des banques de gènes et soutiennent l’élaboration et la mise à jour de stratégies de conservation et d’utilisation durable des ressources génétiques. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’indicateur est lié à un cadre de suivi approuvé par la Commission des ressources génétiques pour l’alimentation et l’agriculture de la FAO, dans lequel l’état et les tendances des ressources génétiques végétales et animales sont décrits au moyen d’indicateurs convenus à l’échelle mondiale et d’évaluations régulières menées par les pays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le nombre de matériaux conservés dans des conditions de stockage à moyen ou à long terme fournit une mesure indirecte de la diversité génétique totale, qui sont gérés de manière à garantir une utilisation future. Dans l’ensemble, les variations positives correspondent donc à une augmentation de l’agrobiodiversité préservée, tandis que les variations négatives à une perte de celle-ci. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il faut faire preuve de prudence dans la déclaration et l’interprétation de l’indicateur. Dans le cas des ressources phytogénétiques, un ajout incontrôlé d’accessions qui sont en fait des doublons d’échantillons déjà conservés et comptabilisés, ou, &lt;em&gt;vice versa&lt;/em&gt;, la suppression de doublons redondants des collections signalées peut conduire à des interprétations erronées. Afin d’éviter les doublons au niveau national, il convient de signaler principalement les collections de base. Une collection active ne peut être signalée que si, en l’absence d’une collection de base, elle remplit également la fonction de la collection de base. Un autre exemple qui doit être surveillé à la fois lors de la déclaration et de l’interprétation des résultats comprend le regroupement ou le fractionnement des accessions, car dans les deux cas, la variation du nombre comptabilisé ne reflète pas une variation de la diversité génétique conservée et sécurisée. Par conséquent, il est essentiel que les pays déclarants et les centres régionaux / internationaux ainsi que les informations demandées sur le niveau des accessions, expliquent également la raison de la diminution ou de l’augmentation du nombre d&apos;accessions, en particulier lorsque cela ne reflète pas une perte ou un gain réel de la diversité génétique conservée et sécurisée. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
