<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 10-5-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Comments and limitations:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data for most countries are reported on a monthly or quarterly basis; a few countries report data on a semi-annual basis and with a lag of more than a quarter. As of end-December 2018, there were 138 FSI reporters. Some countries&amp;#x2019; compilation practices deviate from the FSI Guide methodology in certain areas and are documented in the FSI metadata also posted on the IMF&amp;#x2019;s FSI website. Reporting countries provide all or most core FSIs and some encouraged FSIs that can be used to support the interpretation of these seven SDG indicators. FSI data and metadata reported by countries are available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://data.imf.org/FSI.&quot;&gt;http://data.imf.org/FSI.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires et limites :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données de la plupart des pays sont déclarées sur une base mensuelle ou trimestrielle ; quelques pays déclarent des données sur une base semestrielle et avec un décalage de plus d&apos;un trimestre. À la fin décembre 2018, il y avait 138 déclarants d&apos;ISF. Les pratiques de compilation de certains pays s&apos;écartent de la méthodologie du Guide de l&apos;ISF dans certains domaines et sont documentées dans les métadonnées de l&apos;ISF également publiées sur le site Web de l&apos;ISF du FMI. Les pays déclarants fournissent tous ou la plupart des ISF de base et certains ISF encouragés qui peuvent être utilisés pour soutenir l&apos;interprétation de ces sept indicateurs des ODD. Les données et métadonnées de l&apos;ISF communiquées par les pays sont disponibles à l&apos;adresse &lt;a href=&quot;http://data.imf.org/FSI.&quot;&gt;http://data.imf.org/FSI.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные по большинству стран предоставляются ежемесячно или ежеквартально; несколько стран представляют данные раз в полгода и с задержкой более, чем в квартал. По состоянию на конец декабря 2018 года 138 лиц направляли данные по ПФУ. В некоторых странах методы составления данных отличаются от методологии Руководства ПФУ в определенных областях и задокументированы в метаданных ПФУ, также размещенных на веб-сайте ПФУ МВФ. Отчитывающиеся страны предоставляют все или большинство основных ПФУ, а также некоторые рекомендуемые ПФУ, которые можно использовать для поддержки интерпретации этих семи показателей ЦУР. Данные ПФУ и метаданные, представленные странами, доступны на &lt;a href=&quot;http://data.imf.org/FSI.&quot;&gt; http://data.imf.org/FSI. &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
