<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 10-5-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seven FSIs are included as SDG indicators for 10.5.1 and expressed as percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 - Regulatory Tier 1 capital to assets &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 - Regulatory Tier 1 capital to risk-weighted assets &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 - Nonperforming loans net of provisions to capital &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 - Nonperforming loans to total gross loans &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 - Return on assets &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6 - Liquid assets to short-term liabilities &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7 - Net open position in foreign exchange to capital &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Regulatory Tier 1 capital to assets:&lt;/em&gt; This is the ratio of the core capital (Tier 1) to total (balance sheet) assets. For jurisdictions that have implemented the Basel III leverage ratio, this indicator would be calculated using Tier 1 capital as the numerator and the exposure measure as the denominator, which comprises balance sheet assets, derivatives exposures, securities financing transaction exposures, and off-balance-sheet items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Regulatory Tier 1 capital to risk-weighted assets:&lt;/em&gt; It is calculated using regulatory Tier 1 capital as the numerator and risk-weighted assets as the denominator. The data for this FSI are compiled in accordance with the implemented Basel Accord (i.e., Basel I, Basel II, or Basel III). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nonperforming loans net of provisions to capital:&lt;/em&gt; This FSI is calculated by taking the value of nonperforming loans (NPLs) less the value of specific provisions for NPLs as the numerator and total regulatory capital as the denominator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nonperforming loans to total gross loans&lt;/em&gt;: This FSI is calculated by using the value of NPLs as the numerator and the total value of the loan portfolio (including NPLs, and before the deduction of specific provisions for NPLs) as the denominator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Return on assets&lt;/em&gt;: This FSI is calculated by dividing annualized net income before taxes by the average value of total assets (financial and nonfinancial) over the same period. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Liquid assets to short-term liabilities&lt;/em&gt;: This FSI is calculated by using liquid assets as the numerator and short-term liabilities as the denominator.The components of liquid assets are defined in the IMF&amp;#x2019;s &lt;em&gt;2019 FSIs Compilation Guide&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;2019 FSIs Guide&lt;/em&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Net open position in foreign exchange to capital&lt;/em&gt;: The net open position in foreign exchange should be calculated based on the guidance in the &lt;em&gt;2019 FSIs Guide&lt;/em&gt;. Capital should be total regulatory capital as net open position in foreign exchange is a supervisory concept. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Regulatory Tier 1 capital to assets&lt;/em&gt;: Regulatory Tier 1 capital is calculated based on Basel I, II, or III depending on countries&amp;#x2019; supervisory practices. Denominator is total balance sheet (non-risk weighted) assets. For jurisdictions that have implemented the Basel III leverage ratio, the denominator also includes off-balance-sheet items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Regulatory Tier 1 capital to risk- weighted assets&lt;/em&gt;: Regulatory Tier 1 capital is calculated based on Basel I, II, or III depending on countries&amp;#x2019; supervisory practices. Denominator is risk-weighted assets also calculated based on Basel standards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nonperforming loans (NPLs) net of provisions to capital:&lt;/em&gt; A loan is classified as NPL when payment of principal or interest is past due by 90 days or more, or evidence exists that a full or partial amount of a loan is not going to be recovered. Only specific provisions for NPLs are used in this calculation and they refer to charges against the value of specific NPLs. Data exclude accrued interest on NPLs. Capital is measured as total regulatory capital calculated based on Basel I, II, or III depending on countries&amp;#x2019; supervisory practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nonperforming loans to total gross loans&lt;/em&gt;: A loan is classified as NPL when payment of principal or interest is past due by 90 days or more, or evidence exists that a full or partial amount of a loan is not going to be recovered. The denominator is the total value of the loan portfolio (including NPLs, and before the deduction of specific provisions for NPLs). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Return on assets:&lt;/em&gt; The numerator is annualized net income before taxes. The denominator is the average value of total assets (financial and nonfinancial) over the same period. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Liquid assets to short-term liabilities:&lt;/em&gt; Liquid assets include currency and deposits and other financial assets available on demand or within three months as well as securities traded in liquid markets that can be converted into cash with minimal change in value. The denominator is short-term elements of debt liabilities plus net market value of financial derivatives position. The latter is calculated as financial derivatives liability position minus financial derivative asset position. Short-term refers to three months and should be defined on a remaining maturity basis. If remaining maturity is not available, original maturity can be used as an alternative. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Net open position in foreign exchange to capital:&lt;/em&gt; Net open position should be calculated in accordance with the guidance in the &lt;em&gt;2019 FSIs Guide&lt;/em&gt;. The denominator is total regulatory capital as defined above.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se incluyen siete ISF como indicadores de los ODS para el 10.5.1 y se expresan en porcentaje.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Capital reglamentario de nivel 1 en relación con los activos &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Capital reglamentario de nivel 1 en relación con los activos ponderados en función del riesgo &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Créditos morosos netos de provisiones sobre capital &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Créditos morosos sobre el total de créditos brutos &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rendimiento de los activos &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Activos líquidos sobre pasivos a corto plazo &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Posición abierta neta en divisas sobre capital &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Capital reglamentario de nivel 1 sobre activos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Se trata de la relación entre el capital básico (Tier 1) y los activos totales (de balance). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Capital reglamentario de nivel 1 en relación con los activos ponderados por riesgo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; Se calcula utilizando el capital reglamentario total de nivel 1 como numerador y los activos ponderados por riesgo como denominador. Los datos de este ISF se compilan de acuerdo con las directrices de Basilea I, Basilea II o Basilea III. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Préstamos morosos netos de provisiones sobre el capital &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Este ISF se calcula tomando el valor de los préstamos morosos (NPL) menos el valor de las provisiones específicas para pérdidas de préstamos como numerador y el capital como denominador. El capital se mide como capital reglamentario total. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Préstamos morosos sobre el total de préstamos brutos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; Este ISF se calcula utilizando el valor de los préstamos morosos como numerador y el valor total de la cartera de préstamos (incluidos los préstamos morosos y antes de deducir las provisiones específicas para pérdidas de préstamos) como denominador. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rendimiento de los activos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; Este ISF se calcula dividiendo los ingresos netos anualizados antes de partidas extraordinarias e impuestos (como se recomienda en la Guía de los ISF) por el valor medio de los activos totales (financieros y no financieros) durante el mismo período. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Activos líquidos sobre pasivos a corto plazo &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: Este ISF se calcula utilizando la medida básica de los activos líquidos como numerador y los pasivos a corto plazo como denominador. El coeficiente también puede calcularse tomando como numerador la medida amplia de los activos líquidos. Para las jurisdicciones que han implementado Basilea III, este indicador podría complementarse con el ratio de cobertura de liquidez.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Posición abierta neta en divisas sobre capital&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: La posición abierta neta en divisas debe calcularse sobre la base de la recomendación del Comité de Supervisión Bancaria de Basilea (BCBS). El capital debe ser el capital reglamentario total, ya que la posición abierta neta en divisas es un concepto de supervisión. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Capital regulatorio de nivel 1 en relación con los activos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; El capital regulatorio de nivel 1 se calcula sobre la base de Basilea I, II o III, dependiendo de las prácticas de supervisión de los países. El denominador es el total de activos del balance (no ponderados por el riesgo). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Capital reglamentario de nivel 1 en relación con los activos ponderados por riesgo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: El capital reglamentario de nivel 1 se calcula sobre la base de Basilea I, II o III, dependiendo de las prácticas de supervisión de los países. El denominador son los activos ponderados por riesgo, también calculados según las normas de Basilea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Préstamos morosos (NPLs) netos de provisiones al capital&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; Un préstamo se clasifica como NPL cuando el pago del principal o de los intereses está vencido por 90 días o más, o existe evidencia de que un monto total o parcial de un préstamo no va a ser recuperado. En este cálculo sólo se utilizan las provisiones para pérdidas de préstamos específicos y se refieren a los cargos contra el valor de préstamos específicos. Los datos excluyen los intereses devengados en los préstamos morosos. El capital se mide como capital reglamentario total calculado sobre la base de Basilea I, II o III, dependiendo de las prácticas de supervisión de los países.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Préstamos morosos sobre el total de préstamos brutos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; Un préstamo se clasifica como moroso cuando el pago del principal o de los intereses está vencido desde hace 90 días o existe evidencia de que no se va a recuperar la totalidad o parte del préstamo. El denominador es el valor total de la cartera de préstamos (incluida la morosidad, y antes de deducir las provisiones específicas para préstamos). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rendimiento de los activos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: El numerador es el resultado neto anualizado antes de partidas extraordinarias e impuestos. El denominador es el valor medio de los activos totales (financieros y no financieros) durante el mismo periodo. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Activos líquidos sobre pasivos a corto plazo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; La medida básica de los activos líquidos incluye el efectivo y los depósitos y otros activos financieros disponibles a la vista o en un plazo de tres meses. La medida amplia es igual a la medida básica más los valores negociados en mercados líquidos que pueden convertirse en efectivo con un cambio de valor mínimo. El denominador son los elementos a corto plazo de los pasivos de deuda más el valor de mercado neto (a corto plazo) de la posición de los derivados financieros. Este último se calcula como la posición de pasivo de derivados financieros menos la posición de activo de derivados financieros. El corto plazo se refiere a tres meses y debe definirse sobre la base del vencimiento restante. Si no se dispone del plazo de vencimiento restante, puede utilizarse el plazo de vencimiento original como alternativa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Posición abierta neta en divisas sobre capital&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: La posición abierta neta en divisas es igual al elemento en moneda extranjera y vinculado a la moneda extranjera de los activos del balance y las exposiciones fuera de balance menos el elemento en moneda extranjera y vinculado a la moneda extranjera de los pasivos del balance y las exposiciones fuera de balance. Los instrumentos vinculados a divisas se refieren a cuentas denominadas en moneda nacional, pero sus pagos están vinculados a los tipos de cambio, por lo que están sujetos al riesgo de cambio. El denominador es el capital reglamentario total, tal como se ha definido anteriormente. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Définition : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sept ISF sont inclus en tant qu&apos;indicateurs des ODD pour 10.5.1 et exprimés en pourcentage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fonds propres réglementaires de catégorie 1 par rapport aux actifs &lt;/li&gt;.
&lt;li&gt;Fonds propres réglementaires de catégorie 1 par rapport aux actifs pondérés en fonction des risques &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prêts non productifs nets de provisions sur les fonds propres &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prêts non performants sur le total des prêts bruts &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rendement des actifs &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Liquidités sur passif à court terme &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Position ouverte nette en devises étrangères sur capital &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Fonds propres réglementaires de catégorie 1 sur l&apos;actif &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; : Il s&apos;agit du rapport entre les fonds propres de base (Tier 1) et le total des actifs (bilan). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Fonds propres réglementaires de catégorie 1 par rapport aux actifs pondérés en fonction des risques &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; : &lt;/em&gt; Il est calculé en utilisant le total des fonds propres réglementaires de catégorie 1 comme numérateur et les actifs pondérés en fonction des risques comme dénominateur. Les données de cet ISF sont compilées conformément aux directives de Bâle I, Bâle II ou Bâle III. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Prêts non performants nets de provisions par rapport au capital &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; : &lt;/em&gt; Cet ISF est calculé en prenant la valeur des prêts non performants (PNP) moins la valeur des provisions spécifiques pour pertes sur prêts comme numérateur et le capital comme dénominateur. Le capital est mesuré en tant que capital réglementaire total. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prêts non performants par rapport au total des prêts bruts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; :&lt;/em&gt; Cet ISF est calculé en utilisant la valeur des NPL comme numérateur et la valeur totale du portefeuille de prêts (y compris les NPL, et avant la déduction des provisions spécifiques pour pertes sur prêts) comme dénominateur. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Rendement des actifs &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; : &lt;/em&gt; Cet ISF est calculé en divisant le bénéfice net annualisé avant éléments extraordinaires et impôts (comme recommandé dans le Guide de l&apos;ISF) par la valeur moyenne du total des actifs (financiers et non financiers) sur la même période. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Actifs liquides sur passifs à court terme &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; : Cet ISF est calculé en utilisant la mesure de base des actifs liquides comme numérateur et les engagements à court terme comme dénominateur. Le ratio peut également être calculé en prenant la mesure large des actifs liquides comme numérateur. Pour les juridictions qui ont mis en œuvre Bâle III, cet indicateur pourrait être complété par le ratio de couverture des liquidités.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Position nette ouverte en devises étrangères par rapport au capital &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; : La position ouverte nette en devises devrait être calculée sur la base de la recommandation du Comité de Bâle sur le contrôle bancaire (CBCB). Le capital devrait être le capital réglementaire total car la position nette ouverte en devises étrangères est un concept de supervision. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fonds propres réglementaires de catégorie 1 par rapport aux actifs &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; :&lt;/em&gt; Les fonds propres réglementaires de catégorie 1 sont calculés sur la base de Bâle I, II ou III selon les pratiques de supervision des pays. Le dénominateur est le total des actifs du bilan (non pondérés en fonction des risques). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Fonds propres réglementaires de catégorie 1 par rapport aux actifs pondérés en fonction des risques&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; : Les fonds propres réglementaires de catégorie 1 sont calculés sur la base de Bâle I, II ou III, selon les pratiques de surveillance des pays. Le dénominateur est l&apos;actif pondéré en fonction des risques, également calculé sur la base des normes de Bâle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Prêts non performants (PNP) nets des provisions au capital &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; :&lt;/em&gt; Un prêt est classé comme PNP lorsque le paiement du principal ou des intérêts est en retard de 90 jours ou plus, ou lorsqu&apos;il existe des preuves qu&apos;un montant total ou partiel d&apos;un prêt ne sera pas recouvré. Seules les provisions spécifiques pour pertes sur prêts sont utilisées dans ce calcul et elles font référence à des charges contre la valeur de prêts spécifiques. Les données excluent les intérêts courus dans les NPL. Le capital est mesuré en tant que capital réglementaire total calculé sur la base de Bâle I, II ou III, selon les pratiques de supervision des pays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Prêts non performants par rapport au total des prêts bruts&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; :&lt;/em&gt; Un prêt est classé comme NPL lorsque le paiement du principal ou des intérêts est en retard de 90 jours ou plus, ou lorsqu&apos;il existe des preuves qu&apos;un montant total ou partiel d&apos;un prêt ne sera pas recouvré. Le dénominateur est la valeur totale du portefeuille de prêts (y compris les NPL, et avant la déduction des provisions spécifiques pour pertes sur prêts). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Rendement des actifs &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; : Le numérateur est le bénéfice net annualisé avant éléments exceptionnels et impôts. Le dénominateur est la valeur moyenne de l&apos;actif total (financier et non financier) sur la même période. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Actifs liquides sur passifs à court terme &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; : &lt;/em&gt; La mesure de base des actifs liquides comprend la monnaie fiduciaire et les dépôts et autres actifs financiers disponibles sur demande ou dans les trois mois. La mesure large est égale à la mesure de base plus les titres négociés sur des marchés liquides qui peuvent être convertis en espèces avec une variation de valeur minimale. Le dénominateur est constitué des éléments à court terme des dettes plus la valeur de marché nette (à court terme) de la position en produits financiers dérivés. Cette dernière est calculée comme étant la position de passif des dérivés financiers moins la position d&apos;actif des dérivés financiers. Le court terme fait référence à trois mois et doit être défini sur la base de l&apos;échéance restante. Si l&apos;échéance résiduelle n&apos;est pas disponible, l&apos;échéance initiale peut être utilisée comme alternative. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Position nette ouverte en devises par rapport au capital &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; : La position ouverte nette en devises étrangères est égale à l&apos;élément en devises étrangères et lié à des devises étrangères de l&apos;actif du bilan et des expositions hors bilan moins l&apos;élément en devises étrangères et lié à des devises étrangères du passif du bilan et des expositions hors bilan. Les instruments liés à des devises étrangères font référence à des comptes libellés en monnaie nationale, mais dont les paiements sont liés à des taux de change, et donc soumis à un risque de change. Le dénominateur est le total des fonds propres réglementaires tels que définis ci-dessus. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Семь ПФУ включены как показатели ЦУР для показателя 10.5.1 и выражены в процентах. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Отношение нормативного капитала первого уровня к активам &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Отношение нормативного капитала 1 уровня к активам, взвешенным с учетом риска
&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Отношение необслуживаемых кредитов за вычетом резервов к капиталу &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Отношение необслуживаемых кредитов к общей сумме кредитов &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Прибыль на активы &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Отношение ликвидных активов к краткосрочным обязательствам &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Отношение чистой открытой позиции в иностранной валюте к капиталу &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение нормативного капитала первого уровня к активам &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: Это отношение основного капитала (уровень 1) к совокупным (балансовым) активам. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение нормативного капитала 1 уровня к активам, взвешенным с учетом риска &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Показатель рассчитывается с использованием общего нормативного капитала уровня 1 в качестве числителя и активов, взвешенных с учетом риска, в качестве знаменателя. Данные для этого ПФУ составлены в соответствии с руководящими принципами Базель I, Базель II или Базель III. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение необслуживаемых кредитов за вычетом резервов к капиталу &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Этот ПФУ рассчитывается путем использования стоимости необслуживаемых кредитов (НОК) за вычетом стоимости специального резерва для покрытия убытков по ссудам в числителе и капитала в качестве знаменателя. Капитал оценивается как общий нормативный капитал. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение необслуживаемых кредитов к общей сумме кредитов &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Этот ПФУ рассчитывается путем использования стоимости необслуживаемых кредитов (НОК) в качестве числителя и общей стоимости кредитного портфеля (включая необслуживаемые кредиты и до вычета специальных резервов для покрытия убытков по ссудам) в качестве знаменателя. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Прибыль на активы &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Этот ПФУ рассчитывается путем деления чистой прибыли в годовом исчислении до вычета чрезвычайных обстоятельств и налогов (как рекомендовано в Руководстве по показателям финансовой устойчивости) на среднюю стоимость общих активов (финансовых и нефинансовых) за тот же период. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение ликвидных активов к краткосрочным обязательствам &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: Этот ПФУ рассчитывается с использованием базовой оценки ликвидных активов в качестве числителя и краткосрочных обязательств в качестве знаменателя. Соотношение также можно рассчитать, взяв в качестве числителя широкую оценку ликвидных активов. Для юрисдикций, которые внедрили Базель III, этот показатель может быть дополнен коэффициентом покрытия ликвидности. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение чистой открытой позиции в иностранной валюте к капиталу &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: Чистая открытая позиция в иностранной валюте должна рассчитываться на основании рекомендации Базельского комитета по банковскому надзору (BCBS). Капитал должен составлять совокупный нормативный капитал, поскольку чистая открытая позиция в иностранной валюте является надзорной концепцией. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Отношение нормативного капитала первого уровня к активам &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Нормативный капитал первого уровня рассчитывается на основе Базеля I, II или III в зависимости от надзорной практики страны. Знаменатель - это общая сумма балансовых (без взвешенных с учетом риска) активов. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение нормативного капитала 1 уровня к активам, взвешенным с учетом риска &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: Нормативный капитал первого уровня рассчитывается на основе Базеля I, II или III в зависимости от надзорной практики страны. Знаменатель - это активы, взвешенные с учетом риска, также рассчитанные на основе стандартов Базеля. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение необслуживаемых кредитов за вычетом резервов к капиталу &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Заем классифицируется как НОК, если выплата основной суммы или процентов просрочена на 90 дней или более, или есть доказательства того, что полная или частичная сумма кредита не будет возмещена. В этом расчете используются только специальные резервы для покрытия убытков по ссудам, и они соотносят расходы со стоимостью конкретных ссуд. Данные не включают начисленные проценты по необслуживаемым кредитам. Капитал оценивается как совокупный нормативный капитал, рассчитанный на основе Базеля I, II или III в зависимости от надзорной практики страны. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение необслуживаемых кредитов к общей сумме кредитов &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Заем классифицируется как НОК, если выплата основной суммы или процентов просрочена на 90 дней или более, или есть доказательства того, что полная или частичная сумма кредита не будет возмещена. Знаменатель - это общая стоимость кредитного портфеля (включая необслуживаемые кредиты, и до вычета специальных резервов для покрытия убытков по ссудам). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Прибыль на активы &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: В числителе указывается чистая прибыль до вычета чрезвычайных обстоятельств и налогов в годовом выражении. Знаменатель - это средняя стоимость совокупных активов (финансовых и нефинансовых) за тот же период. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение ликвидных активов к краткосрочным обязательствам &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Базовая оценка ликвидных активов включает валюту, депозиты и другие финансовые активы, доступные по требованию или в течение трех месяцев. Широкие оценки равны базовой оценке плюс ценные бумаги, торгуемые на ликвидных рынках, которые могут быть конвертированы в наличные с минимальным изменением стоимости. Знаменатель представляет собой краткосрочные элементы долговых обязательств плюс чистая (краткосрочная) рыночная стоимость позиции по производным финансовым инструментам. Последний рассчитывается как позиция по обязательствам по производным финансовым инструментам за вычетом позиции по активам по производным финансовым инструментам. Определение &quot;краткосрочный&quot; - это три месяца, и его следует устанавливать на основе оставшегося срока погашения. Если оставшийся срок погашения недоступен, в качестве альтернативы можно использовать первоначальный срок погашения. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение чистой открытой позиции в иностранной валюте к капиталу &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: Чистая открытая позиция в иностранной валюте равна иностранной валюте и связанному с иностранной валютой элементу балансовых активов и внебалансовых рисков, за вычетом иностранной валюты и связанного с иностранной валютой элемента балансовых обязательств и внебалансовых рисков. Связанные с иностранной валютой инструменты относятся к счетам, деноминированным в национальной валюте, но платежи по ним привязаны к обменным курсам, таким образом, подвержены валютному риску. Знаменатель — это совокупный нормативный капитал, как определено выше. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
