<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 17-17-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;The indicator has a established methodology that is available at the website &lt;a href=&quot;http://ppi.worldbank.org/methodology/ppi-methodology&quot;&gt;http://ppi.worldbank.org/methodology/ppi-methodology&lt;/a&gt; and the data collection process is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Team of researcher gather data for each of the regions using public sources (from government and MDBs websites); commercial news databases ( such as Factiva, Business News America, ISI Emerging markets, and the Economist Intelligence Unit&amp;#x2019;s databases) as well as from commercial specialized and industry publications/subscriptions (Thomson Financial&amp;#x2019;s Project Finance International, Euromoney&amp;#x2019;s Project Finance, Media Analytics&amp;#x2019; Global Water Intelligence, Pisent Masons&amp;#x2019; Water Yearbooks, and Platt&amp;#x2019;s Power in Asia, etc.), specialist portal (such as Privatization, IPAnet, and Privatization Barometer), Internet resources (such as web sites of project companies, privatization or PPP agencies, and regulatory agencies) sponsor information (primarily through their Web sites, annual reports, press releases, and financial reports such as 10K and 20F forms submitted to the NYSE) and multilateral development agencies primarily through information on their Websites, annual reports, and other studies.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data is uploaded to an administrative website through a template to make sure data is standardized.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data is validated by a group of experts in Singapore.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data is later uploaded to the public website (www.ppi.worldbank.org) and make it available free of charge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The limitations of the proposed indicator is that it does not account for other sectors such as education and health may account for a significant part of PPPs but they are not captured by the database. Expanding the data to include PPPs in other sector beyond infrastructure is something that the World Bank is considering but it is currently limited by budget constraints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, PPI database does not collect data on civil society partnerships and this will not fit the currently methodology of data gathering and is outside the present work&amp;#x2019;s scope.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
