<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 4-2-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The UNESCO Institute for Statistics produces time series based on enrolment data reported by Ministries of Education or National Statistical Offices and population estimates produced by the UN Population Division. The enrolment data are gathered through the annual Survey of Formal Education. Countries are asked to report data according to the levels of education defined in the International Standard Classification of Education (ISCED) to ensure international comparability of resulting indicators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data received are validated using electronic error detection systems that check for arithmetic errors and inconsistencies and trend analysis for implausible results. Queries are taken up with the country representatives reporting the data so that corrections can be made (of errors) or explanations given (of implausible but correct results). During this process, countries are also encouraged to provide estimates for missing or incomplete data items.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, countries also have an opportunity to see and comment on the main indicators the UIS produces in an annual &amp;#x201C;country review&amp;#x201D; of indicators. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;L’Institut de statistique de l’UNESCO produit des séries chronologiques basées sur les données sur les inscriptions communiquées par les ministères de l’éducation ou les bureaux nationaux de statistique et les estimations de la population produites par la Division de la population des Nations Unies. Les données sur les inscriptions sont recueillies dans le cadre de l’Enquête annuelle sur l’éducation formelle. Les pays sont invités à communiquer des données en fonction des niveaux d’éducation définis dans la Classification internationale type de l’éducation (CITE) afin d’assurer la comparabilité internationale des indicateurs qui en résultent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données reçues sont validées à l’aide de systèmes électroniques de détection d’erreurs qui vérifient les erreurs et les incohérences arithmétiques et l’analyse des tendances pour des résultats invraisemblables. Les demandes sont envoyées aux représentants des pays responsables de déclarer les données afin que des corrections puissent être apportées (des erreurs) ou des explications données (des résultats invraisemblables mais corrects). Au cours de ce processus, les pays sont également encouragés à fournir des estimations pour les éléments de données manquants ou incomplets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En outre, les pays ont également la possibilité de voir et de commenter les principaux indicateurs produits par l’ISU dans le cadre d’un « examen annuel des pays » des indicateurs. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
