<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COMPARABILITY field for indicator 4-2-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nationally-published figures may differ from the international ones because of differences between national education systems and the International Standard Classification of Education (ISCED); or differences in coverage (i.e. the extent to which different types of education &amp;#x2013; e.g. private or special education &amp;#x2013; are included in one rather than the other) and/or between national and the United Nations Population Division (UNPD) population estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fuentes de discrepancias:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las cifras publicadas a nivel nacional pueden diferir de las internacionales debido a las diferencias entre los sistemas educativos nacionales y la Clasificación Internacional Uniforme de la Educación (CINE); o las diferencias en la cobertura (es decir, la medida en que los diferentes tipos de educación &amp;#x2013;, por ejemplo, la educación privada o especial &amp;#x2013;, se incluyen en una y no en la otra) y/o entre las estimaciones de población nacionales y de la División de Población de las Naciones Unidas (DPNU). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources des écarts : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les chiffres publiés au niveau national peuvent différer des chiffres internationaux en raison des différences entre les systèmes éducatifs nationaux et la Classification internationale type de l&apos;éducation (CITE), ou des différences de couverture (c&apos;est-à-dire la mesure dans laquelle différents types d&apos;éducation, par exemple l&apos;enseignement privé ou spécial , sont inclus dans l&apos;un plutôt que dans l&apos;autre) et/ou entre les estimations démographiques nationales et celles de la Division de la population des Nations unies (DPNU).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Опубликованные на национальном уровне данные могут отличаться от международных данных из-за различий между национальными системами образования и Международной стандартной классификацией образования (МСКО); или из-за различий в охвате (т.е. зависит от того, насколько различные типы образования, например, частное или специальное образование, включены в один, а не в другой), и / или из-за различия между национальными оценками населения и оценками Отдела народонаселения ООН (UNPD). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
