<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COMPARABILITY field for indicator 3-d-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The national IHR annual self-assessment and reporting have specific indicators based on IHR requirements for core capacities needed to detect, assess, notify, report and respond, including at points of entry, to public health risks and acute events of domestic and international concern. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;External voluntary evaluation of similar capacities can be done, by the same country, such as using the Joint external evaluation (JEE) tool, supported by several countries, in complement to the self-assessment. More details are available at the Health Security and Emergency Preparedness (SPH) Portal (&lt;a href=&quot;https://extranet.who.int/sph/&quot;&gt;https://extranet.who.int/sph/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Fuentes de discrepancias: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No se hace ninguna estimación. Las puntuaciones regionales y globales se basan todas en los cuestionarios presentados. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;L&apos;auto-évaluation et les rapports annuels nationaux du RSI comportent des indicateurs spécifiques, basés sur les exigences du RSI en matière de capacités de base nécessaires pour détecter, évaluer, informer, signaler et réagir, y compris aux points d&apos;entrée, aux risques pour la santé publique et aux incidents graves d&apos;intérêt national et international. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Une évaluation externe volontaire de capacités similaires peut être effectuée, par le même pays, par exemple en utilisant l&apos;« outil d&apos;évaluation externe conjoint », soutenu par plusieurs pays, en complément de l&apos;auto-évaluation. Plus de détails sur le portail « Health Security and Emergency Preparedness (SPH) Portal » (&lt;a href=&quot;https://extranet.who.int/sph/&quot;&gt;https://extranet.who.int/sph/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Оценка не проводится. Все региональные и глобальные итоги основаны на представленных вопросниках. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
