<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 11-7-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;International data collection process&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data are collected through a standardised questionnaire sent to countries&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-3&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This questionnaire provides specific definitions of data to be collected and it collects a set of metadata to identify possible discrepancies from standard definitions and to assess overall data quality (e.g. sample size, target population, agency responsible for the data collection, etc.). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When needed, data of interest and relevant disaggregations are requested&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data for multiple years are collected to assess data consistency across time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Countries are requested to appoint national focal points (including from NSOs) for the various data topics to ensure technical supervision at country level on collected data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automated and substantive validation procedures are in place when data are processed by the Office to assess their consistency and compliance with standards &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When data from national official sources are missing or not complying with methodological standards, data from other sources are also considered and processed by using the same quality assurance procedures. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-3&quot;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Data will be collected through the UN Crime trends Survey (UN-CTS), the annual questionnaire on crime and criminal justice administered by UNODC &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
