<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 11-7-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Number of persons who experienced a form of physical harassment and/or sexual harassment, divided by the total population. The result would be multiplied by 100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a survey-based indicator that measures the experience of any of a set of behaviours that are collectively referred to as physical harassment and sexual harassment. Questions on physical and sexual harassment are to be measured separately. The results can then be combined. Both numerator and denominator are measured through sample surveys of the general population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The computation of this indicator requires the inclusion of a short module of eight questions in a representative population survey. The following table illustrates the content of the questions needed to compute the indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content of question&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instruction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Experience of sexual harassment in the past three years, by type of harassment&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;If no sexual harassment was experienced, skip to 5, otherwise go to 2.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Most recent type of harassment experienced&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Continue with 3.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Time period of last harassment&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Continue with 4.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Place of last harassment, by type of location&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Go to 5.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Experience of physical harassment in the past three years, by type of harassment&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;If no physical harassment was experienced, skip to END, otherwise go to 6.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Most recent type of harassment experienced&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Continue with 7.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Time period of last harassment&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Continue with 8.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Place of last harassment, by type of location&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Go to END.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the responses to questions, the following indicators can be computed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Prevalence rate of sexual harassment&lt;/u&gt;: Number of persons who experienced at least one form of sexual harassment, divided by the total population. The result would be multiplied by 100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Prevalence rate of physical harassment:&lt;/u&gt; Number of persons who experienced at least one form of physical harassment, divided by the total population. The result would be multiplied by 100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Prevalence rate of physical or sexual harassment (SDG indicator 11.7.2):&lt;/u&gt; Number of persons who experienced either a form of sexual harassment or a form of physical harassment, divided by the total population. The result would be multiplied by 100.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
