<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 4-1-1bc, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Percentage of children and young people in Grade 2 or 3 of primary education, at the end of primary education and the end of lower secondary education achieving at least a minimum proficiency level in (a) reading and (b) mathematics. The minimum proficiency level will be measured relative to new common reading and mathematics scales currently in development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minimum proficiency level is the benchmark of basic knowledge in a domain (mathematics or reading) measured through learning assessments. For example, the Programme for International Student Assessment (PISA) reading test has six proficiency levels, of which Level 2 is described as the minimum proficiency level. In Trends in International Mathematics and Science Study (TIMSS) and Progress in International Reading Literacy Study (PIRLS), there are four proficiency levels: Low, Intermediate, High and Advanced. Students reaching the Intermediate benchmark are able to apply basic knowledge in a variety of situations, similar to the idea of minimum proficiency. Currently, there are no common standards validated by the international community or countries. The indicator shows data published by each of the agencies and organizations specialised in cross-national learning assessments.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Proportion d&apos;enfants et de jeunes en 2e et en 3e année du primaire, à la fin du primaire et à la fin du premier cycle du secondaire qui atteignent au moins le niveau de compétence minimal en i) lecture et ii) mathématiques. Le niveau de compétence minimal sera évalué en fonction de nouvelles échelles de mesure communes actuellement en développement.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le niveau de compétence minimal inclut les connaissances de base dans un domaine (mathématiques, lecture, etc.) mesurées par des évaluations de l&apos;apprentissage. Par exemple, le test de lecture du Programme international pour le suivi des acquis des élèves (PISA) comporte six niveaux de compétence, dont le niveau 2 est décrit comme le niveau de compétence minimal. Pour les évaluations Tendances dans l&apos;étude internationale des mathématiques et des sciences (TIMSS) et Progrès dans l&apos;étude internationale de la maîtrise de la lecture (PIRLS), il existe quatre niveaux de compétence : faible, intermédiaire, élevé et avancé. Les élèves qui atteignent le niveau intermédiaire sont capables d&apos;appliquer les connaissances de base dans diverses situations, comme dans le cas d&apos;une compétence minimale. Actuellement, il n&apos;existe pas de normes communes validées par la communauté internationale. L&apos;indicateur présente les données publiées par chacune des agences et organisations spécialisées dans les évaluations d&apos;apprentissage internationales. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt;Понятия и определения&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Определение:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Процент детей и молодежи, обучающихся во 2-м или 3-м классе начальной школы, выпускников начальной школы и выпускников неполной средней школы, которые достигли по меньшей мере минимального уровня владения навыками i) чтения и ii) математики. Минимальный уровень владения навыками будет оцениваться с помощью новых общих шкал для чтения и математики, которые в настоящее время находятся в разработке.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Понятия:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Минимальный уровень владения навыками является эталоном базовых знаний в какой-либо области (математика или чтение), оцениваемых посредством оценок успеваемости. Например, тест по чтению в рамках Международной программы по оценке образовательных достижений учащихся (PISA) имеет шесть уровней владения навыками, из которых Уровень 2 описывается как минимальный уровень владения навыками. В рамках Международного исследования качества математического и естественнонаучного образования (TIMSS) и Международного исследования качества чтения и понимания текста (PIRLS) существуют четыре уровня владения навыками: Низкий, Средний, Высокий и Продвинутый. Студенты, достигшие среднего эталонного уровня, могут применять базовые знания в различных ситуациях, аналогично идее минимального уровня владения навыками. В настоящее время нет общих стандартов, одобренных международным сообществом или странами. Показатель отображает данные, публикуемые каждым из агентств и организаций, специализирующихся на межнациональных оценках успеваемости.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
