<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 2-5-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genetic resources for food and agriculture provide the building blocks of food security and, directly or indirectly, support the livelihoods of every person on earth. As the conservation and accessibility to these resources are of vital importance, medium- or long- term conservation facilities (genebanks) to preserve and make these resources and their associated information accessible for breeding and research have been established at country, regional and global levels. Inventories of genebank holdings provide a dynamic measure of the existing plant and animal diversity and its level of preservation. Data relevant to this indicator facilitate the monitoring of diversity secured and accessible through genebanks and support the development and updating of strategies for the conservation and sustainable use of genetic resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is related to a monitoring framework endorsed by the FAO Commission on Genetic Resources for Food and Agriculture in which the status and trends of plant and animal genetic resources are described through globally agreed indicators and regular country-driven assessments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of materials conserved under medium- or long-term storage conditions provides an indirect measurement of the total genetic diversity, which are managed to secure for future use. Overall, positive variations are therefore approximated to an increase in the agro-biodiversity secured, while negative variations to a loss of it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caution needs to be paid in the reporting and interpretation of the indicator. In the case of plant genetic resources, an uncontrolled addition of accessions that are in fact duplicates of samples already conserved and accounted for, or, &lt;em&gt;vice versa&lt;/em&gt;, the deletion from the reported collections of redundant duplicates may lead to wrong interpretations. In order to avoid duplicate counting at the national level, primarily base collections should be reported. An active collection could be reported, only when, in the absence of a base collection, it also serves the function of the base collection. Another example that needs to be monitored both while reporting and interpreting the results include the grouping or splitting of accessions, as in both cases the variation in the accounted number does not reflect a variation in the genetic diversity conserved and secured. Therefore, it is crucial that reporting countries and regional/international centres together with the accession level information requested explain also the reason for the decrease or increase in the number of accessions, in particular when this does not reflect a real loss or gain in the genetic diversity conserved and secured.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
