<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 7-b-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Collection process:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The capacity data is collected as part of IRENA&amp;#x2019;s annual questionnaire cycle. Questionnaires are sent to countries at the start of a year asking for renewable energy data for two years previously (i.e. at the start of 2019, questionnaires ask for data for the year 2017). The data is then validated and checked with countries and published in the IRENA Renewable Energy Statistics Yearbook at the end of June. To minimise reporting burden, the questionnaires for some countries are pre-filled with data collected by other agencies (e.g. Eurostat) and are sent to countries for them to complete any additional details requested by IRENA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time as this, preliminary estimates of capacity for the previous year are also collected from official sources where available (e.g. national statistics, data from electricity grid operators) and from other unofficial sources (mostly industry associations for the different renewable energy sectors). These are published at the end of March. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Population data:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the population part of this indicator, IRENA uses population data from the United Nations World Population Prospects. The population data reflects the residents in a country or area regardless of legal status or citizenship. The values are midyear estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United Nations Department of Economic and Social Affairs published information about their methodology on the link below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://population.un.org/wpp/Methodology/&quot;&gt;https://population.un.org/wpp/Methodology/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Proceso de recolección:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos sobre la capacidad se recogen como parte del ciclo de cuestionarios anuales de IRENA. Los cuestionarios se envían a los países a principios de cada año y en ellos se solicitan los datos sobre energías renovables de los dos años anteriores (es decir, a principios de 2019, los cuestionarios piden datos del año 2017). A continuación, los datos se validan y comprueban con los países y se publican en el Anuario de Estadísticas de Energías Renovables de IRENA a finales de junio. Para minimizar la carga de información, los cuestionarios de algunos países se completan previamente con datos recolectados por otros organismos (por ejemplo, Eurostat) y se envían a los países para que completen cualquier detalle adicional solicitado por IRENA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Al mismo tiempo, se recopilan estimaciones preliminares de la capacidad del año anterior a partir de fuentes oficiales cuando están disponibles (por ejemplo, estadísticas nacionales, datos de los operadores de la red eléctrica) y de otras fuentes no oficiales (principalmente asociaciones industriales de los distintos sectores de las energías renovables). Estos datos se publican a finales de marzo. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Datos de población:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para la parte de población de este indicador, IRENA utiliza los datos de población de las Perspectivas de la Población Mundial de las Naciones Unidas. Los datos de población reflejan los residentes en un país o área, independientemente de su estatus legal o ciudadanía. Los valores son estimaciones de mitad de año.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El Departamento de Asuntos Económicos y Sociales de las Naciones Unidas publicó información sobre su metodología en el siguiente enlace:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://population.un.org/wpp/Methodology/&quot;&gt;https://population.un.org/wpp/Methodology/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные по мощности собираются в рамках ежегодного цикла сбора информации с помощью вопросников IRENA. Вопросники рассылаются странам в начале года с просьбой предоставить данные по возобновляемым источникам энергии за второй год, предшествующий текущему (то есть в начале 2019 года в вопросниках запрашиваются данные за 2017 год). Затем осуществляется валидация и проверка данных со странами и их публикация в конце июня в Статистическом ежегоднике IRENA по возобновляемым источниках энергии. Для того, чтобы свести к минимуму бремя отчетности, вопросники для некоторых стран предварительно заполняются данными, собранными другими агентствами (например, Евростатом), и рассылаются странам, чтобы они могли внести любые дополнительные сведения, запрашиваемые IRENA. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В то же время предварительные оценки мощности за предыдущий год также собираются из официальных источников, где они доступны (например, национальной статистики, данных от операторов электросетей), и из других неофициальных источников (в основном отраслевых ассоциаций различных секторов возобновляемой энергетики). Они публикуются в конце марта. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Данные по населению: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Что касается демографической части этого показателя, IRENA использует данные по населению из публикации &quot;Мировые демографические перспективы&quot; Организации Объединенных Наций. Данные по населению отражают количество жителей страны или территории независимо от правового статуса или гражданства. Значения являются ориентировочными на середину года. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Департамент по экономическим и социальным вопросам Организации Объединенных Наций опубликовал информацию о своей методологии, которая расположена в ссылке ниже: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://population.un.org/wpp/Methodology/&quot;&gt; https://population.un.org/wpp/Methodology/ &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
