<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 12-c-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Comments and limitations:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The monitoring and reporting of SDG Indicator 12.c.1 requires capacity within national statistical systems to evaluate direct and indirect transfers of government funds. Data collection by the statistical agencies from the sectoral ministries and state-owned enterprises, including at the sub-national level, which depends on their capacity. There is a need for additional training materials and sharing of experiences on the indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator methodology utilizes a phased monitoring to allow for countries with different capacities to engage in monitoring 12.c.1. The two phases include global monitoring based on price gap estimates plus national monitoring of direct and indirect transfers with optional monitoring of tax expenditure foregone.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для мониторинга и отчетности по показателю 12.c.1 ЦУР необходим потенциал национальных статистических систем для оценки прямых и косвенных трансфертов государственных средств. Сбор данных статистическими агентствами от отраслевых министерств и государственных предприятий, в том числе на субнациональном уровне, который зависит от их потенциала. Необходимы дополнительные учебные материалы и обмен опытом по разработке показателя. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В методологии показателя используется мониторинг, разбитый на этапы, позволяющие странам с разным потенциалом участвовать в мониторинге показателя 12.c.1. Два этапа включают в себя как глобальный мониторинг, основанный на оценках разрыва в уровне цен, так и национальный мониторинг прямых и косвенных трансфертов с дополнительным мониторингом упущенных налоговых расходов. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
