<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 12-c-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Direct transfers are generally reported in government budgets, and well documented in sectoral and Finance Ministries, broken down by programme if not by fuel. Those that meet the SNA definition of &amp;#x201C;subsidies&amp;#x201D; &amp;#x2013; i.e., subsidies on products, and other subsidies on production &amp;#x2013; can also be found in a country&amp;#x2019;s System of National Accounts. Budget documents are publicly available for most countries. The degree to which information on individual programmes is itemized in those reports is highly variable, however. Support to corporations involved in energy production or transformation may sometimes be found in their annual reports, for example. In some cases, researchers may be able to obtain unpublished data from state-owned energy enterprises directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Induced transfer are measured by calculating the price-gap between the producer or consumer price and a reference price, and multiplying that differential by the affected volume produced or consumed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Measuring the value of special features introduced into the tax code to favour certain industries or activities of those industries (such as investment in productive capital) can be a complex endeavour. Some countries do this exercise already, and report the annual value of those tax features in their periodic tax-expenditure reports. Where that is not the case, the analysist must construct a model and estimate the difference in the revenues that would be owed to the government under the baseline conditions and with the special tax feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fossil fuel subsidies should be monitored on an annual basis. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Перевод средств с прямой передачей информации обычно отражаются в государственных бюджетах и хорошо документируются отраслевыми министерствами и министерствами финансов с разбивкой по программам, а иногда и по видам топлива. Те субсидии, которые соответствуют определению субсидий в СНС, т.е. субсидии на продукты и другие субсидии на производство, также можно найти в Системе национальных счетов страны. Бюджетные документы общедоступны для большинства стран. Однако степень детализации информации об отдельных программах в этих отчетах сильно различается. Информацию о поддержке корпораций, занимающихся производством или преобразованием энергии, иногда можно найти, например, в их годовых отчетах. В некоторых случаях исследователи могут напрямую получать неопубликованные данные от государственных энергетических предприятий.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Индуцируемые переводы оцениваются путем вычисления разницы между ценой производителя или потребителя и базовой ценой и умножением этой разницы на произведенный или потребленный объем. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Оценка величины специальных элементов, введенных в налоговый кодекс в пользу определенных отраслей или видов деятельности этих отраслей (например, инвестиций в производительный капитал), может быть сложной задачей. Некоторые страны уже делают это и отчитываются о годовой величине этих налоговых элементов в своих периодических отчетах о налоговых расходах. Если это не делается, то аналитик должен построить модель и оценить разницу в доходах, которые будут причитаться государству при базовых условиях и с особым налоговым элементом.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Субсидии на ископаемое топливо следует контролировать на ежегодной основе. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
