<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REG_AGG field for indicator 6-a-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Regional aggregates:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global and regional aggregates for ODA are derived based on summation of recipient country ODA disbursement for the water sector (purpose codes 14000- series) and agricultural water resources (purpose code 31140) from the OECD Creditor Reporting System. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global and regional proportions of ODA disbursements as part of a government budget are derived for countries based on a summation of ODA for the water sector that is included in the budget divided by a summation of total ODA for water sector. The calculation of global and regional aggregates would only be performed for those countries reporting the amount of ODA for the water sector that is included in the budget. If no data is provided for the amount of ODA in the budget, then the country is excluded from the regional and/or global analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los agregados mundiales y regionales de la AOD se obtienen a partir de la suma de los desembolsos de la AOD de los países receptores para el sector del agua (códigos de propósito 14000- serie) y los recursos hídricos agrícolas (código de propósito 31140) del Sistema de Información de Acreedores de la OCDE. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las proporciones globales y regionales de los desembolsos de AOD como parte de un presupuesto gubernamental se derivan para los países en base a una suma de la AOD para el sector del agua que se incluye en el presupuesto dividida por una suma de la AOD total para el sector del agua. El cálculo de los agregados globales y regionales sólo se realizará para aquellos países que informen de la cantidad de AOD para el sector del agua que se incluye en el presupuesto. Si no se facilitan datos sobre el importe de la AOD en el presupuesto, el país queda excluido del análisis regional y/o global.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Agrégats régionaux : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les agrégats mondiaux et régionaux de l&apos;APD sont calculés sur la base de la somme des décaissements d&apos;APD des pays bénéficiaires pour le secteur de l&apos;eau (codes d&apos;objectif 14000) et les ressources en eau agricoles (code d&apos;objectif 31140) du système de notification des pays créanciers de l&apos;OCDE. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les proportions mondiales et régionales des décaissements d&apos;APD dans le cadre d&apos;un budget gouvernemental sont calculées pour les pays sur la base d&apos;une somme d&apos;APD pour le secteur de l&apos;eau qui est incluse dans le budget, divisée par une somme d&apos;APD totale pour le secteur de l&apos;eau. Le calcul des agrégats mondiaux et régionaux ne serait effectué que pour les pays qui déclarent le montant de l&apos;APD pour le secteur de l&apos;eau qui est inclus dans le budget. Si aucune donnée n&apos;est fournie pour le montant de l&apos;APD dans le budget, le pays est alors exclu de l&apos;analyse régionale et/ou mondiale. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Региональные агрегаты: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Глобальные и региональные агрегированные показатели ОПР получены на основе суммирования выплат ОПР странам-получателям для сектора водных ресурсов (целевые коды серии 14000) и водных ресурсов сельского хозяйства (целевой код 31140) из Системы отчетности кредиторов ОЭСР. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Глобальные и региональные доли выплат ОПР как части государственного бюджета рассчитываются для стран на основе суммирования ОПР для сектора водных ресурсов, которая включена в бюджет, деленная на сумму общей ОПР для сектора водных ресурсов. Расчет глобальных и региональных агрегированных показателей будет выполняться только для тех стран, которые отчитываются об объеме ОПР для сектора водных ресурсов, включенной в бюджет. Если данные по размеру ОПР в бюджете не представлены, то страна исключается из регионального и / или глобального анализа. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
