<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 3-2-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nationally-representative estimates of child mortality can be derived from a number of different sources, including civil registration and sample surveys. Demographic surveillance sites and hospital data are excluded as they are rarely representative. The preferred source of data is a civil registration system that records births and deaths on a continuous basis. If registration is complete and the system functions efficiently, the resulting estimates will be accurate and timely. However, many countries do not have well-functioning vital registration systems. In such cases, household surveys, such as the UNICEF-supported Multiple Indicator Cluster Surveys (MICS), the USAID-supported Demographic and Health Surveys (DHS) and periodic population censuses have become the primary sources of data on under-five mortality. These surveys ask women about the survival of their children, and it is these reports that provide the basis of child mortality estimates for a majority of low- and middle- income countries. These data, however, are often subject to sampling or/and non-sampling errors, which might be substantial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Civil registration&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Civil registration data are the preferred data source for under-five, infant and neonatal mortality estimation. The calculation of the under-five and infant mortality rates from civil registration data is derived from a standard period abridged life table. For civil registration data (with available data on the number of deaths and mid-year populations), initially annual observations were constructed for all observation years in a country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Population census and household survey data&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of survey data comes in one of two forms: the full birth history (FBH), whereby women are asked for the date of birth of each of their children, whether the child is still alive, and if not the age at death; and the summary birth history (SBH), whereby women are asked only about the number of their children ever born and the number that have died (or equivalently the number still alive).&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
