<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 16-7-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This survey-based indicator measures self-reported levels of &amp;#x2018;external political efficacy&amp;#x2019;, that is, the extent to which people think that politicians and/or political institutions will listen to, and act on, the opinions of ordinary citizens. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address both dimensions covered by this indicator, SDG indicator 16.7.2 uses two well-established survey questions, namely: 1) one question measuring the extent to which people feel they &lt;em&gt;have a say&lt;/em&gt; in what the government does (focus on &lt;em&gt;inclusive&lt;/em&gt; participation in decision-making) and 2) another question measuring the extent to which people feel the political system allows them to have an &lt;em&gt;influence &lt;/em&gt;on politics (focus on &lt;em&gt;responsive &lt;/em&gt;decision-making).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All efforts should be made to disaggregate survey results on these two questions by sex, age group, income level, education level, place of residence (administrative region e.g. province, state, district; urban/rural), disability status, and nationally relevant population groups. A detailed questionnaire and implementation manual to produce the indicator is defined in the SDG 16 Survey Initiative&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decision-making:&lt;/strong&gt; It is implicit in indicator 16.7.2 that &amp;#x2018;decision-making&amp;#x2019; refers to decision-making in the public governance realm (and not all decision-making). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inclusive &lt;/em&gt;decision-making: &lt;/strong&gt;Decision-making processes which provide people with an opportunity to &amp;#x2018;have a say&amp;#x2019;, that is, to voice their demands, opinions and/or preferences to decision-makers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Responsive &lt;/em&gt;decision-making:&lt;/strong&gt; Decision-making processes where politicians and/or political institutions listen to and act on the stated demands, opinions and/or preferences of people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; The SDG 16 Survey Initiative jointly developed by UNDP, UNODC and OHCHR provides a high quality, well tested tool that countries can use to measure progress on many of the survey-based indicators under SDG16. It can support data production on peace, justice and inclusion (SDG 16). The methodology was welcomed by the 53&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; United Nations Statistical Commission (E/2022/24-E/CN.3/2022/41). &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</data>
</root>
