<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 9-c-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator is based on an internationally agreed definition and methodology, which have been developed under the coordination of ITU, through its Expert Groups and following an extensive consultation process with countries. It is also a core indicator of the Partnership on Measuring ICT for Development&amp;apos;s Core List of Indicators, which has been endorsed by the UN Statistical Commission (last time in 2014).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ITU collects data for this indicator through an annual questionnaire from national regulatory authorities or Information and Communication Technology Ministries, who collect the data from Internet service providers.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Este indicador se basa en una definición y una metodología acordadas internacionalmente, que se han desarrollado bajo la coordinación de la UIT, a través de sus Grupos de Expertos y tras un amplio proceso de consulta con los países. También es un indicador básico de la Lista Básica de Indicadores de la Asociación para la Medición de las TIC para el Desarrollo, que ha sido aprobada por la Comisión de Estadística de las Naciones Unidas (la última vez en 2014).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La UIT recopila datos para este indicador a través de un cuestionario anual de las autoridades reguladoras nacionales o de los Ministerios de Tecnologías de la Información y la Comunicación, que recogen los datos de los proveedores de servicios de Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Sources de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur repose sur une définition et une méthodologie convenues au niveau international, qui ont été élaborées sous la coordination de l&apos;UIT, par l&apos;intermédiaire de ses groupes d&apos;experts et à la suite d&apos;un vaste processus de consultation avec les pays. Il s&apos;agit également d&apos;un indicateur de base de la liste des indicateurs de base du Partenariat sur la mesure des TIC pour le développement qui a été approuvée par la Commission statistique des Nations unies (la dernière fois en 2014).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;UIT recueille des données pour cet indicateur par le biais d&apos;un questionnaire annuel auprès des autorités réglementaires nationales ou des ministères des technologies de l&apos;information et de la communication, qui collectent les données auprès des fournisseurs de services Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Этот показатель основан на согласованном на международном уровне определении и методологии, которые были разработаны при координации МСЭ путем привлечения к работам экспертных групп и после обширного процесса консультаций со странами. Показатель также является базовым показателем Основного перечня показателей Партнерства по измерению ИКТ в целях развития, который был одобрен Статистической комиссией ООН (последний раз в 2014 году) .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; МСЭ собирает данные для этого показателя с помощью ежегодного вопросника от национальных регулирующих органов или министерств информационных и коммуникационных технологий, которые, в свою очередь, собирают данные от поставщиков Интернет-услуг. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
