<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The OTHER_DOC field for indicator 6-5-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URLs: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&lt;/a&gt; . This contains the latest survey instrument, monitoring guide, and all supporting documentation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwp.org/en/sdg6support/&quot;&gt;https://www.gwp.org/en/sdg6support/&lt;/a&gt; : SDG 6 IWRM Support Programme. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- AMCOW 2018: Status Report on the Implementation of Water Resources Management in Africa: a regional report for SDG indicator 6.5.1 on IWRM implementation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- UNEP 2018: Progress on integrated water resources management. Global baseline for SDG 6 Indicator 6.5.1: degree of IWRM implementation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- United Nations Economic and Social Commission for West Asia (2019). Status Report on the Implementation of Integrated Water Resources Management in the Arab Region: Progress on SDG indicator 6.5.1. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- UN-Water initiative on integrated monitoring of SDG 6. &lt;a href=&quot;http://sdg6data.org&quot;&gt;http://sdg6data.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- UN-Water, 2016: Water and Sanitation Interlinkages across the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development. Geneva.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contiene el último instrumento de encuesta, la guía de seguimiento y toda la documentación de apoyo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Referencias:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- AMCOW 2018: Informe de situación sobre la implementación de la gestión de los recursos hídricos en África: un informe regional para el indicador 6.5.1 de los ODS sobre la implementación de la GIRH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- PNUMA 2018: Progreso en la gestión integrada de los recursos hídricos. Línea de base global para el indicador 6.5.1 del ODS: grado de implementación de la GIRH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Comisión Económica y Social de las Naciones Unidas para Asia Occidental (2019). Informe de situación sobre la aplicación de la gestión integrada de los recursos hídricos en la región árabe: Avances en el indicador 6.5.1 de los ODS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Iniciativa de ONU-Agua sobre el seguimiento integrado del ODS 6. &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;http://sdg6data.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- ONU-Agua, 2016: Interrelaciones del agua y el saneamiento en la Agenda 2030 para el Desarrollo Sostenible. Ginebra.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Références&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il contient le dernier instrument d&apos;enquête, le guide de suivi et tous les documents d&apos;appui. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Références:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- AMCOW 2018 : Rapport sur l&apos;état de la mise en œuvre de la gestion des ressources en eau en Afrique : un rapport régional pour l&apos;indicateur 6.5.1 du ODD sur la mise en œuvre de la GIRE. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- PNUE 2018 : Progrès en matière de gestion intégrée des ressources en eau. Base de référence mondiale pour l&apos;ODD 6 Indicateur 6.5.1 : degré de mise en œuvre de la GIRE. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Commission économique et sociale des Nations Unies pour l&apos;Asie occidentale (2019). Rapport sur l&apos;état d&apos;avancement de la mise en œuvre de la gestion intégrée des ressources en eau dans la région arabe : Progrès sur l&apos;indicateur ODD 6.5.1. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Initiative de l&apos;ONU-Eau sur la surveillance intégrée du SDG 6 &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;http://sdg6data.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- ONU-Eau, 2016 : Les liens entre l&apos;eau et l&apos;assainissement dans le cadre de l&apos;Agenda 2030 pour le développement durable. Genève. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt; http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Здесь содержится новейший инструмент обследования, руководство по мониторингу и вся сопроводительная документация. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Ссылки: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; - Африканский совет министров по водным ресурсам (AMCOW) 2018 год: Отчет о состоянии внедрения управления водными ресурсами в Африке: региональный отчет по показателю 6.5.1 ЦУР по реализации КУВР. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; - Программа ООН по окружающей среде (ЮНЕП) 2018 год: Прогресс в области комплексного управления водными ресурсами. Глобальный базовый уровень для показателя 6.5.1 ЦУР 6: степень реализации КУВР. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; - Экономическая и социальная комиссия Организации Объединенных Наций для Западной Азии (2019 год). Отчет о состоянии внедрения комплексного управления водными ресурсами в арабском регионе: прогресс в отношении показателя 6.5.1 ЦУР. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; - Инициатива &quot;ООН Водные ресурсы&quot; по комплексному мониторингу достижения ЦУР 6. &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt; http://sdg6data.org &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; - Механизм «ООН — Водные ресурсы», 2016 год: Взаимосвязь водоснабжения и санитарии в Повестке дня в области устойчивого развития на период до 2030 года. Женева. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
