<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REG_AGG field for indicator 6-5-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Regional aggregates:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the Agenda 2030 principle of &amp;#x201C;leaving no one behind&amp;#x201D;, regional and global values will be based on simple, un-weighted averages of country scores. The country scores will be presented as a whole number, and regional and global averages will also be presented as a whole number. Global averages will be based on country values, not regional averages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regional values may be assembled by regional bodies responsible for water resources in the region, such as the African Ministerial Council on Water (AMCOW), the European Environment Agency (EEA), and the United Nations Economic and Social Commission for West Asia (ESCWA).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Agrégats régionaux : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conformément au principe de l&apos;Agenda 2030 &amp;#x201C; qui consiste à ne laisser personne derrière &amp;#x201D;, les valeurs régionales et mondiales seront basées sur des moyennes simples et non pondérées des scores des pays. Les scores des pays seront présentés comme un nombre entier, et les moyennes régionales et mondiales seront également présentées comme un nombre entier. Les moyennes mondiales seront basées sur les valeurs des pays, et non sur les moyennes régionales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les valeurs régionales peuvent être rassemblées par les organismes régionaux responsables des ressources en eau dans la région, tels que le Conseil ministériel africain sur l&apos;eau (AMCOW), l&apos;Agence européenne pour l&apos;environnement (AEE) et la Commission économique et sociale des Nations Unies pour l&apos;Asie occidentale (CESAO).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
