<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DOC_METHOD field for indicator 12-3-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The main source of loss data at the national level are: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Official reports of loss estimates in the commodity balance sheets, Supply Utilization Accounts or Food Balance Sheets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data sources for agricultural production and on-farm losses are mainly national agricultural surveys that are conducted by the Ministry of Agricultural/Livestock and/or the National Statistical Office. The surveys are usually annual, and in the absence of direct measurements, results are based on interview-based data on lost quantities of crop, animals and animal products. Agricultural censuses, which FAO recommends conducting every ten years, may be the only available source of loss estimates in a number of countries that do not carry out annual surveys. Off-farm loss data along the value chain may be obtained through specialized surveys (supplemented by research) through the national agri-food industry system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Methodology for monitoring SDG Target 12.3 : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/CA2640EN/ca2640en.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/CA2640EN/ca2640en.pdf&lt;/a&gt; has been published as a guide for countries in calculating the index along with a method to aggregate data from subnational stages of the supply chain to the national level. Subnational disaggregation will identify where losses occur and the scope of impact, sets the focus on where to make investments and aids in targeting intervention strategies and policies to decrease food losses along the supply chains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Guidelines for the measurement of harvest and post-harvest losses of grain produced by the Global Strategy are available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://gsars.org/en/guidelines-on-the-measurement-of-harvest-and-post-harvest-losses/&quot;&gt;http://gsars.org/en/guidelines-on-the-measurement-of-harvest-and-post-harvest-losses/&lt;/a&gt; with an on-line training course available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://gsars.org/en/training-course-on-post-harvest-losses-english/#more-3855&quot;&gt;http://gsars.org/en/training-course-on-post-harvest-losses-english/#more-3855&lt;/a&gt; . Additional material is available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/sustainable-development-goals/indicators/1231/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/sustainable-development-goals/indicators/1231/en/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other important documents that can guide countries in the measurement and compilation of the FLI are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports on pilot testing the FLI : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/ca6691en/ca6691en.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/ca6691en/ca6691en.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E-learning course on SDG Sub-Indicator 12.3.1a : &lt;a href=&quot;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=605&quot;&gt;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=605&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
