<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The QUALITY_ASSURE field for indicator 12-3-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;For FAO, a sound statistical basis is essential in monitoring progress towards national and international development goals and targets. To ensure quality standards are maintained, the organization developed a Quality Assurance Framework for the FAO Statistics system (FAO SQAF) consisting of a quality framework and a mechanism to ensure the compliance of FAO statistics to the quality framework itself. The SQAF is available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/i3664e/i3664e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/i3664e/i3664e.pdf&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With respect to officially reported loss data submitted by countries through the annual Agriculture Production Questionnaire, loss data is validated during the whole Supply Utilization Account/Food Balance Sheet processing and validation that entails a purely statistical approach based on outlier detection tests and validation routines and a consultative approach where countries are requested for additional information or clarifications. The same approach applies to the date received in 2019 though the ad hoc questionnaire on &amp;#x201C;Food Losses from Production to the Retail stage&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More generally FAO complies with &amp;#x201C;Guidelines on global data flows&amp;#x201D; approved by UNSC 2018 for the national data submitted to FAO for the SDGs Indicators Database. With respect to losses that is extremely scarce dataset (7% of reported records in FAOSTAT in the period 1990-2016), and to the extent that country data has to be estimated with an econometric model, the estimates are validated with countries via an email asking for an authorization to publish them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The available basic data still does not allow for the publication of the Food Loss Index at the country level but only at the regional level by commodity groups. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
