<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The QUALITY_ASSMNT field for indicator 12-3-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Datasets (production, trade and utilizations), once cross-checked and validated, form the basis for the compilation of the Food Balance Sheets (FBS). The FBS are an accounting framework whereby supply (production + imports + stock withdrawals) should equal utilization (export + food processing + feed + seed + industrial use, etc.). It should be noted that, within the FBS framework, post-harvest/slaughter losses (up to the retail level) are considered as utilization, and thus a component in the balancing of the FBS. The FBS framework provides a snapshot of the agricultural supply situation at the national level, and allows for a cross-referenced structure whereby data, official or estimated/imputed, may be further analyzed and validated (e.g. animal numbers may result as being under-reported/estimated). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Les ensembles de données (production, commerce et utilisations), une fois recoupés et validés, constituent la base de la compilation des bilans alimentaires (FBS). Les FBS sont un cadre comptable dans lequel l&apos;offre (production + importations + retraits de stocks) doit être égale à l&apos;utilisation (exportation + transformation alimentaire + alimentation animale + semences + utilisation industrielle, etc.) Il convient de noter que, dans le cadre du FBS, les pertes post-récolte/abattage (jusqu&apos;au niveau du détail) sont considérées comme une utilisation, et donc une composante de l&apos;équilibrage du FBS. Le cadre FBS fournit un instantané de la situation de l&apos;offre agricole au niveau national et permet une structure de références croisées grâce à laquelle les données, officielles ou estimées/imputées, peuvent être analysées plus en détail et validées (par exemple, le nombre d&apos;animaux peut être considéré comme étant sous-déclaré/estimé). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
