<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 6-3-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of the UNSD and OECD/Eurostat databases, data on wastewater generation and treatment are not widely available, and what data do exist may not align with international definitions and classifications (e.g. ISIC codes). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For statistics on total wastewater generated and treated, missing values are not imputed. No estimated or modelled data are produced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some countries do not separately report the volume of wastewater generated by households. In the absence of reported data on domestic wastewater generation, an estimate of the wastewater generated at the household level will be made. It can be estimated that 80% of the water supply which enters private households will subsequently exit the household as wastewater. Therefore, if data are available on per capita water consumption, these can be used to estimate domestic wastewater generation. If data on per capita water consumption are not available, data from household surveys and censuses can be used to indicate the proportion of the population which has water supplies available on premises (e.g. municipal piped water, private boreholes with overhead tanks) and the proportion of the population which collects water from off-premises sources (e.g. communal standposts, community boreholes). In the absence of other data on domestic water consumption, it can be estimated that households with on-premises water supply consume approximately 120 litres per capita per day, and therefore generate 96 litres of wastewater per capita per day; those with off-premises water supply are assumed to consume approximately 20 litres per capita per day, and therefore generate 16 litres of wastewater per capita per day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Missing values needed for calculation of the proportion of domestic wastewater which receives appropriate treatment will be handled in a similar way to the calculation of &amp;#x2018;safely managed sanitation services&amp;#x2019; for SDG indicator 6.2.1. Domestic wastewater which enters sewage lines will be assumed to reach centralized wastewater treatment plants, unless national data is available about leakage from sewage lines. The volume of domestic wastewater estimated to reach treatment plants will be compared against the volume of wastewater reported to be received at wastewater plants, and the volume reportedly received will be taken as an upper limit to the amount of domestic wastewater which receives off-site treatment. If data are available on the proportion of wastewater flows received by centralized treatment plants which receive secondary treatment or better, this proportion can be assumed to apply equally to the flows generated by households, industries, and services which discharge into public sewers. Domestic wastewater which enters on-site storage and treatment systems such as septic tanks will be assumed to be safely treated if national data on compliance of on-site wastewater treatment systems to relevant standards are available. In the absence of such data, half of the wastewater discharged into on-site storage and treatment systems will be considered to receive safe treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the data limitations, especially on non-household wastewater, data currently available on compliance with discharge permits could be used to better to estimate the industrial flows treated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &amp;#x2018;regional aggregates&amp;#x2019;.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
