<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DOC_METHOD field for indicator 16-3-3, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;Methodological documentation from surveys conducted at national level is available (e.g. household survey in Nigeria conducted by the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS) and UNODC; Governance, Public Safety and Justice Survey conducted by Statistics South Africa in 2019, Kenya Integrated Household Budget Survey 2015-2016 conducted by KNBS; Argentina - Unmet Legal Needs and Access to Justice conducted by the Subsecretar&amp;#xED;a de Acceso a la Justicia Ministerio de Justicia y Derechos Humanos; or Colombia &amp;#x2013; Survey of Citizen Security and Coexistence conducted by DANE). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the Legal Needs Surveys and Access to Justice methodological guidance published by OECD in 2019 provides methodological guidance for developing the questionnaires and conducting such surveys. This guide brings together the experience gained through more than 60 national surveys conducted by governments and civil society organizations in more than 30 jurisdictions in the last 25 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2022, the United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime (UNODC) together with the United Nations Development Program (UNDP) and the Office of the United Nations High Commissioner on Human Rights (OHCHR) published the SDG 16 Survey Questionnaire&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-7&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-7&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and Implementation Manual&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-8&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-8&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, which contain internationally standardised survey question wording (in the five official UN languages) as well as implementation guidance related to this indicator. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-7&quot;&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; See &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sdg16hub.org/topic/sdg-16-survey-initiative-questionnaire&quot;&gt;SDG 16 Initiative Questionnaire&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-7&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-8&quot;&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; See &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sdg16hub.org/topic/sdg-16-survey-initiative-implementation-manual&quot;&gt;SDG 16 Initiative Implementation Manual&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-8&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</data>
</root>
