<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The CLASS_SYSTEM field for indicator 8-10-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="en">## Concepts

Account at a financial institution includes respondents who report having an account at a bank or at another type of financial institution, such as a credit union, microfinance institution, cooperative, or the post office (if applicable), or having a debit card in their own name. In addition, it includes respondents who report receiving wages, government transfers, or payments for agricultural products into an account at a financial institution in the past 12 months; paying utility bills or school fees from an account at a financial institution in the past 12 months; or receiving wages or government transfers into a card in the past 12 months. Mobile money account includes respondents who report personally using GSM Association (GSMA) Mobile Money for the Unbanked (MMU) services in the past 12 months to pay bills or to send or receive money. In addition, it includes respondents who report receiving wages, government transfers, or payments for agricultural products through a mobile phone in the past 12 months.
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">## Понятия

К имеющим счет в финансовом учреждении относятся респонденты, которые сообщают о наличии счета в банке или другом учреждении, например, в кредитном союзе, микрофинансовом учреждении, кооперативе или почтовом отделении (если применимо), или о наличии у них дебетовой карты на свое имя. Кроме того, к их числу относятся респонденты, которые сообщают о получении заработной платы, государственных трансфертов или платежей за сельскохозяйственную продукцию на счет в финансовом учреждении за последние 12 месяцев; об оплате коммунальных услуг или сборов за обучение со счета в финансовом учреждении за последние 12 месяцев; или о получении заработной платы или государственных трансфертов на банковскую карточку за последние 12 месяцев. Счет &quot;Мобильные деньги&quot; включает в себя респондентов, которые за последние 12 месяцев лично воспользовались услугами &quot;Мобильные деньги&quot; для лиц, не имеющие доступа к банковским услугам Ассоциации глобальной системы мобильно связи (GSMA) для оплаты счетов, отправки или получения денег. Кроме того, в него входят респонденты, которые сообщают о получении заработной платы, государственных трансфертов или платежей за сельскохозяйственную продукцию по мобильному телефону в течение последних 12 месяцев.
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
