<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COMPARABILITY field for indicator 8-10-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global Findex Database is an individual level survey, measuring an individual&amp;#x2019;s perception of ownership of accounts. It assumes financial inclusion is an individual-level concept which may create two potential discrepancies. First, the data may deviate from supply side data which counts the number of accounts and may overstate the level of financial inclusion in a country if a significant number of adults have an account they do not use and did not formally close. Second, not all demand-side data is the same and that the data from different demand-side surveys cannot necessarily be compared if the survey method is different. In particular, surveys of individuals cannot be compared directly with surveys of household heads, since the use of financial services can differ considerably between different household members.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fuentes de discrepancias:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global Findex es una encuesta a nivel individual que mide la titularidad de cuentas por parte de los individuos&amp;#x2019;. Dado que la inclusión financiera es un concepto a nivel individual, ésta es la medida adecuada. Otras encuestas que se realizan a nivel de hogar pueden medir el acceso a la financiación a través de otro miembro del hogar, lo que puede sobreestimar la inclusión financiera.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources des divergences : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global Findex est une enquête au niveau individuel qui mesure le nombre d&apos;individus possédant un compte. Comme l&apos;inclusion financière est un concept individuel, il s&apos;agit de la mesure appropriée. D&apos;autres enquêtes réalisées au niveau des ménages peuvent mesurer l&apos;accès au financement par un autre membre du ménage, ce qui peut surestimer l&apos;inclusion financière.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Охват населения финансовыми услугами ФИНДЕКС- это опрос на уровне отдельных лиц, служащий для оценки индивидуального владения счетами. Поскольку доступ к финансовым услугам является понятием индивидуального уровня, эта процедура является подходящим инструментом оценки. Иные обследования, проводимые на уровне домохозяйств, могут включать оценку доступа к финансовым услугам при посредничестве другого члена домохозяйства, что может завысить уровень охвата финансовыми услугами.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
