<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 8-10-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World Bank&amp;#x2019;s Global Findex database is based on individual level surveys worldwide, conducted every three years. The first round of the survey was done in 2011, and the second in 2014. The third round will be done in 2017. The database covers about 140 countries. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La base de datos Global Findex del Banco Mundial&amp;#x2019;se basa en encuestas a nivel individual en todo el mundo, realizadas cada tres años. La primera ronda de la encuesta se realizó en 2011, y la segunda en 2014. La tercera ronda se realizará en 2017. La base de datos abarca unos 140 países.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commentaires et limites : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La base de données Global Findex de la Banque mondiale est basée sur des enquêtes individuelles menées tous les trois ans dans le monde entier. Le premier cycle de l&apos;enquête a été réalisé en 2011, le second en 2014, et le troisième en 2017. La base de données couvre environ 140 pays.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Глобальная база данных по охвату населения финансовыми услугами (ФИНДЕКС) основана на информации, получаемой из индивидуальных опросов, проводимых во всех странах мира каждые три года. Первый раунд опросов был проведен в 2011 году, а второй в 2014 году. Третий раунд будет проведен в 2017 году. База данных охватывает около 140 стран.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
