<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REG_AGG field for indicator 8-10-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regional aggregates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Country level; the percentage of adults owning accounts is multiplied by the number of adults in the country. Then for regional values, sum across all countries in the region is taken and divided by the total adults living in the region. Similarly, for global figures, the same calculation is repeated for all countries.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A nivel de país; el porcentaje de adultos que poseen cuentas se multiplica por el número de adultos del país. A continuación, para los valores regionales, se toma la suma de todos los países de la región y se divide por el total de adultos que viven en ella. Del mismo modo, para las cifras globales, se repite el mismo cálculo para todos los países.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agrégats régionaux : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Au niveau national, le pourcentage d&apos;adultes possédant un compte est multiplié par le nombre d&apos;adultes dans le pays. Ensuite, pour les valeurs régionales, la somme de tous les pays de la région est prise et divisée par le nombre total d&apos;adultes vivant dans la région. De façon similaire, pour les chiffres mondiaux, le même calcul est répété pour tous les pays.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Региональные агрегаты:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;На уровне страны; процент взрослых, владеющих счетами, умножается на количество взрослых в стране. Затем для региональных значений берется сумма по всем странам региона и делится на общее количество взрослых, проживающих в этом регионе. Аналогичным образом для глобальных значений один и тот же расчет повторяется для всех стран.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
