<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 5-a-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;Customary law &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since customary law is not a homogenous system of law, assessing whether it establishes equal rights to land ownership and/or control for women and men is very challenging. Therefore, the methodology determines that customary law will only be considered to the extent that it has been recognized in the legal framework. However, this also means that reporting data does not cover the legal systems where customary law has not been formalized but continues to govern family and land matters, possibly constituting a major factor of discrimination against women. Further, given that customary law does not exist in all countries, it is not universally applicable. The methodology has addressed this issue by creating a dual system of computation of the results, which is explained below in section 4. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geographical scope. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data collected for the SDG indicator 5.a.2 is collected at the national level to ensure that it adequately represents the national legal system. This means that the 5.a.2 assessment to determine the existence of the proxies should focus on legal and policy instruments that have nationwide authority. In countries where law-making power for land or gender matters does not reside with the central authority (or is shared between the national government and a sub-national government), the assessment may require analysing laws at state, provincial or county level. However, any research at sub-national level can only be undertaken &lt;em&gt;after &lt;/em&gt;mapping and analysing the relevant provisions in the overarching legal framework at constitutional and federal level for a focused and efficient data collection process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case the assessment requires data collection and data analysis at the sub-national level, a sample of the states, provinces or counties will be established, including the most populous states up until reaching 50 percent of the total country&amp;#x2019;s population. Since the results must have nationwide authority, the proxy should be located in the laws of each state, province or county that is part of the sample. If it is not the case, the proxy is not present.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
