<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 16-10-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number of countries that adopt and implement constitutional, statutory and/or policy guarantees for public access to information&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus of this indicator is thus on the status of adoption and implementation of constitutional, statutory and/or policy guarantees for public access to information. The definition relates directly to &amp;#x201C;public access to information&amp;#x201D;, which is wider than, but is also very much based upon, the established fundamental freedoms of expression and association. Conversely, these freedoms also both impact on the environment for public access to information. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conceptually, &amp;#x2018;public access to information&amp;#x2019; refers to &amp;#x201C;the presence of a robust system through which information is made available to citizens and others.&amp;#x201D; Such a system represents a combination of intellectual, physical, and social elements that affect the availability of information to individuals. In other words, in discussing the issue of public access to information, it is important to recognize that any measurement of its practical outworking needs to take into account how individuals perceive the quality of information in the public domain, the nature of the communicative infrastructure in place to facilitate access, and how that information is ultimately utilized by individuals as members of a particular polity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, then, these are the issues that go into legislation and policy on public access. More specifically, such legislation and policy take the form of Freedom of Information laws (FOI laws) which are aimed at allowing access by the general public to data held by national governments and, increasingly, by private companies whose work intersect with government operations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emergence of freedom of information legislation was a response to increasing dissatisfaction with the secrecy surrounding government policy development and decision making. They establish a &amp;quot;right-to-know&amp;quot; legal process by which requests may be made for government-held information, to be received freely or at minimal cost, barring standard exceptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a formulation has a basis in international agreements. For example, the right to freedom of expression, which is not only recognized as a basic human right in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights (1948), is also upheld in the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights (1966), the European Convention on Human Rights (1950), the American Convention on Human Rights (1969) and the African Charter on Human and Peoples&amp;#x2019; Rights (1981), thus lending itself to universal political recognition and application. More specifically, in the European context, reference may be made to the Council of Europe Convention on Access to Official Documents, adopted on 18 June 2009. In the Americas, the Organization of American States&amp;#x2019; Inter-American Juridical Committee developed a set of Principles on the Right of Access to Information in 2008.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
