<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 3-3-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Country teams use UNAIDS-supported Spectrum software to develop estimates annually. The country teams are comprised primarily of epidemiologists, demographers, monitoring and evaluation specialists and technical partners. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UNAIDS Reference Group on Estimates, Modelling and Projections provides technical guidance on the development of the HIV component of the Spectrum software (www.epidem.org). The Spectrum software is developed by Avenir Health (www.avenirhealth.org)&amp;#x2014;which includes a module, the Estimates and Projections Package, which is developed by the East-West Center (www.eastwestcenter.org). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt; Proceso de recolección:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Los equipos nacionales utilizan software compatible con ONUSIDA para desarrollar estimaciones anualmente. Los equipos nacionales están compuestos principalmente por epidemiólogos, demógrafos, especialistas en monitoreo y evaluación y socios técnicos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; El software utilizado para producir las estimaciones es Spectrum&amp;#x2014; desarrollado por Avenir Health (www.avenirhealth.org)&amp;#x2014; y el Paquete de Estimaciones y Proyecciones, que es desarrollado por el Centro Este-Oeste (&lt;a href=&quot;www.eastwestcenter.org&quot;&gt;www.eastwestcenter.org&lt;/a&gt;). El Grupo de Referencia de ONUSIDA sobre estimaciones, modelización y proyecciones proporciona orientación técnica sobre el desarrollo del componente del VIH del software (&lt;a href=&quot;www.epidem.org&quot;&gt;www.epidem.org&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Les équipes des pays utilisent le logiciel Spectrum soutenu par l&apos;ONUSIDA pour élaborer des estimations annuelles. Les équipes nationales sont composées principalement d&apos;épidémiologistes, de démographes, de spécialistes du suivi et de l&apos;évaluation et de partenaires techniques. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Groupe de référence sur les estimations, modèles et projections de l&apos;ONUSIDA fournit des conseils techniques sur le développement de la composante VIH du logiciel Spectrum ((en anglais) www.epidem.org). Le logiciel Spectrum est développé par « Avenir Health » ((en anglais) www.avenirhealth.org) – qui comprend un module d&apos;estimations et de projections qui est développé par le « East-West Center » ((en anglais) www.eastwestcenter.org). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Страновые группы используют поддерживаемое ЮНЭЙДС программное обеспечение для составления ежегодной оценки. Страновые группы состоят в основном из эпидемиологов, демографов, специалистов по мониторингу и оценке и технических партнеров. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для составления оценок используется программное обеспечение Spectrum, разработанное организацией Avenir Health (www.avenirhealth.org), и пакет для создания оценок и прогнозов, разработанный Восточно-западным центром (&lt;a href = &quot;www.eastwestcenter.org&quot;&gt;www.eastwestcenter.org&lt;/a&gt;). Контрольная группа ЮНЭЙДС по оценкам, моделированию и прогнозам предоставляет техническое руководство по разработке компонента программного обеспечения, связанного с ВИЧ (&lt;a href=&quot;www.epidem.org&quot;&gt;www.epidem.org&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
