<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 3-5-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the reporting period 2013-2017, 62 countries have provided data on drug use disorders and 98 countries provided data on drug treatment. The availability and accuracy of data on the number of people with drug use disorders and people in treatment for the use of drugs is gradually increasing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the number of alcohol use disorders data are currently available for 188 Member States (for 2016) and validated through the process of country consultation. Data are regularly updated and presented through WHO Global Health Observatory. For utilization of treatment by people with alcohol use disorders, data are currently available for at least 30 countries and further data collection is ongoing &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For contextual information on treatment services, WHO has collected data from more than 85 countries; data collection for other is ongoing and to be accomplished till the end of 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During 2013-2017, 34 countries have provided at least two datapoints for both numerator and denominator necessary for the calculation of the SDG indicator on drug use disorders. With the improved ARQ, it is expected that the number of responses and quality of data reported will increase after 2021. For the alcohol, data on denominator are available for a long period since establishment of GISAH in 1997 and the indicator has been tentatively calculated for at least 30 countries in 2019, with contextual information available for 85. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the policy importance, the indicator will be disaggregated to provide data for drugs and alcohol. Depending on data availability, it will be additionally disaggregated by following: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;by treatment interventions (pharmacological, psychosocial, rehabilitation and aftercare) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;by sex &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;by age groups &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In relation to drug use disorders, the following types of drugs should be considered: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cannabis (including herb and resin) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;opioids (opium, heroin, medicinal products containing opioids and other opioids)), &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cocaine type, &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;amphetamines (amphetamine, methamphetamine, medicinal products containing ATS), &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ecstasy-type substances, &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sedatives and tranquilizers, &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hallucinogens &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;solvents and inhalants &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NPS &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</data>
</root>
