<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 14-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;At this moment, data collection is separate for the national and regional/global levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global/regional level: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fish stocks that FAO has monitored since 1974 represent a wide spectrum of data availability, ranging from data-rich and formally assessed stocks to those that have very little information apart from catch statistics by FAO major fishing area and those with no stock assessment at all. For the purposes of using the best available data and information and maintaining consistency among stocks and assessors, a procedure has been defined to identify relevant stock status information (FAO 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National level: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO collects national data through a questionnaire sent to the Principal Focal Point (PFP) of each country. The PFP organises an institutional set-up which identifies the competent authorities to develop a reference list of stocks and completes the questionnaire. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the initial stages of national data reporting, the information or data collected through the questionnaire from a country will initially only inform the indicator for the individual countries, also acknowledging the need for a learning curve along the few first questionnaire inquiries. As a result, the global/regional indicator remains during these initial stages separate from the national indicators. However, FAO is working on a convergence (where possible) of the two processes, and good-quality stock status assessments reported by countries for the national indicators will be included in the regional/global indicator calculations, depending on the evolution and further standardization of country reporting over the next 3-5 years..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this effort, due to the heterogeneity of reporting from countries in the same FAO Major Fishing Area, and the necessary inclusion of straddling and highly migratory stocks and fisheries in the regional and global indicator, it is unlikely that a full convergence will be achieved in a short time-frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is applicable for countries with marine borders (or those bordering the Caspian Sea) and therefore excludes landlocked countries from data collection and processing. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
