<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DOC_METHOD field for indicator 14-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Methods and guidance available to countries for the compilation of the data at the national level:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In each country, the data available for each stock and expertise level to conduct different types of assessments will differ. Some countries may have classic stock assessments already conducted for many of their stocks, while others may have very few or no assessments available. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some countries, little stock assessment has been done. To help these countries and to facilitate their reporting, FAO prepared online materials and tools, including a selection of methods that can be used to evaluate stock status with data limited methods such as length-based and catch-only methods. The strengths and limitations of these methods are discussed in an eLearning course (Lesson 4), and caveats were also provided to avoid misuse and exercise cautions in practice. Furthermore, capacity building workshops have been organised to provide support to countries in stock assessment and reporting on the SDG 14.4.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eLearning course:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=502&quot;&gt;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=502&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt;Доступные странам методы и руководства для составления данных на национальном уровне:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;В каждой стране данные, доступные для каждого запаса и уровня знаний для проведения различных типов оценок, будут разными. Некоторые страны могут уже иметь проведенные классические оценки многих своих запасов, в то время как другие могут иметь очень мало оценок или вообще их не иметь. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Для некоторых стран было проведено мало оценок запасов. Чтобы помочь этим странам и облегчить процесс составления отчетности, ФАО подготовила онлайн-материалы и инструменты, включая набор методов, которые можно использовать для оценки состояния запаса с помощью методов с ограниченными данными, таких как методы, основанные на длине и только на данных по улову. Сильные и слабые стороны этих методов обсуждаются в курсе электронного обучения (Урок 4), а также были сделаны предостережения, чтобы избежать неправильного использования и соблюдать осторожность на практике. Кроме того, были организованы семинары по наращиванию потенциала для оказания поддержки странам в оценке запасов и составлении отчетности по ЦУР 14.4.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eLearning course:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=502&quot;&gt;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=502&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
