<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 14-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The indicator measures the sustainability of fishery resources, and as an end-result is a measure of Target 14.4. Its derivation requires catch data and fishing effort and other biological or technical parameters as well together with technical expertise necessary to perform stock assessment. The indicator at global level is estimated by the FAO based on the methodology developed in the 1980s. Although regular updates were carried out to incorporate technical advances and changes in major fish species, some discrepancies between regions may occur in the representativeness of the reference list in practical fisheries. However, this will not pose a large impact on the reliability of the indicator&amp;#x2019;s temporal trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the national level, the composition of stocks within the reference list of stocks and the selection criteria used to develop the list will vary between countries, making the indicator suitable for checking countries&amp;#x2019; own progress over time. However, this reduces the comparability of sustainability levels between countries.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador mide la sostenibilidad de los recursos pesqueros y es una medida de resultado final de la meta 14.4. Su derivación requiere los datos y los conocimientos técnicos necesarios para realizar la evaluación de las poblaciones. El indicador a nivel mundial es estimado por la FAO basándose en la metodología desarrollada en los años 80. Aunque se han realizado actualizaciones periódicas para incorporar los avances técnicos y los cambios en las principales especies de peces, pueden producirse algunas discrepancias entre las regiones en cuanto a la representatividad de la lista de referencia en las pesquerías prácticas. Sin embargo, esto no supondrá un gran impacto en la fiabilidad de las tendencias temporales del indicador.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En el ámbito nacional, la composición de las poblaciones dentro de la lista de referencia de poblaciones y los criterios de selección utilizados para elaborar la lista variarán entre los países, lo que hace que el indicador sea adecuado para comprobar el progreso propio de los países a lo largo del tiempo. Sin embargo, esto reduce la comparabilidad de los niveles de sostenibilidad entre países. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires et limites :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur mesure la durabilité des ressources halieutiques et constitue une mesure du résultat final de la cible 14.4. Son calcul nécessite les données et l&apos;expertise technique nécessaires à l&apos;évaluation des stocks. L&apos;indicateur au niveau mondial est estimé par la FAO sur la base de la méthodologie développée dans les années 1980. Bien que des mises à jour régulières aient été effectuées pour incorporer les progrès techniques et les changements dans les principales espèces de poissons, certaines divergences entre les régions peuvent se produire dans la représentativité de la liste de référence dans les pêcheries pratiques. Toutefois, cela n&apos;aura pas un impact important sur la fiabilité des tendances temporelles de l&apos;indicateur&amp;#x2019;678.
&lt;p&gt;Au niveau national, la composition des stocks dans la liste de référence des stocks et les critères de sélection utilisés pour développer la liste varieront entre les pays, rendant l&apos;indicateur approprié pour vérifier les progrès des pays&amp;#x2019; eux-mêmes au fil du temps. Cependant, cela réduit la comparabilité des niveaux de durabilité entre les pays.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt;Комментарии и ограничения:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Показатель отражает устойчивость рыбных ресурсов и является критерием оценки конечного результата Задачи 14.4. Его расчет требует данных и технических знаний, необходимых для выполнения оценки запасов. Показатель на глобальном уровне оценивается ФАО на основе методологии, разработанной в 1980-х годах. Хотя регулярно проводились обновления для включения технических достижений и изменений основных видов рыб, но между регионами могут возникать некоторые расхождения в репрезентативности справочного списка в практическом рыболовстве. Однако это не окажет большого влияния на достоверность временных трендов показателя.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;На национальном уровне состав запасов в справочном списке запасов и критерии отбора, используемые для составления списка, будут различаться в зависимости от страны, что делает показатель пригодным для проверки собственного странового прогресса с течением времени. Однако это снижает сопоставимость уровней разумного использования ресурсов между странами. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
