<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 14-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator, &amp;quot;Proportion of marine fish stocks within biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot;, measures the sustainability of the world&amp;apos;s marine capture fisheries by the abundance of the exploited fish stocks with respect to MSY levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each level of reporting (National, Regional, Global) the indicator is calculated as the ratio between the number of exploited fish stocks classified as &amp;quot;within biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot; and the total number of stocks in the Reference List that were classified with a determined status (within/not within &amp;quot;biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;msub&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;P&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/msub&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;x&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;100&lt;/mn&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;x&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;100&lt;/mn&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where Ps is the percentage of stocks classified as &amp;quot;within biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot; for the Reference List of stocks. Ns is the number of stocks in the Reference List classified as &amp;quot;within biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot;, Nu is the number of stocks in the Reference List classified as &amp;quot;outside biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot; and N = Ns + Nu is the total number of stocks in the Reference List that have been classified as within or outside &amp;quot;biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Classifying individual stocks as within/outside &amp;quot;biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to keep consistency with the 14.4 target (&amp;quot;at least to levels that can produce maximum sustainable yield as determined by their biological characteristics&amp;quot; and other earlier international agreements, including the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS), a fish stock is classified as &amp;quot;within biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot; if its abundance is estimated (considering uncertainty) to be equal to or greater than the level that can produce the Maximum Sustainable Yield (MSY). In contrast, when abundance falls below the MSY level, the stock is classified as &amp;quot;outside biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A wide array of methods and approaches (including documented expert opinion) is used to classify stock status relative to the abundance producing MSY. This varies among countries, regions and stocks. Nevertheless, the reliability of the classification is assessed by FAO as part of the process of producing the index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maximum Sustainable Yield (MSY)&lt;/strong&gt; is commonly defined as the greatest average amount of catch that can be harvested in the long-term from a stock under constant and current environmental conditions (e.g., habitat, water conditions, species composition and interactions, and anything that could affect birth, growth, or death rates of the stock), without affecting the long-term productivity of the stock. A stock can produce MSY if its abundance is above a certain level, usually around 50% of its unexploited abundance (but actual value can vary around that level, depending on the biological characteristics of the stock). See more at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fao.org/faoterm/en/?defaultCollId=21&quot;&gt;https://www.fao.org/faoterm/en/?defaultCollId=21&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MSY-based reference points are the most common type of reference points used in fisheries management today. This is primarily because, for decades, reference points from surplus production models have most often been set based on the concept of MSY and they are the basic benchmarks for the sustainability of fisheries set by the UN Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS, Article 61(3)). For more on Reference Points in Fish Stock Assessment, see Caddy and Mahon (1995), Cadima (2003) or Haddon (2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BMSY&lt;/strong&gt;: Biomass corresponding to Maximum Sustainable Yield from a production model or from an age-based analysis using a stock recruitment model. Often used as a biological reference point in fisheries management, it is the calculated long-term average biomass value expected if fishing at FMSY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A population is:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#x201C;A group of individuals of the same species living in the same area at the same time and sharing a common gene pool, with little or no immigration or emigration.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A biological stock is: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#x201C;A subpopulation of a species inhabiting a particular geographic area, having similar biological characteristics (e.g. growth, reproduction, mortality) and negligible genetic mixing with other adjacent subpopulations of the same species.&amp;quot; (FAO, 2004-2021).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Reference List of Stocks: i&lt;/strong&gt;t is not possible to classify the sustainability of exploitation for all the exploited stocks from a country, region or the world. Therefore, the indicator must be calculated based on a subset of these stocks. The list of the stocks that are classified for status and used to calculate the indicators is called the &amp;quot;Reference List of Stocks&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Reference List of Stocks is built differently for the Regional/Global and the National levels. The process of building the Reference List of Stocks for regional and global level are described in FAO (2011). At National level, countries are requested to define a list of stocks, based on an agreed set of criteria (Appendix 1). National and shared stocks can be included, but not straddling stocks (stocks that are distributed both in national EEZ and Areas Beyond National Jurisdiction).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this moment, there is not a direct correspondence between the national level Reference Lists (that are defined by each country) and the regional and global Reference lists (that are defined by FAO).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;move956633181111111111111111&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The detailed description of all necessary concepts can be found in the e-learning course (FAO 2019-2021).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador Proporción de las poblaciones de peces marinos dentro de niveles biológicamente sostenibles mide la sostenibilidad de las pesquerías de captura marina del mundo por su abundancia. Una población de peces cuya abundancia es igual o superior al nivel que puede producir el rendimiento máximo sostenible (RMS) se clasifica como biológicamente sostenible. Por el contrario, cuando la abundancia cae por debajo del nivel de RMS, la población se considera biológicamente insostenible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El RMS se define como la mayor cantidad de capturas que puede obtenerse de forma continua de una población en condiciones ambientales constantes y actuales (por ejemplo, el hábitat, las condiciones del agua, la composición y las interacciones de las especies y todo lo que pueda afectar a las tasas de natalidad, crecimiento o mortalidad de la población) sin afectar a la productividad a largo plazo de la población. El indicador mide la sostenibilidad de los recursos pesqueros basándose en un buen equilibrio entre el uso humano y la conservación ecológica.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los puntos de referencia basados en el RMS son el tipo más común de puntos de referencia utilizados en la gestión de la pesca hoy en día. Esto se debe principalmente a que, durante décadas, los puntos de referencia de los modelos de producción de excedentes se han establecido con mayor frecuencia basándose en el concepto de RMS y son los puntos de referencia básicos para la sostenibilidad de las pesquerías establecidos por la Convención de las Naciones Unidas sobre el Derecho del Mar (UNCLOS, artículo 61(3)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Población de peces&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;se refiere a un grupo de individuos de una sola especie o a veces de especies combinadas que viven en una zona definida de la que se obtienen capturas en una pesquería.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cada país debe establecer una &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lista de referencia de poblaciones&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; que consiste en una lista de poblaciones seleccionadas según las directrices de la FAO, con respecto a las cuales se informará del indicador (Apéndice 1). La lista de referencia debe incluir las poblaciones nacionales y compartidas, pero no las poblaciones transzonales, tal y como se definen a continuación.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Las poblaciones nacionales&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; se encuentran completamente dentro de una ZEE y/o aguas territoriales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Poblaciones compartidas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;están distribuidas dentro de la ZEE y/o las aguas territoriales de dos o más países adyacentes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Las poblaciones transzonales&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; se desplazan a través de las fronteras entre las aguas de la ZEE o entre la ZEE y alta mar (por ejemplo, las poblaciones de atún), y que son capturadas por múltiples países. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se pide a los países que informen sobre las poblaciones que figuran en su lista de referencia, incluidas las que son objeto de seguimiento mediante &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;evaluaciones oficiales de las poblaciones&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; por parte de un organismo autorizado, mediante un proceso científico y utilizando los mejores datos y datos científicos disponibles. Estas evaluaciones podrían basarse en métodos clásicos o con datos limitados. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La evaluación de poblaciones utiliza información biológica, datos pesqueros como las estadísticas de capturas y el esfuerzo pesquero, y datos de estudios científicos para estimar la dinámica de las poblaciones de peces con fines de gestión. Los métodos de evaluación de poblaciones incluyen modelos dinámicos biológicos, modelos estructurados por edad, métodos basados en la talla y modelos de reclutamiento de poblaciones.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Définition :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur Proportion de stocks de poissons marins se situant dans des niveaux biologiquement viables mesure la viabilité des pêcheries de capture marines du monde par leur abondance. Un stock de poissons dont l&apos;abondance est égale ou supérieure au niveau qui peut produire le rendement maximal durable (RMD) est considéré comme biologiquement durable. En revanche, lorsque l&apos;abondance tombe en dessous du niveau du RMD, le stock est considéré comme biologiquement non durable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le RMD est défini comme la plus grande quantité de prises qui peut être récoltée de façon continue à partir d&apos;un stock dans des conditions environnementales constantes et actuelles (par exemple, l&apos;habitat, les conditions de l&apos;eau, la composition et les interactions des espèces, et tout ce qui pourrait affecter les taux de naissance, de croissance ou de mortalité du stock) sans affecter la productivité à long terme du stock. L&apos;indicateur mesure la durabilité des ressources halieutiques sur la base d&apos;un bon équilibre entre l&apos;utilisation humaine et la conservation écologique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les points de référence basés sur le RMD sont le type de points de référence le plus communément utilisé dans la gestion des pêches aujourd&apos;hui. Cela s&apos;explique principalement par le fait que, pendant des décennies, les points de référence des modèles de production excédentaire ont le plus souvent été fixés sur la base du concept de RMD et qu&apos;ils constituent les repères de base pour la durabilité des pêches fixés par la Convention des Nations unies sur le droit de la mer (UNCLOS, article 61(3)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Un stock de poissons&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;désigne un groupe d&apos;individus d&apos;une seule espèce ou parfois d&apos;espèces combinées vivant dans une zone définie et dont les captures sont effectuées dans le cadre d&apos;une pêche&lt;/p&gt;.
Une &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;liste de référence des stocks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; devrait être établie par chaque pays et consiste en une liste de stocks sélectionnés selon les directives de l&apos;Organisation pour l&apos;alimentation et l&apos;agriculture (FAO), par rapport auxquels l&apos;indicateur sera rapporté (Annexe 1). La liste de référence devrait inclure les stocks nationaux et partagés, mais pas les stocks chevauchants tels que définis ci-dessous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Les stocks nationaux &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; sont entièrement situés dans une ZEE et/ou des eaux territoriales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Les stocks partagés &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;sont répartis dans la ZEE et/ou les eaux territoriales de deux pays adjacents ou plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Les stocks chevauchants&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; se déplacent à travers les frontières entre les eaux de la ZEE ou entre la ZEE et la haute mer (par exemple, les stocks de thon), et sont capturés par plusieurs pays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il est demandé aux pays de faire rapport sur les stocks énumérés dans sa liste de référence, y compris ceux qui sont surveillés par des &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;évaluations officielles des stocks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; par une agence faisant autorité, selon un processus scientifique et en utilisant les meilleures données scientifiques disponibles. Ces évaluations pourraient être basées sur des méthodes classiques ou limitées aux données. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;évaluation des stocks utilise des informations biologiques, des données de pêche telles que les statistiques de capture et l&apos;effort de pêche, et des données d&apos;enquêtes scientifiques pour estimer la dynamique de la population des stocks de poissons à des fins de gestion. Les méthodes d&apos;évaluation des stocks comprennent les modèles biologiques dynamiques, les modèles structurés par âge, les méthodes basées sur la longueur et les modèles de recrutement des stocks.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Показатель «Доля морских рыбных запасов , находящихся в биологически устойчивых пределах» отражает устойчивость мирового морского рыболовства по их численности. Рыбный запас, численность которого находится на уровне или выше, чем уровень, на котором может осуществляться максимальный устойчивый улов (МУУ), классифицируется как биологически устойчивый. Напротив, когда численность падает ниже уровня МУУ, запас считается биологически неустойчивым. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; МУУ определяется как наибольший объем улова, который можно непрерывно извлекать из запаса при постоянных и текущих экологических условиях (например, среда обитания, водные условия, состав и взаимоотношения видов, а также все, что может повлиять на уровни рождаемости, роста или убыли запаса), не влияя на долгосрочную продуктивность запаса. Показатель отражает устойчивость рыбных ресурсов на основе разумного соотношения между использованием человеком и сохранением окружающей среды. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Реперные точки, базирующиеся на MУУ, являются наиболее распространенным типом контрольных точек, используемых сегодня в управлении рыболовством. Это происходит прежде всего потому, что на протяжении десятилетий контрольные точки из моделей избыточного производства чаще всего устанавливались на основе концепции MУУ, и они являются основными ориентирами устойчивости рыболовства, установленными Конвенцией ООН по морскому праву (UNCLOS, Статья 61 (3). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Рыбные запасы &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; относятся к группе особей одного вида или иногда комбинированных видов, обитающих в определенном районе, уловы из которого получены в ходе промысла. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Справочный список запасов должен быть составлен каждой страной и состоять из списка запасов, отобранных в соответствии с руководящими принципами ФАО, по которым будет составляться отчетный показатель (Приложение 1). Справочный список должен включать национальные и совместные запасы, но не трансграничные запасы, как определено ниже. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Национальные запасы &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; находятся полностью в пределах ИЭЗ (исключительной экономической зоны) и / или территориальных вод. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Совместные запасы &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt; распределены в пределах ИЭЗ и / или территориальных вод двух или более соседних стран. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Трансграничные запасы &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; перемещаются через границы между водами ИЭЗ или между ИЭЗ и открытым морем (например, запасы тунца), и эти запасы вылавливаются несколькими странами. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Странам предлагается отчитываться о запасах, перечисленных в их справочном списке, в том числе о тех, которые отслеживаются с помощью &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; официальных оценок запасов &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; авторитетным агентством, с помощью научного процесса и с использованием наилучших имеющихся научных методов и данных. Эти оценки могут быть основаны на классическом методе или методе ограниченных данных. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;При оценке запасов используется биологическая информация, данные о промысле, такие как статистика уловов и интенсивность вылова, а также данные научных обследований для оценки динамики популяции рыбных запасов в целях управления. Методы оценки запасов включают биологические динамические модели, модели оценки рыбных запасов на основе возрастной структуры, методы оценка рыбных запасов на основе размерного состава и модели воспроизводства запаса. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
