<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The INST_MANDATE field for indicator 5-1-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;The World Bank works closely with international agencies, regional development banks, donors, and other partners to develop frameworks, guidance, and standards of good practice for statistics, build consensus and define internationally agreed indicators, establish data exchange processes and methods, and help countries improve statistical capacity. Since 2009, the World Bank Group&amp;#x2019;s Women, Business and the Law project has contributed to the study of gender equality and informed discussions on improving women&amp;apos;s economic opportunities and empowerment through a unique dataset that measures the legal differences in access to economic opportunities between men and women in 190 economies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OECD Development Centre&amp;#x2019;s core mission is to provide a platform for evidence-based policy dialogue between OECD and non-OECD countries to design better policies, by identifying policy solutions to improve lives in developing countries. Through its Gender Programme, particularly since the creation of the Social Institutions and Gender Index (SIGI) in 2009, the OECD Development Centre has played an instrumental role in highlighting the data gaps and fostering policy dialogue and mutual learning on the social institutions that discriminate against women and girls across their life cycle. It is also building the capacity of member states in data collection through the SIGI Country Studies, and advocates for more, better, and comparable data through its SIGI Global and Regional Reports and policy dialogue events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UN Women is committed through its work at the global, regional, and county level to support Member States in filling critical gaps in generating and using data, statistics, evidence, and analysis on gender equality in crucial areas. As part of its mandate, the organization supports Member States in setting norms. It conducts research, and compiles and provides evidence, including good practices and lessons learned, to inform intergovernmental debates and decisions. It also assists in implementing norms and standards through its country programs. In addition, it leads and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unwomen.org/en/how-we-work/un-system-coordination&quot;&gt;coordinates&lt;/a&gt; the UN system&amp;#x2019;s work in support of gender equality and the empowerment of women.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
