<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 3-3-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computation method:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimates of TB incidence are produced through a consultative and analytical process led by WHO and are published annually. These estimates are based on annual case notifications, assessments of the quality and coverage of TB notification data, national surveys of the prevalence of TB disease and information from death (vital) registration systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimates of incidence for each country are derived, using one or more of the following approaches depending on available data: (i) incidence = case notifications/estimated proportion of cases detected; (ii) capture-recapture modelling, (iii) incidence = prevalence/duration of condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uncertainty bounds are provided in addition to best estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details are available from TB impact measurement: policy and recommendations for how to assess the epidemiological burden of TB and the impact of TB control and from the online technical appendix to the WHO global tuberculosis report 2017 and &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1603.00278&quot;&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/1603.00278&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt; Méthodologie&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Méthode de calcul :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les estimations de l’incidence de la tuberculose sont produites au moyen d’un processus consultatif et analytique dirigé par l’OMS et sont publiées chaque année. Ces estimations sont fondées sur des notifications annuelles de cas, des évaluations de la qualité et de la couverture des données de notification de la tuberculose, des enquêtes nationales sur la prévalence de la tuberculose et des informations provenant des systèmes d’enregistrement des décès (vitaux). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Des estimations de l’incidence pour chaque pays sont obtenues, en utilisant une ou plusieurs des approches suivantes selon les données disponibles : (i) incidence = notifications de cas/proportion estimée de cas détectés ; (ii) modélisation capture-recapture, (iii) incidence = prévalence/durée de l’état. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Des limites d’incertitude sont fournies en plus des meilleures estimations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les détails sont disponibles à partir de la mesure de l’impact de la tuberculose : politiques et recommandations sur la façon d’évaluer le fardeau épidémiologique de la tuberculose et l’impact de la lutte antituberculeuse et de l’annexe technique en ligne au rapport mondial de l’OMS sur la tuberculose 2017 et &lt;a href=&quot;https ://arxiv.org/abs/1603.00278&quot;&gt;https ://arxiv.org/abs/1603.00278&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Оценки заболеваемости ТБ производятся в рамках консультативно-аналитического процесса под руководством ВОЗ и публикуются ежегодно. Эти оценки основаны на ежегодных уведомлениях о случаях заболевания, оценке качества и охвате данных уведомлений о ТБ, национальных исследованиях распространенности ТБ и информации из систем регистрации смертей (регистрации актов гражданского состояния). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Оценки заболеваемости для каждой страны производятся с использованием одного или нескольких из следующих подходов в зависимости от имеющихся данных: (i) заболеваемость = уведомления о случаях / расчетная доля выявленных случаев; (ii) моделирование выявления-повторного выявления, (iii) заболеваемость = распространенность / продолжительность состояния. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Границы неопределенности приводятся в дополнение к наилучшим оценкам. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Подробная информация доступна в разделе Оценка воздействия ТБ: политика и рекомендации по оценке эпидемиологического бремени ТБ и воздействия контроля за ТБ, а также в техническом приложении (в онлайн-режиме) к Глобальному докладу ВОЗ о туберкулезе за 2017 год и &lt;a href = &quot;https: //arxiv.org/abs/1603.00278&quot;&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/1603.00278&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
