<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 2-a-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Data for the denominator are annually collected from countries using the FAO questionnaire on Government Expenditure on Agriculture (GEA), developed in collaboration with the IMF., For countries with missing information, data is supplemented with data collected by the IMF, regional organizations or published on official national governmental websites. The official counterpart(s) at country level are, depending on the country, from the national statistics office, the ministry of finance (or other central planning agency), or the ministry of agriculture. Validation and consultation were conducted through various FAO commissions and committees, including its two agricultural statistics commissions in Africa and the Asia and Pacific, its Committee on Agriculture and Livestock Statistics in Latin America and the Caribbean, and its Committee on Agriculture. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proceso de recolección:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos para el denominador se recolectan anualmente de los países utilizando el cuestionario de la FAO sobre el gasto público en agricultura (GEA), desarrollado en colaboración con el FMI. Los datos de los países pueden complementarse, en el caso de los países que faltan, con datos recolectados por el FMI o publicados en los sitios web oficiales de los gobiernos nacionales. La(s) contraparte(s) oficial(es) a nivel de país son, según el país, de la oficina nacional de estadística, el ministerio de hacienda (u otro organismo central de planificación) o el ministerio de agricultura. La validación y la consulta se llevaron a cabo a través de varias comisiones y comités de la FAO, incluidas sus dos comisiones de estadísticas agrícolas en África y Asia y el Pacífico, su Comité de Estadísticas Agrícolas y Ganaderas en América Latina y el Caribe, y su Comité de Agricultura.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Les données pour le dénominateur sont recueillies chaque année auprès des pays à l&apos;aide du questionnaire de la FAO sur les dépenses publiques en agriculture (DPA), élaboré en collaboration avec le FMI. Pour les pays dont les informations sont manquantes, les données sont complétées par des données recueillies par le FMI ou par les organisations régionales ou publiées sur les sites Web officiels des gouvernements nationaux. Les homologues officiels au niveau national sont, selon le pays, le bureau national de statistique, le ministère des finances (ou une autre agence centrale de planification) ou le ministère de l&apos;agriculture. La validation et la consultation ont été menées par le biais de diverses commissions et comités de la FAO, notamment ses deux commissions de statistiques agricoles en Afrique et en Asie et Pacifique, son Comité des statistiques de l&apos;agriculture et de l&apos;élevage en Amérique latine et dans les Caraïbes, et son Comité de l&apos;agriculture. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные для знаменателя ежегодно собираются от стран с использованием вопросника ФАО по государственным расходам на сельское хозяйство (ГРСХ), разработанного в сотрудничестве с МВФ. Данные по странам, которые не представляют информацию, могут быть дополнены данными, собранными МВФ, или опубликованными на официальных национальных правительственных веб-сайтах. Официальными партнерами на страновом уровне являются, в зависимости от страны, национальное статистическое управление, министерство финансов (или другое центральное планирующее агентство ) или министерство сельского хозяйства. Валидация и консультации проводились различными комиссиями и комитетами ФАО, включая две комиссии по сельскохозяйственной статистике в Африке и Азиатско-Тихоокеанском регионе, Комитет по статистике сельского хозяйства и животноводства в Латинской Америке и Карибском бассейне и Комитет по сельскому хозяйству. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
