<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COMPARABILITY field for indicator 2-a-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When in-country compilation errors are identified and FAO has modified government expenditure data reported by countries, or where errors are found in comparison with the IMF GFS COFOG data or fiscal data published on national authorities&amp;apos; websites after querying to national respondents, there may be some difference between data reported by FAO and unrevised national figures.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fuentes de discrepancia:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dado que la FAO no altera los datos de gasto público comunicados por los países y utiliza las estimaciones de las cuentas nacionales publicadas por la División de Estadística de las Naciones Unidas (en las que se pueden imputar algunos datos nacionales), no debería haber diferencias entre los datos comunicados por la FAO y las cifras nacionales.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources des divergences : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lorsque des erreurs de compilation dans le pays sont identifiées et que la FAO a modifié les données de dépenses publiques déclarées par les pays, ou lorsque des erreurs sont constatées lors de la comparaison avec les données du FMI sur les SFP de la CFAP ou les données fiscales publiées sur les sites Web des autorités nationales après interrogation des répondants nationaux, il peut y avoir une certaine différence entre les données déclarées par la FAO et les chiffres nationaux non révisés.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Поскольку ФАО не корректирует данные по государственным расходам, представляемые странами, и использует оценки национальных счетов, публикуемые Статистическим отделом ООН (где некоторые национальные данные могут быть вменены), то не должна возникать разница между данными, представляемыми ФАО, и национальными данными. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
