<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REG_AGG field for indicator 2-a-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Global and regional estimates are compiled by first separately summing across countries the four individual components of the index: government expenditure on agriculture, total government expenditure, agriculture value-added, and GDP. These are added only for those countries in a region (or globally) for which all components are available, and the index is then calculated for this larger region.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las estimaciones mundiales y regionales se elaboran sumando primero por separado en todos los países los cuatro componentes individuales del índice: el gasto público en agricultura, el gasto público total, el valor agregado de la agricultura y el PIB. Éstos se suman solo para aquellos países de una región (o a nivel mundial) para los que se dispone de todos los componentes, y luego se calcula el índice para esta región más amplia.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agrégats régionaux :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les estimations mondiales et régionales sont compilées en additionnant d&apos;abord séparément les quatre composantes individuelles de l&apos;indice, soit : les dépenses publiques pour l&apos;agriculture, les dépenses publiques totales, la valeur ajoutée de l&apos;agriculture et le PIB. Celles-ci sont ajoutées uniquement pour les pays d&apos;une région (ou du monde) pour lesquels toutes les composantes sont disponibles, et l&apos;indice est ensuite calculé pour cette région plus vaste.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Региональные агрегаты: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Глобальные и региональные оценки составляются сначала путем отдельного суммирования по странам четырех отдельных компонентов индекса: государственных расходов на сельское хозяйство, общих государственных расходов, добавленной стоимости в сельском хозяйстве и ВВП. Они суммируются только по тем странам в регионе (или во всем мире), у которых доступны все компоненты, а затем рассчитывается индекс для более крупного региона.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
