<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 2-a-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;Indice d’orientation agricole des dépenses publiques est défini comme la part de l&apos;agriculture dans les dépenses publiques, divisée par la part de la valeur ajoutée de l&apos;agriculture dans le PIB, l&apos;agriculture désignant le secteur de l&apos;agriculture, de la sylviculture, de la pêche et de la chasse. La mesure est un indice sans monnaie, calculé comme le rapport entre ces deux parts. Les gouvernements nationaux sont tenus de calculer les dépenses publiques selon les statistiques de finances publiques (SFP) et la classification des fonctions des administrations publiques (CFAP), et la part de la valeur ajoutée de l&apos;agriculture dans le PIB selon le système de comptabilité nationale (SCN).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;agriculture désigne le secteur de l&apos;agriculture, de la sylviculture, de la pêche et de la chasse, ou la division A de la CITI Rév. 4 (égale à la division A+B de la CITI Rév. 3.2). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les dépenses publiques sont toutes les dépenses et acquisitions d&apos;actifs non financiers associés au soutien d&apos;un secteur particulier, tel que défini dans le Manuel des statistiques de finances publiques (GFSM) 2014 élaboré par le Fonds monétaire international (FMI). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les dépenses publiques sont classées selon la Classification des fonctions des administrations publiques (CFAP), une classification élaborée par l&apos;Organisation de coopération et de développement économiques (OCDE) et publiée par la Division statistique des Nations Unies (DSNU). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La valeur ajoutée agricole et le PIB sont basés sur le système de comptabilité nationale (SCN). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Agriculture Orientation Index (AOI) for Government Expenditures is defined as the Agriculture share of Government Expenditure, divided by the Agriculture value added share of GDP, where Agriculture refers to the agriculture, forestry, fishing and hunting sector. The measure is a currency-free index, calculated as the ratio of these two shares. National governments are requested to compile Government Expenditures according to the Government Finance Statistics (GFS) and the Classification of the Functions of Government (COFOG), and Agriculture value added share of GDP according to the System of National Accounts (SNA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agriculture refers to the agriculture, forestry, fishing and hunting sector, or Division A of ISIC Rev 4 (equal to Division A+B of ISIC Rev 3.2). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Government Expenditure are all expense and acquisition of non-financial assets associated with supporting a particular sector, as defined in the Government Finance Statistics Manual (GFSM) 2014 developed by the International Monetary Fund (IMF). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Government Expenditure are classified according to the Classification of the Functions of Government (COFOG), a classification developed by the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) and published by the United Nations Statistical Division (UNSD). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agriculture value-added and GDP are based on the System of National Accounts (SNA). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
