<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 10-7-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During various development stages of the methodologies from 2014 to 2016, the following 10 countries were involved in initial small-scale pilot tests of the methodology: Ethiopia in Africa; Mexico in Latin America; India, Malaysia, Nepal, Pakistan, Russia, and the Philippines in Asia and the Pacific; and Italy in Europe. The datasets and documentation for these surveys are be found at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.knomad.org/data/recruitment-costs&quot;&gt;https://www.knomad.org/data/recruitment-costs&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These survey have produced data for the following countries/corridors: Indonesia &amp;#x2013; Korea; Thailand &amp;#x2013; Korea; Vietnam &amp;#x2013; Korea; Vietnam &amp;#x2013; Malaysia;The Philippines &amp;#x2013; Qatar;Nepal &amp;#x2013; Qatar; India &amp;#x2013; Qatar;India &amp;#x2013; Kuwait; Bangladesh &amp;#x2013; Kuwait;Sri Lanka &amp;#x2013; Kuwait;Egypt &amp;#x2013; Kuwait;Ethiopia &amp;#x2013; Saudi Arabia; Pakistan &amp;#x2013; Saudi Arabia;Pakistan &amp;#x2013; UAE;Ecuador &amp;#x2013; Spain;Morocco &amp;#x2013; Spain;Bulgaria &amp;#x2013; Spain;Poland &amp;#x2013; Spain;Guatemala &amp;#x2013; Mexico;Honduras &amp;#x2013; Mexico ;El Salvador &amp;#x2013; Mexico; Russia &amp;#x2013; Kyrgyzstan; Russia -Tajikistan; Russia &amp;#x2013; Uzbekistan; India-Saudi Arabia; Philippines-Saudi Arabia; Nepal &amp;#x2013; Sauidi Arabia; Nepal &amp;#x2013; Malaysia; Nepal &amp;#x2013; Qatar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much recently at national level, the Lao PDR Statistics Bureau was involved in conducting a pilot of the draft methodology using its LFS 2017 with an additional module on migration costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In principle, the countries are expected to collect data one every two years, depending on the data production capacity of the country. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desired disaggregation includes: sex, age group, education groups, and major destination countries (as recruitment costs have been documented to vary considerably by migration corridors).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional statistics may be presented by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;type of migration process (documented, undocumented migrant workers)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;occupation (ISCO-08): to assess skills levels such as high-skill and low-skill groups&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;major occupational groups: to assess which skills groups have the highest recruitment costs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;major industry (ISIC Rev.4): to assess main sectors where migrant workers are engaged and to assess recruitment costs in industries of key policy concern (e.g. agriculture, construction, retail, and domestic work)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
