<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 10-3-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator is defined as the proportion of the population (adults) who self-report that they personally experienced discrimination or harassment during the last 12 months based on ground(s) prohibited by international human rights law. International human rights law refers to the body of international legal instruments aiming to promote and protect human rights, including the Universal Declaration of Human Rights and subsequent international human rights treaties adopted by the United Nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discrimination is any distinction, exclusion, restriction or preference or other differential treatment that is directly or indirectly based on prohibited grounds of discrimination, and which has the intention or effect of nullifying or impairing the recognition, enjoyment or exercise, on an equal footing, of human rights and fundamental freedoms in the political, economic, social, cultural or any other field of public life.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Harassment is a form of discrimination when it is also based on prohibited grounds of discrimination. Harassment may take the form of words, gestures or actions, which tend to annoy, alarm, abuse, demean, intimidate, belittle, humiliate or embarrass another or which create an intimidating, hostile or offensive environment. While generally involving a pattern of behaviours, harassment can take the form of a single incident.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-3&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International human rights law provides lists of the prohibited grounds of discrimination. The inclusion of &amp;#x201C;other status&amp;#x201D; in these lists indicate that they are not exhaustive and that other grounds may be recognized by international human rights mechanisms. A review of the international human rights normative framework helps identify a list of grounds that includes race, colour, sex, language, religion, political or other opinion, national origin, social origin, property, birth status, disability, age, nationality, marital and family status, sexual orientation, gender identity, health status, place of residence, economic and social situation, pregnancy, indigenous status, afro-descent and other status.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-4&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-4&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; In practice, it will be difficult to include all potentially relevant grounds of discrimination in household survey questions. For this reason, it is recommended that data collectors identify contextually relevant and feasible lists of grounds, drawing on the illustrative list and formulation of prohibited grounds of discrimination outlined in the methodology section below, and add an &amp;#x201C;other&amp;#x201D; category to reflect other grounds that may not have been listed explicitly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; See, for instance, Art. 1 of the International Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Racial Discrimination (ICERD); Art. 1 of the Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Discrimination against Women (CEDAW); Art. 2 of the Convention on the Rights of Persons with Disabilities (CRPD); General Comment 18 of the Human Rights Committee (paragraphs 6 and 7) and General Comment 20 of the Committee on Economic, Social and Cultural Rights (paragraph 7). &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-3&quot;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; See, for instance, General Comment 20 of the Committee on Economic, Social and Cultural Rights, and United Nations Secretary-General&amp;#x2019;s bulletin (ST/SGB/2008/5) on Prohibition of discrimination, harassment, including sexual harassment, and abuse of authority. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-4&quot;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; More information on the grounds of discrimination prohibited by international human rights law is available at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ohchr.org/Documents/Issues/HRIndicators/HumanRightsStandards.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ohchr.org/Documents/Issues/HRIndicators/HumanRightsStandards.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-4&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
