<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 16-7-1c, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No global source of data that comprehensively covers this indicator is available at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there are three existing data collection efforts, but they only partially cover the scope of the indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;UNODC Survey on Crime Trends and the Operations of Criminal Justice Systems (CTS):&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-17&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-17&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;The CTS, through focal points/ coordinating officers, gathers data from UN Member States on the number of &amp;#x2018;professional judges or magistrates&amp;#x2019;, including authorized associate judges and magistrates, defined as full-time and part-time officials authorized to hear specifically criminal cases, including in appeal courts, and to make dispositions in a court of law. Data is disaggregated by sex only. The CTS is confined to criminal courts, which include any legal body authorized to pronounce a conviction under national criminal law. Data on all levels of criminal courts is collected, but the survey does not disaggregate data to distinguish between judges in higher-level courts from those in lower-level courts. Data collection through the CTS is conducted on an annual basis. The most recent available data is for 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;World Bank, Women, Business and the Law Report:&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-18&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-18&quot;&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;The Women, Business and the Law Report includes data on the percentage of female judges and chief justices in constitutional courts for the 153 economies where constitutional courts exist. The most recent report was published in 2021, and it is the fifth edition in a series of biennial reports.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CEPEJ, European Judicial Systems &amp;#x2013; Efficiency and Quality of Justice Report:&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-19&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-19&quot;&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;The Efficiency and Quality of Justice Report includes data on the percentage of women working at all levels of courts, including first instance, second instance, and supreme courts, and it includes data on the proportion of female &amp;#x2018;court presidents&amp;#x2019; and &amp;#x2018;professional judges&amp;#x2019; for 47 countries within Europe. &amp;#x2018;Professional judges&amp;#x2019; are part-time and full-time judges who have been trained, who are paid as such, and whose main function is to work as a judge and not as a prosecutor. The report also collects data on the percentage of female &amp;#x2018;non-judge staff&amp;#x2019; disaggregated by the &lt;em&gt;Rechtspfleger&lt;/em&gt; function (or similar bodies) for 47 countries within Europe. The most recent report was published in 2020 and is updated every two years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No global source of data that comprehensively covers this indicator is available at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned throughout the above discussions, a three-way disaggregation of the data is recommended, along the following cumulative levels:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Type of position&lt;em&gt; (judges; registrars)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Level of court &lt;em&gt;(&amp;#x2018;supreme/constitutional courts,&amp;#x2019; &amp;#x2018;higher-level courts&amp;#x2019; and &amp;#x2018;lower-level courts&amp;#x2019;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Various demographic characteristics:&lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sex &lt;em&gt;(male; female)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Age group &lt;em&gt;(below 45 years; 45-54; 55-64; 65 and above)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Disability status &lt;em&gt;(disability; no disability)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Population subgroup &lt;em&gt;(country-specific)&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-20&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-20&quot;&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-17&quot;&gt;16&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unodc.org/unodc/en/data-and-analysis/United-Nations-Surveys-on-Crime-Trends-and-the-Operations-of-Criminal-Justice-Systems.html&quot;&gt;https://www.unodc.org/unodc/en/data-and-analysis/United-Nations-Surveys-on-Crime-Trends-and-the-Operations-of-Criminal-Justice-Systems.html&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-17&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-18&quot;&gt;17&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://wbl.worldbank.org&quot;&gt;https://wbl.worldbank.org&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-18&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-19&quot;&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coe.int/en/web/cepej/cepej-work/evaluation-of-judicial-systems&quot;&gt;https://www.coe.int/en/web/cepej/cepej-work/evaluation-of-judicial-systems&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-19&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-20&quot;&gt;19&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Population groups would be defined at the country level as relevant to the country context and could include indigenous, linguistic, ethnic, racial, social, income, cultural, geographic, nationality, migrant, displaced, refugee, political, sexual orientation, civil status, and/or religious groups, using guidance from OHCHR&amp;#x2019;s A Human-Rights Based Approach to Data on countries&amp;#x2019; obligation to collect and publish data disaggregated by grounds of discrimination recognized in international human rights law. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-20&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
