<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 7-1-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;Data availability:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For cooking fuels, coverage of 170 countries is available through the WHO Global Household Energy Database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For lighting fuels, the WHO database includes data for 125 countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For heating fuels, the WHO database includes data for 71 countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time series:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 1960 to 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disaggregated estimates for different end-uses (i.e. cooking, heating and lighting; with expected improvements in household surveys, this will be possible for heating and lighting for all countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disaggregation of access to clean fuel and technologies for cooking by rural or urban place of residence is possible for all countries with survey data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gender disaggregation by main user (i.e. cook) of cooking energy will be available with expected improvements in household surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gender disaggregation of head of household for cooking, lighting and heating is available&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Energy is a service provided at the household, rather than individual level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, it is used differentially by men and women and has different impacts on their health and well-being. What will be possible, in principle, is to report energy access disaggregated by the main user of cooking energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, WHO&amp;apos;s Household energy database includes country data from thirty countries on the time spent by children collecting fuelwood and water disaggregated by sex. With the improvements in data collection via the below mentioned survey harmonization process, data will be available reporting time spent exclusively on fuel collection rather than in combination with water collection.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
