<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 3-7-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The percentage of women of reproductive age (15-49 years) currently using a modern method of contraception among those who desire either to have no (additional) children or to postpone the next pregnancy. The indicator is also referred to as the demand for family planning satisfied with modern methods. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The percentage of women of reproductive age (15-49 years) who have their need for family planning satisfied with modern methods is also referred to as the proportion of demand satisfied by modern methods. The components of the indicator are contraceptive prevalence (any method and modern methods) and unmet need for family planning. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contraceptive prevalence is the percentage of women who are currently using, or whose partner is currently using, at least one method of contraception, regardless of the method used. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For analytical purposes, contraceptive methods are often classified as either modern or traditional. Modern methods of contraception include female and male sterilization, the intra-uterine device (IUD), the implant, injectables, oral contraceptive pills, male and female condoms, vaginal barrier methods (including the diaphragm, cervical cap and spermicidal foam, jelly, cream and sponge), lactational amenorrhea method (LAM), emergency contraception and other modern methods not reported separately (e.g., the contraceptive patch or vaginal ring). Traditional methods of contraception include rhythm (e.g., fertility awareness-based methods, periodic abstinence), withdrawal and other traditional methods not reported separately. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unmet need for family planning is defined as the percentage of women of reproductive age who want to stop or delay childbearing but are not using any method of contraception. The standard definition of unmet need for family planning includes women who are fecund and sexually active in the numerator, and who report not wanting any (more) children, or who report wanting to delay the birth of their next child for at least two years or are undecided about the timing of the next birth, but who are not using any method of contraception. The numerator also includes pregnant women whose pregnancies were unwanted or mistimed at the time of conception; and postpartum amenorrheic women who are not using family planning and whose last birth was unwanted or mistimed. Further information on the operational definition of the unmet need for family planning, as well as survey questions and statistical programs needed to derive the indicator, can be found at the following website of the USAID Demographic and Health Surveys Program: &lt;a href=&quot;http://measuredhs.com/Topics/Unmet-Need.cfm&quot;&gt;http://measuredhs.com/Topics/Unmet-Need.cfm&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
