<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 15-8-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator aims to quantify trends in: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commitment by countries to relevant multinational agreements, specifically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1) National adoption of invasive alien species relevant policy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Percentage of countries with &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(a) national legislation and policy relevant to invasive alien species. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(b) if targets and objectives within national strategies for preventing and controlling invasive alien species are aligned with Aichi Target 9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The translation of policy arrangements into action by countries to implement policy and actively prevent and control invasive alien species (IAS) and the resourcing of this action, specifically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(2) National allocation of resources towards the prevention or control of IAS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An &amp;#x201C;Alien&amp;#x201D; species is described as one which has been introduced outside its natural distribution range because of intentional or accidental dispersion by human activity. An alien species which has become established in a natural or semi-natural ecosystem or habitat, is an agent of change, and threatens native biological diversity is known as an &amp;#x201C;Invasive alien species&amp;#x201D; (Convention on Biological Diversity 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The introduction of an alien species can be intentional or unintentional /accidental. Alien species have been introduced intentionally for forestry, ornamental purposes, for aquaculture/mariculture, hunting, fisheries etc. Examples of unintentional or accidental introductions include: alien species that have escaped from gardens, aquaculture containment facilities, forestry, horticulture; pets and aquarium species that are released in the wild; transport contaminants and stowaways including in ballast water or as hull fouling organisms, and seeds carried in soil, equipment, vehicles etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mechanisms of impact of invasive species include competition, predation, hybridisation, and disease transmission, parasitism, herbivory and trampling and rooting. The outcomes of these impacts lead to biodiversity loss, habitat degradation, and loss of ecosystem services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments and limitations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The adoption of legislation does not necessarily indicate the existence of regulations or policy to implement the legislation or how successful such implementation has been on the ground. There remains a need for further indicator development to make this link clearer. Legislation does not necessarily capture all efforts against invasive alien species that are happening at the national level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allocation of resources to facilitate the implementation of IAS management action is difficult to measure, particularly in a way that is comparable across countries. Proxies used to measure allocation of resources included- allocation of a budget line to invasive species management activities (including prevention, rapid response, and active management); appointed staff to carry out any IAS related activities; active programmes/ projects etc.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
