<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DOC_METHOD field for indicator 11-2-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;Data for indicator 11.2.1 is to be collected at the city/urban level and aggregates made to the national level. For countries which have adequate capacity (personnel, systems, resources) and baseline data, the indicator can be computed for all cities/urban areas then averages used to report on national performances. For countries which do not have the capacity to collect data and undertake computations for all their cities/urban areas, UN-Habitat has proposed the use of the National Sample of Cities Approach, which allows them to select a representative sample from where weighted national aggregates can be undertaken. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guidance on implementation of the National Sample of Cities Approach is available here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://unhabitat.org/sites/default/files/2020/06/national_sample_of_cities_english.pdf&quot;&gt;https://unhabitat.org/sites/default/files/2020/06/national_sample_of_cities_english.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UN-Habitat will continuously undertake capacity building on the sampling approach, and directly support countries to develop a national sample of cities where needed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UN-Habitat has developed a step-by-step data compilation and computation methodological document, which is applicable at the city and national level. The document is available here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://unhabitat.org/sites/default/files/2020/06/indicator_11.2.1_training_module_public_transport_system.pdf&quot;&gt;https://unhabitat.org/sites/default/files/2020/06/indicator_11.2.1_training_module_public_transport_system.pdf&lt;/a&gt;. The agency also provides on-the-task training to countries on a need basis, as well as continuous technical support throughout the data compilation process to ensure alignment of national processes with the globally adopted methodology.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
