<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COMPARABILITY field for indicator 11-1-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;As national agencies are responsible for data collection, no differences between country produced data and international estimated data on the indicator are expected to arise if standard methodologies and procedures are followed at all stages of the reporting process. Where such discrepancies exist, these will be resolved through planned technical meetings and capacity development workshops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Missing data and other local variables and frequency of data collection usually affects the figures reported at the global and national level. For this indicator, national data will be used to derive global figures. In instances where global values differ from national figures, efforts will be made for harmonization. There are many instances where lack of new data will be replaced with modelled data for the global figures. These figures will be acceptable for reporting at the national and global levels with the relevant notes attached to such figures. This is likely to be the case for countries where they have long intervals of collection of new data, or where countries face unstable situations such post-disaster or post-war years.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Fuentes de discrepancia entre las cifras mundiales y nacionales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dado que los organismos nacionales son los responsables de la recolección de datos, no se espera que surjan diferencias entre los datos producidos por el país y los datos internacionales estimados sobre el indicador si se siguen metodologías y procedimientos estándar en todas las fases del proceso de elaboración de informes. La falta de datos y otras variables locales, así como la frecuencia de la recolección de datos, suelen afectar a las cifras comunicadas a nivel mundial y nacional. Para este indicador, se utilizarán los datos nacionales para obtener las cifras globales. En los casos en los que los valores globales difieran de las cifras nacionales, se hará un esfuerzo de armonización.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Sources des divergences :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comme les agences nationales sont responsables de la collecte des données, aucune différence entre les données produites par les pays et les données internationales estimées ne devraient exister si les méthodologies et procédures standard sont suivies, et ce à toutes les étapes du processus de déclaration. Les données manquantes et les autres variables locales ainsi que la fréquence de la collecte des données ont généralement une incidence sur les chiffres communiqués aux niveaux mondial et national. Pour cet indicateur, les données nationales seront utilisées pour obtenir des chiffres globaux. Dans les cas où les valeurs globales diffèrent des chiffres nationaux, des efforts seront déployés pour les harmoniser.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Поскольку ответственность за сбор данных несут национальные учреждения, ожидается, что при соблюдении стандартных методологий и процедур на всех этапах процесса отчетности не возникнет никаких разногласий между данными, полученными от страны, и оценочными данными по этому показателю, полученными на международном уровне. Отсутствие данных и других локальных переменных и частота сбора данных обычно влияют на отчетные данные на глобальном и национальном уровнях. Для этого показателя национальные данные будут использоваться для получения глобальных оценок. В случаях, когда глобальные значения отличаются от национальных данных, будут предприняты усилия по их согласованию&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
