<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 11-1-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All countries are expected to fully report on this indicator more consistently with few challenges where missing values will be reported at the national/global level. At the national level, it is possible that missing values will be recorded perhaps representing gaps of non-measurements among populations whose status of slum-hood or informality or inadequate housing is not recorded, unknown or where data is unavailable. Because the values will be aggregated at the national levels, missing values will be less observed at these levels, but are likely to affect the estimates. At the survey and data collection level, survey procedures for managing missing values will be applied based on the unit of analysis/ primary sampling units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global estimates will be adjusted with modelling based on trends to cater for missing information or data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Regional and global estimates for global monitoring&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regional and global estimates will be derived from national figures with an appropriate disaggregation level. Specialized tools will be developed and agreed upon with local and international stakeholders. Systems of quality assurance on the use of the tools, analysis and reporting will be deployed regionally, and global to ensure that standards are uniform and that definitions are universally applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We expect that investments in improved data collection and monitoring at country level will produce incentives for governments to improve reporting and performance and also greater readiness to engage with multiple stakeholders in data collection and analysis and in achieving better understanding of the strengths and weaknesses of existing slum definitions and their applications. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sources of differences between global and national figures:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As national agencies are responsible for data collection, no differences between country produced data and international estimated data on the indicator are expected to arise if standard methodologies and procedures are followed at all stages of the reporting process. Missing data and other local variables and frequency of data collection usually affects the figures reported at the global and national level. For this indicator, national data will be used to derive global figures. In instances where global values differ from national figures, efforts will be made for harmonization.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel de país: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se espera que todos los países informen completamente sobre este indicador de forma más consistente, con pocos desafíos en los que los valores faltantes se informarán a nivel nacional/global. A nivel nacional, es posible que se registren valores faltantes que tal vez representen lagunas de no medición entre las poblaciones cuya situación de tugurización o informalidad o vivienda inadecuada no se registra, se desconoce o no hay datos disponibles. Dado que los valores se agregarán a nivel nacional, los valores faltantes se observarán menos en estos niveles, pero es probable que afecten a las estimaciones. A nivel de la encuesta y de la recopilación de datos, se aplicarán los procedimientos de la encuesta para la gestión de los valores faltantes sobre la base de la unidad de análisis/unidades primarias de muestreo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel regional y global:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las estimaciones globales se ajustarán con una modelización basada en las tendencias para cubrir la información o los datos que falten.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Traitement des valeurs manquantes : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Au niveau national :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il est attendu que tous les pays soient en mesure de rapporter cet indicateur de façon cohérence et complète. Pour certains pays, il est possible qu&apos;il y ait des données manquantes pour certains groupes particuliers, dont les données ne sont pas enregistrées, sont inconnues ou ne sont pas disponibles, mais des données nationales devraient néanmoins être disponibles. Au niveau de la collecte des données, les procédures propres aux enquêtes relatives au traitement des valeurs manquantes seront appliquées selon l’unité d’analyse ou l’unité d’échantillonnage primaire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aux niveaux régional et mondial :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les estimations globales seront ajustées grâce à une modélisation basée sur les tendances afin de tenir compte des données manquantes.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ожидается, что все страны будут в полной мере отчитываться по этому показателю с меньшим количеством проблем, в то время как информация об отсутствующих значениях будет представляться на национальном / глобальном уровне. На национальном уровне, возможно, что отсутствующие значения будут отражать пробелы из-за недоучтенных результатов обследований среди групп населения, чей статус обитателей трущоб, неформальных поселений или проживающих в недостаточных жилищах не регистрируется или он неизвестен или когда данные отсутствуют. Поскольку значения будут агрегированы на национальных уровнях, отсутствующие значения будут меньше фиксироваться на этих уровнях, но это может повлиять на оценки. При проведении обследования и на уровне сбора данных будут применяться процедуры обследования, предназначенные для администрирования отсутствующих значений, основанные на единице анализа / первичных элементах выборки.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;На региональном и глобальном уровнях:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Глобальные оценки будут скорректированы с помощью моделирования, основанного на динамике, позволяющей учитывать отсутствие информации или данных. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
