<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 15-2-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x201C;Sustainable forest management&amp;#x201D; (SFM) is a central concept for Goal 15 and target 15.1 as well as for target 15.2. It has been formally defined, by the UN General Assembly, as follows: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[a] dynamic and evolving concept [that] aims to maintain and enhance the economic, social and environmental values of all types of forests, for the benefit of present and future generations&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#x201D; (Resolution A/RES/62/98) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is composed of five sub-indicators that measure progress towards all dimensions of sustainable forest management. The environmental values of forests are covered by three sub-indicators focused on the extension of forest area, biomass within the forest area and protection and maintenance of biological diversity, and of natural and associated cultural resources. Social and economic values of forests are reconciled with environmental values through sustainable management plans. The sub-indicator provides further qualification to the management of forest areas, by assessing areas which are independently verified for compliance with a set of national or international standards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sub-indicators are: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Annual forest area change rate &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Above-ground biomass stock in forest &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proportion of forest area located within legally established protect areas &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proportion of forest area under a long-term forest management plan &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forest area under an independently verified forest management certification scheme &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A dashboard is used to assess progress related to the five sub-indicators. The adoption of the dashboard approach aims at ensuring consideration of all dimensions of sustainable forest management and provides for clear view of areas where progress has been achieved. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See Annex 1 with Terms and Definitions. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x201C;La gestión forestal sostenible&amp;#x201D; (GFS) es un concepto central para el Objetivo 15 y la meta 15.1, así como para la meta 15.2. La Asamblea General de la ONU lo ha definido formalmente de la siguiente manera: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt; [un] concepto dinámico y evolutivo [que] tiene por objeto mantener y aumentar los valores económicos, sociales y ambientales de todos los tipos de bosques, en beneficio de las generaciones presentes y futuras&lt;/em&gt; &amp;#x201D; (Resolución A/RES/62/98) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador se compone de cinco subindicadores que miden el progreso hacia todas las dimensiones de la gestión forestal sostenible. Los valores ambientales de los bosques están cubiertos por tres subindicadores centrados en la extensión de la superficie forestal, la biomasa dentro de la superficie forestal y la protección y el mantenimiento de la diversidad biológica, así como de los recursos naturales y culturales asociados. Los valores sociales y económicos de los bosques se concilian con los valores ambientales mediante planes de gestión sostenible. El subindicador proporciona una mayor calificación a la gestión de las áreas forestales, evaluando las áreas que son verificadas de forma independiente para el cumplimiento de un conjunto de normas nacionales o internacionales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Los subindicadores son: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tasa de cambio neto anual de la superficie forestal &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Existencias de biomasa por encima del suelo en los bosques &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Proporción de la superficie forestal situada en zonas de protección legalmente establecidas &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proporción de la superficie forestal sometida a un plan de gestión forestal a largo plazo &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Superficie forestal sometida a un sistema de certificación de la gestión forestal verificado de forma independiente &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se utiliza un tablero de control para evaluar los progresos relacionados con los cinco subindicadores. La adopción del enfoque del tablero de mando tiene como objetivo garantizar la consideración de todas las dimensiones de la gestión forestal sostenible y proporciona una visión clara de las áreas en las que se han logrado avances. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Véase el anexo 1 con términos y definiciones. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Définition : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La gestion durable des forêts(GDF) est un concept central pour l&apos;objectif 15 et la cible 15.1 ainsi que pour la cible 15.2. Elle a été formellement définie, par l&apos;Assemblée générale des Nations Unies, comme suit : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt;&quot; [un] concept dynamique et évolutif [qui] vise à maintenir et à renforcer les valeurs économiques, sociales et environnementales de tous les types de forêts, au profit des générations actuelles et futures&lt;/em&gt; &quot;(Résolution A/RES/62/98) &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur se compose de cinq sous-indicateurs qui mesurent les progrès réalisés dans toutes les dimensions de la gestion durable des forêts. Les valeurs environnementales des forêts sont couvertes par trois sous-indicateurs axés sur l&apos;extension de la zone forestière, la biomasse dans la zone forestière et la protection et le maintien de la diversité biologique, ainsi que des ressources naturelles et culturelles associées. Les valeurs sociales et économiques des forêts sont conciliées avec les valeurs environnementales par des plans de gestion durable. Le sous-indicateur fournit une qualification supplémentaire à la gestion des zones forestières, en évaluant les zones dont la conformité à un ensemble de normes nationales ou internationales est vérifiée de manière indépendante. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les sous-indicateurs sont : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Taux de changement net annuel de la surface forestière &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stock de biomasse aérienne dans la forêt &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proportion de la superficie forestière située dans des zones protégées légalement établies &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proportion de la superficie forestière faisant l&apos;objet d&apos;un plan de gestion forestière à long terme &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Superficie forestière soumise à un système de certification de gestion forestière vérifié de manière indépendante &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Un tableau de bord est utilisé pour évaluer les progrès liés aux cinq sous-indicateurs. L&apos;adoption de l&apos;approche du tableau de bord vise à garantir la prise en compte de toutes les dimensions de la gestion durable des forêts et permet de visualiser clairement les domaines dans lesquels des progrès ont été réalisés. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Concepts : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voir l&apos;annexe 1 avec les termes et définitions. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &amp;#x201C;Неистощительное ведение лесного хозяйства (НВЛХ) является центральной концепцией цели 15 и задачи 15.1, а также задачи 15.2. Генеральная Ассамблея ООН официально определила его следующим образом: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt; [a] динамичная и эволюционирующая концепция, (которая) нацелена на сохранение и повышение экономической, социальной и экологической ценности всех видов лесов на благо нынешнего и будущих поколений. &lt;/em&gt;(Резолюция A/RES/62/98)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель состоит из пяти субпоказателей, которые отражают прогресс во всех аспектах неистощительного ведение лесного хозяйства. Экологические ценности лесов охватываются тремя субпоказателями, сфокусированными на увеличении площади лесов, биомассы в пределах лесной площади и защите и поддержании биологического разнообразия, а также природных и связанных культурных ресурсов. Социальные и экономические ценности лесов согласовываются с экологическими ценностями посредством планов рационального использования. Субпоказатель накладывает дополнительные квалификационные требования к использованию лесных территорий путем оценки территорий, которые проходят независимую проверку на соответствие ряду национальных или международных стандартов. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Субпоказатели: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Темп годового чистого изменения площади лесов &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Запасы наземной лесной биомассы &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Доля лесных площадей, расположенных в пределах установленных законом охраняемых
территорий &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Доля лесных площадей, имеющих долгосрочный план управления лесами &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Площадь лесов, на которых действует система сертификации использования лесов,
прошедшая независимую проверку &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Информационная панель используется для оценки прогресса, связанного с пятью субпоказателями. Принятие подхода с использованием информационной панели направлено на обеспечение учета всех аспектов рационального лесопользования и дает четкое представление об областях, в которых был достигнут прогресс. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Понятия: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; См. Приложение 1 Обозначения и Определения. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
