<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The OTHER_METHOD field for indicator 7-1-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="en">## Treatment of missing values

* **At country level**

    Given the low frequency and the regional distribution of some surveys, a number of countries have gaps in available data. To develop the historical evolution and starting point of electrification rates, a simple modeling approach was adopted to fill in the missing data points - around 1990, around 2000, and around 2010. Therefore, a country can have a continuum of zero to three data points. There are 42 countries with zero data point and the weighted regional average was used as an estimate for electrification in each of the data periods. 170 countries have between one and three data points and missing data are estimated by using a model with region, country, and time variables. The model keeps the original observation if data is available for any of the time periods. This modeling approach allowed the estimation of electrification rates for 212 countries over these three time periods (Indicated as &quot;Estimate&quot;).
* **At regional and global levels**

    NA
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">## Обработка пропущенных значений

* **На уровне страны**

    Учитывая низкую частоту проведения и региональное распределение некоторых обследований, в ряде стран имеются пробелы в имеющихся данных. Чтобы проследить историю развития и определить время начала роста темпов электрификации, был принят простой метод моделирования для заполнения недостающих данных - в районе 1990, 2000 и 2010 годов. Следовательно, страна может иметь от нуля до трех значений показателя. Существует 42 страны, у которых нет данных, а средневзвешенное значение по региону использовалось в качестве оценки электрификации в каждом из периодов данных. 170 стран имеют от одного до трех значений данных, а недостающие данные оцениваются с использованием модели с региональными, страновыми и временными переменными. Модель придерживается исходного наблюдения, если доступны данные за любой период времени. Этот метод моделирования позволил оценить показатели уровня электрификации для 212 стран за эти три периода времени (обозначено как «Оценка»).
* **На региональном и глобальном уровнях**

    Не Доступно
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
