<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 7-1-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The World Bank aims to estimate demand side access rates in order to better understand the access levels experienced by the population. This is different from the supply side access rates usually provided by governments, ministries, etc. The data collected is compiled from national household surveys and censuses. But since these are carried out infrequently, it is difficult to understand the ground level trends for short term periods. Collecting data for rural areas as well as last-mile connectivity problems also cause errors in data collection that could skew results. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the existing global household survey evidence base provides a good starting point for tracking household energy access, it also presents several limitations that will need to be addressed over time. In many parts of the world, the presence of an electricity connection in the household does not necessarily guarantee that the energy supplied is adequate in quality and reliability or affordable in cost and it would be desirable to have fuller information about these critical attributes of the service, which have been highlighted in SDG7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Substantial progress has already been made toward developing and piloting a new methodology known as the Multi-Tier Framework for Measuring Energy Access (World Bank) which is able to capture these broader dimensions of service quality and would make it possible to go beyond a simple yes/no measure of energy access to a more refined approach that recognizes different levels of energy access, and also takes into account the affordability and reliability of energy access explicitly referenced in the language of SDG7. The methodology for the Multi-Tier Framework for Measuring Energy Access has already been published based on a broad consultative exercise and represents a consensus view across numerous international agencies working in the field. Discussions are also progressing with the World Bank&amp;#x2019;s Household Survey Technical Working Group regarding the mainstreaming of this methodology into the standardized household questionnaire design that will be applied every three years in all low-income countries between 2015 and 2030 as part of the broader SDG monitoring exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The adoption of this methodology will allow &amp;#x2013; over time &amp;#x2013; the more refined measurement of energy access, making it possible to report more disaggregated information regarding the type of electricity supply (grid or off-grid), the capacity of electricity supply provided (in Watts), the duration of service (daily hours and evening hours), the reliability of service (in terms of number and length of unplanned service interruptions), the quality of service (in terms of voltage fluctuations), as well as affordability and legality of service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another advantage of this approach is that they can be applied not only to measuring energy access at the household level, but also its availability to support enterprises and deliver critical community services, such as health and education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methodological challenges associated with the measurement of energy access are more fully described the Global Tracking Framework (2013) (Chapter 2, Section 1, page 75-82), and in the ESMAP (2015) Report &amp;#x201C;Beyond Connections: Energy Access Redefined&amp;#x201D; both of which are referenced below.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt; Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El Banco Mundial tiene como objetivo estimar las tasas de acceso de la demanda para comprender mejor los niveles de acceso experimentados por la población. Esto es diferente de las tasas de acceso de la oferta que suelen proporcionar los gobiernos, los ministerios, etc. Los datos recolectados se compilan a partir de encuestas nacionales de hogares y censos. Pero dado que estos se llevan a cabo con poca frecuencia, es difícil entender las tendencias de base para períodos a corto plazo. La recolección de datos para las zonas rurales, así como los problemas de conectividad en recta final, también causan errores en la recolección de datos que podrían sesgar los resultados. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Si bien la base de evidencia existente de la encuesta mundial de hogares proporciona un buen punto de partida para rastrear el acceso a la energía en los hogares, también presenta varias limitaciones que deberán abordarse con el tiempo. En muchas partes del mundo, la presencia de una conexión eléctrica en el hogar no garantiza necesariamente que la energía suministrada sea adecuada en calidad y fiabilidad o asequible en costo y sería deseable tener información más completa sobre estos atributos críticos del servicio, que se han destacado en el ODS7. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ya se han logrado avances sustanciales en el desarrollo y la puesta a prueba de una nueva metodología conocida como el Marco de Múltiples Niveles para medir el acceso a la energía (Banco Mundial), que es capaz de capturar estas dimensiones más amplias de la calidad del servicio y permitiría ir más allá de una simple medida de sí/no del acceso a la energía a un enfoque más refinado que reconoce los diferentes niveles de acceso a la energía, y también tiene en cuenta la asequibilidad y confiabilidad del acceso a la energía a la que se hace referencia explícita en el lenguaje del ODS7. La metodología para el marco de varios niveles para medir el acceso a la energía ya se ha publicado sobre la base de un amplio ejercicio consultivo y representa una opinión consensuada entre numerosos organismos internacionales que trabajan sobre el terreno. También están avanzando las discusiones con el Grupo de Trabajo Técnico de Encuestas de Hogares del Banco Mundial sobre la integración de esta metodología en el diseño estandarizado del cuestionario de hogares que se aplicará cada tres años en todos los países de bajos ingresos entre 2015 y 2030 como parte del ejercicio más amplio de monitoreo de los ODS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La adopción de esta metodología permitirá &amp;#x2013; a lo largo del tiempo &amp;#x2013; la medición más refinada del acceso a la energía, lo que permitirá presentar información más desagregada sobre el tipo de suministro de electricidad (red o fuera de la red), la capacidad de suministro de electricidad proporcionada (en vatios), la duración del servicio (horas diarias y horas de la tarde), la fiabilidad del servicio (en términos de número y duración de interrupciones no planificadas del servicio), la calidad del servicio (en términos de fluctuaciones de tensión), así como la asequibilidad y legalidad del servicio. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otra ventaja de este enfoque es que pueden aplicarse no solo a la medición del acceso a la energía a nivel de los hogares, sino también a su disponibilidad para apoyar a las empresas y prestar servicios comunitarios críticos, como la salud y la educación. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los desafíos metodológicos asociados con la medición del acceso a la energía se describen más detalladamente en el Marco de Seguimiento Global (2013) (Capítulo 2, Sección 1, página 75-82), y en el Informe ESMAP (2015) &amp;#x201C;Beyond Connections: Energy Access Redefined&amp;#x201D; ambos de los cuales se hace referencia a continuación. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt; Commentaires et limites : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La Banque mondiale vise à estimer les taux d&apos;accès du côté de la demande afin de mieux comprendre les niveaux d&apos;accès rencontrés par la population. Ceci est différent des taux d&apos;accès du côté de l&apos;offre généralement fournis par les gouvernements, les ministères, etc. Les données collectées sont compilées à partir d&apos;enquêtes et de recensements nationaux auprès des ménages. Mais comme celles-ci sont rarement effectuées, il est difficile de comprendre les tendances au niveau du sol pour des périodes à court terme. La collecte de données pour les zones rurales ainsi que les problèmes de connectivité du dernier kilomètre entraînent également des erreurs dans la collecte de données qui pourraient fausser les résultats. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Bien que la base de données existante de l&apos;enquête mondiale sur les ménages constitue un bon point de départ pour suivre l&apos;accès à l&apos;énergie des ménages, elle présente également plusieurs limites qui devront être résolues au fil du temps. Dans de nombreuses régions du monde, la présence d&apos;une connexion électrique dans le ménage ne garantit pas nécessairement que l&apos;énergie fournie est adéquate en qualité et en fiabilité ou abordable en coût et il serait souhaitable d&apos;avoir des informations plus complètes sur ces attributs critiques du service. , qui ont été mis en évidence dans l&apos;ODD7. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Des progrès substantiels ont déjà été accomplis dans l&apos;élaboration et la mise à l&apos;essai d&apos;une nouvelle méthodologie connue sous le nom de Cadre à plusieurs niveaux pour mesurer l&apos;accès à l&apos;énergie (Banque mondiale), qui est en mesure de saisir ces dimensions plus larges de la qualité de service et permettrait d&apos;aller au-delà une simple mesure oui / non de l&apos;accès à l&apos;énergie à une approche plus raffinée qui reconnaît les différents niveaux d&apos;accès à l&apos;énergie, et prend également en compte l&apos;accessibilité et la fiabilité de l&apos;accès à l&apos;énergie explicitement référencées dans le langage de l&apos;ODD7. La méthodologie du cadre à plusieurs niveaux pour mesurer l&apos;accès à l&apos;énergie a déjà été publiée sur la base d&apos;un vaste exercice de consultation et représente un consensus entre de nombreuses agences internationales travaillant dans ce domaine. Des discussions sont également en cours avec le groupe de travail technique sur les enquêtes auprès des ménages de la Banque mondiale concernant l’intégration de cette méthodologie dans la conception standard du questionnaire sur les ménages qui sera appliquée tous les trois ans dans tous les pays à faible revenu entre 2015 et 2030 dans exercice plus large de suivi des ODD. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L&apos;adoption de cette méthodologie permettra , au fil du temps, la mesure plus fine de l&apos;accès à l&apos;énergie, permettant de rapporter des informations plus désagrégées concernant le type d’approvisionnement en électricité (réseau ou hors réseau), la capacité de l&apos;alimentation électrique fournie (en Watts), la durée de service (heures journalières et heures du soir), la fiabilité du service (en nombre et en durée d&apos;interruptions de service imprévues), la qualité de service (en termes de fluctuations de tension), ainsi que l&apos;accessibilité et la légalité du service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Un autre avantage de cette approche est qu&apos;elle peut être appliquée non seulement pour mesurer l&apos;accès à l&apos;énergie au niveau des ménages, mais aussi sa disponibilité pour soutenir les entreprises et fournir des services communautaires essentiels, tels que la santé et l&apos;éducation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les défis méthodologiques associés à la mesure de l&apos;accès à l&apos;énergie sont décrits plus en détail dans le Cadre mondial de suivi (2013) (chapitre 2, section 1, pages 75-82) et dans le rapport ESMAP (2015) «Beyond Connections : Energy Access Redefined », tous deux référencés ci-dessous. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Всемирный банк стремится оценить уровень доступа со стороны спроса, чтобы лучше понять уровни доступа, с которыми сталкивается население. Такой подход отличается от показателей доступа со стороны предложения, обычно предоставляемых правительствами, министерствами и т. д. Сбор данных производится при проведении национальных обследований домашних хозяйств и переписей населения. Но поскольку они проводятся нечасто, трудно понять тенденции на самом нижнем уровне за краткосрочные периоды. Сбор данных по сельским районам, а также проблемы со связью на «последней миле» также вызывают ошибки в сборе данных, которые могут исказить результаты. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Хотя существующая база данных глобальных обследований домашних хозяйств является хорошей отправной точкой для отслеживания доступа домашних хозяйств к энергии, она также представляет несколько ограничений, которые необходимо будет устранить с течением времени. Во многих частях мира наличие подключения к электросети в домашнем хозяйстве не обязательно гарантирует, что поставляемая энергия является адекватной по качеству и надежности или доступной по стоимости, и было бы желательно иметь более полную информацию об этих важнейших характеристиках услуги, которые были выделены в ЦУР7. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Уже достигнут значительный прогресс в разработке и апробации новой методологии, известной как Многоуровневая система измерения доступа к энергии (Всемирный банк), которая способна охватить эти более широкие аспекты качества услуг и позволит выйти за рамки простой оценки доступа к энергии в виде ответа «да / нет» и перейти к более совершенному подходу, который устанавливает разные уровни доступа к энергии, а также принимает во внимание ценовую доступность и надежность доступа к энергии, о которых явно идет речь в ЦУР7. Опубликованная Методология многоуровневой системы измерения доступа к энергии создана на основе широких консультаций и представляет собой согласованную точку зрения многих международных агентств, работающих в этой области. Также продолжаются обсуждения с Технической рабочей группой Всемирного банка по обследованию домашних хозяйств относительно включения этой методологии в стандартизированный план вопросника для обследования домашних хозяйств, который будет применяться каждые три года во всех странах с низким уровнем дохода в период с 2015 по 2030 годы в рамках более широкого эксперимента по мониторингу ЦУР.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Принятие этой методологии позволит &quot;в динамике по времени&quot; проводить более точное измерение доступа к энергии, позволяющее представлять более дезагрегированную информацию о типе электроснабжения (сетевое или внесетевое), мощности предоставляемой электроэнергии (в ваттах), продолжительности обслуживания (дневные и вечерние часы), надежности обслуживания (с точки зрения количества и продолжительности незапланированных перерывов в обслуживании), качестве обслуживания (с точки зрения колебаний напряжения), а также ценовой доступности и юридической правомерности услуги. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Еще одним преимуществом этого подхода является то, что его можно применять не только для оценки доступа к энергии на уровне домохозяйств, но и ее доступности для снабжения предприятий и предоставления важнейших общественных услуг, таких как здравоохранение и образование. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Методологические проблемы, связанные с оценкой доступа к энергии, более полно описаны в Глобальной системе отслеживания (2013 год) (глава 2, раздел 1, стр. 75-82) и в отчете Программы помощи в области управления сектором энергетики (ЭСМАП)(2015 год) &quot; За рамками подключений: Новое определение доступа к энергии&quot;, оба упомянуты ниже. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
