<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 1-3-1a, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Rationale and interpretation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Access to at least a basic level of social protection throughout the life cycle is a human right. The principle of universality of social protection evidences the importance of social protection systems in guaranteeing decent living conditions to the whole population, throughout their lives. The proportion of the population covered by social protection systems/floors provides an indication of the extent to which universality is accomplished, and thus, how secure are the population&amp;apos;s living conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Measurements of &lt;strong&gt;effective coverage&lt;/strong&gt; should reflect how in reality legal provisions are implemented. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It refers to the percentage of people actually receiving benefits of contributory and non-contributory social protection programmes, plus the number of persons actively contributing to social insurance schemes.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Justification et interprétation :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;accès à un niveau minimum de protection sociale tout au long de la vie est un droit de l&apos;homme. Le principe d&apos;universalité de la protection sociale met en évidence l&apos;importance des systèmes de protection sociale pour garantir des conditions de vie décentes à l&apos;ensemble de la population, tout au long de leur vie. La proportion de la population couverte par les systèmes/seuils de protection sociale donne une indication de la mesure dans laquelle l&apos;universalité est accomplie, et donc de la sécurité des conditions de vie de la population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les mesures de la &lt;strong&gt;couverture effective&lt;/strong&gt; devraient refléter la manière dont les dispositions légales sont mises en œuvre dans la réalité. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il s&apos;agit du pourcentage de personnes qui reçoivent effectivement des prestations des programmes de protection sociale contributifs et non contributifs, plus le nombre de personnes qui contribuent activement aux régimes d&apos;assurance sociale.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
