<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 1-3-1a, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The indicator reflects the proportion of persons effectively covered by a social protection system, including social protection floors. It also reflects the main components of social protection: child and maternity benefits, support for persons without a job, persons with disabilities, victims of work injuries and older persons. &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Effective coverage of social protection is measured by the number of people who are either actively contributing to a social insurance scheme or receiving benefits (contributory or non-contributory).&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;Concepts: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social protection systems include contributory and non-contributory schemes for children, pregnant women with newborns, people in active age, older persons, for victims of work injuries and persons with disabilities. Social protection floors provide at least a basic level in all main contingencies along the life cycle, as defined in the Social Protection Floors Recommendation 2012 (no. 202) referred to in SDG 1.3. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When assessing coverage and gaps in coverage, distinctions need to be made between coverage by (1) contributory social insurance, (2) universal schemes covering all residents (or all residents in a given category), and (3) means-tested schemes potentially covering all those who pass the required test of income and/or assets.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur reflète la proportion de personnes effectivement couvertes par un système de protection sociale, y compris les seuils de protection sociale. Il reflète également les principales composantes de la protection sociale : allocations familiales et de maternité, soutien aux personnes sans emploi, aux personnes handicapées, aux victimes d&apos;accidents du travail et aux personnes âgées. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La couverture effective de la protection sociale est mesurée par le nombre de personnes qui cotisent activement à un régime d&apos;assurance sociale ou qui reçoivent des prestations (contributives ou non contributives).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les systèmes de protection sociale comprennent des régimes contributifs et non contributifs pour les enfants, les femmes enceintes et les nouveau-nés, les personnes en âge actif, les personnes âgées, pour les victimes d&apos;accidents du travail et les personnes handicapées. Les seuils de protection sociale fournissent au moins un niveau de base dans toutes les principales éventualités tout au long du cycle de vie, tel que défini dans la recommandation sur les seuils de protection sociale 2012 (n° 202) mentionnée dans l&apos;ODD 1.3. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lorsque l&apos;on évalue la couverture et les lacunes de la couverture, il convient de faire des distinctions entre la couverture par (1) l&apos;assurance sociale contributive, (2) les régimes universels couvrant tous les résidents (ou tous les résidents d&apos;une catégorie donnée), et (3) les régimes sous condition de ressources couvrant potentiellement tous ceux qui passent le test requis de revenu et/ou de patrimoine.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
