<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 12-7-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; &lt;strong&gt;At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With regard to the developed SPP government implementation assessment itself, missing values do not significantly impact the calculated score, as governments may report on some sub-indicators only (B, C, D, E, F), only sub-indicator A being mandatory (A: Existence of a SPP action plan/policy, and/or SPP regulatory requirements).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With regard to the general assessment of SPP implementation at country level&lt;strong&gt;, it should however be noted that it had been&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;originally planned to calculate a country-level SPP implementation Index based on the aggregation of three sub-indices reflecting three different levels of government&lt;/strong&gt;, including &lt;strong&gt;a weighting representing the government&amp;#x2019;s share of procurement &lt;/strong&gt;in total public procurement value at country level (formula shown below), which would provide a fairer evaluation of SPP efforts at country level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual scope of the national/federal government&amp;#x2019;s SPP implementation might indeed vary considerably from one country to another, as in some countries, SPP implementation when directed by the central government may apply to most public entities in the country, while in other countries, implementation conducted by the federal government might only represent a small share of public procurement at country level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first data collection exercise however &lt;strong&gt;showed that the total public procurement value&lt;/strong&gt;, at country level or at the level of the considered government, &lt;strong&gt;is not always available&lt;/strong&gt;, therefore not allowing for the calculation of such an index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first reporting exercise, the assessed level of SPP implementation and further classification in groups, is therefore mainly based on the calculated SPP National/Federal Government Score, taking account of national/federal government SPP implementation efforts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subnational submissions received may however also be evaluated following the same evaluation framework, and, through the calculation of a similar score, be classified according to their level of SPP implementation, and compared with similar-level governments (higher-level subnational government &amp;#x2013; such as provinces, or states in the case of Brazil and the US &amp;#x2013; and lower-level subnational government &amp;#x2013; such as cities and municipalities).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; &lt;strong&gt;At regional and global levels:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As SDG 12.7.1. indicator measures the number of countries implementing SPP action plans and policies, therefore missing data (countries not submitting reports on their implementation of SPP) do not significantly impact the indicator measurement.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
