<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 17-7-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environmentally Sound Technologies (ESTs) are technologies that have the potential for significantly improved environmental performance relative to other technologies. ESTs protect the environment, are less polluting, use resources in a sustainable manner, recycle more of their wastes and products, and handle all residual wastes in a more environmentally acceptable way than the technologies for which they are substitutes. ESTs are not just individual technologies. They can also be defined as total systems that include know-how, procedures, goods and services, and equipment, as well as organizational and managerial procedures for promoting environmental sustainability. This means that any attempt to provide an assessment of investment into ESTs on either a global or national level must incorporate ways to track funding flows into both hard and soft technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this indicator is to develop a methodology for tracking the total amount of approved funding to promote the development, transfer, dissemination and diffusion of environmentally sound technologies. A two-pronged approach is suggested: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Level 1. Use globally available data to create a proxy of funding flowing to countries for environmentally sound technologies, or of trade in environmentally sound technologies &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Level 2. Collect national data on investment in environmentally sound technologies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are five crucial elements which make up Goal 17 - finance, capacity building, systemic issues, technology and trade- all of which must be aligned for the Goal to be achieved. One of the key lessons over the last couple of decades has been that in order to achieve potential growth, measurement of financial flows (in terms of amount, type, geography, donor, recipient and investors) is a necessary step in such a transformation. In order to understand systemic issues, trade, capacity building, technology lock-in, innovation and deployment, we must understand how, why and where finance is being deployed. Only then we can begin to realign its flows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In deciding which technologies are most appropriate, there will always be trade-offs between cost and a range of economic, social, health and environmental impacts, to be determined based on national or local contexts and priorities. It would also not be feasible for all countries to strive towards the best available technologies globally if these are not appropriate in a domestic context. Given the highly contextual nature of ESTs, it is therefore something that is better defined at the national level, taking into account the national context and mainstream technologies nationally. However, there is a real need to support national, sub-national governments and other actors with decision-making and defining the most nationally or locally appropriate technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
