<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 1-4-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator was reclassified from Tier III to &lt;strong&gt;Tier II &lt;/strong&gt;during the 6&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Meeting of IAEG-SDG. An internationally established methodology exists but data is not regularly produced by countries. Administrative data are routinely produced by land administration institutions. The 116 countries reporting having electronic land information systems, can generate the required data at a low cost on a routine basis, and at high levels of disaggregation, once the queries for the SDG dashboard are put in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nationally representative multi-topic household&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;surveys have collected land related data in many countries.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;These provide information, separately for residential and non-residential land, on (i) the share of individuals with legally documented rights; and (ii) the share of individuals who perceive their rights to be secure. Nationally representative household surveys will also provide data on two other key elements, namely (i) reported type of documentation and (ii) perception of tenure security by tenure type and other disaggregations discussed above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator will be disaggregated by sex and type of tenure, using the standards developed by the working group on data disaggregation, which is a subgroup of the Inter-Agency Expert Group on SDGs&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-10&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-10&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-10&quot;&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/sdgs/files/meetings/iaeg-sdgs-meeting-05/12_14.%20Data%20disaggregation_plenary.pdf&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/sdgs/files/meetings/iaeg-sdgs-meeting-05/12_14.%20Data%20disaggregation_plenary.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-10&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
