<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 1-4-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;In 2016, a total of 116 countries reported having electronic land information systems in place. Countries with paper-based systems will have more difficulties with reporting on administrative data and household surveys will be the main source of data for this indicator in these countries. The expansion of digitization of records and land data management is one way to facilitate the ease of reporting administrative data for this indicator. Coverage may, however, be geographically skewed, for example towards urban or specific rural regions where cadastral coverage is concentrated, and therefore sub-national dimensions should be properly considered and conveyed in narrative reporting by specific countries to accompany the headline data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In federal countries with decentralized land registry systems and no centralized reporting yet, data reporting systems for aggregation will be put in place. For countries where the land administration system does not yet collect information on gender, and gender disaggregation cannot be computed using other core data (social security numbers, ID etc), land agencies are encouraged to start expanding this by recording also the gender of owners/users of newly registered land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the national household surveys&amp;#x2019; target samples are sufficiently large to provide the statistical power for disaggregation by sex and tenure type at rural /urban and sub-national levels. Inferring the extent to which the adult population is tenure secure based on the existing web of surveys, will require the use of a standardized set of questions so that surveys can be combined. However, even nationally representative surveys tend to cover certain segments of the population (those living in agricultural areas, families in which there are women of reproductive age, official urban areas etc.). Even when all the existing surveys are aggregated, there may be pockets of the population that are not captured by the surveys and for which there is thus no data on tenure security. This may include families living in areas that are too far or costly to reach, like forest areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Household surveys generally collect household-level data from proxy respondents. Family members who are not the head or the most knowledgeable person in their households are not interviewed, as is also noted in the methodological note for the IAEG-SDG Secretariat for Indicator 5.a.1. This approach is problematic for measuring tenure rights and security due to the introduction of non-random measurement errors&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-7&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-7&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. For instance, proxy reporting by one member of the household tends to incorrectly assign rights and misjudge and underestimate both women&amp;#x2019;s and men&amp;#x2019;s rights and use of land. Indicator 1.4.2 should therefore be based on self-reported rather than proxy data. If not all household members are surveyed, only those surveyed should be reported, estimating the global adult population based on the smaller sample enumerated. This lack of information affects only the numerators of the indicator; it has no bearing on the denominator which should always be the total adult population. In other words, the indicator reports and tracks the proportion of the population for which there is self-reported data stating that they are tenure secure. People for whom there is no information cannot be assumed to be tenure secure and therefore are not counted in the numerator. NSOs should report the data collected from household surveys as individual level data that corresponds to the respondent and is not extrapolated to the rest of his/her household. Any limitations in the representativeness of this data should be clearly noted in the country specific metadata submitted with the reporting, including who was included in the enumeration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data will still be used for countries that do not yet have survey instruments in place that survey individuals, while capacity for expanding sampling and individual self-reporting by NSOs is expanded progressively through DHS, MICS, LSMS and other type of surveys in coordination with FAO and UN-Women. Addressing this challenge will require combined efforts. Custodians of the land rights indicators1.4.2 and 5.a.1, and relevant stakeholders from the land sector, will work with custodians from other SDG indicators also require surveying of individuals, and in particular the NSOs, to identify effective approaches to start filling the void on self-reported data. NSOs need to be supported to collect data by interviewing individual adult household member. The custodians will leverage the work of the UN - Evidence and Data for Gender Equality &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/edge/&quot;&gt;EDGE project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-8&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-8&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, in particular, which is the most advanced in using and testing gender sensitive methodologies and approaches. They have found the approach feasible and have developed training materials and data collection instruments suitable for this effort.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-7&quot;&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Findings from the Methodological Experiment on Measuring Asset Ownership from A Gender Perspective (MEXA) experiment revealed that data from proxy respondents yield different estimates than self-reported data, with variations by asset, by type of ownership and by the sex of the owner. For instance, the study found that self-reported data increase both women&amp;#x2019;s and men&amp;#x2019;s reported ownership of agricultural land in Uganda. Such increase is greater for men (15 percentage points) than for women (10 percentage points), and is less pronounced when we consider documented ownership (+7 percentage points for men and +2 percentage points for women) (Kilic and Moylan, 20160. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-7&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-8&quot;&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/edge/&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/edge/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-8&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
