<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COMPARABILITY field for indicator 8-2-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main limitations of the use of labour productivity as a global indicator arise from problems in the international comparability of data, more specifically from methodological differences across countries. Even though national output measures, in particular GDP estimates, are derived mainly from national accounts which should be based on internationally agreed principles consolidated in the United Nations SNA, there are still significant obstacles to the international consistency of national accounts estimates. These range from differences in the treatment of the output of service sectors to adjustments for price changes and variations in the coverage of informal activities and the underground economy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employment or labour input figures also suffer from comparability issues, especially in terms of differences in age coverage, the definition of employment, geographical and institutional coverage, the treatment of special groups and the coverage of informal employment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In cases where the contribution to GDP of forms of work other than employment are expected to be significant, such as in the case of own-use production of goods (subsistence agriculture and fishing) or volunteer work, the exclusion of participation and time-spent in these productive activities can be an important source of bias in the resulting indicators.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt; Fuentes de discrepancias:&lt;/h2&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Sources des divergences : &lt;/h2&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt;Источники расхождений:&lt;/h2&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
