<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 8-2-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computation method:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Real GDP per employed person = GDP at constant prices/Total employment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The numerator and denominator of the equation above should refer to the same reference period, for example, the same calendar year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we call the real GDP per employed person &amp;#x201C;LabProd&amp;#x201D;, then the annual growth rate of real GDP per employed person is calculated as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annual growth rate of real GDP per employed person&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;= ((LabProd in year n) &amp;#x2013; (LabProd in year n-1))/((LabProd in year n-1)) x 100&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PIB real por persona ocupada = PIB a precios constantes/empleo total&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El numerador y el denominador de la ecuación anterior deben referirse al mismo periodo de referencia, por ejemplo, el mismo año natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Si llamamos al PIB real por persona ocupada &amp;#x201C;LabProd&amp;#x201D;, entonces la tasa de crecimiento anual del PIB real por persona ocupada se calcula como sigue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tasa de crecimiento anual del PIB real por ocupado&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;= ((LabProd en el año n) &amp;#x2013; (LabProd en el año n-1))/((LabProd en el año n-1)) x 100&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Méthodologie&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Méthode de calcul :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PIB réel par personne occupée = PIB à prix constants/emploi total&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;]Le numérateur et le dénominateur de l&apos;équation ci-dessus doivent se référer à la même période de référence, par exemple, la même année civile &lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;Si nous appelons le PIB réel par personne employée &amp;#x201C;LabProd&amp;#x201D;, alors le taux de croissance annuel du PIB réel par personne employée est calculé comme suit :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taux de croissance annuel du PIB réel par personne occupée &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;= ((LabProd à l&apos;année n) &amp;#x2013; (LabProd à l&apos;année n-1))/((LabProd à l&apos;année n-1)) x 100 &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Реальный ВВП на каждого занятого = ВВП в постоянных ценах / общая занятость &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Числитель и знаменатель приведенного выше уравнения должны относиться к одному и тому же отчетному периоду, например, к одному календарному году. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Если мы назовем реальный ВВП на каждого занятого &amp;#x201C; LabProd&amp;#x201D;, то годовые темпы роста реального ВВП на каждого занятого рассчитываются следующим образом: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Годовые темпы роста реального ВВП на каждого занятого &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; = ((LabProd в год n) &amp;#x2013; (LabProd в год n-1)) / ((LabProd в год n-1)) x 100 &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
