<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COMPARABILITY field for indicator 2-c-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;FAO relies on the Food Price Indices as reported in FAOSTAT as well as on available official domestic food price data that it compiles in the Food Price Monitoring and Analysis (FPMA) tool to calculate the indicator. The FPMA database brings together price series for main food commodities (mainly cereal products) in selected markets in countries around the world. As a result, the indicator estimated by FAO can differ from the indicator estimated at country level, as it may be calculated on prices for a different market or commodity. When food products that are most relevant to the country differ from the five commodities that FAO calculates, countries are strongly encouraged to produce the IFPA of those food items and monitor their price volatilities. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;La FAO s’appuie sur les indices des prix des denrées alimentaires tels qu’ils sont présentés dans FAOSTAT ainsi que sur les données officielles disponibles sur les prix alimentaires qu’elle compile dans l’outil de surveillance et d’analyse des prix des denrées alimentaires (SAPA) pour calculer l’indicateur. La base de données de SAPA rassemble des séries de prix pour les principaux produits alimentaires (principalement les produits céréaliers) sur certains marchés dans des pays du monde entier. En conséquence, l’indicateur estimé par la FAO peut différer de l’indicateur estimé au niveau des pays, car il peut être calculé sur les prix d’un marché ou d’un produit différent. Lorsque les produits alimentaires les plus pertinents pour le pays diffèrent des cinq produits calculés par la FAO, les pays sont fortement encouragés à produire l’IAPA de ces produits alimentaires et à surveiller la volatilité de leurs prix. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
