<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 2-c-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At country level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; For the domestic food commodity prices, the data is republished data harvested from national governmental organizations without imputation of missing values. For the purpose of the indicator, if more than 3 consecutive months of data are missing or if less than 5 years are available the series may be dropped from monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the food price index in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/faostat/en/#data/CP&quot;&gt;FAOSTAT&lt;/a&gt;, the data is republished data harvested from other international organizations without imputation of missing values. For the purpose of the indicator, if more than 3 consecutive months of data are missing or if less than 5 years are available the series may be dropped from monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At regional and global levels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not Applicable&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Au niveau national &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour les prix intérieurs des produits alimentaires de base, les données sont des données republiées récoltées auprès d&apos;organisations gouvernementales nationales sans imputation des valeurs manquantes. Pour les besoins de l&apos;indicateur, si plus de 3 mois consécutifs de données manquent ou si moins de 5 ans sont disponibles, le suivi de la série peut être abandonné. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour l&apos;indice des prix alimentaires dans &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/faostat/fr/#data/CP&quot;&gt;FAOSTAT&lt;/a&gt;, les données sont des données republiées récoltées auprès d&apos;autres organisations internationales sans imputation des valeurs manquantes. Pour les besoins de l&apos;indicateur, si plus de 3 mois consécutifs de données sont manquants ou si moins de 5 ans sont disponibles, le suivi de la série peut être abandonné.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aux niveaux régional et mondial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sans objet&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
