<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 10-c-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The target includes two components. The first component is that transaction costs for migrant remittances should be 3% or less by 2030. This transaction cost should be intended as &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x201C;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global average total cost of sending $200 (or equivalent in local sending currency) and expressed as % of amount sent&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/strong&gt; This indicator is readily available and published on a quarterly basis by the World Bank in the Remittance Prices Worldwide database, which covers 365 country corridors, from 48 sending to 105 receiving countries. The second component is to eliminate corridor where cost is 5% or higher. This should be intended in the sense that it should be possible for remittance senders to send money to the beneficiary for an average cost of 5% or less of the amount sent. For this purpose, it should suffice that in each corridor there are at least 3 services, meeting a defined set of service requirements (including service quality, reach etc.), for which the average is 5% or less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;International remittance transfer.&lt;/strong&gt; A cross-border person-to-person payment of relatively low value. The transfers are typically recurrent payments by migrant workers (who send money to their families in their home country every month). In the report, the term &amp;#x201C;remittance transfer&amp;#x201D; is used for simplicity (ie it is assumed the transfer is international).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remittance service.&lt;/strong&gt; A service that enables end users to send and/or receive remittance transfers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remittance service provider (RSP).&lt;/strong&gt; An entity, operating as a business, that provides a remittance service for a price to end users, either directly or through agents. These include both banks and money transfer operators, as defined below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Money transfer operator (MTO).&lt;/strong&gt; A non-deposit taking payment service provider where the service involves payment per transfer (or possibly payment for a set or series of transfers) by the sender to the payment service provider (for example, by cash or bank transfer) &amp;#x2013; i.e. as opposed to a situation where the payment service provider debits an account held by the sender at the payment service provider. MTOs may include both traditional players focusing on delivering funds in cash and innovative players which may adopt a variety of different business models for the delivery of the transactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price. &lt;/strong&gt;The total cost to the end users of sending a remittance transfer (including the fees charged to the sender and the margin by which the exchange rate charged to the end users is above the current interbank exchange rate).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transparent service&lt;/strong&gt;. A remittance service for which the sending cost can be split into its two components: transfer fee and foreign exchange margin. If a provider does not disclose the foreign exchange rate applicable to the transaction, then the service is considered not transparent. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El objetivo incluye dos componentes. El primer componente es que los costos de transacción de las remesas de los emigrantes deben ser del 3% o menos para 2030. Este costo de transacción debe entenderse como &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x201C;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Costo total medio mundial del envío de 200 dólares (o su equivalente en la moneda local de envío) y expresado como % de la cantidad enviada&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/strong&gt; Este indicador está fácilmente disponible y es publicado trimestralmente por el Banco Mundial en la base de datos Remittance Prices Worldwide, que cubre 365 corredores de países, desde 48 países emisores a 105 receptores. El segundo componente consiste en eliminar los corredores en los que el costo es igual o superior al 5%. La intención es que los remitentes de remesas puedan enviar dinero al beneficiario por un costo medio del 5% o menos de la cantidad enviada. Para ello, debería bastar con que en cada corredor haya al menos 3 servicios, que cumplan un conjunto definido de requisitos de servicio (incluyendo la calidad del servicio, el alcance, etc.), para los que la media sea del 5% o menos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transferencia internacional de remesas.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Pago transfronterizo de persona a persona de valor relativamente bajo. Las transferencias suelen ser pagos recurrentes de los trabajadores inmigrantes (que envían dinero a sus familias en su país de origen cada mes). En el informe, el término &amp;#x201C;transferencia de remesas&amp;#x201D; se utiliza para simplificar (es decir, se asume que la transferencia es internacional).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Servicio de remesas.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Servicio que permite a los usuarios finales enviar y/o recibir transferencias de remesas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Proveedor de servicios de remesas (PSR).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Entidad, que opera como negocio, que proporciona un servicio de remesas por un precio a los usuarios finales, ya sea directamente o a través de agentes. Entre ellos se encuentran tanto los bancos como los operadores de transferencias de dinero, tal y como se definen a continuación.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Operador de transferencias monetarias (MTO).&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Un proveedor de servicios de pago que no acepta depósitos y en el que el servicio implica el pago por transferencia (o posiblemente el pago de un conjunto o serie de transferencias) por parte del remitente al proveedor de servicios de pago (por ejemplo, mediante efectivo o transferencia bancaria) &amp;#x2013;, es decir, en contraposición a una situación en la que el proveedor de servicios de pago carga una cuenta del remitente en el proveedor de servicios de pago. Los MTO pueden incluir tanto actores tradicionales centrados en la entrega de fondos en efectivo como actores innovadores que pueden adoptar una variedad de modelos de negocio diferentes para la entrega de las transacciones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Precio. &lt;/strong&gt;Costo total para los usuarios finales del envío de una transferencia de remesas (incluidas las comisiones cobradas al remitente y el margen por el que el tipo de cambio cobrado a los usuarios finales es superior al tipo de cambio interbancario vigente).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Définition :&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; La cible comprend deux composantes. D&apos;une part, les coûts de transaction pour les envois de fonds des migrants devraient être de 3 % ou moins d&apos;ici 2030. Ce coût correspond au &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x201C;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Coût total moyen d&apos;envoi de 200 $ (ou l&apos;équivalent en devise locale) exprimé en % du montant envoyé &amp;#x201D;.&lt;/strong&gt; Cet indicateur est disponible et publié sur une base trimestrielle par la Banque mondiale dans la base de données Remittance Prices Worldwide (RPW), qui couvre 365 circuits d&apos;envois, de 48 pays d&apos;envoi à 105 pays de réception. La deuxième composante consiste à éliminer les circuits d&apos;envois où le coût est de 5 % ou plus. Il devrait ainsi être possible pour les expéditeurs d&apos;envoyer des fonds à des bénéficiaires pour un coût moyen de 5 % ou moins du montant envoyé. Pour ce, il devrait suffire que pour chaque circuit d&apos;envoi, il existe au moins 3 services répondant à un ensemble défini d&apos;exigences (incluant la qualité du service, la portée, etc.) et pour lesquels le coût moyen est de 5 % ou moins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Concepts :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transfert international de fonds. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Paiement transfrontalier de personne à personne de valeur relativement faible. Les transferts sont généralement des paiements récurrents effectués par des travailleurs migrants (qui envoient de l&apos;argent à leur famille dans leur pays d&apos;origine chaque mois). Le terme &amp;#x201C;transfert de fonds&amp;#x201D; est utilisé à des fins de simplification (c&apos;est-à-dire qu&apos;il est supposé que le transfert est international).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Service d&apos;envoi de fonds. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Désigne un service permettant aux utilisateurs d&apos;envoyer et/ou de recevoir des fonds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fournisseur de services de transfert de fonds (FSTF). &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Désigne une entité opérant en tant qu&apos;entreprise et fournissant un service payant d&apos;envoi de fonds, soit directement, soit par l&apos;intermédiaire d&apos;agents. Il s&apos;agit à la fois de banques et d&apos;opérateurs de transfert de fonds, tels que définis ci-dessous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Opérateur de transfert de fonds (OTF). &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Désigne un service d&apos;envoi de fonds sans dépôt où l&apos;expéditeur transfère des fonds pour un envoi (ou une série d&apos;envois) au prestataire de services (par exemple, en espèces ou par virement bancaire) &amp;#x2013; contrairement à une situation où le prestataire de services débite un compte détenu par l&apos;expéditeur. Les OTF incluent les acteurs traditionnels axés sur la remise de fonds en espèces et des acteurs innovants adoptant une variété de modèles pour la complétion des transferts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Prix. &lt;/strong&gt;Coût total pour les utilisateurs de l&apos;envoi d&apos;un virement (y compris les frais facturés à l&apos;expéditeur et la différence entre le taux de change facturé et le taux de change interbancaire courant).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Задача состоит из двух компонентов. Первый компонент заключается в том, что операционные затраты, связанные с переводом мигрантами денежных средств, должны составить 3% или менее к 2030 году. Эти операционные затраты должны рассматриваться как Глобальные средние общие затраты на перевод 200 долларов (или эквивалентной суммы в местной валюте отправки) и выражаться в процентах от отправленной суммы. Этот показатель легко доступен и публикуется Всемирным банком на ежеквартальной основе в базе данных Remittance Prices Worldwide (Мировые цены на денежные переводы), которая охватывает 365 страновых коридоров из 48 стран-отправителей в 105 стран-получателей. Вторым компонентом является процесс ликвидации коридора, где стоимость составляет 5% или больше. Это следует понимать в том смысле, что отправители денежных переводов должны иметь возможность отправлять деньги получателю по средней стоимости 5% или менее от отправленной суммы. Для этого должно быть достаточно того, чтобы в каждом коридоре было как минимум 3 услуги, отвечающие определенному набору требований к услугам (включая качество обслуживания, охват и т. д.), для которых средняя стоимость составляет 5% или менее.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Международный перевод.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Трансграничный платеж от человека к человеку по относительно низкой стоимости. Переводы, как правило, представляют собой периодические платежи трудящихся-мигрантов (которые ежемесячно отправляют деньги своим семьям на родину). В отчете термин &quot;перевод денежных средств&quot; используется для простоты (то есть предполагается, что перевод является международным).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Услуга денежных переводов. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Услуга, которая позволяет конечным пользователям отправлять и / или получать переводы денежных средств. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Поставщик услуг денежных переводов. &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Субъект, действующий как коммерческая структура, предоставляющий услуги по денежным переводам за определенную плату конечным пользователям либо напрямую, либо через агентов. К ним относятся как банки, так и операторы денежных переводов, как это определено ниже&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Оператор денежных переводов. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;Поставщик услуг денежных переводов, не осуществляющий депонирования, когда услуга включает в себя плату за перевод (или, возможно, плату за набор или серию переводов) отправителя поставщику услуг денежных переводов (например, наличными или банковским переводом), то есть в отличие от ситуации, когда поставщик услуг денежных переводов списывает средства со счета, принадлежащего отправителю у поставщика услуг денежных переводов. Операторы денежных переводов могут включать в себя как традиционных игроков, ориентированных на доставку средств наличными, так и инновационных игроков, которые могут использовать различные бизнес-модели для осуществления транзакций. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Стоимость. &lt;/strong&gt;Общая стоимость отправки перевода для конечных пользователей (в том числе комиссионные, взимаемые с отправителя, и маржа, на которую обменный курс, взимаемый с конечных пользователей, выше текущего межбанковского обменного курса).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
