<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 3-7-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The adolescent birth rate is computed as a ratio. The numerator is the number of live births to women aged 15-19 years, and the denominator an estimate of exposure to childbearing by women aged 15-19 years. The computation is the same for the age group 10-14 years. The numerator and the denominator are calculated differently for civil registration, survey and census data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computation formula: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adolescent Birth Rate (15-19) = (number of births to women ages 15-19/mid-year population of women ages 15-19) * 1,000&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of civil registration data, the numerator is the registered number of live births born to women aged 15-19 years during a given year, and the denominator is the estimated or enumerated population of women aged 15-19 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of survey data, the numerator is the number of live births obtained from retrospective birth histories of the interviewed women who were 15-19 years of age at the time of the births during a reference period before the interview, and the denominator is person-years lived between the ages of 15 and 19 years by the interviewed women during the same reference period. The reported observation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;year corresponds to the middle of the reference period. For some surveys without data on retrospective birth histories, computation of the adolescent birth rate is based on the date of last birth or the number of births in the 12 months preceding the survey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With census data, the adolescent birth rate is computed on the basis of the date of last birth or the number of births in the 12 months preceding the enumeration. The census provides both the numerator and the denominator for the rates. In some cases, the rates based on censuses are adjusted for under- registration based on indirect methods of estimation. For some countries with no other reliable data, the own-children method of indirect estimation provides estimates of the adolescent birth rate for a number of years before the census.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever data are available, adolescent fertility at ages 10-14 years are also computed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a thorough treatment of the different methods of computation, see Handbook on the Collection of Fertility and Mortality Data, United Nations Publication, Sales No. E.03.XVII.11, &lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/SeriesF/SeriesF_92E.pdf)&quot;&gt;(https://unstats.un.org/unsd/demographic/standmeth/handbooks/Handbook_Fertility_Mortality.pdf).&lt;/a&gt;.Indirect methods of estimation are analyzed in Manual X: Indirect Techniques for Demographic Estimation, United Nations Publication, Sales No. E.83.XIII.2. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La tasa de natalidad en adolescentes se calcula como un ratio. El numerador es el número de nacidos vivos de mujeres de 15 a 19 años, y el denominador una estimación de la exposición a la maternidad de las mujeres de 15 a 19 años. El cálculo es el mismo para el grupo de edad de 10 a 14 años. El numerador y el denominador se calculan de forma diferente para los datos del registro civil, encuestas y censos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En el caso de los datos de registro civil, el numerador es el número registrado de nacidos vivos de mujeres de 15 a 19 años durante un año determinado, y el denominador es la población estimada o enumerada de mujeres de 15 a 19 años.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En el caso de los datos de encuestas, el numerador es el número de nacidos vivos obtenido a partir de las historias de nacimiento retrospectivas de las mujeres entrevistadas que tenían entre 15 y 19 años en el momento de los nacimientos durante un período de referencia anterior a la entrevista, y el denominador son los años-persona vividos entre las edades de 15 y 19 años por las mujeres entrevistadas durante el mismo período de referencia. El año de observación comunicado corresponde a la mitad del periodo de referencia. En el caso de algunas encuestas que no cuentan con datos sobre la historia de los nacimientos retrospectivos, el cálculo de la tasa de natalidad de las adolescentes se basa en la fecha del último nacimiento o en el número de nacimientos en los 12 meses anteriores a la encuesta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Con los datos del censo, la tasa de natalidad en adolescentes se calcula sobre la base de la fecha del último nacimiento o el número de nacimientos en los 12 meses anteriores a la enumeración. El censo proporciona tanto el numerador como el denominador de las tasas. En algunos casos, las tasas basadas en los censos se ajustan para tener en cuenta el subregistro basado en métodos indirectos de estimación. En algunos países que no disponen de otros datos fiables, el método de estimación indirecta de los hijos propios proporciona estimaciones de la tasa de natalidad de las adolescentes durante varios años antes del censo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Si se dispone de datos, también se puede calcular la fecundidad de las adolescentes de 10 a 14 años.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para un tratamiento exhaustivo de los diferentes métodos de cálculo, véase &lt;em&gt;Manual sobre la recolección de Datos de Fertilidad y Mortalidad, Publicación de Naciones Unidas, Núm. de Ventas E.03.XVII.11&lt;/em&gt; (accesible públicamente en &lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/SeriesF/SeriesF_92E.pdf%20&quot;&gt;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/SeriesF/SeriesF_92E.pdf&lt;/a&gt;). Los métodos indirectos de estimación se analizan en &lt;em&gt;Manual X: Técnicas indirectas de estimación demográfica, Publicación de las Naciones Unidas, Nº de venta E.83.XIII.2 &lt;/em&gt;(accesible públicamente en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.un.org/esa/population/publications/Manual_X/Manual_X.htmpdf&quot;&gt;http://www.un.org/esa/population/publications/Manual_X/Manual_X.pdf&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Le taux de natalité chez les adolescentes est calculé sous forme de ratio. Le numérateur est le nombre de naissances vivantes chez les femmes âgées de 15 à 19 ans et le dénominateur, une estimation de l’exposition à la maternité par les femmes âgées de 15 à 19 ans. Le calcul est le même pour le groupe d’âge 10-14 ans. Le numérateur et le dénominateur sont calculés différemment pour les données de l’état civil, d’enquête et de recensement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Formule de calcul : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taux de natalité chez les adolescentes (15-19 ans) = (nombre de naissances chez les femmes âgées de 15 à 19 ans / population de femmes de 15 à 19 ans en milieu d’année) * 1 000 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dans le cas des données de l’état civil, le numérateur est le nombre enregistré de naissances vivantes nées de femmes âgées de 15 à 19 ans au cours d’une année donnée, et le dénominateur est la population estimée ou dénombrée de femmes âgées de 15 à 19 ans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dans le cas des données d’enquête, le numérateur est le nombre de naissances vivantes obtenues à partir des antécédents de naissance rétrospectifs des femmes interrogées qui étaient âgées de 15 à 19 ans au moment de la naissance au cours d’une période de référence avant l’entrevue, et le dénominateur représente les années-personnes vécues entre 15 et 19 ans par les femmes interrogées au cours de la même période de référence. L’année déclarée correspond au milieu de la période de référence. Pour certaines enquêtes sans données rétrospectives sur les antécédents de naissance, le calcul du taux de natalité chez les adolescentes est basé sur la date de la dernière naissance ou le nombre de naissances au cours des 12 mois précédant l’enquête. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avec les données du recensement, le taux de natalité chez les adolescentes est calculé sur la base de la date de la dernière naissance ou du nombre de naissances au cours des 12 mois précédant le dénombrement. Le recensement fournit à la fois le numérateur et le dénominateur des taux. Dans certains cas, les taux fondés sur les recensements sont ajustés pour tenir compte de la sous-couverture en utilisant des méthodes d’estimation indirectes. Pour certains pays qui n’ont pas d’autres données fiables, la méthode d’estimation indirecte des propres enfants fournit des estimations du taux de natalité chez les adolescentes pendant un certain nombre d’années avant le recensement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chaque fois que des données sont disponibles, la fécondité des adolescentes âgées de 10 à 14 ans peut également être calculée. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour un traitement approfondi des différentes méthodes de calcul, consulter le Manuel de collecte de données sur la fécondité et la mortalité, Publication des Nations Unies, Numéro de vente : F.03.XVII.11, (&lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/demographic-social/Standards-and-Methods/files/Handbooks/fertility-and-mortality/SeriesF_92-F.pdf&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/demographic-social/Standards-and-Methods/files/Handbooks/fertility-and-mortality/SeriesF_92-F.pdf&lt;/a&gt;). Les méthodes indirectes d’estimation sont analysées dans le document (en anglais) « Manual X: Indirect Techniques for Demographic Estimation », Publication des Nations Unies, Numéro de vente : E.83.XIII.2. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.un.org/en/development/desa/population/publications/pdf/mortality/Manual_X.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.un.org/en/development/desa/population/publications/pdf/mortality/Manual_X.pdf&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Коэффициент подростковой рождаемости рассчитывается в виде соотношения. В числителе указывается количество живорождений у девушек-подростков в возрасте 15-19 лет, а в знаменателе - оценка общего числа деторождений девушками-подростками в возрасте 15-19 лет. Такой же расчет производится для возрастной группы 10-14 лет. Числитель и знаменатель рассчитываются по-разному для данных регистрации актов гражданского состояния, обследований домохозяйств и переписи населения. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Если используются данные регистрации актов гражданского состояния, то числителем является учтенное число живорожденных от девушек-подростков в возрасте 15–19 лет в течение данного года, а знаменатель - это оценочное или наличное количество девушек-подростков в возрасте 15–19 лет. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Если используются данные обследования домохозяйств, то числитель - это число живорождений, полученное из ретроспективных историй рождений опрошенных женщин, которым было 15-19 лет на момент родов, которые произошли в течение отчетного периода, предшествующего обследованию, и знаменатель - это человеко-годы, прожитые опрошенными девушками-подростками в возрасте от 15 до 19 лет в течение того же отчетного периода. Год регистрации наблюдений соответствует срединной точке отчетного периода. Для некоторых обследований, в которых отсутствуют данные по ретроспективным историям рождений, расчет подростковой рождаемости основывается на дате последних родов или числе рождений за 12 месяцев, предшествующих обследованию.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;При использовании данных переписи населения расчет коэффициента подростковой рождаемости основывается на дате последних родов или числе рождений за 12 месяцев, предшествующих переписи населения. Информация, полученная в ходе переписи населения, используется как в числителе, так и в знаменателе при расчете коэффициентов. В некоторых случаях коэффициенты, основанные на данных переписи населения, корректируются с учетом неполной регистрации на основе косвенных методов оценки. Для некоторых стран, в которых нет других надежных данных, косвенная оценка повозрастных коэффициентов рождаемости с использованием метода &quot;собственные дети&quot; позволяет оценить уровень подростковой рождаемости за многолетний период, предшествующий переписи. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Если есть данные, можно также рассчитать подростковую фертильность в возрасте 10–14 лет. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Подробное описание различных методов расчета см. в &lt;em&gt; Справочнике по сбору данных по фертильности и смертности, публикация Организации Объединенных Наций, в продаже под № E.03.XVII.11 &lt;/em&gt; (общедоступно по адресу: &lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/SeriesF/SeriesF_92E.pdf%20&quot;&gt; http://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/SeriesF/SeriesF_92E.pdf&lt;/a &gt;). Косвенные методы оценки анализируются в &lt;em&gt; Руководстве X: Косвенные методы демографической оценки, Публикация Организации Объединенных Наций, в продаже под № E.83.XIII.2 &lt;/em&gt; (общедоступно по адресу &lt;a href = &quot;http: // www.un.org/esa/population/publications/Manual_X/Manual_X.htmpdf&quot;&gt;http://www.un.org/esa/population/publications/Manual_X/Manual_X.pdf)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
