<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 3-7-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; At country level&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no attempt to provide estimates for individual countries or areas when country or area data are not available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; At regional and global levels&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The regional or global aggregates of the adolescent birth rate for the age group 15-19 years are from the latest revision of World Population Prospects produced by the Population Division. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In cases when data are missing or assessed as unreliable, estimates for individual countries or areas are generated either through expert-based opinion reviewing and weighting each observation analytically, or, in more recent years, using automated statistical methods, or by using a bias- adjusted data model to control for systematic biases between different types of data. See United Nations, Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division (2019). World Population Prospects 2019: Methodology of the United Nations population estimates and projections (ST/ESA/SER.A/425), available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://population.un.org/wpp/Publications/Files/WPP2019_Methodology.pdf&quot;&gt;https://population.un.org/wpp/Publications/Files/WPP2019_Methodology.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel de país:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No se intenta proporcionar estimaciones para países o zonas individuales cuando no se dispone de datos de países o zonas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel regional y mundial:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los agregados regionales o mundiales de la tasa de natalidad en adolescentes para el grupo de edad de 15 a 19 años proceden de la última revisión de las Perspectivas de la Población Mundial elaborada por la División de Población de las Naciones Unidas. En los casos en los que faltan datos o se consideran poco fiables, las estimaciones para los distintos países o zonas se generan mediante la opinión de expertos, revisando y ponderando cada observación de forma analítica o, en los años más recientes, utilizando métodos estadísticos automatizados, o utilizando un modelo de datos ajustado al sesgo para controlar los sesgos sistemáticos entre los distintos tipos de datos. Véase Naciones Unidas, Departamento de Asuntos Económicos y Sociales, División de Población (2019). Perspectivas de la población mundial 2019: Revisión, Metodología de las estimaciones y proyecciones de población de las Naciones Unidas, (ST/ESA/SER.A/425), disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;https://population.un.org/wpp/Publications/Files/WPP2019_Methodology.pdf&quot;&gt;https://population.un.org/wpp/Publications/Files/WPP2019_Methodology.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;· Au niveau national&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il n’y a aucune tentative de fournir des estimations pour des pays ou des zones individuels lorsque les données de pays ou de zones ne sont pas disponibles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· Aux niveaux régional et mondial&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les agrégats régionaux ou mondiaux du taux de natalité chez les adolescentes pour le groupe d’âge des 15-19 ans proviennent de la dernière révision des Perspectives de la population mondiale produite par la Division de la population. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dans les cas où les données sont manquantes ou jugées peu fiables, des estimations pour des pays ou des régions individuels sont générées soit par l’examen et la pondération analytiques de chaque observation par des experts, soit, au cours des dernières années, à l’aide de méthodes statistiques automatisées, soit en utilisant un modèle de données ajusté pour le biais pour contrôler les biais systématiques entre différents types de données. Consulter le document (en anglais) : Nations Unies, Département des affaires économiques et sociales, Division de la population (2019). « World Population Prospects 2019: Methodology of the United Nations population estimates and projections » (ST/ESA/SER. A/425), disponible à l’adresse suivante : &lt;a href=&quot;https://population.un.org/wpp/Publications/Files/WPP2019_Methodology.pdf&quot;&gt;https://population.un.org/wpp/Publications/Files/WPP2019_Methodology.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Не предпринимается попыток предоставить оценки для отдельных стран или территорий, если данные по стране или территории недоступны. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Региональные или глобальные агрегированные показатели подростковой рождаемости в возрастной группе 15-19 лет взяты из последней редакции &quot;Мировые демографические перспективы&quot;, подготовленной Отделом народонаселения. Учитывая случаи, когда данные отсутствуют или оцениваются как ненадежные, оценки для отдельных стран или территорий генерируются либо на основе экспертного мнения, аналитического обзора и взвешивания каждого наблюдения, либо, в более поздние годы, с использованием автоматизированных статистических методов, либо с использованием модели данных, скорректированных на смещение, для контроля систематических смещений между различными типами данных. См. Организация Объединенных Наций, Департамент по экономическим и социальным вопросам, Отдел народонаселения (2019 год). Мировые демографические перспективы за 2019 год: Пересмотр, методология оценок и прогнозов ООН в области народонаселения (ST/ESA/SER.A/425), доступно по адресу &lt;a href=&quot;https://population.un.org/wpp/Publications/Files/WPP2019_Methodology.pdf&quot;&gt;https://population.un.org/wpp/Publications/Files/WPP2019_Methodology.pdf.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
