<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 3-7-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Traitement des valeurs manquantes :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Au niveau national&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aucune estimation n&apos;est calculée lorsque les données ne sont pas disponibles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aux niveaux régional et mondial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les agrégats régionaux et mondiaux du taux de natalité des adolescentes pour le groupe d&apos;âge 15 à 19 ans proviennent de la dernière version des Perspectives de la population mondiale (WPP) produite par la Division de la population de l’ONU. Pour les cas où les données ne sont pas disponibles ou de bonne qualité, des estimations sont produites soit en consultant des experts et en ajustant le poids des différentes observations, soit en utilisant un modèle permettant de contrôler les biais systématiques des différentes types de données. Pour plus de détails, il est possible de consulter DSÉA, Division de la population (2019). World Population Prospects 2019: Methodology of the United Nations population estimates and projections (ST/ESA/SER.A/425), disponible à :   &lt;a href=&quot;https://population.un.org/wpp/Publications/Files/WPP2017_Methodology.pdf&quot;&gt;https://population.un.org/wpp/Publications/Files/WPP2017_Methodology.pdf&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Treatment of missing values:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At country level:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no attempt to provide estimates for individual countries or areas when country or area data are not available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At regional and global levels:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The regional or global aggregates of the adolescent birth rate for the age group 15-19 years are from the latest revision of World Population Prospects (WPP) produced by the Population Division. In cases where data reviewing and weighting each observation analytically, or, in more recent years, using automated statistical methods, or by using a bias-adjusted data model to control for systematic biases between different types of data. See United Nations, Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division (2017). World Population Prospects: The 2017 Revision, Methodology of the United Nations Population Estimates and Projections, Working Paper No. ESA/P/WP.250 (publicly accessible at &lt;a href=&quot;https://esa.un.org/unpd/wpp/Publications/Files/WPP2017_Methodology.pdf&quot;&gt;https://esa.un.org/unpd/wpp/Publications/Files/WPP2017_Methodology.pdf&lt;/a&gt;).are missing or assessed as unreliable, estimates for individual countries or areas are generated either through expert-based opinion, &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
