<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 3-8-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The mechanisms for collecting data from countries vary across the 14 tracer indicators, however in many cases a UN agency or interagency group has assembled and analysed relevant national data sources and then conducted a formal country consultation with country governments to review or produce comparable country estimates. For the UHC service coverage index, once this existing information on the 14 tracer indicators is collated, WHO conducts a country consultation with nominated focal points from national governments to review inputs and the calculation of the index. WHO does not undertake new estimation activities to produce tracer indicator values for the service coverage index; rather, the index is designed to make use of existing and well-established indicator data series to reduce reporting burden. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Proceso de recolección:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los mecanismos de recolección de datos de los países varían en función de los 14 indicadores trazadores; sin embargo, en muchos casos, un organismo de las Naciones Unidas o un grupo interinstitucional ha reunido y analizado las fuentes de datos nacionales pertinentes y, a continuación, ha llevado a cabo una consulta formal con los gobiernos de los países para revisar o producir estimaciones nacionales comparables. Para el índice de cobertura de servicios de la CSU, una vez que se ha cotejado esta información existente sobre los 14 indicadores de seguimiento, la OMS lleva a cabo una consulta por país con los puntos focales designados por los gobiernos nacionales para revisar las aportaciones y el cálculo del índice. La OMS no lleva a cabo nuevas actividades de estimación para producir valores de indicadores trazadores para el índice de cobertura de servicios; más bien, el índice está diseñado para hacer uso de series de datos de indicadores existentes y bien establecidos para reducir la carga de notificación.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Les mécanismes de collecte de données auprès des pays varient d’un pays à l’autre, mais dans de nombreux cas, une agence des Nations Unies ou un groupe interinstitutions a rassemblé et analysé des sources de données nationales pertinentes, puis a mené une consultation officielle auprès des gouvernements nationaux pour examiner ou produire des estimations comparables par pays. Pour l’indice de couverture des services de santé, une fois que ces informations existantes sur les 14 indicateurs traceurs sont rassemblées, l’OMS mène une consultation nationale avec les points focaux proposés par les gouvernements nationaux pour examiner les intrants et le calcul de l’indice. L’OMS n’entreprend pas de nouvelles activités d’estimation pour produire des valeurs d’indicateurs traceurs pour l’indice de couverture des services; l’indice est plutôt conçu pour utiliser les séries de données d’indicateurs existantes et bien établies afin de réduire le fardeau de déclaration. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Механизмы сбора страновых данных различаются по всем 14 контрольным показателям, однако во многих случаях агентство ООН или межведомственная группа подбирают и анализируют соответствующие национальные источники данных, а затем проводят официальные страновые консультации с правительственными органами стран для проверки или получения сопоставимых оценок по стране. Что касается индекса охвата услугами ВОУЗ, то после сопоставления существующей информации по 14 показателям Всемирная организация здравоохранения проводит страновые консультации с назначенными координаторами от национальных правительственных органов для анализа исходных данных и расчета индекса. ВОЗ не предпринимает новых оценочных мероприятий для получения значений контрольных показателей для индекса охвата услугами; скорее, индекс разработан для использования существующих и хорошо зарекомендовавших себя рядов данных по показателям с целью снижения бремени отчетности. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
