<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The OTHER_DOC field for indicator 3-8-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2017/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2017/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thelancet.com/pdfs/journals/langlo/PIIS2214-109X(17)30472-2.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.thelancet.com/pdfs/journals/langlo/PIIS2214-109X(17)30472-2.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For historical development of methods, see:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/UHC_WHS2016_TechnicalNote_May2016.pdf?ua=1&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/UHC_WHS2016_TechnicalNote_May2016.pdf?ua=1&lt;/a&gt; (superseded by this document)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2015/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2015/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2014/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2014/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/uhc2014&quot;&gt;http://collections.plos.org/uhc2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Annex 1: Metadata for tracer indicators used to measure the coverage of essential health services for monitoring SDG indicator 3.8.1.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please send any comments or queries to: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:uhc_stats@who.int&quot;&gt;uhc_stats@who.int&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tracer area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Family planning&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indicator definition&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Percentage of women of reproductive age (15&amp;#x2212;49 years) who are married or in-union who have their need for family planning satisfied with modern methods.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Numerator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Number of women aged 15-49 who are married or in-union who use modern methods&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Denominator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Total number of women aged 15-49 who are married or in-union in need of family planning&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Main data sources&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Population-based health surveys&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of measurement&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Household surveys include a series of questions to measure modern contraceptive prevalence rate and demand for family planning. Total demand for family planning is defined as the sum of the number of women of reproductive age (15&amp;#x2013;49 years) who are married or in a union and who are currently using, or whose sexual partner is currently using, at least one contraceptive method, and the unmet need for family planning. Unmet need for family planning is the proportion of women of reproductive age (15&amp;#x2013;49 years) either married or in a consensual union, who are fecund and sexually active but who are not using any method of contraception (modern or traditional), and report not wanting any more children or wanting to delay the birth of their next child for at least two years. Included are:&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;all pregnant women (married or in a consensual union) whose pregnancies were unwanted or mistimed at the time of conception;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;all postpartum amenorrhoeic women (married or in consensual union) who are not using family planning and whose last birth was unwanted or mistimed;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;all fecund women (married or in consensual union) who are neither pregnant nor postpartum amenorrhoeic, and who either do not want any more children (want to limit family size), or who wish to postpone the birth of a child for at least two years or do not know when or if they want another child (want to space births), but are not using any contraceptive method.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Modern methods include female and male sterilization, the intra-uterine device (IUD), the implant, injectables, oral contraceptive pills, male and female condoms, vaginal barrier methods (including the diaphragm, cervical cap and spermicidal foam, jelly, cream and sponge), lactational amenorrhea method (LAM), emergency contraception and other modern methods not reported separately.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of estimation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The United Nations Population Division produces a systematic and comprehensive series of annual estimates and projections of the percentage of demand for family planning that is satisfied among married or in-union women. A Bayesian hierarchical model combined with country-specific data are used to generate the estimates, projections and uncertainty assessments from survey data. The model accounts for differences by data source, sample population, and contraceptive methods. &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;See here for details: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.un.org/en/development/desa/population/theme/family-planning/cp_model.shtml&quot;&gt;http://www.un.org/en/development/desa/population/theme/family-planning/cp_model.shtml&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;UHC-related notes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tracer area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Pregnancy and delivery care&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indicator definition&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Percentage of women aged 15-49 years with a live birth in a given time period who received antenatal care four or more times &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Numerator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Number of women aged 15&amp;#x2212;49 years with a live birth in a given time period who received antenatal care four or more times&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Denominator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Total number of women aged 15&amp;#x2212;49 years with a live birth in the same period.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Main data sources&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Household surveys and routine facility information systems.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of measurement&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Data on four or more antenatal care visits is based on questions that ask if and how many times the health of the woman was checked during pregnancy. Household surveys that can generate this indicator include DHS, MICS, RHS and other surveys based on similar methodologies. Service/facility reporting systems can be used where the coverage is high, usually in higher income countries.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of estimation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;WHO maintains a data base on coverage of antenatal care: &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.ANTENATALCARECOVERAGE4&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.ANTENATALCARECOVERAGE4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;UHC-related notes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Ideally this indicator would be replaced with a more comprehensive measure of pregnancy and delivery care, for example the proportion of women who have a skilled provider attend the birth or an institutional delivery. A challenge in measuring skilled attendance at birth is determining which providers are &amp;#x201C;skilled&amp;#x201D;. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tracer area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Child immunization&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indicator definition&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Percentage of infants receiving three doses of diphtheria-tetanus-pertussis containing vaccine&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Numerator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Children 1 year of age who have received three doses of diphtheria-tetanus-pertussis containing vaccine&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Denominator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;All children 1 year of age&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Main data sources&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Household surveys and facility information systems.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of measurement&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;For survey data, the vaccination status of children aged 12&amp;#x2013;23 months is collected from child health cards or, if there is no card, from recall by the care-taker. For administrative data, the total number of doses administered to the target population is extracted.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of estimation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Together, WHO and UNICEF derive estimates of DTP3 coverage based on data officially reported to WHO and UNICEF by Member States, as well as data reported in the published and grey literature. They also consult with local experts - primarily national EPI managers and WHO regional office staff - for additional information regarding the performance of specific local immunization services. Based on the available data, consideration of potential biases, and contributions from local experts, WHO/UNICEF determine the most likely true level of immunization coverage. &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;For details, see here: &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/bulletin/volumes/87/7/08-053819/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/bulletin/volumes/87/7/08-053819/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/immunization/monitoring_surveillance/routine/coverage/en/index4.html&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/immunization/monitoring_surveillance/routine/coverage/en/index4.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;UHC-related notes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;There is variability in national vaccine schedules across countries. Given this, one option for monitoring full child immunization is to monitor the fraction of children receiving vaccines included in their country&amp;#x2019;s national schedule. A second option, which may be more comparable across countries and time, is to monitor DTP3 coverage as a proxy for full child immunization. Diphtheria-tetanus-pertussis containing vaccine often includes other vaccines, e.g., against Hepatitis B and Haemophilus influenza type B, and is a reasonable measure of the extent to which there is a robust vaccine delivery platform within a country. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tracer area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Child treatment (care-seeking for symptoms of pneumonia)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indicator definition&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Percentage of children under 5 years of age with suspected pneumonia (cough and difficult breathing NOT due to a problem in the chest and a blocked nose) in the two weeks preceding the survey taken to an appropriate health facility or provider.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Numerator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Number of children with suspected pneumonia in the two weeks preceding the survey taken to an appropriate health provider.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Denominator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Number of children with suspected pneumonia in the two weeks preceding the survey.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Main data sources&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Household surveys&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of measurement&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;During the UNICEF/WHO Meeting on Child Survival Survey-based Indicators, held in New York, 17&amp;#x2013;18 June 2004, it was recommended that acute respiratory infections (ARI) be described as &amp;#x201C;presumed pneumonia&amp;#x201D; to better reflect probable cause and the recommended interventions. The definition of presumed pneumonia used in the Demographic and Health Surveys (DHS) and in the Multiple Indicator Cluster Surveys (MICS) was chosen by the group and is based on mothers&amp;#x2019; perceptions of a child who has a cough, is breathing faster than usual with short, quick breaths or is having difficulty breathing, excluding children that had only a blocked nose. The definition of &amp;#x201C;appropriate&amp;#x201D; care provider varies between countries.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;WHO maintains a data base of country-level observations from household surveys that can be accessed here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.38?lang=en&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.38?lang=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of estimation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;There are currently no internationally comparable estimates for this indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;UHC-related notes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;This indicator is not typically measured in higher income countries with well-established health systems. &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;For countries without observed data, coverage was estimated from a regression that predicts coverage of care-seeking for symptoms of pneumonia (on the logit scale), obtained from the WHO data base described above, as a function of the log of the estimated under-five pneumonia mortality rate, which can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/healthinfo/global_burden_disease/estimates/en/index2.html&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/healthinfo/global_burden_disease/estimates/en/index2.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tracer area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tuberculosis treatment&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indicator definition&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Percentage of incidence TB cases that are detected and successfully treated in a given year&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Numerator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Number of new and relapse cases detected in a given year and successfully treated&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Denominator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Number of new and relapse cases in the same year&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Main data sources&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Facility information systems, surveillance systems, population-based health surveys with TB diagnostic testing, TB register and related quarterly reporting system (or electronic TB registers)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of measurement&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;This indicator requires three main inputs:&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;(1) The number of new and relapse TB cases diagnosed and treated in national TB control programmes and notified to WHO in a given year.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;(2) The number of incident TB cases for the same year, typically estimated by WHO.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;(3) Percentage of TB cases successfully treated (cured plus treatment completed) among TB cases notified to the national health authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The final indicator = (1)/(2) x (3)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of estimation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Estimates of TB incidence are produced through a consultative and analytical process led by WHO and are published annually. These estimates are based on annual case notifications, assessments of the quality and coverage of TB notification data, national surveys of the prevalence of TB disease and information from death (vital) registration systems. Estimates of incidence for each country are derived, using one or more of the following approaches depending on available data:&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;1. incidence = case notifications/estimated proportion of cases detected;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;2. incidence = prevalence/duration of condition;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;3. incidence = deaths/proportion of incident cases that die. &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;These estimates of TB incidence are combined with country-reported data on the number of cases detected and treated, and the percentage of cases successfully treated, as described above.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;UHC-related notes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;To compute the indicator using WHO estimates, one can access necessary files here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/tb/country/data/download/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/tb/country/data/download/en/&lt;/a&gt;, and compute the indicator as = c_cdr x c_new_tsr&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tracer area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;HIV treatment&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indicator definition&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Percentage of people living with HIV currently receiving antiretroviral therapy (ART)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Numerator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Number of adults and children who are currently receiving ART at the end of the reporting period&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Denominator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Number of adults and children living with HIV during the same period&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Main data sources&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Facility reporting systems, sentinel surveillance sites, population-based surveys&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of measurement&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Numerator: The numerator can be generated by counting the number of adults and children who received antiretroviral combination therapy at the end of the reporting period. Data can be collected from facility-based ART registers or drug supply management systems. These are then tallied and transferred to cross sectional monthly or quarterly reports which can then be aggregated for national totals. Patients receiving ART in the private sector and public sector should be included in the numerator.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Denominator: Data on the number of people with HIV infection may come from population-based surveys or, as is common in sub-Saharan Africa, surveillance systems based on antenatal care clinics.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of estimation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Estimates of antiretroviral treatment coverage among people living with HIV for 2000-2018 are derived as part of the 2019 UNAIDS&amp;apos; estimation round. &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;To estimate the number of people living with HIV across time in high burden countries, UNAIDS in collaboration with countries uses an epidemic model (Spectrum) that combines surveillance data on prevalence with the current number of patients receiving ART and assumptions about the natural history of HIV disease progression. &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Since ART is now recommended for all individuals living with HIV, monitoring ART coverage is less complicated than before, when only those with a certain level of disease severity were eligible to receive ART.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Estimates of ART coverage can be found here: http://aidsinfo.unaids.org/&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;UHC-related notes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Comparable estimates of ART coverage in high income countries, in particular time trends, are not always available.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tracer area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Malaria prevention&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indicator definition&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Percentage of population in malaria-endemic areas who slept under an ITN the previous night.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Numerator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Number of people in malaria-endemic areas who slept under an ITN.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Denominator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Total number of people in malaria endemic areas.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Main data sources&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Data on household access and use of ITNs come from nationally representative household surveys such as Demographic and Health Surveys, Multiple Indicator Cluster Surveys, and Malaria Indicator Surveys. Data on the number of ITNs delivered by manufacturers to countries are compiled by Milliner Global Associates, and data on the number of ITNs distributed within countries are reported by National Malaria Control Programs.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of measurement&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Many recent national surveys report the number of ITNs observed in each respondent household. Ownership rates can be converted to the proportion of people sleeping under an ITN using a linear relationship between access and use that has been derived from 62 surveys that collect information on both indicators. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of estimation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Mathematical models can be used to combine data from household surveys on access and use with information on ITN deliveries from manufacturers and ITN distribution by national malaria programmes to produce annual estimates of ITN coverage. WHO uses this approach in collaboration with the Malaria Atlas Project. Methodological details can be found in the Annex of the World Malaria Report 2015: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/malaria/publications/world-malaria-report-2015/report/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/malaria/publications/world-malaria-report-2015/report/en/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;UHC-related notes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;WHO produces comparable ITN coverage estimates for 40 high burden countries. For other countries, ITN coverage is not included in the UHC service coverage index due to data limitations. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tracer area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Water and sanitation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indicator definition&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Percentage of households using at least basic sanitation facilities&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Numerator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Population living in a household with: flush or pour-flush to piped sewer system, septic tank or pit latrine; ventilated improved pit latrine; pit latrine with slab; or composting toilet.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Denominator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Total population&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Main data sources&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Population-based household surveys and censuses&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of measurement&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Household-level responses, weighted by household size, are used to compute population coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of estimation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The WHO/UNICEF Joint Monitoring Programme has produced regular estimates of coverage of at least basic sanitation for MDG monitoring. After compiling a database of available data sources, for each country, simple linear regressions are fitted to the country&amp;#x2019;s data series to obtain an in-sample estimate, as well as to produce a 2-year extrapolation beyond the last available data point, after which coverage is held constant for 4 years and then assumed missing. This is done separately for urban and rural regions, and then combined to obtain national coverage estimates. Details of the methodology and most recent estimates can be found here: http://www.wssinfo.org/&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;UHC-related notes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The SDG indicator for sanitation (SDG 6.2.1) is an expanded version of the MDG indicator, incorporating the quality of sanitation facilities. It is not for UHC monitoring due to lower data availability. A joint indicator that identifies the proportion of households with access to both safe water and sanitation could also be considered.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tracer area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Prevention of cardiovascular disease&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indicator definition&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Age-standardized prevalence of normal blood pressure among adults aged 18+, regardless of treatment status&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Numerator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Number of adults aged 18 or older with systolic blood pressure &amp;lt;140 mm Hg and diastolic blood pressure &amp;lt;90 mm Hg (regardless of treatment status)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Denominator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Number of adults aged 18 or older&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Main data sources&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Population-based surveys and surveillance systems&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of measurement&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Data sources recording measured blood pressure are used (self-reported data are excluded).&amp;#xA0;If multiple blood pressure readings are taken per participant, the first reading is dropped and the remaining readings are averaged.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of estimation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;For producing comparable national estimates, data observations of prevalence defined in terms of alternate SBP and/or DBP cutoffs are converted into prevalence of raised blood pressure, defined as systolic blood pressure &amp;gt;=140 mm Hg or diastolic blood pressure &amp;gt;=90 mm Hg using regression equations. A Bayesian hierarchical model is then fitted to these data to calculate age-sex-year-country specific prevalences, which accounts for national vs. subnational data sources, urban vs. rural data sources, and allows for variation in prevalence across age and sex. Age-standardized estimates are then produced by applying the crude estimates to the WHO Standard Population. Details on the statistical methods are here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(16)31919-5/fulltext&quot;&gt;http://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(16)31919-5/fulltext&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;WHO and the NCD Risk Factor Collaboration (NCD-RisC) has produced comparable estimates for this indicator up through year 2015, which are available here: &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.A875STANDARD?lang=en&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.A875STANDARD?lang=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;UHC-related notes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Prevalence estimates are converted to the prevalence of normal blood pressure for incorporation into the UHC index, so that a value of 100% is the optimal target. This is computed as: normal blood pressure prevalence = 1 &amp;#x2013; raised blood pressure prevalence. The above estimates are done separately for men and women; for the UHC tracer indicator a simple average of values for men and women is computed.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Normal blood pressure is the sum of the percentage of individuals who do not have hypertension, and the percentage of individuals whose hypertension is controlled by medication. The absence of hypertension is a result of prevention efforts via promotion of physical activity and healthy diets, as well as other factors. Hypertension controlled with medication is a result of effective treatment. This indicator is thus a proxy for both effective health promotion and effective medical services. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tracer area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Management of diabetes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indicator definition&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Age-standardized mean fasting plasma glucose for adults aged 18 years and older&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Main data sources&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Population-based surveys and surveillance systems&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of measurement&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Fasting plasma glucose (FPG) levels are determined by taking a blood sample from participants who have fasted for at least 8 hours. Other related biomarkers, such as hemoglobin A1c (HbA1c), were used to help calculate estimates (see below).&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of estimation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;For producing comparable national estimates, data observations based on mean FPG, oral glucose tolerance test (OGTT), HbA1c, or combinations therein, are all converted to mean FPG. A Bayesian hierarchical model is then fitted to these data to calculate age-sex-year-country specific prevalences, which accounts for national vs. subnational data sources, urban vs. rural data sources, and allows for variation in prevalence across age and sex. Age-standardized estimates are then produced by applying the crude estimates to the WHO Standard Population. Methodological details can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/diabetes/global-report/en/&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/diabetes/global-report/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;UHC-related notes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;An individual&amp;#x2019;s FPG may be low because of effective treatment with glucose-lowering medication, or because the individual is not diabetic as a result of health promotion activities or other factors such as genetics. Mean FPG is thus a proxy for both effective promotion of healthy diets and behaviors and effective treatment of diabetes. &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The above estimates are done separately for men and women; for the UHC tracer indicator a simple average of values for men and women is computed.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tracer area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tobacco control&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indicator definition&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Age-standardized prevalence of adults &amp;gt;=15 years not smoking tobacco in last 30 days &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Numerator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Adults 15 years and older who have not smoked tobacco in the last 30 days&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Denominator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Adults 15 years and older&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Main data sources&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Household surveys&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of measurement&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&amp;#x201C;Current tobacco smoking&amp;quot; includes cigarettes, cigars, pipes or any other smoked tobacco products used in the past 30 days. Data are collected via self-report in surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of estimation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;WHO estimates prevalence of current tobacco (non) smoking with a negative binomial meta-regression model, which generates comparable estimates by adjusting for differences in age groups and indicator definition across national surveys included in the analysis. These estimates are done separately for men and women. Methodological details can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(15)60264-1/supplemental&quot;&gt;http://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(15)60264-1/supplemental&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;UHC-related notes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Prevalence of not smoking tobacco is computed as 1 minus the prevalence of tobacco smoking.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tracer area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Hospital access&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indicator definition&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Hospital beds per capita, relative to a maximum threshold of 18 per 10,000 population&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Numerator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Number of hospital beds (should exclude labor and delivery beds)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Denominator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Total population&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Main data sources&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Administrative systems / Health facility reporting system&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of measurement&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Country administrative systems are used to total the number of hospital beds, which are divided by the total estimated population, and multiplied by 10,000. &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;WHO regional offices and other groups collect information on national hospital bed density, including the following online resources:&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rho.emro.who.int/rhodata/node.main.A36&quot;&gt;https://rho.emro.who.int/rhodata/node.main.A36&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;WHO AFRO regional observatory: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aho.afro.who.int/en/data-statistics/hospital-beds-10-000-population&quot;&gt;http://www.aho.afro.who.int/en/data-statistics/hospital-beds-10-000-population&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;WHO EURO European Health for All Database: &lt;a href=&quot;https://gateway.euro.who.int/en/datasets%20european-health-for-all-database/&quot;&gt;https://gateway.euro.who.int/en/datasets european-health-for-all-database/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;OECD: &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.oecd.org/healtheqt/hospital-beds.htm&quot;&gt;https://data.oecd.org/healtheqt/hospital-beds.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of estimation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Using available data, the indicator is computed relative to a threshold value of 18 hospital beds per 10,000 population. This threshold is below the observed OECD high income country minimum (since year 2000) of 20 per 10,000 and tends to correspond to an inpatient hospital admission rate of around 5 per 100 per year. This indicator is designed to capture low levels of hospital capacity; the maximum threshold is used because very high hospital bed densities are not necessary an efficient use of resources. The indicator is computed as follows, using country data on hospital bed density (&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;), which results in values ranging from 0 to 100:&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Country with a hospital bed density &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 18 per 10,000 per year, the indicator = &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; /18*100. &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Country with a hospital bed density &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; &amp;gt;= 18 per 10,000 per year, the indicator = 100.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;UHC-related notes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;An alternative indicator could be hospital in-patient admission rate, relative to a maximum threshold. However, that indicator is currently not reported widely across regions, in particular the African Region. In countries where both hospital beds per capita and in-patient admission rates are available, they are highly correlated.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tracer area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Health workforce&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indicator definition&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Health professionals (physicians, psychiatrists, and surgeons) per capita, relative to maximum thresholds for each cadre&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Numerator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Number of physicians, psychiatrists and surgeons&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Denominator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Total population&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Main data sources&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;National database or registry of health workers, ideally coupled with regular assessment of completeness using census data, professional association registers, or facility censuses.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of measurement&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The classification of health workers is based on criteria for vocational education and training, regulation of health professions, and activities and tasks of jobs, i.e., a framework for categorizing key workforce variables according to shared characteristics. The WHO framework largely draws on the latest revisions to the internationally standardized classification systems of the International Labour Organization (International Standard Classification of Occupations), United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (International Standard Classification of Education), and the United Nations Statistics Division (International Standard Industrial Classification of All Economic Activities). &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Methodological details and data can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Data are from the following sources:&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Physicians: &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.HWFGRP_0020?lang=en&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.HWFGRP_0020?lang=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Psychiatrists: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2017/en/&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2017/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Surgeons: &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.HWF9?lang=en%20&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.HWF9?lang=en&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;(data here were supplemented by prior editions of the the database)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of estimation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Using available data, the indicator is computed by first rescaling, separately, health worker density ratios for each of the three cadres (physicians, psychiatrists and surgeons) relative to the minimum observed values across OECD countries since 2000, which are as follows: physicians = 0.9 per 1000, psychiatrists = 1 per 100,000, and surgeons = 14 per 100,000. This rescaling is done in the same way as that for the hospital bed density indicator described above, resulting in indicator values that range from 0 to 100 for each of the three cadres. For example, using country data on physicians per 1000 population (&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;), the cadre-specific indicator would be computed as:&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Country with &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.9 per 1000 per year, the cadre-specific indicator = &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; /0.9*100. &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Country with &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; &amp;gt;= 0.9 per 1000 per year, the cadre-specific indicator = 100.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;As a final step, the geometric mean of the three cadre-specific indicator values is computed to obtain the final indicator of health workforce density.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;UHC-related notes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The &amp;#x201C;physicians&amp;#x201D; category would ideally be expanded to include all &amp;#x201C;core health professionals&amp;#x201D;, such as nurses and midwives. However, no internationally comparable data base exists that uses consistent definitions of non-physician core health professionals to allow for fully accurate cross-country comparisons. &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;For countries without observed data, the density of surgeons was estimated from a regression that predicts the log of surgeons per 100,000, obtained from the WHO data base described above, as a function of the log of GDP per capita, as estimated by the World Bank.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tracer area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Health security&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indicator definition&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;International Health Regulations (IHR) core capacity index, which is the average percentage of attributes of 13 core capacities that have been attained at a specific point in time. &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The 13 core capacities are: (1) National legislation, policy and financing; (2) Coordination and National Focal Point communications; (3) Surveillance; (4) Response; (5) Preparedness; (6) Risk communication; (7) Human resources; (8) Laboratory; (9) Points of entry; (10) Zoonotic events; (11) Food safety; (12) Chemical events; (13) Radionuclear emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Numerator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Number of attributes attained&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Denominator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Total number of attributes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Main data sources&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Key informant survey&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of measurement&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Key informants report on attainment of a set of attributes for each of 13 core capacities using a standard WHO instrument, as described here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/10665/84933/1/WHO_HSE_GCR_2013.2_eng.pdf&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/10665/84933/1/WHO_HSE_GCR_2013.2_eng.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Capacity-level indicator values can be found here: &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.IHRSPARALL?lang=en&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.IHRSPARALL?lang=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method of estimation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The indicator is computed by averaging, across the 13 core capacities, the percentage of attributes for each capacity that have been attained.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;UHC-related notes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Countries began reporting IHR core capacity attainment to WHO for the year 2010. The earliest available IHR score for each country is used for all years 2000-2009.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Rfrences&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/fr/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/fr/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rfrences : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2017/fr/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2017/fr/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thelancet.com/pdfs/journals/langlo/PIIS2214-109X(17)30472-2.pdf &gt;http://www.thelancet.com/pdfs/journals/langlo/PIIS2214-109X(17)30472-2.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/fr/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/fr/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour le dveloppement historique des mthodes, voir : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/UHC_WHS2016_TechnicalNote_May2016.pdf?ua=1&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/UHC_WHS2016_TechnicalNote_May2016.pdf?ua=1&lt;/a&gt; (remplac par ce document)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2015/fr/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2015/fr/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2014/fr/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2014/fr/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/uhc2014&quot;&gt;http://collections.plos.org/uhc2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Annexe 1 : Mtadonnes pour les indicateurs traceurs utiliss pour mesurer la couverture des services de sant essentiels pour la surveillance de lindicateur des ODD 3.8.1.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please envoyer des commentaires ou des requtes  : &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:uhc_stats@who.int&quot;&gt;uhc_stats@who.int&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;tracer&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; planification familiale&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;indicateur&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Percentage des femmes en ge de procrer (15 et #x2212;49 ans) maries ou en union qui ont besoin dune planification familiale satisfaite des mthodes &lt;/p&gt; modernes.
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Numrateur&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Nombre de femmes ges de 15  49 ans maries ou en union qui utilisent des mthodes modernes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Denominator&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; nombre total de femmes ges de 15  49 ans maries ou en union qui ont besoin de planification familiale&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Principales sources de donnes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; de sant bases sur la population&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method de mesure&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;household comprennent une srie de questions visant  mesurer le taux de prvalence de la contraception moderne et la demande de planification familiale. La demande totale de planification familiale est dfinie comme la somme du nombre de femmes en ge de procrer (15 et #x2013;49 ans) qui sont maries ou en union et qui utilisent actuellement, ou dont le partenaire sexuel utilise actuellement, au moins une mthode contraceptive, et le besoin non satisfait de planification familiale. Le besoin non satisfait de planification familiale est la proportion de femmes en ge de procrer (15 et #x2013;49 ans) maries ou en union consensuelle, qui sont fcondes et sexuellement actives mais qui nutilisent aucune mthode de contraception (moderne ou traditionnelle), et qui dclarent ne plus vouloir denfants ou vouloir retarder la naissance de leur prochain enfant pendant au moins deux ans. Inclus sont:&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; toutes les femmes enceintes (maries ou en union consensuelle) dont les grossesses ntaient pas dsires ou mal planifies au moment de la conception &lt;/p&gt;;
        &lt;p&gt;toutes les femmes amnorrhoeic post-partum (maries ou en union consensuelle) qui nont pas recours  la planification familiale et dont la dernire naissance na pas t dsire ou mal &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;toutes les femmes fcondes (maries ou en union consensuelle) qui ne sont ni enceintes ni post-partum amnorrhoeic, et qui soit ne veulent plus denfants (veulent limiter la taille de la famille), ou qui souhaitent reporter la naissance dun enfant pendant au moins deux ans ou ne savent pas quand ou si elles veulent un autre enfant (veulent espacer les naissances), mais nutilisent aucune mthode contraceptive.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Les mthodes modernes incluent la strilisation fminine et masculine, le dispositif intra-utrin (DIU), limplant, les injectables, les pilules contraceptives orales, les prservatifs masculins et fminins, les mthodes de barrire vaginale (y compris le diaphragme, le cap cervical et la mousse spermicide, la gele, la crme et lponge), la mthode de lamnorrhe lactationnelle (LAM), la contraception durgence et dautres mthodes modernes non dclares sparment.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Method de lestimation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;La Division de la population des Nations Unies produit une srie systmatique et exhaustive destimations annuelles et de projections du pourcentage de la demande de planification familiale qui est satisfaite chez les femmes maries ou en union. Un modle hirarchique baysien combin  des donnes spcifiques  chaque pays
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2017/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2017/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thelancet.com/pdfs/journals/langlo/PIIS2214-109X(17)30472-2.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.thelancet.com/pdfs/journals/langlo/PIIS2214-109X(17)30472-2.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    .:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/UHC_WHS2016_TechnicalNote_May2016.pdf?ua=1&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/UHC_WHS2016_TechnicalNote_May2016.pdf?ua=1&lt;/a&gt; (superseded by this document)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2015/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2015/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2014/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2014/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://collections.plos.org/uhc2014&quot;&gt;http://collections.plos.org/uhc2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt; 1.    ,           3.8.1 . &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;       : &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:uhc_stats@who.int&quot;&gt;uhc_stats@who.int&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;    (15 - 49 ),       ,           &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;          15-49 ,   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;           15-49 ,    &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;                   .             (15 - 49 ),                          ,      .      -      (15 - 49 ),      ,       ,    -   (  ),  ,                .  :&lt;/p&gt;
           (     ),         ; &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;      (    ),             ; &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;    (     ),        ,        (   ),      ,   ,     ,          (    ),      . &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;       ,   (), , ,   ,    ,    ( ,     , ,   ),    (),      ,      .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;                  ,    ,      .              ,        .      ,     . &lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt;  . : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.un.org/en/development/desa/population/theme/family-planning/cp_model.shtml&quot;&gt;http://www.un.org/en/development/desa/population/theme/family-planning/cp_model.shtml&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;,   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;    15-49 ,       ,         &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;    15-49 ,       ,        &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;     15-49 ,        .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;       &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;            ,   ,          .   ,       ,  DHS, MICS, RHS   ,    .     /    ,   ,        .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;       : &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.ANTENATALCARECOVERAGE4&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.ANTENATALCARECOVERAGE4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;,   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;              , ,  ,           .       ,  ,     .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; ,      ,   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  1 ,      ,   .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;     1 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;      &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;   ,       12  23       ,   ,    .         ,    .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;           ,    (3)   ,       -,   ,      &quot;&quot; .       -             -          .    ,       ,  /        . &lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt;  . : &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/bulletin/volumes/87/7/08-053819/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/bulletin/volumes/87/7/08-053819/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/immunization/monitoring_surveillance/routine/coverage/en/index4.html&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/immunization/monitoring_surveillance/routine/coverage/en/index4.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;,   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;      .  ,           ,  ,      .  ,          , -    3      .   ,       , ,   B     B,     ,         . &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  (     )&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;     5      (   ,  -       )    ,  ,        .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;         ,  ,    .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;        ,  .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;   /     ,   - 17-18  2004 ,       ()   ,         .   ,         (DHS)        (MICS),         ,  ,  ,  ,  ,     ,   ,      .  &quot;&quot;       . &lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt;             ,      : &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.38?lang=en&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.38?lang=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;           .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;,   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;               . &lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt;  ,     ,      ,           ( -),     ,  ,              ,    : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/healthinfo/global_burden_disease/estimates/en/index2.html&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/healthinfo/global_burden_disease/estimates/en/index2.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;   ,         &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;    ,      &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;        &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  ,  ,         ,        (   )&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;      : &lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt; (1)      ,                  . &lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt; (2)          . &lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt; (3)   ,   (    )   ,       .&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  = (1)/(2) x (3)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;      -       .         ,        ,           (  ).                   : &lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt; 1.  =    /    ; &lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt; 2.  =  /  ; &lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt; 3.  =   /      . &lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt;               ,       ,   .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;,   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;      ,       : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/tb/country/data/download/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/tb/country/data/download/en/&lt;/a&gt;, and compute the indicator as = c_cdr x c_new_tsr&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; ,   ,       ()&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;   ,      &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;   ,   ,    &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  ,   ,  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;:   ,     ,        .               .          ,         . ,       ,     . &lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt; :      -      ,          ,   ,    .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;    ,     2000-2018 ,         2019 .&lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt;    ,   ,           ,         (Spectrum),          ,  ,       -. &lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt;      ,   ,     ,  ,            . &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;     : http://aidsinfo.unaids.org/&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;,   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;         ,    ,   .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;      ,         .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;      ,       &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;       .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;          ()          ,        ,         .    ,    ,  Milliner Global Associates,     ,   ,      .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;       ,    -.        ,   ,        ,      62 ,       . &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;                                    .          .              2015 :&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/malaria/publications/world-malaria-report-2015/report/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/malaria/publications/world-malaria-report-2015/report/en/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;,   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;       40     .             -  . &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; ,      &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;,   ,  :      ,       ;     ;    ;   .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;     &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;   ,    ,     .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;    /     ,   ,      .                  ,    ,          ,        4 ,    .        ,         .           .: http://www.wssinfo.org/&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;,   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;     ( 6.2.1)      ,    .       -    .     ,   ,      ,     .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; - &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;           18+,    &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;    18        &lt;140  . .     &lt;90  . . (   )&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;    18   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  ,     (   ).         ,   ,    .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;        ,         /  ,      ,      &gt; = 140  . .     &gt; = 90 . . .    .             , ,   ,       ,              .              .       : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(16)31919-5/fulltext&quot;&gt;http://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(16)31919-5/fulltext&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;        -  (NCD-RisC)         2015 ,   : &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.A875STANDARD?lang=en&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.A875STANDARD?lang=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;,   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;            ,    100%   .   :     = 1 -    .        ;            &lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt;    -    ,   ,   ,     .      ,        ,    . ,  , -    .  ,        ,     .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;             18   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;     ()      ,    8 .   ,    A1c (HbA1c),     (. ).&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;       ,     ,       (OGTT), HbA1c   ,     .             , ,   ,       ,              .              .     : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/diabetes/global-report/en/&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/diabetes/global-report/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;,   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;     -      - ,              ,   .  ,            ,     . &lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt;        ;           .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;       &gt; = 15 ,       30  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  15   ,       30 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  15   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&quot; &quot;  , ,       ,    30 .      .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;     ()      -,                ,   .        .     :&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(15)60264-1/supplemental&quot;&gt;http://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(15)60264-1/supplemental&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;,   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;      1   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;          18  10 000 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;   (      )&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  /    &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;        ,           10 000. &lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt;           -   ,   -:&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rho.emro.who.int/rhodata/node.main.A36&quot;&gt;https://rho.emro.who.int/rhodata/node.main.A36&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;   AFRO: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aho.afro.who.int/en/data-statistics/hospital-beds-10-000-population&quot;&gt;http://www.aho.afro.who.int/en/data-statistics/hospital-beds-10-000-population&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;    &quot;  &quot;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://gateway.euro.who.int/en/datasets%20european-health-for-all-database/&quot;&gt;https://gateway.euro.who.int/en/datasets european-health-for-all-database/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.oecd.org/healtheqt/hospital-beds.htm&quot;&gt;https://data.oecd.org/healtheqt/hospital-beds.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;         18    10 000 .             ( 2000 ),  20  10 000, ,  ,     5  100  .          ;   ,             .              (x),     0  100:&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;     x &lt;18  10 000  ,  = &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; /18*100. &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;     x&gt; = 18  10 000  ,  = 100.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;,   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;          .           ,    .  ,        ,    ,   .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;   (,   )           &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; ,   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;      ,            ,      .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;         ,   ,       ,              .                 (   ),      ,    (   )       (       ). &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;       : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;    :&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.HWFGRP_0020?lang=en&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.HWFGRP_0020?lang=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2017/en/&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/healthinfo/universal_health_coverage/report/2017/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.HWF9?lang=en%20&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.HWF9?lang=en&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;(        )&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  ,                 (,   )         2000 ,    :  = 0,9  1000,  = 1  100000,  = 14  100000.      ,       ,  ,          0  100      . ,       1000   (&lt;em&gt; x &lt;/em&gt;),       :&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  x &lt;0,9  1000  ,   = x / 0,9 * 100 &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  x&gt; = 0,9  1000  ,   = 100&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;            ,       .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;,   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&quot;&quot;       ,     &quot;  &quot;,     .         ,         ,   ,       . &lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt;  ,     ,       ,       100000 ,     ,  ,            &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;    -  (),       13  ,        &lt;/p&gt;
         &lt;p&gt;  13   : (1)  ,   ; (2)      ; (3) ; (4) ; (5) ; (6)   ; (7)  ; (8) ; (9)  ; (10)  ; (11)  ; (12)     ; (13)   .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;          13       ,   : &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/10665/84933/1/WHO_HSE_GCR_2013.2_eng.pdf&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/10665/84933/1/WHO_HSE_GCR_2013.2_eng.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;      : &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.IHRSPARALL?lang=en&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.IHRSPARALL?lang=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;     13  ,      .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;,   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;           -  ()  2010 .  2000-2009            .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
