<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SDG_RELATED_INDICATORS field for indicator 3-8-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Related indicators as of February 2020&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UHC service coverage index is designed to summarize existing indicators of health service coverage to ensure consistency with the SDGs and other global initiatives and reduce duplication and reporting burden. Currently, two other SDG indicators are included in the index (3.a.1 and 3.d.1). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator 3.8.1 should always be interpreted together with the other SDG UHC indicator, 3.8.2, which measures financial protection.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt; Indicateurs connexes en date de février 2020&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L’indice de couverture des services de l’UHC est conçu pour résumer les indicateurs existants de la couverture des services de santé afin d’assurer l’uniformité avec les ODD et d’autres initiatives mondiales et de réduire le fardeau des doubles emplois et des rapports. À l’heure actuelle, deux autres indicateurs des ODD sont inclus dans l’indice (3.a.1 et 3.d.1). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L’indicateur 3.8.1 doit toujours être interprété avec l’autre indicateur UHC des ODD, 3.8.2, qui mesure la protection financière. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Связанные показатели по состоянию на февраль 2020 года &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Индекс охвата услугами ВОУЗ (Всеобщий охват услугами здравоохранения) предназначен для обобщения существующих показателей охвата услугами здравоохранения, чтобы обеспечить согласованность с показателями ЦУР и другими глобальными инициативами и уменьшить дублирование и бремя отчетности. В настоящее время в индекс включены два других показателя ЦУР (3.a.1 и 3.d.1). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель 3.8.1 всегда следует интерпретировать вместе с другим показателем ЦУР 3.8.2, включенным в ВОУЗ, который оценивает финансовую защищенность.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
