<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SDG_RELATED_INDICATORS field for indicator 3-8-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The universal health coverage (UHC) service coverage index is designed to summarize existing indicators of health service coverage to ensure consistency with the SDGs and other global initiatives and reduce duplication and reporting burden. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator 3.8.1 should always be interpreted together with the other SDG UHC indicator, 3.8.2, which measures financial protection.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Indicadores relacionados en febrero de 2020&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El índice de cobertura de servicios de la Cobertura Sanitaria Universal (CSU) está diseñado para resumir los indicadores existentes de la cobertura de los servicios de salud con el fin de garantizar la coherencia con los ODS y otras iniciativas mundiales y reducir la duplicación y la carga de información. Actualmente, el índice incluye otros dos indicadores de los ODS (3.a.1 y 3.d.1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador 3.8.1 debe interpretarse siempre junto con el otro indicador de ODS sobre la cobertura sanitaria universal, el 3.8.2, que mide la protección financiera.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;L’indice de couverture des services de santé est conçu pour résumer les indicateurs existants de la couverture des services de santé afin d’assurer l’uniformité avec les ODD et d’autres initiatives mondiales et de réduire les doublons et le fardeau de déclaration. À l’heure actuelle, deux autres indicateurs des ODD sont inclus dans l’indice (3.a.1 et 3.d.1). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’indicateur 3.8.1 doit toujours être interprété avec l’autre indicateur de couverture sanitaire universelle des ODD, 3.8.2, qui mesure la protection financière. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Связанные показатели по состоянию на февраль 2020 года &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Индекс охвата услугами ВОУЗ (Всеобщий охват услугами здравоохранения) предназначен для обобщения существующих показателей охвата услугами здравоохранения, чтобы обеспечить согласованность с показателями ЦУР и другими глобальными инициативами и уменьшить дублирование и бремя отчетности. В настоящее время в индекс включены два других показателя ЦУР (3.a.1 и 3.d.1). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель 3.8.1 всегда следует интерпретировать вместе с другим показателем ЦУР 3.8.2, включенным в ВОУЗ, который оценивает финансовую защищенность.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
