<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DOC_METHOD field for indicator 16-5-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;In 2018, UNODC together with the United Nations Development Program (UNDP) and the UNODC-INEGI Centre of Excellence published the Manual on Corruption Surveys, which provides Member States with detailed guidelines not only for planning and implementing corruption surveys, but for also analyzing and reporting on corruption survey data. The Manual deals with deals with corruption surveys among the general population as well as businesses. The Manual is available in multiple UN languages at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unodc.org/unodc/data-and-analysis/corruption-manuals.html&quot;&gt;https://www.unodc.org/unodc/data-and-analysis/corruption-manuals.html&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2022, the United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime (UNODC) together with the United Nations Development Program (UNDP) and the Office of the United Nations High Commissioner on Human Rights (OHCHR) published the SDG 16 Survey Questionnaire and Implementation Manual, which contain internationally standardised survey question wording (in the five official UN languages) as well as implementation guidance related to this indicator. The questionnaire and manual are available in multiple languages at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sdg16hub.org/topic/sdg-16-survey-initiative-questionnaire&quot;&gt;https://www.sdg16hub.org/topic/sdg-16-survey-initiative-questionnaire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sdg16hub.org/topic/sdg-16-survey-initiative-implementation-manual&quot;&gt;https://www.sdg16hub.org/topic/sdg-16-survey-initiative-implementation-manual&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNODC. 2023. Statistical framework to measure corruption&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
