<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 17-5-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;SDG indicator 17.5.1 calls for the measurement of both adoption and implementation of investment promotion regimes. The adoption of investment promotion regimes for LDCs is an important yet not sufficient means for strengthening the global partnership for the SGDs (Goal 17). Subsequent implementation of these regimes is necessary for making the tool effective. However, getting comprehensive and reliable data on the implementation stage (i.e. how many investments in LDCs have actually been promoted through the promotion regime?) will be difficult. These data are usually not publicly available. However, to some extent, data may exist in aggregate form (see below). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, UNCTAD research indicated that many developed countries and some emerging economies have national investment promotion regimes in place that encourage investment abroad. Usually, however, these promotion regimes are available for outward investment in any country &amp;#x2013; not only for investment in LDCs or other developing economies. Some types of investment policy tools can be more country-specific, like bilateral investment treaties (BITs). The indicator reporting started with preliminary estimates covering BITs, relying on comprehensive and country specific UNCTAD data on BITs. Over the past decade, broad consensus formed on the need to reform the BIT regime. UNCTAD provides detailed policy guidance to support the reform action of countries and regions. Data on the actual number of countries with an outward FDI promotion scheme that can benefit developing countries, including LDCs, constitutes a more accurate measurement for this indicator. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
