<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The ADJUSTMENT field for indicator 3-7-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Generally, there is no discrepancy between data presented and data published in survey reports. However, some published national data have been adjusted by the Population Division to improve comparability. Notes are used in the data set to indicate when adjustments were made and where data differed from standard definitions. Surveys might differ in the classification of modern and traditional methods. To improve comparability of data over time and across countries, method classifications used in some survey are adjusted to follow the classification described above. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The global indicator represents all women of reproductive age. Some survey estimates represent women who are married or in a union and this is indicated in a note.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;En général, il n’y a pas de divergence entre les données présentées et les données publiées dans les rapports d’enquête. Toutefois, certaines données nationales publiées ont été ajustées par la Division de la population afin d’améliorer la comparabilité. Des notes sont utilisées pour l’ensemble de données afin d&apos;indiquer quand des ajustements ont été apportés et où les données différaient des définitions standard. Les enquêtes peuvent différer dans la classification des méthodes modernes et traditionnelles. Afin d’améliorer la comparabilité des données dans le temps et entre les pays, les classifications des méthodes utilisées dans certaines enquêtes sont ajustées pour suivre la classification décrite ci-dessus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’indicateur global représente toutes les femmes en âge de procréer. Certaines estimations d’enquête représentent des femmes mariées ou en union libre, ce qui est indiqué dans une note. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
