<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REL_CAL_POLICY field for indicator 3-7-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Updated data compilations on the indicator are released by the Population Division biennially in July as a comprehensive compilation of data and model-based annual estimates and projections up to 2030 at the national, regional and global level. See:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations, Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division (2022). World Contraceptive Use 2022. New York: United Nations. (https://www.un.org/development/desa/pd/data/world-contraceptive-use)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations, Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division (2022). Estimates and Projections of Family Planning Indicators 2022. New York: United Nations. (https://www.un.org/development/desa/pd/data/family-planning-indicators)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data are also available in the interactive data portal of the Population Division (https://population.un.org/dataportal/home)&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Publicación de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La División de Población publica datos actualizados sobre el indicador en el primer trimestre de cada año. La próxima publicación está prevista para el primer trimestre de 2020. La División de Población publica anualmente una amplia recopilación de datos y estimaciones anuales basadas en modelos y proyecciones hasta 2030 a nivel nacional, regional y mundial. Véase: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naciones Unidas, Departamento de Asuntos Económicos y Sociales, División de Población (2020). Uso Mundial de Anticonceptivos 2020. Nueva York: Naciones Unidas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naciones Unidas, Departamento de Asuntos Económicos y Sociales, División de Población (2020). Estimaciones y proyecciones de los indicadores de planificación familiar 2020. Nueva York: Naciones Unidas. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Des compilations de données mises à jour sur l’indicateur sont publiées par la Division de la population en mars de chaque année sous la forme d’une compilation complète de données et d’estimations et de projections annuelles fondées sur des modèles jusqu’en 2030 aux niveaux national, régional et mondial. Consulter les adresses suivantes (en anglais) : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nations Unies, Département des Affaires Économiques et Sociales, Division de la population (2021). « World Contraceptive Use 2021 ». New York : Nations Unies. (https://www.un.org/development/desa/pd/data/world-contraceptive-use) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nations Unies, Département des Affaires Économiques et Sociales, Division de la population (2021). « Estimates and Projections of Family Planning Indicators 2021 ». New York : Nations Unies. (https://www.un.org/development/desa/pd/data/family-planning-indicators) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont également disponibles dans le portail interactif de données de la Division de la population (https://population.un.org/dataportal/home)&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Выпуск данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Обновленные данные по показателю публикуются Отделом народонаселения в первом квартале каждого года. Следующая публикация ожидается в первом квартале 2020 года. Отдел народонаселения ежегодно публикует всеобъемлющую подборку данных и годовых оценок на основе моделей и прогнозов до 2030 года на национальном, региональном и глобальном уровнях. См .: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Организация Объединенных Наций, Департамент по экономическим и социальным вопросам, Отдел народонаселения (2020 год). Мировое исследование использования контрацепции за 2020 год. Нью-Йорк: Организация Объединенных Наций. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Организация Объединенных Наций, Департамент по экономическим и социальным вопросам, Отдел народонаселения (2020 г.). Оценки и прогнозы показателей планирования семьи на 2020 год. Нью-Йорк: Организация Объединенных Наций.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
