<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 3-3-5, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are currently being reported by 191 countries, with good coverage of all regions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2010-2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disaggregation by disease is required; ending the epidemic of NTDs requires a reduction in the number of people requiring interventions for each NTD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disaggregation by age is required for PC: preschool-aged children (1-4 years), school-aged (5-14 years) and adults (= 15 years). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actualmente, 185 países comunican los datos, con una buena cobertura de todas las regiones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Es necesario el desglose por enfermedad; para acabar con la epidemia de las ETD es necesario reducir el número de personas que requieren intervenciones para cada ETD. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se requiere un desglose por edad para la QP: niños en edad preescolar (1-4 años), en edad escolar (5-14 años) y adultos (= 15 años).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Disponibilité des données :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont actuellement déclarées par 185 pays, avec une bonne couverture de toutes les régions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Séries chronologiques :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2010-2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Désagrégation :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Une ventilation par maladie est requise; pour mettre fin à l&apos;épidémie de MTN, il faut réduire le nombre de personnes nécessitant des interventions pour chaque MTN. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Une ventilation par âge est requise pour la CP : enfants d&apos;âge préscolaire (1-4 ans), enfants d&apos;âge scolaire (5-14 ans) et adultes (= 15 ans). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные в настоящее время представляют 185 стран с хорошим охватом всех регионов. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Требуется дезагрегирование по болезням; Прекращение эпидемии ЗТБ подразумевает сокращение количества лиц, которым требуется лечение по поводу каждой забытой тропической болезни. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для профилактической химиотерапии требуется дезагрегирование по возрасту: дети дошкольного возраста (1-4 года), школьники (5-14 лет) и взрослые (= 15 лет). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
