<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The QUALITY_ASSURE field for indicator 3-3-5, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Quality assurance:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Training materials for the Integrated NTD database are available here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/neglected_diseases/data/ntddatabase/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/neglected_diseases/data/ntddatabase/en/&lt;/a&gt;. A user guide and video tutorial for the joint reporting mechanism and set of reporting forms are available here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/neglected_diseases/preventive_chemotherapy/reporting/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/neglected_diseases/preventive_chemotherapy/reporting/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details about individual NTD data are available via: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/gho/neglected_diseases/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/gho/neglected_diseases/en/&lt;/a&gt;. For NTDs requiring preventive chemotherapy, reports are signed by the NTD coordinator or a Ministry of Health representative to formally endorse the country&amp;#x2019;s request for medicines (when applicable) and data. They are submitted to the WHO Representative of the concerned WHO Country office.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Assurance de la qualité : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le matériel de formation pour la base de données intégrée NTD est disponible ici : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/neglected_diseases/data/ntddatabase/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/neglected_diseases/data/ntddatabase/en/&lt;/a&gt;. Un guide de l&apos;utilisateur et un didacticiel vidéo pour le mécanisme de notification conjointe et l&apos;ensemble des formulaires de notification sont disponibles ici : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/neglected_diseases/preventive_chemotherapy/reporting/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/neglected_diseases/preventive_chemotherapy/reporting/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les détails concernant les données individuelles sur les ATN sont disponibles via : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/gho/neglected_diseases/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/gho/neglected_diseases/en/&lt;/a&gt;. Pour les ATN nécessitant une chimiothérapie préventive, les rapports sont signés par le coordinateur des ATN ou un représentant du ministère de la santé afin d&apos;approuver officiellement la demande de médicaments (le cas échéant) et de données du pays &amp;#x2019;. Ils sont soumis au représentant de l&apos;OMS du bureau de pays concerné. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
