<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 9-3-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Rationale:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Industrial enterprises are classified to small compared to large or medium for their distinct nature of economic organization, production capability, scale of investment and other economic characteristics. &amp;#x201C;Small-scale industries&amp;#x201D; can be run with a small amount of capital, relatively unskilled labor and using local materials. Despite their small contribution to total industrial output, their role in job creation, especially in developing countries is recognized to be significant where the scope of absorbing surplus labor force from traditional sectors such as agriculture or fishery is very high. &amp;#x201C;Small-scale industries&amp;#x201D; are capable of meeting domestic demand of basic consumer goods such as food, clothes, furniture, etc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus &amp;#x201C;small-scale industries&amp;#x201D; play an important role in the economy. However, it has quite limited access to financial services, especially in developing countries. In order to improve the skill of workers and technology for production, small-scale industrial enterprises require financial support in the form of preferential loan, credit etc. This indicator shows how widely financial institutions are serving the &amp;#x201C;small-scale industries&amp;#x201D;. Together with the indicator SDG 9.3.1, this indicator reflects the main message of the target 9.3 which promotes to increase the access of &amp;#x201C;small-scale industries&amp;#x201D; to financial services.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt; Justification:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les entreprises industrielles sont classées comme petites par rapport aux grandes ou moyennes entreprises en raison de leur nature distincte d’organisation économique, de leur capacité de production, de leur échelle d’investissement et d’autres caractéristiques économiques. &amp;#x201C; Les petites industries&amp;#x201D; peuvent être gérées avec une petite quantité de capital, une main-d’œuvre relativement peu qualifiée et en utilisant des matériaux locaux. Malgré leur faible contribution à la production industrielle totale, leur rôle dans la création d’emplois, en particulier dans les pays en développement, est reconnu comme important lorsque la marge d’absorption de la main-d’œuvre excédentaire des secteurs traditionnels tels que l’agriculture ou la pêche est très élevée. &amp;#x201C; Les petites industries&amp;#x201D; sont capables de répondre à la demande intérieure de biens de consommation de base tels que la nourriture, les vêtements, les meubles, etc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Ainsi&amp;#x201C;, les petites industries&amp;#x201D; jouent un rôle important dans l’économie. Toutefois, l’accès aux services financiers est assez limité, en particulier dans les pays en développement. Afin d’améliorer les compétences des travailleurs et la technologie pour la production, les petites entreprises industrielles ont besoin d’un soutien financier sous forme de prêt préférentiel, de crédit, etc. Cet indicateur montre à quel point les institutions financières servent largement les petites industries &amp;#x201C;&amp;#x201D;. Avec l’indicateur ODD 9.3.1, cet indicateur reflète le message principal de l’objectif 9.3 qui favorise l’accès des petites industries &amp;#x201C;&amp;#x201D; aux services financiers. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
