<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 9-3-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="en">## Rationale

Industrial enterprises are classified to small compared to large or medium for their distinct nature of economic organization, production capability, scale of investment and other economic characteristics. “Small-scale industries” can be run with a small amount of capital, relatively unskilled labor and using local materials. Despite their small contribution to total industrial output, their role in job creation, especially in developing countries is recognized to be significant where the scope of absorbing surplus labor force from traditional sectors such as agriculture or fishery is very high. “Small-scale industries” are capable of meeting domestic demand of basic consumer goods such as food, clothes, furniture, etc. 

Thus “small-scale industries” play an important role in the economy. However, it has quite limited access to financial services, especially in developing countries. In order to improve the skill of workers and technology for production, small-scale industrial enterprises require financial support in the form of preferential loan, credit etc. This indicator shows how widely financial institutions are serving the “small-scale industries”. Together with the indicator SDG 9.3.1, this indicator reflects the main message of the target 9.3 which promotes to increase the access of “small-scale industries” to financial services.
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">## Обоснование

Промышленные предприятия классифицируются как малые по сравнению с крупными или средними по характеру экономической организации, производственным мощностям, масштабам инвестиций и другим экономическим характеристикам. &quot;Малые предприятия&quot; могут работать с небольшим капиталом, относительно неквалифицированной рабочей силой и с использованием местных материалов. Несмотря на их небольшой вклад в общий объем промышленного производства, их роль в создании рабочих мест, особенно в развивающихся странах, признается значительной там, где масштабы поглощения избыточной рабочей силы из таких традиционных секторов, как сельское хозяйство или рыболовство, весьма высоки. &quot;Малые предприятия&quot; способны удовлетворить внутренний спрос на основные потребительские товары, такие как продукты питания, одежда, мебель и т.д.

Таким образом, &quot;малые производства&quot; играют важную роль в экономике. Однако они имеют весьма ограниченный доступ к финансовым услугам, особенно в развивающихся странах. В целях повышения квалификации работников и технологического уровня производства малые промышленные предприятия нуждаются в финансовой поддержке в виде льготных кредитов, займов и т.д. Этот показатель показывает, насколько широко финансовые учреждения обслуживают &quot;малые предприятия&quot;. Вместе с показателем ЦУР 9.3.1 данный показатель отражает основную идею целевой задачи 9.3, способствующей расширению доступа &quot;малых производств&quot; к финансовым услугам.
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
