<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 4-1-1a, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Data availability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Time series:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data available since 2000. The indicator will be reported annually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator is published disaggregated by sex. Other disaggregation such as location, socio-economic status, immigrant status, ethnicity and language of the test at home are based on data produced by international organizations administering cross learning assessment detailed in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://tcg.uis.unesco.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2020/08/metadata-4.1.1.pdf&quot;&gt;expanded metadata document&lt;/a&gt; and validated by countries. Parity indexes are estimated in the reporting of Indicator 4.5.1. Information on the disaggregation of variable for Indicator 4.1.1 are presented in the following tables.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Datos disponibles desde el año 2000. El indicador se comunicará anualmente.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador se publica desglosado por sexo. Otros desgloses, como la ubicación, la situación socioeconómica, la condición de inmigrante, el origen étnico y el idioma de la prueba en el hogar, se basan en los datos producidos por las organizaciones internacionales que administran la evaluación del aprendizaje cruzado, detallados en el documento de &lt;a href=&quot;http://tcg.uis.unesco.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2020/08/metadata-4.1.1.pdf&quot;&gt;metadatos ampliados&lt;/a&gt; y validados por los países. Los índices de paridad se estiman en el informe del indicador 4.5.1. La información sobre el desglose de la variable para el Indicador 4.1.1 se presenta en las siguientes tablas.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Séries chronologiques : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Données disponibles depuis 2000. L&apos;indicateur sera déclaré annuellement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Désagrégation :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’indicateur est publié ventilé par sexe. D’autres désagrégations telles que l’emplacement, le statut socio-économique, le statut d’immigrant, l’origine ethnique et la langue du test à la maison sont basées sur des données produites par des organisations internationales administrant une évaluation de l’apprentissage croisée détaillée dans le document (en anglais) de métadonnées &lt;a href=&quot;http://tcg.uis.unesco.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2020/09/metadata-4.1.1.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; et validée par les pays. Les indices de parité sont estimés dans le rapport de l’indicateur 4.5.1. Les informations sur la désagrégation de la variable pour l&apos;indicateur 4.1.1 sont présentées dans les tableaux suivants.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные доступны с 2000 года. Показатель будет представляться ежегодно. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель публикуется с разбивкой по полу. Другое дезагрегирование, такое как по местоположению, социально-экономическому статусу, иммиграционному статусу , этнической принадлежности и языку, на котором проводилось тестирование дома, основано на данных, предоставленных международными организациями, проводящими перекрестную оценку успеваемости, подробно описано в &lt;a href=&quot;http://tcg.uis.unesco.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2020/08/metadata-4.1.1.pdf&quot;&gt; документе, содержащем расширенные метаданные &lt;/a&gt; и подтверждено странами. Индексы равенства отражаются в отчетности по показателя 4.5.1. Информация о дезагрегировании переменной для показателя 4.1.1 представлена в следующих таблицах. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
