<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 4-1-1a, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Data availability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Time series:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data available since 2000. The indicator will be reported annually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator is published disaggregated by sex. Other disaggregation such as location, socio-economic status, immigrant status, ethnicity and language of the test at home are based on data produced by international organizations administering cross learning assessment detailed in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://tcg.uis.unesco.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2020/08/metadata-4.1.1.pdf&quot;&gt;expanded metadata document&lt;/a&gt; and validated by countries. Parity indexes are estimated in the reporting of Indicator 4.5.1. Information on the disaggregation of variable for Indicator 4.1.1 are presented in the following tables.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilité des données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Séries chronologiques : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Données disponibles depuis 2000. L&apos;indicateur fera l&apos;objet d&apos;un rapport annuel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Désagrégation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur est publié ventilé par sexe. D&apos;autres ventilations telles que le lieu, le statut socio-économique, le statut d&apos;immigrant, l&apos;ethnicité et la langue du test à domicile sont basées sur des données produites par des organisations internationales administrant l&apos;évaluation de l&apos;apprentissage croisé, détaillées dans le &lt;a href=&quot;http://tcg.uis.unesco.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2020/08/metadata-4.1.1.pdf&quot;&gt;document de métadonnées étendues &lt;/a&gt; et validées par les pays. Les indices de parité sont estimés dans le rapport de l&apos;indicateur 4.5.1. Les informations sur la désagrégation de la variable pour l&apos;Indicateur 4.1.1 sont présentées dans les tableaux suivants. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
