<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 4-1-1a, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computation method:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of children and/or young people at the relevant stage of education n in year t achieving or exceeding the pre-defined proficiency level in subject s expressed as a percentage of the number of children and/or young people at stage of education n, in year t, in any proficiency level in subject s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MPL&lt;sub&gt;t,n,s,&lt;/sub&gt; = MP&lt;sub&gt;t,n,s&lt;/sub&gt; / P&lt;sub&gt;t,n&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MP&lt;sub&gt;t,n,s&lt;/sub&gt; = the number of children and young people at stage of education n, in year t, who have achieved or exceeded the minimum proficiency level in subject s. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P&lt;sub&gt;t,n &lt;/sub&gt;= the number of children and young people at stage of education n, in year t, in any proficiency level in subject s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;n = the stage of education that was assessed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;s = the subject that was assessed (reading or mathematics).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Harmonize various data sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address the challenges posed by the limited capacity of some countries to implement cross-national, regional, and national assessments, actions have been taken by the UIS and its partners. The strategies are used according to its level of precision and following a &lt;a href=&quot;http://gaml.uis.unesco.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2019/05/GAML6-WD-2-Protocol-for-reporting-4.1.1_v1.pdf&quot;&gt;reporting protocol&lt;/a&gt; that includes the national assessments under specific circumstances. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Out-of-school children &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, 263 million children, adolescents and youth were out of school, representing nearly one-fifth of the global population of this age group. 63 million, or 24% of the total, are children of primary school age (typically 6 to 11 years old); 61 million, or 23% of the total, are adolescents of lower secondary school age (typically 12 to 14 years old); and 139 million, or 53% of the total, are youth of upper secondary school age (about 15 to 17 years old). Not all these kids will be permanently outside school, some will re-join the educational system and, eventually, complete late, while some of them will enter late. The quantity varies per country and region and demands some adjustment in the estimate of Indicator 4.1.1. There is currently a discussion on how to implement these adjustments to reflect all the population. In 2017, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://uis.unesco.org/en/blog/helping-countries-improve-their-data-out-school-children&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;UIS proposed to make adjustments using the out-of-school children (OOSC)&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and the completion rates. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; UIS (2017a). More than one-half of children and adolescents are not learning worldwide. Montreal and UIS (2017b). Counting the number of children not learning: Methodology for a global composite indicator for education. Montreal. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Méthodologie&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Méthode de calcul :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le nombre d&apos;enfants et/ou de jeunes à l&apos;étape d&apos;éducation n concernée au cours de l&apos;année t atteignant ou dépassant le niveau de compétence prédéfini dans les matières s, exprimé en pourcentage du nombre d&apos;enfants et/ou de jeunes à l&apos;étape d&apos;éducation n, au cours de l&apos;année t, dans tout niveau de compétence dans les matières s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NCP&lt;sub&gt;t,n,s, &lt;/sub&gt; = MP&lt;sub&gt;t,n,s&lt;/sub&gt; / P&lt;sub&gt;t,n&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;où : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CM&lt;sub&gt;t,n,s&lt;/sub&gt; = le nombre d&apos;enfants et de jeunes au stade d&apos;éducation n, au cours de l&apos;année t, qui ont atteint ou dépassé le niveau de compétence minimum dans la matière s. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P&lt;sub&gt;t,n &lt;/sub&gt;= le nombre d&apos;enfants et de jeunes à l&apos;étape d&apos;éducation n, en année t, dans tout niveau de compétence dans la matière s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;n = le stade de l&apos;éducation qui a été évalué. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;s = la matière qui a été évaluée (lecture ou mathématiques). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harmoniser les différentes sources de données.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour relever les défis posés par la capacité limitée de certains pays à mettre en œuvre des évaluations transnationales, régionales et nationales, des mesures ont été prises par l&apos;ISU et ses partenaires. Les stratégies sont utilisées en fonction de leur niveau de précision et selon un protocole de rapport &lt;a href=&quot;http://gaml.uis.unesco.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2019/05/GAML6-WD-2-Protocol-for-reporting-4.1.1_v1.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; qui inclut les évaluations nationales dans des circonstances spécifiques. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enfants non scolarisés. &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En 2016, 263 millions d&apos;enfants, d&apos;adolescents et de jeunes n&apos;étaient pas scolarisés, ce qui représente près d&apos;un cinquième de la population mondiale de cette tranche d&apos;âge. 63 millions, soit 24 % du total, sont des enfants en âge de fréquenter l&apos;école primaire (généralement de 6 à 11 ans) ; 61 millions, soit 23 % du total, sont des adolescents en âge de fréquenter l&apos;école secondaire inférieure (généralement de 12 à 14 ans) ; et 139 millions, soit 53 % du total, sont des jeunes en âge de fréquenter l&apos;école secondaire supérieure (environ 15 à 17 ans). Tous ces jeunes ne seront pas définitivement exclus de l&apos;école, certains réintégreront le système éducatif et finiront éventuellement leurs études avec retard, tandis que d&apos;autres y entreront tardivement. La quantité varie selon les pays et les régions et exige un certain ajustement dans l&apos;estimation de l&apos;indicateur 4.1.1. Une discussion est en cours sur la manière de mettre en œuvre ces ajustements pour refléter l&apos;ensemble de la population. En 2017, l&apos;ISU &lt;a href=&quot;http://uis.unesco.org/en/blog/helping-countries-improve-their-data-out-school-children&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt; a proposé de procéder à des ajustements en utilisant les enfants non scolarisés (OOSC) &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; et les taux d&apos;achèvement. 2573]&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; ISU (2017a). Plus de la moitié des enfants et des adolescents n&apos;apprennent pas dans le monde entier. Montréal et ISU (2017b). Comptage du nombre d&apos;enfants n&apos;apprenant pas : Méthodologie pour un indicateur composite global pour l&apos;éducation. Montréal. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
