<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The ADJUSTMENT field for indicator 7-2-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The country specific commodity balances underlying the IEA energy data are based on national energy data of heterogeneous nature converted and adapted to fit the IEA format and methodology. Considerable effort has been made to ensure that the data adhere to the IEA definitions based on the guidelines provided by IRES. Nevertheless, energy statistics at the national level are often collected using criteria and definitions which differ, sometimes considerably, from those of international organisations. This is especially true for non-OECD countries, which are submitting data to the IEA on a voluntary basis. The IEA has identified most of these differences and, where possible, adjusted the data to meet international definitions. For details on recognized country specific anomalies and the corresponding adjustments, please refer to country specific notes included in the IEA World energy balances documentation file available at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://wds.iea.org/wds/pdf/WORLDBAL_Documentation.pdf&quot;&gt;wds.iea.org/wds/pdf/WORLDBAL_Documentation.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, UNSD also needs to adjust certain data to fit the international methodology set by IRES, thus ensuring data comparability across countries. Data from all countries are submitted voluntarily to UNSD, sometimes via non-standard formats or through sharing of national publications. The identification of such deviations from the standard is an ongoing task, and UNSD has started publishing some of this information in a supplement to the Energy Statistics Database named &amp;#x201C;Notes on sources&amp;#x201D;, available at: unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/pubs/yearbook/, with the goal of increasing transparency and providing more and more information with time.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
