<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 7-2-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Data availability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the various existing data sources, primarily the IEA Energy Balances and the UN Energy Statistics Database, annual total and renewable energy consumption for every country and area can be collected. The &lt;em&gt;Tracking SDG7: The Energy Progress Report&lt;/em&gt; (formerly &lt;em&gt;Sustainable Energy for All Global Tracking Framework&lt;/em&gt;) is reporting this indicator at a global level between 2010 and 2030. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Time series:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2000 &amp;#x2013; present &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disaggregation of the data on consumption of renewable energy, e.g. by resource and end-use sector, could provide insights into other dimensions of the goal, such as affordability and reliability. For solar energy, it may also be of interest to disaggregate between on grid and off-grid capacity. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilité des données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entre les différentes sources de données existantes, principalement les bilans énergétiques de l&apos;AIE et la base de données des statistiques énergétiques des Nations unies, la consommation annuelle totale et la consommation d&apos;énergie renouvelable pour chaque pays et chaque région peuvent être collectées. Le &lt;em&gt;Tracking SDG7 : The Energy Progress Report&lt;/em&gt; (anciennement &lt;em&gt;Cadre mondial de suivi de l&apos;énergie durable pour tous&lt;/em&gt;) présente cet indicateur au niveau mondial entre 2010 et 2030. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Série chronologique : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2000 &amp;#x2013; présent &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Désagrégation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La ventilation des données sur la consommation d&apos;énergie renouvelable, par exemple par ressource et par secteur d&apos;utilisation finale, pourrait donner un aperçu d&apos;autres dimensions de l&apos;objectif, telles que le caractère abordable et la fiabilité. Pour l&apos;énergie solaire, il peut également être intéressant de ventiler les données entre les capacités en réseau et hors réseau. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Среди различных существующих источников данных, в первую очередь Энергетического баланса МЭА и Статистической базы данных ООН по энергетике, можно собирать данные по общему годовому потреблению энергии из возобновляемых источников для каждой страны и региона. &lt;em&gt; Отслеживание ЦУР 7: Отчет о прогрессе в энергетике &lt;/em&gt; (ранее &lt;em&gt; Глобальная структура отслеживания устойчивой энергетики для всех&lt;/em&gt;) представляет этот показатель на глобальном уровне в период с 2010 по 2030 год. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 2000 - настоящее время &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Дезагрегирование данных по потреблению возобновляемой энергии, например, по ресурсам и сектору конечного использования, может дать представление о других аспектах цели, таких как ценовая доступность и надежность. Что касается солнечной энергии, то в ней также может заинтересовать разделение мощности на сетевую и не входящую в энергосистему. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
