<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 3-5-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At country level &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For drug use disorder, data will be provided for countries where information is available for both numerator and denominator. No data estimates will be done at the national level. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For alcohol, when information on service utilization is missing in a country, several approaches will be used to produce estimates based on all available pieces of contextual service capacity data in the country and regionally. Link to be established between service availability and service utilization to get rough understanding on number of people who might be using services for countries where no direct information on number of people using services is available at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At regional and global level &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sub-regional and regional aggregates are produced when enough data at the country level are available (a minimum number of countries and a minimum percentage of population coverage). When data are available, sub-regional estimates are created first and then aggregated at regional level. The global level is computed as aggregation of regional estimates. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;• Au niveau national :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour les troubles liés à la consommation de drogues, des données seront fournies pour les pays où des informations sont disponibles pour le numérateur et le dénominateur. Aucune estimation des données ne sera faite au niveau national. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour l’alcool, lorsque l’information sur l’utilisation des services est manquante dans un pays, plusieurs approches seront utilisées pour produire des estimations fondées sur toutes les données contextuelles disponibles au sujet de la capacité des services dans le pays et à l’échelle régionale. Il y a un lien à établir entre la disponibilité et l&apos;utilisation des services pour obtenir une compréhension approximative du nombre de personnes qui pourraient utiliser les services dans les pays où aucune information directe sur le nombre de personnes utilisant les services n’est disponible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;• Aux niveaux régional et mondial :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des agrégats sous-régionaux et régionaux sont produits lorsque suffisamment de données au niveau national sont disponibles (un nombre minimum de pays et un pourcentage minimum de la couverture de la population). Lorsque les données sont disponibles, des estimations sous-régionales sont d’abord créées, puis agrégées au niveau régional. Le niveau mondial est calculé comme une agrégation d’estimations régionales. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
