<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The QUALITY_ASSURE field for indicator 3-5-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;At UNODC, quality assurance measures are in place to collect, process and disseminate statistical data. They build on the &amp;#x2018;Principles governing international statistical activities&amp;#x2019; and regulate the collection, processing, publication and dissemination of data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All data for SDG indicators as compiled by the Office are sent to countries (through the relevant national focal points) for their review before statistical data are officially released by UNODC. When countries provide feedback/comments on the data, a technical discussion is conducted to identify a common position. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At WHO quality assurance measures are in place for producing the health statistics that include the main indicators on alcohol consumption and its health consequences. WHO Technical Advisory Group on Alcohol and Drug Epidemiology provides technical advice and input to WHO activities on monitoring alcohol consumption and treatment capacity for substance use disorders in its Member States. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data compilation is to be performed centrally by WHO and UNODC based on data collected from countries that later will be validated through official focal points. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;À l’ONUDC, des mesures d’assurance de la qualité sont en place pour recueillir, traiter et diffuser des données statistiques. Ils s’appuient sur les « principes régissant les activités statistiques internationales » et réglementent la collecte, le traitement, la publication et la diffusion des données. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toutes les données relatives aux indicateurs des ODD compilées par le Bureau sont envoyées aux pays (par l’intermédiaire des points focaux nationaux concernés) pour examen avant que les données statistiques ne soient officiellement publiées par l’ONUDC. Lorsque les pays fournissent des commentaires sur les données, une discussion technique est menée pour identifier une position commune. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;À l’OMS, des mesures d’assurance de la qualité sont en place pour produire des statistiques sanitaires qui comprennent les principaux indicateurs sur la consommation d’alcool et ses conséquences sur la santé. Le Groupe consultatif technique de l’OMS sur l’épidémiologie de l’alcool et des drogues fournit des conseils techniques et des contributions aux activités de l’OMS sur la surveillance de la consommation d’alcool et la capacité de traitement des troubles liés à la toxicomanie dans ses États membres. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La compilation des données doit être effectuée de manière centralisée par l’OMS et l’ONUDC sur la base des données recueillies auprès des pays qui seront ensuite validées par les points focaux officiels. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
