<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 14-7-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definitions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator expresses the value added of sustainable marine capture fisheries as a proportion of Gross Domestic Product (GDP).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;u&gt;Gross Domestic Product (GDP)&lt;/u&gt; is the value of all final goods and services produced in an economy in a given period, which is equivalent to the sum of the value added (VA) from all sectors in an economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;u&gt;value added of marine capture fisheries&lt;/u&gt; measures the value of fish harvested from marine stocks, minus the value of goods and services that are used in the production process (such as raw materials and utilities). It includes activities that are normally integrated into the process of production and occur at sea, such as fishing vessels which process or preserve their catch on board. However, it does not include the processing or preserving of fish when it occurs in land based facilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;u&gt;fish stock&lt;/u&gt; is a subset of a species (fish, crustacean, mollusc, etc.) or a population inhabiting a geographical area and participating in the same reproductive process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Maximum sustainable yield (MSY)&lt;/u&gt; is the highest theoretical equilibrium yield that can be continuously taken (on average) from a stock under existing (average) environmental conditions without significantly affecting the reproduction process. A stock fished at &lt;u&gt;(MSY)&lt;/u&gt; is referred to as &lt;u&gt;biologically sustainable&lt;/u&gt;, as it may remain stable or grow while sustaining losses from fishing and natural sources of mortality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;FAO Fishing Areas for Statistical Purposes&lt;/u&gt; are arbitrary areas to facilitate comparison of data, improving the possibilities of cooperation in statistical matters.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic concepts associated with this indicator are part of the following international instruments and classification schemes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;The 1982 United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS)&lt;/u&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-3&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This instrument is the basis upon which all the subsequent instruments are built. UNCLOS defines the rights and responsibilities of nations concerning their use of the world&amp;apos;s oceans, establishing guidelines for businesses, the environment, and the management of marine natural resources. It is a binding instrument, although its principles may also be applied by countries who are not a party to it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;The 1995 FAO Code of Conduct for Responsible Fisheries (CCRF)&lt;/u&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-4&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-4&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This instrument provides the necessary framework for national and international efforts to ensure sustainable exploitation of aquatic living resources in harmony with the environment by establishing principles and standards applicable to the conservation, management, and development of all fisheries.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The FAO Code of Conduct for Responsible Fisheries relies on the concept of MSY when setting general principles and standards for fisheries management. Article 7.2.1 details how management measures should be &amp;#x201C;based on the best scientific evidence available&amp;#x201D; and &amp;#x201C;designed to maintain or restore stocks at levels capable of producing maximum sustainable yield, as qualified by relevant environmental and economic factors, including the special requirements of developing countries.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;United Nation&amp;#x2019;s International Standard Classification of All Economic Activities (ISIC)&lt;/u&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-5&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-5&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All components of marine capture fisheries are clearly defined within section A 0311 ISIC revision&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; FAO fishing areas for statistical purposes: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/cwp-on-fishery-statistics/handbook/general-concepts/major-fishing-areas-general/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/cwp-on-fishery-statistics/handbook/general-concepts/major-fishing-areas-general/en/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-3&quot;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; UNCLOS: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.un.org/Depts/los/convention_agreements/texts/unclos/unclos_e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.un.org/Depts/los/convention_agreements/texts/unclos/unclos_e.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-4&quot;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; CCRF: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/v9878e/V9878E.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/v9878e/V9878E.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-4&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-5&quot;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; ISIC revision 4: &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/seriesm/seriesm_4rev4e.pdf&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/seriesm/seriesm_4rev4e.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-5&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</data>
</root>
