<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COMPARABILITY field for indicator 7-1-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;h2&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There may be discrepancies between internationally reported and nationally reported figures. The reasons are the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modelled estimates versus survey data point.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use of different definitions of polluting (or previously solid) fuels (wood only or wood and any other biomass, e.g. dung residues; kerosene included or not as polluting fuels).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use of different total population estimate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estimates are expressed as percentage of population using polluting (or solid) fuels (as per SDG indicator) as compared to percentage of household using polluting (or solid) fuels (as assessed by surveys such as DHS or MICS).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the estimates presented here, values above 95% polluting fuel use are reported as &amp;#x201C;&amp;gt;95&amp;#x201D;, and values below 5% as &amp;#x201C;&amp;lt;5.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changes in modelling methodology:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to 2018, estimates of the proportion of the population primarily relying on solid fuels were obtained from a multilevel model with region and nonparametric functions of time as the only covariates (Bonjour et al. 2013). For tracking SDG7 in 2018 and 2019 this model was used to estimate polluting and clean fuel use, though this time it was implemented in the Bayesian framework for increased robustness and more reliable quantification of uncertainty. For 2020, the model has been expanded to allow estimates for individual fuels, and extra flexibility has been added to the functions of time to better capture nonlinear trends in some countries (Stoner et al. 2019). These refinements have been introduced alongside an ever-expanding collection of data, which underwent a major quality-control effort. Due to the increased data availability, borrowing of information across regions is no longer essential, hence time is now the only covariate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On both occasions where the model changed, the WHO conducted a thorough sensitivity analysis, including full country-by-country comparisons of estimates between the existing model and the candidate model. In most cases, estimates of the proportion using clean fuels exhibited little change, see annex below. Where larger discrepancies were identified, they were carefully investigated to determine the likely cause. Many of these were in fact the result of the new model better capturing nonlinear trends.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
