<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The INST_MANDATE field for indicator 1-2-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The UN Statistical Commission has adopted &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/statcom/49th-session/documents/BG-Item-3a-IAEG-SDGs-DataFlowsGuidelines-E.pdf&quot;&gt;Guidelines on Data Flows and Global Data Reporting for the SDGs&lt;/a&gt;, which aim to establish efficient and transparent mechanisms for reporting on SDG data from national to international levels. The guidelines define a framework for national and international agencies to work together to improve the transmission and validation of SDG data at the global level. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Statistical Commission sets these guidelines under the overarching Fundamental Principles of Official Statistics and the Principles Governing International Statistical Activities, emphasizing in particular the principles of transparency, collaboration and communication, and professional and ethical standards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guidelines mandate that SDG indicators be based on data produced and owned by national statistical systems, and that national statistical offices (NSOs) play a central coordinating role in the reporting process. The guidelines outline the roles and responsibilities of entities involved in the compilation of SDG data for global reporting, including NSOs, other national institutions, and international organizations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the national level, the NSO, as coordinator of the National Statistical System, is expected to identify a national data provider for each indicator and liaise between national entities and international custodian agencies. For SDG Indicator 1.2.2, the data provider would be the national entity that is leading the development and monitoring of a measure of national multidimensional poverty recognized as official by the government. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the global level, custodian agencies are mandated to compile national SDG indicator data, to harmonize it to ensure quality, international comparability and the computation of regional aggregates, and to report (upload) the data to the Global SDG Indicator Database. In many instances, custodian agencies also support the methodological development of indicators and provide technical assistance to under-resourced national statistical systems. Custodian agencies are expected to publish a timeline of data collection activities, to ensure transparency and sufficient time for NSOs and national data providers to respond to requests for SDG data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SDG 1.2.2 is different from other SDG indicators in two important ways. Firstly, it is nationally defined and not a uniform measure across countries, and therefore it is not internationally comparable. Secondly, its custodians are NSOs and not international agencies. Because of these characteristics, UNDP, UNICEF and the World Bank collaborate as special partner agencies to provide a platform for compiling national SDG 1.2.2 data and reporting it to the global SDG database, a function typically performed by custodian agencies. While the special partner agencies strive to ensure that reported data is official and of good quality, they do not perform any harmonization or other processing of the data. The Guidelines on Data Flows and Global Data Reporting for the SDGs also require that national metadata be submitted at the same time as SDG data, to ensure accuracy and international comparability. The variety of methodologies for SDG Indicator 1.2.2 increases the relevance of national metadata as an instrument to ensure high quality and the accuracy of reported data. The three agencies also have extensive portfolios of technical assistance and capacity support to countries for the development of their national measures of multidimensional poverty. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;La Commission de statistique des Nations Unies a adopté les lignes directrices (en anglais) &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/statcom/49th-session/documents/BG-Item-3a-IAEG-SDGs-DataFlowsGuidelines-E.pdf&quot;&gt;« Guidelines on Data Flows and Global Data Reporting for the SDGs »&lt;/a&gt;, qui visent à établir des mécanismes efficaces et transparents pour la communication des données sur les ODD du niveau national au niveau international. Les lignes directrices définissent un cadre permettant aux agences nationales et internationales de travailler ensemble pour améliorer la transmission et la validation des données des ODD au niveau mondial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Commission de statistique établit ces lignes directrices dans le cadre des Principes fondamentaux de la statistique officielle et des Principes régissant les activités statistiques internationales, en mettant l&apos;accent en particulier sur les principes de transparence, de collaboration et de communication, ainsi que sur les normes professionnelles et éthiques. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les directives stipulent que les indicateurs des ODD doivent être basés sur des données produites et détenues par les systèmes statistiques nationaux, et que les bureaux nationaux de statistique jouent un rôle de coordination central dans le processus de notification. Les lignes directrices décrivent les rôles et les responsabilités des entités impliquées dans la compilation des données sur les ODD pour les rapports mondiaux, y compris les bureaux nationaux de statistique (BNS), d&apos;autres institutions nationales et les organisations internationales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Au niveau national, le BNS, en tant que coordonnateur du système statistique national, est censé identifier un fournisseur national de données pour chaque indicateur et assurer la liaison entre les entités nationales et les agences dépositaires internationales. Pour l&apos;indicateur ODD 1.2.2, le fournisseur de données serait l&apos;entité nationale qui dirige le développement et le suivi d&apos;une mesure de la pauvreté multidimensionnelle nationale reconnue comme officielle par le gouvernement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Au niveau mondial, les agences dépositaires sont mandatées pour compiler les données des indicateurs nationaux des ODD, pour les harmoniser afin d&apos;assurer la qualité, la comparabilité internationale et le calcul des agrégats régionaux, et pour télécharger les données dans la base de données mondiale des indicateurs des ODD. Dans de nombreux cas, les agences dépositaires soutiennent également le développement méthodologique des indicateurs et fournissent une assistance technique aux systèmes statistiques nationaux qui manquent de ressources. Les agences dépositaires doivent publier un calendrier des activités de collecte de données, afin d&apos;assurer la transparence et suffisamment de temps pour que les BNS et les fournisseurs de données nationaux répondent aux demandes de données sur les ODD. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur 1.2.2 des ODD diffère des autres indicateurs ODD de deux manières importantes. Premièrement, il est défini au niveau national et n&apos;est pas une mesure uniforme entre les pays, et n&apos;est donc pas comparable au niveau international. Deuxièmement, ses agences dépositaires sont des BNS et non des agences internationales. En raison de ces caractéristiques, le PNUD, l&apos;UNICEF et la Banque mondiale collaborent en tant qu&apos;agences partenaires spéciales pour fournir une plate-forme pour compiler les données nationales sur l&apos;indicateur 1.2.2 des ODD et les télécharger dans la base de données mondiale sur les ODD, une fonction généralement remplie par les agences dépositaires. Alors que les agences partenaires spéciales s&apos;efforcent de s&apos;assurer que les données déclarées sont officielles et de bonne qualité, elles n&apos;effectuent aucune harmonisation ou autre traitement des données. Les lignes directrices sur les flux de données et la communication de données mondiales pour les ODD exigent également que les métadonnées nationales soient soumises en même temps que les données des ODD, afin de garantir l&apos;exactitude et la comparabilité internationale. La variété des méthodologies pour l&apos;indicateur 1.2.2 des ODD accroît la pertinence des métadonnées nationales en tant qu&apos;instrument pour garantir la haute qualité et l&apos;exactitude des données communiquées. Les trois agences disposent également de vastes portefeuilles d&apos;assistance technique et de soutien aux capacités des pays pour le développement de leurs mesures nationales de la pauvreté multidimensionnelle. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
