<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 1-2-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments and limitations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be clearly noted that data in the above-mentioned series are not comparable across countries. For instance, AF methodology and AROPE are fundamentally very different, and although both produce some headcount ratio of people who are considered as &amp;quot;multidimensionally poor&amp;quot;, their definition of multidimensionality of poverty is utterly different, and so should not be compared. Also, even when they use the same approach, such as, AF, AROPE or MODA, the numbers are not comparable across countries, as the important parameters to calculate the figures such as the number of indicators, the weight allocated to each indicator, how to divide the age group of children are tailored to the country specific context. Furthermore, even in the same country, if the methodology is different, the number should not be compared. For instance, some countries calculate child multidimensional poverty headcount by using both AF and MODA methodologies, but their numbers could be very different as the dimensions and indicators used in both approaches differ significantly. To overcome these comparability issues, UNDP produces global Multidimensional Poverty Index (MPI), which is the product of multiplying multidimensional headcount and average number of deprivations using the same dimensions and indicators covering more than 100 countries. However, most of these numbers are not officially approved by each country, and sometimes the nationally calculated MPI is different from the global MPI due to some difference of the parameters, therefore, in this platform, the global MPI is not included in the Global SDG Database. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commentaires et limites :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il convient de noter clairement que les données des séries susmentionnées ne sont pas comparables d&apos;un pays à l&apos;autre. Par exemple, la méthodologie AF et AROPE sont fondamentalement très différentes, et bien que les deux produisent un certain ratio d&apos;effectifs de personnes considérées comme &quot;multidimensionnellement pauvres&quot;, leur définition de la multidimensionnalité de la pauvreté est totalement différente, et ne doit donc pas être comparée . De plus, même lorsqu&apos;ils utilisent la même approche, comme AF, AROPE ou MODA, les chiffres ne sont pas comparables d&apos;un pays à l&apos;autre, car les paramètres importants pour calculer les chiffres tels que le nombre d&apos;indicateurs, le poids alloué à chaque indicateur et comment diviser le groupe d&apos;âge des enfants sont adaptés au contexte spécifique du pays. De plus, si la méthodologie est différente dans un même pays, le nombre ne doit pas être comparé. Par exemple, certains pays calculent la pauvreté multidimensionnelle des enfants en utilisant à la fois les méthodologies AF et MODA, mais leurs chiffres peuvent être très différents car les dimensions et les indicateurs utilisés dans les deux approches diffèrent considérablement. Pour surmonter ces problèmes de comparabilité, le PNUD produit un indice mondial de pauvreté multidimensionnelle (IPM), qui est le produit de la multiplication des effectifs multidimensionnels et du nombre moyen de privations en utilisant les mêmes dimensions et indicateurs couvrant plus de 100 pays. Cependant, la plupart de ces chiffres ne sont pas officiellement approuvés par chaque pays, et parfois l&apos;IPM calculé au niveau national est différent de l&apos;IPM mondial en raison de certaines différences de paramètres. Par conséquent, dans cette plate-forme, l&apos;IPM mondial n&apos;est pas inclus dans la base de données mondiale des ODD. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
