<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 1-2-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following four series are used to monitor the SDG 1.2.2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Official multidimensional poverty headcount, by sex, and age (% of population)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The percentage of people who are multidimensionally poor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) Average share of weighted deprivations (intensity) for total population&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The average share of weighted dimensions in which poor people are deprived among total population &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3) Official multidimensional poverty headcount (% of total households)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The percentage of households who are multidimensionally poor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4) Average share of weighted deprivations (intensity) for total households&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The average share of weighted dimensions in which poor people are deprived among total households &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5) Multidimensional deprivation for children (% of population under 18)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The percentage of children who are simultaneously deprived in multiple dimensions of well-being&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design of a measure of multidimensional poverty is different in each country, but regardless of the exact methodology selected, it still follows a similar process to define the features of the measure, which include: i) the purpose of the measure; ii) the unit of identification (most frequently either the household or the individuals); iii) the dimensions and respective indicators that delimit which deprivations should be measured; iv) the methodology for developing the measure (including deprivation cut-offs, weights, and poverty cut-offs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most commonly used method is the Alkire Foster (AF) methodology which identifies dimensions, typically health, education and living standards and several indicators in each dimension. The unit of analysis could be either the individual or the household. The individuals or households are considered as multidimensionally poor if they are deprived in multiple dimensions, exceeding certain thresholds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EU countries, North Macedonia and Turkey have a different approach to measure the multidimensional poverty using the concept of &amp;quot;people at risk of poverty or social exclusion&amp;quot; (AROPE) calculated by EUROSTAT using the data from EU statistics on income and living conditions (EU-SILC). AROPE consists of three indicators, and individuals are considered as &amp;quot;at risk of poverty or social exclusion&amp;quot; if they are &amp;quot;at risk of poverty&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;severely materially deprived&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;living in a household with a very low work intensity&amp;quot;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a multidimensional poverty measure specifically designed for children. A child is considered multidimensionally poor if s/he is simultaneously deprived in multiple dimensions. It identifies the dimensions of poverty and the indicators under each dimension, and has a similar structure to the AF methodology. However, it is different in that it focuses on the life-cycle of children, creating different sets of dimensions and indicators for different age groups (e.g., for ages 0-4, 5-11, 12-14, 15-17 years), and conducts analyses separately for each age group. In the global SDG database, the multidimensional poverty headcount (%) for the overall 0-17 age group has been used for countries reporting individual measures of child multidimensional poverty.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Définition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les quatre séries suivantes sont utilisées pour suivre l’ODD 1.2.2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dénombrement officiel de la pauvreté multidimensionnelle, selon le sexe et l’âge (% de la population)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Le pourcentage de personnes qui sont multidimensionnellement pauvres&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nombre moyen de privations (intensité)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Le pourcentage moyen de dimensions desquelles les pauvres sont privés&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dénombrement officiel de la pauvreté multidimensionnelle (% du total des ménages)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Le pourcentage de ménages qui sont multidimensionnellement pauvres&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Privation multidimensionnelle chez les enfants (% de la population de moins de 18 ans)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Le pourcentage d’enfants qui sont simultanément privés de multiples dimensions du bien-être&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Concepts :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le dénombrement officiel de la pauvreté multidimensionnelle est calculé par chaque pays à l’aide de méthodologies différentes. La méthode la plus couramment utilisée est la méthodologie Alkire Foster (AF) qui identifie les dimensions, généralement la santé, l’éducation et les niveaux de vie et plusieurs indicateurs dans chaque dimension. L’unité d’analyse peut être individuelle ou domestique. Les individus ou les ménages sont considérés comme multidimensionnellement pauvres s’ils sont privés dans de multiples indicateurs dépassant certains seuils. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; D’autre part, les pays de l’UE et la Macédoine du Nord utilisent une approche complètement différente pour mesurer la pauvreté multidimensionnelle en utilisant le concept de « personnes menacées de pauvreté ou d’exclusion sociale » (AROPE). L’AROPE se compose de trois indicateurs, et les personnes seront considérées comme « à risque de pauvreté ou d’exclusion sociale » si elles sont « à risque de pauvreté » ou « gravement démunies matériellement » ou « vivant dans un ménage avec une très faible intensité de travail ». &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La privation multidimensionnelle chez les enfants est calculée sur la base de la méthodologie appelée analyse du chevauchement des privations multiples (MODA). Un enfant est considéré comme multidimensionnellement pauvre s’il est simultanément privé dans plusieurs dimensions. La méthodologie identifie également les dimensions et les indicateurs sous chaque dimension, et a une structure similaire à la méthodologie AF. Cependant, elle est étonnamment différente puisqu&apos;elle se concentre sur le cycle de vie des enfants et crée différents ensembles de dimensions et d’indicateurs pour différents groupes d’âge, par exemple, 0-4, 5-11, 12-14, 15-17, et effectue une analyse séparément pour chaque groupe d’âge. Dans la base de données mondiale sur les ODD, le dénombrement multidimensionnel de la pauvreté (%) pour l’ensemble de la tranche d’âge de 0 à 17 ans a été utilisé. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
