<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 3-3-4, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimates are available for 194 Member States and for the six WHO Regions, as well as at global level. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimates are available for pre- vaccine era, 2015 and 2018 and 2020 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;age groups (i.e. under five years of age, 5 years and older (although these estimates are not reported) and the general population); sex/gender if possible. Although the data for the latter is scarce. In addition, data at national, regional and global level. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt; Disponibilidad de los datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Se dispone de estimaciones para 194 Estados Miembros y para las seis Regiones de la OMS, así como a nivel mundial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Serie temporal:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Las estimaciones están disponibles para la era prevacuna, mientras que las estimaciones de 2015 y 2017 están en proceso de revisión.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Grupos de edad (es decir, menores de cinco años y población en general); sexo/género si es posible. Aunque los datos de estos últimos son escasos. Además, datos a nivel nacional, regional y mundial.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disponibilité des données :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des estimations sont disponibles pour 194 États membres et pour les six régions de l&apos;OMS, ainsi qu&apos;au niveau mondial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Séries chronologiques :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des estimations sont disponibles pour l&apos;ère pré-vaccinale, 2015, 2018 et 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Désagrégation :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les variables disponibles sont : groupes d&apos;âge (c&apos;est-à-dire les moins de cinq ans, les cinq ans et plus (bien que ces estimations ne sont pas déclarées) et la population générale); sexe / genre si possible. Bien que les données concernant ce dernier point soient rares. En outre, les données sont disponibles aux niveaux national, régional et mondial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Оценки доступны по 194 государствам-членам и шести регионам ВОЗ, а также на глобальном уровне. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Имеются оценки на период до вакцинации, оценки за 2015 и 2017 годы находятся в процессе пересмотра. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Возрастные группы (т.е. моложе пяти лет и общая совокупность населения); пол / гендер, если возможно. Хотя данных по последнему показателю немного. Кроме того, имеются данные на национальном, региональном и глобальном уровне. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
