<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The QUALITY_ASSURE field for indicator 3-3-4, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Quality assurance:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WHO&amp;#x2019;s estimates use a methodology reviewed by the Immunization and Vaccines Related Implementation Research Advisory Committee (IVIR-AC) and presented to the Strategic Advisory Group of Experts (SAGE). These estimates have been documented following the Guidelines for Accurate and Transparent Health Estimates Reporting (GATHER).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WHO provided Member States the opportunity to review and comment on data and estimates as part of the so called country consultation process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Assurance de la qualité : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Les estimations de l&apos;OMS utilisent une méthodologie examinée par le Comité consultatif de recherche sur la mise en œuvre de la vaccination et des vaccins (IVIR-AC) et présentée au Groupe consultatif stratégique d&apos;experts (SAGE). Ces estimations ont été documentées en suivant les Directives pour une communication précise et transparente des estimations sanitaires (GATHER).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;L&apos;OMS a donné aux États membres la possibilité d&apos;examiner et de commenter les données et les estimations dans le cadre du processus dit de consultation des pays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Обеспечение качества: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; В оценках ВОЗ используется методология, рассмотренная Консультативным комитетом по исследованиям в области иммунизации и вакцинации (IVIR-AC) и представленная Стратегической консультативной группе экспертов (СКГЭ) по иммунизации. Эти оценки были задокументированы в соответствии с Руководством по составлению точных и прозрачных отчетов об оценках здоровья (GATHER). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; ВОЗ предоставила государствам-членам возможность проанализировать и прокомментировать данные и оценки в рамках так называемого процесса страновых консультаций. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
