<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 3-3-4, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator is measured indirectly through the proportion of children 5 years of age who have developed chronic HBV infection (i.e. the proportion that tests positive for a marker of infection called hepatitis B surface antigen [HBsAg]).&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-1&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hepatitis B surface antigen: a protein from the virus&amp;#x2019;s coat. A positive test for HBsAg indicates active HBV infection. The immune response to HBsAg provides the basis for immunity against HBV, and HBsAg is the main component of HepB.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Global Hepatitis Report 2017. World Health Organization. ISBN 978-92-4-156545-5. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Documenting the Impact of Hepatitis B Immunization: best practices for conducting a serosurvey. Immunization, Vaccines and Biologicals. World Health Organization. WHO/IVB/11.08 &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt; Conceptos y definiciones &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Definición: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Este indicador se mide indirectamente a través de la proporción de niños de 5 años que han desarrollado una infección crónica por el VHB (es decir, la proporción que da positivo en un marcador de infección llamado antígeno de superficie de la hepatitis B [HBsAg]). &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-1&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;[1] &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Antígeno de superficie de la hepatitis B: una proteína de la cubierta del virus. Una prueba positiva para HBsAg indica una infección activa por VHB. La respuesta inmunitaria al HBsAg proporciona la base para la inmunidad contra el VHB, y el HBsAg es el componente principal de la Hepatitis B. &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt; [2] &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Conceptos: &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-1&quot;&gt; 1 &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Informe mundial sobre hepatitis 2017. Organización Mundial de la Salud. ISBN 978-92-4-156545-5. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt; 2 &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Documentación del impacto de la inmunización contra la hepatitis B: mejores prácticas para realizar una encuesta serológica. Inmunizaciones, Vacunas y Biológicos. Organización Mundial de la Salud. WHO / IVB / 11.08 &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Définition : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur est mesuré indirectement par la proportion d&apos;enfants de 5 ans qui ont développé une infection chronique par le virus de l&apos;hépatite B (VHB) (c&apos;est-à-dire la proportion de ceux qui sont testés positifs pour un marqueur d&apos;infection appelé antigène de surface de l&apos;hépatite B [HBsAg])&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-1&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antigène de surface de l&apos;hépatite B : une protéine du manteau du virus. Un test positif pour l&apos;antigène de surface du virus de l&apos;hépatite B (HBsAg) indique une infection active par le VHB. La réponse immunitaire à l&apos;antigène constitue la base de l&apos;immunité contre le VHB, et l&apos;HBsAg est le principal composant de l&apos;hépatite B &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt; [2] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts : &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-1&quot;&gt;1 &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p&gt; Rapport mondial sur l&apos;hépatite 2017. Organisation mondiale de la santé. ISBN 978-92-4-156545-5. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Documenter l&apos;impact de la vaccination contre l&apos;hépatite B : meilleures pratiques pour la conduite d&apos;une enquête sérologique. Immunisation, vaccins et produits biologiques. Organisation mondiale de la santé. WHO/IVB/11.08 &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Этот показатель косвенно отображается посредством доли детей в возрасте 5 лет, у которых развилась хроническая инфекция вируса гепатита В (ВГВ) (т.е. доли детей с положительным результатом теста на маркер инфекции, называемой поверхностным антигеном вируса гепатита B [HBsAg]). &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-1&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Поверхностный антиген вируса гепатита В: белок оболочки вируса. Положительный тест на HBsAg указывает на активную инфекцию ВГВ. Иммунная реакция на HBsAg обеспечивает основу иммунитета против ВГВ, а HBsAg является основным компонентом гепатита B. &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Глобальный доклад по гепатиту, 2017 год. Всемирная организация здравоохранения. ISBN 978-92-4-156545-5. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Документирование воздействия иммунизации против гепатита B: передовой опыт проведения серологического исследования. Иммунизация, вакцины и биопрепараты. Всемирная организация здравоохранения. ВОЗ / IVB / 11.08 &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
