<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 7-3-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IEA and UN Energy Balances combined provide total energy supply data for all countries on an annual basis. GDP data are available for most countries on an annual basis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2000 &amp;#x2013; present &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disaggregation of energy intensity, e.g. by final consumption sectors or end-uses, could provide further insights into progress towards energy efficiency. At present it is only feasible to calculate such sector disaggregation for the following sectors &amp;#x2013; industry, residential, transport, agriculture, households &amp;#x2013; as reported in the Tracking SDG7: The Energy Progress Report (formerly Sustainable Energy for All Global Tracking Framework). It would be desirable, over time, to develop more refined sectoral level energy intensity indicators that make it possible to look at energy intensity by industry (e.g. cement, steel) or by type of vehicle (e.g. cars, trucks), for example. Doing so will not be possible without further statistical data collection, also including collaboration with relevant institutions and energy consumers. Full methodological explanations are provided in the IEA &lt;em&gt;Energy Efficiency Indicators: Fundamentals on Statistics &lt;/em&gt;manual available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iea.org/reports/energy-efficiency-indicators-fundamentals-on-statistics&quot;&gt;iea.org/reports/energy-efficiency-indicators-fundamentals-on-statistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decomposition analysis of energy intensity trends seeks to filter out factors that affect energy demand, such as economy wide scale and structure shifts, from more narrowly defined energy intensity shifts. This analysis is also reported in the &lt;em&gt;Tracking SDG7: The Energy Progress Report&lt;/em&gt; or in the &lt;em&gt;IEA Energy Efficiency Indicators Highlights&lt;/em&gt; available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iea.org/reports/energy-efficiency-indicators-fundamentals-on-statistics&quot;&gt;iea.org/reports/energy-efficiency-indicators&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los balances energéticos de la AIE y de la ONU combinados proporcionan datos sobre el suministro total de energía para todos los países sobre una base anual. Los datos del PIB están disponibles para la mayoría de los países sobre una base anual. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1990-actualidad &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La desagregación de la intensidad energética, por ejemplo, por sectores de consumo final o usos finales, podría proporcionar más información sobre el progreso hacia la eficiencia energética. En la actualidad, sólo es posible calcular tales desgloses sectoriales para los siguientes sectores &amp;#x2013;: industria, residencial, transporte, agricultura y hogares &amp;#x2013;, tal y como se recoge en el &lt;em&gt;Seguimiento del ODS7: Informe sobre los progresos realizados en materia de energía&lt;/em&gt; (anteriormente &lt;em&gt;Marco de seguimiento mundial de la energía sostenible para todos&lt;/em&gt;). Sería deseable, con el tiempo, desarrollar indicadores de intensidad energética a nivel sectorial más refinados que permitan observar la intensidad energética por industria (por ejemplo, cemento, acero) o por tipo de vehículo (por ejemplo, coches, camiones), por ejemplo. Esto no será posible sin la colaboración estadística de los sectores consumidores de energía pertinentes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; El análisis de descomposición de las tendencias de la intensidad energética trata de filtrar los factores que afectan a la demanda de energía, como los cambios de escala y estructura de la economía, de los cambios de intensidad energética definidos más estrictamente. La metodología aplica el análisis de descomposición para aislar una medida más refinada de la intensidad energética, una que tamiza el cambio temporal de los pesos relativos del sector. Este análisis también se recoge en el &lt;em&gt;Seguimiento del ODS7: Informe sobre los progresos en materia de energía&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilité des données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les bilans énergétiques combinés de l&apos;AIE et des Nations unies fournissent des données sur l&apos;approvisionnement total en énergie pour tous les pays sur une base annuelle. Les données relatives au PIB sont disponibles pour la plupart des pays sur une base annuelle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Séries chronologiques : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1990-présent &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Désagrégation : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La ventilation de l&apos;intensité énergétique, par exemple par secteur de consommation finale ou par utilisation finale, pourrait fournir des indications supplémentaires sur les progrès réalisés en matière d&apos;efficacité énergétique. À l&apos;heure actuelle, il n&apos;est possible de calculer ces ventilations sectorielles que pour les secteurs suivants : industrie, résidentiel, transport, agriculture, ménages, comme indiqué dans le &lt;em&gt;Tracking SDG7 : The Energy Progress Report &lt;/em&gt; (anciennement &lt;em&gt;Sustainable Energy for All Global Tracking Framework &lt;/em&gt;). Il serait souhaitable, avec le temps, de développer des indicateurs d&apos;intensité énergétique plus affinés au niveau sectoriel qui permettent d&apos;examiner l&apos;intensité énergétique par industrie (par exemple, ciment, acier) ou par type de véhicule (par exemple, voitures, camions), par exemple. Cela ne sera pas possible sans une collaboration statistique avec les secteurs consommateurs d&apos;énergie concernés. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;analyse de la décomposition des tendances de l&apos;intensité énergétique cherche à filtrer les facteurs qui affectent la demande d&apos;énergie, tels que les changements d&apos;échelle et de structure des économies à grande échelle, des changements d&apos;intensité énergétique plus étroitement définis. La méthodologie applique l&apos;analyse de la décomposition pour isoler une mesure plus précise de l&apos;intensité énergétique, qui élimine le décalage temporel des poids relatifs des secteurs. Cette analyse est également présentée dans le &lt;em&gt;Tracking SDG7 : The Energy Progress Report &lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Энергетические балансы МЭА и ООН вместе взятые предоставляют данные по общим поставкам энергии по всем странам на годовой основе. Данные по ВВП доступны по большинству стран на годовой основе. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временный ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; С 1990 года по настоящее время &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Дезагрегирование по энергоемкости, например по секторам конечного потребления или конечным пользователям, может дать дополнительные аналитические оценки, касающиеся прогресса в области энергоэффективности. В настоящее время возможно рассчитать такую секторальную разбивку только для следующих секторов - промышленность, жилищное строительство, транспорт, сельское хозяйство, домашние хозяйства - как указано в &lt;em&gt; Отслеживании ЦУР 7: Отчет о прогрессе в энергетике&lt;/em&gt; (ранее известном как &lt;em&gt;Рамочная программа глобального отслеживания устойчивой энергетики для всех&lt;/em&gt;). Было бы желательно со временем разработать более точные показатели энергоемкости на секторальном уровне, которые позволили бы рассматривать энергоемкость по отраслям (например, цемент, сталь) или по типу транспортных средств (например, легковые и грузовые автомобили). Это будет невозможно без статистического сотрудничества с соответствующими энергопотребляющими секторами. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Анализ методом разложения тенденций энергоемкости призван отфильтровать факторы, влияющие на спрос на энергию, такие как масштаб экономики и структурные сдвиги, из более узко определенных сдвигов в энергоемкости. В методологии применяется анализ методом разложения с тем, чтобы выделить более точный показатель энергоемкости, который отсеивает временной сдвиг относительных весов секторов. Этот анализ также представлен в &lt;em&gt;Отслеживании ЦУР 7: Отчет о прогрессе в энергетике&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
