<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for the indicator 8-a-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;Goal 8: Promote sustained, inclusive and sustainable economic growth, full and productive employment and decent work for all&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 8.a: Increase Aid for Trade support for developing countries, in particular least developed countries, including through the Enhanced Integrated Framework for Trade-related Technical Assistance to Least Developed Countries&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 8.a.1: Aid for Trade commitments and disbursements&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last updated: 19 July 2016&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Institutional information&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organization(s):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aid for Trade commitments and disbursements is the gross disbursements and commitments of total Official Development Assistance (ODA) from all donors for aid for trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DAC defines Official Development Assistance (ODA) as &amp;#x201C;those flows to countries and territories on the DAC List of ODA Recipients and to multilateral institutions which are i) provided by official agencies, including state and local governments, or by their executive agencies; and ii) each transaction is administered with the promotion of the economic development and welfare of developing countries as its main objective; and is concessional in character and conveys a grant element of at least 25 per cent (calculated at a rate of discount of 10 per cent). (See &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other official flows (OOF),excluding officially supported export credits, are defined as transactions by the official sector which do not meet the conditions for eligibility as ODA, either because they are not primarily aimed at development, or because they are not sufficiently concessional. See &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/documentupload/DCDDAC(2016)3FINAL.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/documentupload/DCDDAC(2016)3FINAL.pdf&lt;/a&gt;, Para 24.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aid for Trade is captured in the CRS through sector codes in the 331 series and the aid for trade marker. see here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/purposecodessectorclassification.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/purposecodessectorclassification.htm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2018;All donors&amp;#x2019; refers to DAC donors, non-DAC donors and multilateral organisations. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OECD/DAC has been collecting data on official and private resource flows from 1960 at an aggregate level and 1973 at an activity level through the Creditor Reporting System (CRS data are considered complete from 1995 for commitments at an activity level and 2002 for disbursements).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data are reported by donors according to the same standards and methodologies (see here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are reported on an annual calendar year basis by statistical reporters in national administrations (aid agencies, Ministries of Foreign Affairs or Finance, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Collection process:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A statistical reporter is responsible for the collection of DAC statistics in each providing country/agency. This reporter is usually located in the national aid agency, Ministry of Foreign Affairs or Finance etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendar&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Data collection:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are published on an annual basis in December for flows in the previous year. Detailed 2015 flows will be published in December 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Data release:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;December 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data providers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are reported on an annual calendar year basis by statistical reporters in national administrations (aid agencies, Ministries of Foreign Affairs or Finance, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data compilers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OECD&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Rationale:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total Official Development Assistance (ODA) and Other Official Flows (OOF) to developing countries quantify the public effort that donors provide to developing countries for aid for trade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comments and limitations:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data in the Creditor Reporting System are available from 1973. However, the data coverage is considered complete from 1995 for commitments at an activity level and 2002 for disbursements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computation method:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sum of ODA and OOF flows from all donors to developing countries for aid for trade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Treatment of missing values:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At country level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to high quality of reporting, no estimates are produced for missing data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At regional and global levels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not applicable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Regional aggregates:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global and regional figures are based on the sum of ODA and OOF flows for aid for trade activities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data availability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a donor basis for all DAC countries and many non-DAC providers (bilateral and multilateral) that report to the DAC on aid for scholarships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a recipient basis for all developing countries eligible for ODA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator can be disaggregated by donor, recipient country, type of finance, type of aid, trade policy and regulations and trade related adjustment sub-sectors, etc..&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DAC statistics are standardized on a calendar year basis for all donors and may differ from fiscal year data available in budget documents for some countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;www.oecd.org/dac/stats&quot;&gt;www.oecd.org/dac/stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See all links here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
