<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 14-b-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data is based on the replies to three questions of the CCRF questionnaire. It is usually provided from administrative sources, as best identified by the national fisheries administration responsible for replying to the CCRF questionnaire. The data is based on the presence of relevant laws, regulations, policies, plans or strategies and how these have been implemented so both legislative, management, and other documentation must be consulted to respond to the queries.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Sources de données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont basées sur les réponses à trois questions du questionnaire de la CCRF. Elles proviennent généralement de sources administratives, identifiées au mieux par l&apos;administration nationale des pêches chargée de répondre au questionnaire de la CCRF. Les données sont basées sur la présence de lois, de règlements, de politiques, de plans ou de stratégies pertinents et sur la manière dont ils ont été mis en œuvre, de sorte que la documentation législative, de gestion et autre doit être consultée pour répondre aux questions.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные основаны на ответах на три вопроса из вопросника Кодекса ведения ответственного рыболовства (КВОР). Обычно информация предоставляется из административных источников, лучшим из которых является национальная администрация рыболовства, ответственная за подготовку ответов на вопросник КВОР. Данные основаны на наличии соответствующих законов, постановлений, обязательных политических процедур, планов или стратегий, а также на том, как они были реализованы, поэтому для ответа на запросы необходимо обращаться к законодательной, управленческой и другой документации. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
