<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 2-2-2b, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Child growth is an internationally accepted outcome reflecting child nutritional status. Child wasting refers to a child who is too thin for his or her height and is the result of recent rapid weight loss or the failure to gain weight. A child who is moderately or severely wasted has an increased risk of death, but treatment is possible. Child wasting is one of the World Health Assembly nutrition target indicators.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El crecimiento infantil es un resultado aceptado internacionalmente que refleja el estado nutricional del niño. La emaciación infantil se refiere a un niño que está demasiado delgado para su estatura y es el resultado de una rápida pérdida de peso reciente o de la imposibilidad de ganar peso. Un niño con emaciación moderada o grave tiene un mayor riesgo de muerte, pero es posible tratarlo. La emaciación infantil es uno de los indicadores objetivo de nutrición de la Asamblea Mundial de la Salud.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;La croissance de l&apos;enfant est un résultat internationalement accepté reflétant l&apos;état nutritionnel de l&apos;enfant. L&apos;émaciation infantile fait référence à un enfant trop maigre pour sa taille et est le résultat d&apos;une perte de poids rapide récente ou d&apos;un manque de poids. Un enfant émacié modérément ou gravement a un risque accru de décès, mais un traitement est possible. L&apos;émaciation infantile est l&apos;un des indicateurs cibles de la nutrition de l&apos;Assemblée mondiale de la Santé. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Рост ребенка - это международно-признанный показатель, отражающий состояние питания ребенка. Определение &quot;детское истощение&quot; относится к ребенку, который слишком худ для своего роста и это является результатом недавней быстрой потери веса или неспособности набрать вес. Ребенок с умеренной или тяжелой формой истощения имеет повышенный риск наступления смерти, но лечение возможно. Детское истощение является одним из целевых показателей Всемирной ассамблеи здравоохранения в области питания. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
