<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 9-1-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definitions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passenger and freight volumes are respectively measured in passenger-km and tonne-km, and broken down by mode of transport. For the purposes of monitoring this indicator, passenger-km data are split between aviation, road (broken down between passenger cars, buses and motorcycles) and rail, and tonne-km are split between aviation, road, rail and inland waterways. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As maritime data are not widely available, only tonnes (rather than tonne-km) data at the regional level have been shared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aviation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The International Civil Aviation Organization (ICAO) through its Statistics Division have established standard methodologies and definitions to collect and report traffic (passenger and freight volume) data related to air transport. These standards and methodologies have been adopted by the 191 Member States of ICAO and also by the Industry stakeholders i.e. air carriers and airports. The data of ICAO is used by States and also the World Bank for its development indicators. ICAO uses Air Transport Reporting Forms A, AS, B and C to arrive at the passenger and freight volumes for air transport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Precise definition of all different concepts and metadata related to Air Transport Reporting Forms A, AS, B and C to arrive at the passenger and freight volumes for air transport. approved by the ICAO Statistics Division and Member States can be found at the ICAO website given below -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.icao.int/sustainability/pages/eap-sta-excel.aspx/&quot;&gt;http://www.icao.int/sustainability/pages/eap-sta-excel.aspx/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Road, Rail, Inland waterways, Pipelines&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ITF and UNECE, in collaboration with Eurostat, collect data on rail and road, inland waterway and pipeline statistics on an annual basis from all their collective Member countries. Data are collected from Transport Ministries, statistical offices and other institution designated as official data source. Although there are clear definitions for all the terms used in this survey, countries might have different methodologies to calculate tonne-kilometres and passenger-kilometres. Methods could be based on traffic or mobility surveys, use very different sampling methods and estimating techniques which could affect the comparability of their statistics. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Official statistics for road, rail, inland waterways and pipeline transport are only available for UNECE or ITF member States. Data for these modes for other countries come from the ITF&amp;#x2019;s global transport model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For definitions of all relevant terms, the UNECE/ITF/Eurostat Glossary for Transport Statistics can be consulted. The 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; edition of this publication should be released in 2019. The fourth edition from 2009 is available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unece.org/fileadmin/DAM/trans/main/wp6/pdfdocs/glossen4.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.unece.org/fileadmin/DAM/trans/main/wp6/pdfdocs/glossen4.pdf&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
