<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 16-5-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collection process:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The World Bank conducts the Enterprise Surveys in client countries. The surveys are comparable as the survey methodology is applied in a consistent manner across countries: obtaining suitable sample frames, eligibility criteria for respondent firms, survey sample design, core questionnaire elements across every country, standardized QC checks on the received data, standardized computation of sampling weights, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Processus de collecte :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Banque mondiale mène les Enquêtes sur les entreprises dans les pays clients. Les enquêtes sont comparables car la méthodologie d&apos;enquête est appliquée de manière cohérente dans tous les pays : obtention de bases de sondage, critères d&apos;éligibilité des entreprises interrogées, plan de sondage, éléments du questionnaire de base, contrôles de qualité normalisés, calcul normalisé des poids d&apos;échantillonnage, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Процесс сбора:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Всемирный банк проводит Обследования предприятий в странах-клиентах. Обследования сопоставимы, поскольку методология обследования применяется согласованным образом в различных странах: приобретение надлежащего инструментария для проведения выборочного обследования, критерии отбора фирм-респондентов, план выборки обследования, основные элементы вопросника для каждой страны, стандартизированные процедуры проверки качества полученных данных, стандартизированный расчет весов выборки и т. д.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
