<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 16-5-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator value is not imputed for countries which do not have an Enterprise Survey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regional and global aggregates of the indicator are derived from completed surveys. A single point estimate is created for each country and a global/regional aggregate takes a simple average of every country&amp;#x2019;s point estimate (when there is available data for that country). For example the East Asia Pacific average (point estimate) for the indicator does not include Japan since there is no Enterprise Survey for Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A nivel de país:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El valor del indicador no se imputa para los países que no disponen de una encuesta de empresas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A nivel regional y mundial:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los agregados regionales y globales del indicador se derivan de las encuestas completadas. Se crea una única estimación puntual para cada país y un agregado global/regional toma una media simple de la estimación puntual de cada país(cuando hay datos disponibles para ese país). Por ejemplo, la media (estimación puntual) del indicador para Asia Oriental y el Pacífico no incluye a Japón, ya que no existe una encuesta de empresas para este país.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traitement des valeurs manquantes :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Au niveau national :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur n&apos;est pas imputé pour les pays pour lesquels il n&apos;y a pas de données.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aux niveaux régional et international :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les agrégats régionaux et mondiaux sont dérivés des enquêtes complétées. Une estimation ponctuelle unique est créée pour chaque pays et les agrégats mondial/régionaux constituent une moyenne simple des estimations ponctuelles des pays, lorsqu&apos;il y a des données disponibles. Par exemple, la moyenne de l&apos;Asie de l&apos;Est et du Pacifique (estimation ponctuelle) n&apos;inclut pas le Japon puisqu&apos;il n&apos;y a pas de données pour ce pays.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Значение показателя не вменяется для стран, которые не проводят обследование предприятий.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Региональные и глобальные агрегаты этого показателя получены на основе данных завершенных обследований. Для каждой страны производится одна элементная оценка, а глобальный / региональный агрегат является средним арифметическим значением элементных оценок для каждой страны (если имеются данные для этой страны). Например, среднее значение (точечной оценки) данного показателя для Восточной Азии и Тихоокеанского региона не включает Японию, поскольку в Японии не проводится обследование предприятий.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
