<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 16-5-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rationale for this indicator is to ascertain whether firms are solicited for gifts or informal payments (i.e. bribes) when meeting with tax officials. Paying taxes are required of formal forms in most countries and hence the rational for this indicator is to measure the incidence of corruption during this routine interaction. The key strength of the Enterprise Survey is that most of the questions in the survey pertain to the actual, day-to-day experiences of the firm; this question regarding corruption during tax inspections/meetings is not an opinion-based question but rather a question grounded in the firm&amp;#x2019;s reality.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Justificación: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La justificación de este indicador es determinar si se solicita a las empresas obsequios o pagos informales (es decir, sobornos) cuando se reúnen con funcionarios fiscales. El pago de impuestos es un requisito formal en la mayoría de los países y, por lo tanto, la razón de este indicador es medir la incidencia de la corrupción durante esta interacción rutinaria. La fortaleza clave de Enterprise Survey es que la mayoría de las preguntas de la encuesta pertenecen a las experiencias reales del día a día de la empresa; esta cuestión relativa a la corrupción durante las inspecciones / reuniones fiscales no es una cuestión de opinión, sino más bien una cuestión basada en la realidad de la empresa &amp;#x2019;. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Justification :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur vise à vérifier si les entreprises sont sollicitées pour des cadeaux ou des paiements informels (c&apos;est-à-dire des pots-de-vin) lors de leurs rencontres avec les agents du fisc. Dans la plupart des pays, le paiement des impôts est exigé par des interactions formelles et cet indicateur vise à mesurer l&apos;incidence de la corruption lors de ces interactions. La force principale des Enquêtes sur les entreprises est que la plupart de ses questions se rapportent aux expériences réelles et quotidiennes des entreprises. Par exemple, cette question concernant la corruption lors des inspections/réunions fiscales n&apos;est pas une question d&apos;opinion mais plutôt une question liée à la réalité des entreprises.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Обоснование:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Обоснование этого показателя заключается в том, чтобы выяснить, вымогают ли при встречах налоговые чиновники у фирм подарки или неофициальные платежи (т.е. взятки). В большинстве стран уплата налогов является формальной процедурой, и, следовательно, обоснованием для данного показателя является оценка распространенности коррупции в ходе такого рутинного взаимодействия. Основным преимуществом Обследования предприятий является то, что большинство вопросов в нем относится к фактическому, каждодневному опыту фирмы; вопрос, касающийся коррупции во время налоговых проверок/встреч, не является вопросом, ответ на который основан на мнении, а скорее вопросом, ответ на который основан на реальном положении дел.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
