<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The OTHER_DOC field for indicator 5-5-1b, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;ECLAC, 2016a. CEPALSTAT: Databases and statistical publications. https://oig.cepal.org/en/autonomies/autonomy-decision-making (accessed January-April 2016)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European Commission, 2016a. Database on women and men in decision-making (WMID). &lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/justice/gender-equality/gender-decision-making/database/index_en.htm&quot;&gt;http://ec.europa.eu/justice/gender-equality/gender-decision-making/database/index_en.htm&lt;/a&gt; (accessed January-April 2016)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European Commission, International Monetary Fund, Organization for Economic Co-operation, and Development, United Nations, and the World Bank, 2009&lt;em&gt;. The 2008 System of National Accounts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Praia City Group on Governance Statistics, 2020. Handbook on Governance Statistics. https://localgov.unwomen.org/sites/default/files/resource-pdf/2021-04/Handbook_governance_statistics.pdf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNECE, 2016a. Public life and decision-making database. &lt;a href=&quot;http://w3.unece.org/PXWeb2015/pxweb/en/STAT/STAT__30-GE__05-PublicAnddecision&quot;&gt;http://w3.unece.org/PXWeb2015/pxweb/en/STAT/STAT__30-GE__05-PublicAnddecision&lt;/a&gt; (accessed January-April 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNDP, 2014. Gender Equality: Women&amp;#x2019;s participation and leadership in governments at the local level. Asia and the Pacific 2013. Bangkok, UNDP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations, 2011. &lt;em&gt;Using Administrative and Secondary Sources for Official Statistics: A Handbook of Principles and Practices&lt;/em&gt;. UNECE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UN Women, 2021. Women in Local Government Website. &lt;a href=&quot;https://localgov.unwomen.org/&quot;&gt;https://localgov.unwomen.org/&lt;/a&gt; (accessed May 2023).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UN Women and UNDP, 2015. Inclusive Electoral Processes: A guide for Electoral Management Bodies on Promoting Gender Equality and Women&amp;#x2019;s Participation.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEPAL, 2016a. CEPALSTAT: Bases de datos y publicaciones estadísticas. &lt;a href=&quot;http://interwp.cepal.org/sisgen/ConsultaIntegrada.asp?idAplicacion=11&amp;amp;idioma=e&quot;&gt;http://interwp.cepal.org/sisgen/ConsultaIntegrada.asp?idAplicacion=11&amp;amp;idioma=e&lt;/a&gt; (consultado entre enero y abril de 2016)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comisión Europea, 2016a. Base de datos sobre mujeres y hombres en la toma de decisiones (WMID). &lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/justice/gender-equality/gender-decision-making/database/index_en.htm&quot;&gt;http://ec.europa.eu/justice/gender-equality/gender-decision-making/database/index_en.htm&lt;/a&gt; (consultado en enero-abril de 2016)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comisión Europea, Fondo Monetario Internacional, Organización para la Cooperación y el Desarrollo Económico, Naciones Unidas y Banco Mundial, 2009&lt;em&gt;. Sistema de Cuentas Nacionales 2008.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNECE, 2016a. Base de datos sobre la vida pública y la toma de decisiones. &lt;a href=&quot;http://w3.unece.org/PXWeb2015/pxweb/en/STAT/STAT__30-GE__05-PublicAnddecision&quot;&gt;http://w3.unece.org/PXWeb2015/pxweb/en/STAT/STAT__30-GE__05-PublicAnddecision&lt;/a&gt; (accessed January-April 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PNUD, 2014. Igualdad de género: Participación y liderazgo de las mujeres en los gobiernos a nivel local. Asia y el Pacífico 2013. Bangkok, PNUD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naciones Unidas, 2011. &lt;em&gt;Utilización de fuentes administrativas y secundarias para las estadísticas oficiales: Un manual de principios y prácticas&lt;/em&gt;. UNECE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNPAN (Red de Administración Pública de las Naciones Unidas), 2016. Glosario de administración pública de la ONU. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unpan.org/Directories/Glossary/tabid/1398/language/en-US/Default.aspx%20&quot;&gt;http://www.unpan.org/Directories/Glossary/tabid/1398/language/en-US/Default.aspx&lt;/a&gt; (marzo de 2016)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONU Mujeres, 2017. Examen de las constituciones nacionales y las leyes de los gobiernos locales. Sin publicar. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONU Mujeres y el PNUD, 2015. Procesos electorales inclusivos: Una guía para los organismos de gestión electoral sobre la promoción de la igualdad de género y la participación de las mujeres.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;(À moins d&apos;indication contraire, les références sont en anglais)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEPALC, 2016a. « CEPALSTAT: Databases and statistical publications ». &lt;a href=&quot;http://interwp.cepal.org/sisgen/ConsultaIntegrada.asp?idAplicacion=11&amp;amp;idioma=e&quot;&gt;http://interwp.cepal.org/sisgen/ConsultaIntegrada.asp?idAplicacion=11&amp;amp;idioma=e&lt;/a&gt; (consulté janvier-avril 2016)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commission européenne, 2016a. Base de données sur les femmes et les hommes dans la prise de décision. &lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/info/policies/justice-and-fundamental-rights/gender-equality_fr&quot;&gt;https://ec.europa.eu/info/policies/justice-and-fundamental-rights/gender-equality_fr&lt;/a&gt; (consulté janvier-avril 2016)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commission européenne, Fonds monétaire international, Organisation de coopération et de développement économiques, Nations Unies et Banque mondiale, 2009.&lt;em&gt;Le Système des comptes nationaux de 2008&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNECE, 2016a. « Public life and decision-making database ». &lt;a href=&quot;http://w3.unece.org/PXWeb2015/pxweb/en/STAT/STAT__30-GE__05-PublicAnddecision&quot;&gt;http://w3.unece.org/PXWeb2015/pxweb/fr/STAT/STAT__30-GE__05-PublicAnddecision&lt;/a&gt; (consulté de janvier à avril 2016). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PNUD, 2014. « Gender Equality: Women&apos;s participation and leadership in governments at the local level ». Asie et Pacifique 2013. Bangkok, PNUD. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nations Unies, 2011.« Using Administrative and Secondary Sources for Official Statistics: A Handbook of Principles and Practices ». UNECE. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNPAN (Réseau d’administration publique des Nations Unies), 2016. « UN Public Administration Glossary ». http://www.unpan.org/Directories/Glossary/tabid/1398/language/en-US/Default.aspx (mars 2016)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONU Femmes, 2017. « Review of National Constitutions and Local Government Acts ». Non publié. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONU Femmes et PNUD, 2015. « Inclusive Electoral Processes: A guide for Electoral Management Bodies on Promoting Gender Equality and Women&apos;s Participation ». &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ЭКЛАК, 2016a. CEPALSTAT: Базы данных и статистические публикации. &lt;a href=&quot;http://interwp.cepal.org/sisgen/ConsultaIntegrada.asp?idAplicacion=11&amp;amp;idioma=e&quot;&gt; http://interwp.cepal.org/sisgen/ConsultaIntegrada.asp?idAplicacion=11 &amp;amp; idioma = e &lt;/a&gt; (по состоянию на январь-апрель 2016 года) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Европейская комиссия, 2016a. База данных по женщинам и мужчинам, участвующим в процессах принятия решений (WMID). &lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/justice/gender-equality/gender-decision-making/database/index_en.htm&quot;&gt; http://ec.europa.eu/justice/gender-equality/gender-decision-making/database/index_en.htm &lt;/a&gt; (по состоянию на январь-апрель 2016 года) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Европейская комиссия, Международный валютный фонд, Организация экономического сотрудничества и развития, Организация Объединенных Наций и Всемирный банк, 2009 год. &lt;em&gt;. Система национальных счетов 2008 года. &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ЕЭК ООН, 2016a. База данных по общественной жизни и принятию решений. &lt;a href=&quot;http://w3.unece.org/PXWeb2015/pxweb/en/STAT/STAT__30-GE__05-PublicAnddecision&quot;&gt; http://w3.unece.org/PXWeb2015/pxweb/en/STAT/STAT__30-GE__05-PublicAnddecision &lt;/a&gt; (по состоянию на январь-апрель 2016 года). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ПРООН, 2014 год. Гендерное равенство: участие и лидерство женщин в органах власти на местном уровне. Азиатско-Тихоокеанский регион, 2013 год. Бангкок, ПРООН. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ООН, 2011 год. &lt;em&gt; Использование административных и вторичных источников данных для официальной статистики: Справочник принципов и практики &lt;/em&gt;. ЕЭК ООН &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ЮНПАН (Сеть Организации Объединенных Наций государственного управления), 2016 год. Глоссарий ООН по государственному управлению. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unpan.org/Directories/Glossary/tabid/1398/language/en-US/Default.aspx%20&quot;&gt; http://www.unpan.org/Directories/Glossary/tabid/1398/language/en-US/Default.aspx &lt;/a&gt; (март 2016 года.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Структура «ООН-женщины», 2017 год. Обзор национальных конституций и законов о местных органах власти. Не опубликовано. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Структура «ООН-женщины» и ПРООН, 2015 год. Инклюзивные избирательные процессы: руководство для органов по проведению выборов по продвижению гендерного равенства и участию женщин. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
