<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 5-5-1b, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Indicator 5.5.1(b) refers to the representation of women among elected positions of legislative/deliberative bodies of local government. This is a strength, because it ensures comparability across countries, at low cost, and mirrors the SDG indicator measuring women&amp;#x2019;s representation at national level, in parliament. This is also a limitation in that the indicator does not consider other positions in local government. Local government officials holding executive positions who are not simultaneously holding a position within the legislative/deliberative body, or who are appointed and not elected, are not considered in this indicator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is recommended that women&amp;#x2019;s representation in executive positions, particularly at the level of the head of the executive (such as mayor), is monitored separately at national and global levels, but not as a headline SDG indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importantly, the indicator refers to representation among members of local government and not the quality of their participation. Countries may therefore consider assessing political participation through national or subnational studies involving qualitative and/or quantitative methods of research. Additional indicators of political participation may also be monitored at national level, such as women&amp;#x2019;s share among voters and candidates in local elections, to monitor the closing of other gaps on women&amp;#x2019;s political participation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, aspects of local governance beyond the formal institutions of local government, such as public administration staff, are not included in the indicator 5.5.1(b), and may be covered by other indicators in the SDG framework, particularly within the Goal 16 on inclusive societies.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador 5.5.1(b) se refiere a la representación de las mujeres entre los cargos electos de los órganos legislativos/deliberativos del gobierno local. Esto es un punto fuerte, ya que garantiza la comparabilidad entre países, a bajo costo, y refleja el indicador de los ODS que mide la representación de las mujeres a nivel nacional, en el parlamento. También es una limitación, ya que el indicador no tiene en cuenta otros cargos en el gobierno local. Los funcionarios del gobierno local que ocupan cargos ejecutivos y que no ocupan simultáneamente un cargo en el órgano legislativo/deliberativo, o que son nombrados y no elegidos, no se tienen en cuenta en este indicador. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se recomienda que la representación de las mujeres en los cargos ejecutivos, en particular a nivel del jefe del ejecutivo (como el alcalde), se supervise por separado a nivel nacional y mundial, pero no como un indicador principal de los ODS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Es importante destacar que el indicador se refiere a la representación entre los miembros del gobierno local y no a la calidad de su participación. Por lo tanto, los países pueden considerar la evaluación de la participación política a través de estudios nacionales o subnacionales que incluyan métodos de investigación cualitativos y/o cuantitativos. También se pueden supervisar otros indicadores de participación política a nivel nacional, como la proporción de mujeres entre los votantes y los candidatos en las elecciones locales, para supervisar el cierre de otras brechas en la participación política de las mujeres. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Por último, los aspectos de la gobernanza local más allá de las instituciones formales del gobierno local, como el personal de la administración pública, no están incluidos en el indicador 5.5.1(b), y pueden estar cubiertos por otros indicadores en el marco de los ODS, en particular dentro del Objetivo 16 sobre sociedades inclusivas.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt; Commentaires et limitations:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L’indicateur 5.5.1(b) fait référence à la représentation des femmes parmi les postes élus des organes législatifs/délibératifs des administrations locales. Il s’agit d’une force, car elle assure la comparabilité entre les pays, à faible coût, et reflète l’indicateur des ODD mesurant la représentation des femmes&amp;#x2019; au niveau national, au parlement. Il s’agit également d’une limitation en ce que l’indicateur ne tient pas compte d’autres postes dans les administrations locales. Les fonctionnaires des administrations locales occupant des postes de direction qui n’occuperont pas simultanément un poste au sein de l’organe législatif ou délibératif, ou qui sont nommés et non élus, ne sont pas pris en considération dans cet indicateur. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Il est recommandé que la représentation des femmes dans les postes de direction, en particulier au niveau du chef de l’exécutif (comme le maire), soit surveillée séparément aux niveaux national et mondial, mais pas comme indicateur global des ODD. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Fait important, l’indicateur fait référence à la représentation entre les membres des administrations locales et non à la qualité de leur participation. Les pays peuvent donc envisager d’évaluer la participation politique au moyen d’études nationales ou infranationales impliquant des méthodes de recherche qualitatives et/ou quantitatives. D’autres indicateurs de participation politique peuvent également être surveillés au niveau national, tels que la part des femmes&amp;#x2019; parmi les électeurs et les candidats aux élections locales, afin de surveiller la combler d’autres écarts sur la participation politique des femmes&amp;#x2019;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Enfin, les aspects de la gouvernance locale au-delà des institutions formelles des administrations locales, tels que le personnel de l’administration publique, ne sont pas inclus dans l’indicateur 5.5.1(b) et peuvent être couverts par d’autres indicateurs dans le cadre des ODD, en particulier dans le cadre de l’objectif 16 sur les sociétés inclusives. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель 5.5.1 (b) касается представленности женщин на выборных должностях законодательных / совещательных органов местного самоуправления. Это сильное качество, поскольку при этом обеспечивается сопоставимость по странам при низких затратах и отражается показатель ЦУР, определяющий представительство женщин на национальном уровне, в парламенте. Но здесь же есть и ограничение, поскольку показатель не учитывает другие должности в органах местного самоуправления. Должностные лица местных органов власти, занимающие руководящие должности, которые одновременно не занимают должности в законодательном / совещательном органе, или которые назначаются, но не избираются, в этом показателе не учитываются. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Рекомендуется, чтобы представительство женщин на руководящих должностях, особенно на уровне главы исполнительной власти (например, мэра), отслеживалось отдельно на национальном и глобальном уровнях, а не в качестве основного показателя ЦУР. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Важно отметить, что показатель относится к представительству среди членов местного самоуправления, а не к качеству их участия. Поэтому страны могут рассмотреть возможность оценки политического участия с помощью национальных или субнациональных исследований с использованием качественных и / или количественных методов исследования. Дополнительные показатели участия в политической жизни также можно отслеживать на национальном уровне, например, доля женщин среди избирателей и кандидатов на местных выборах, чтобы отслеживать устранение других пробелов в участии женщин в политической жизни. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Наконец, аспекты местного управления, выходящие за рамки официальных институтов местного самоуправления, такие как персонал государственной администрации, не включены в показатель 5.5.1 (b) и могут быть охвачены другими показателями в структуре ЦУР, особенно в рамках Цели 16 по обществам, предоставляющим равные возможности для всех. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
