<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 15-1-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forest area:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officially nominated national correspondents and their teams prepare the country reports for the Global Forest Resources Assessment. Some countries prepare more than one report as they also report on dependent territories. For the remaining countries and territories where no information is provided, a report is prepared by FAO using existing information, literature search, remote sensing or a combination of two or more of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All data are provided to FAO by countries in the form of a country report through an online platform following a standard format, which includes the original data and reference sources and descriptions of how these have been used to estimate the forest area for different points in time. The online platform is used for all data entry, review and quality control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Land area:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Land Use, Irrigation and Agricultural Practices FAO Questionnaire, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/economic/ess/ess-home/questionnaires/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/economic/ess/ess-home/questionnaires/en/&lt;/a&gt;, is sent annually to 205 countries and territories reaching out the National Focal Points in National Institutions, typically National Statistical Offices, Ministries of Agriculture or other relevant Agencies. The questionnaire is sent in Excel format together with accompanying cover letter explaining FAO mandate and scope of the data collection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data returned in questionnaire are checked against previous reports and for consistency with the other land categories reported in questionnaire. Depending on questionnaire completeness and in case of non-reporting, Land area data may be derived by subtracting the Inland waters area and the Coastal waters area from the Country area. Missing Land area data are also imputed by carry-forward of the latest value officially reported by the country. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Proceso de recolección:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los corresponsales nacionales designados oficialmente y sus equipos preparan los informes de los países para la evaluación. Algunos preparan más de un informe, ya que también informan sobre los territorios dependientes. Para el resto de países y territorios en los que no se proporciona información, la FAO prepara un informe utilizando la información existente, la búsqueda bibliográfica, la teledetección o una combinación de dos o más de ellas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todos los datos son proporcionados a la FAO por los países en forma de informe nacional a través de una plataforma en línea siguiendo un formato estándar, que incluye los datos originales y las fuentes de referencia y las descripciones de cómo se han utilizado para estimar la superficie forestal para diferentes puntos en el tiempo. La plataforma en línea se utilizó para toda la entrada de datos, la revisión y el control de calidad.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Processus de collecte : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les correspondants nationaux officiellement nommés et leurs équipes préparent les rapports nationaux pour l&apos;évaluation. Certains préparent plus d&apos;un rapport car ils font également rapport sur les territoires dépendants. Pour les autres pays et territoires pour lesquels aucune information n&apos;est fournie, un rapport est préparé par la FAO en utilisant les informations existantes, la recherche documentaire, la télédétection ou une combinaison de deux ou plusieurs de ces éléments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toutes les données sont fournies à la FAO par les pays sous la forme d&apos;un rapport national via une plateforme en ligne suivant un format standard, qui inclut les données originales et les sources de référence et les descriptions de la manière dont elles ont été utilisées pour estimer la superficie forestière à différents moments. La plateforme en ligne a été utilisée pour toutes les saisies, révisions et contrôles de qualité des données.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Официально назначенные национальные корреспонденты и их группы готовят страновые доклады для оценки. Некоторые из них готовят более одного доклада, поскольку они также отчитываются о зависимых территориях. По остальным странам и территориям, по которым информация не предоставляется, ФАО готовит доклад, используя существующую информацию, поиск по литературным источникам, дистанционное зондирование или сочетание двух или более из этих методов.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Все данные предоставляются ФАО странами в форме странового доклада через онлайновую платформу в соответствии со стандартным форматом, который включает исходные данные и справочные источники, а также описание того, как они использовались для оценки лесных площадей за различные периоды времени. Онлайновая платформа используется для ввода всех данных, их проверки и контроля качества.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
