<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 1-a-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The source of data varies by country depending on the availability:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For public expenditure on education:&lt;/strong&gt; government expenditure datasets, expenditure reports in national and sub-national budgets, the IMF Government Finance Statistics database, Public Expenditure Reviews published by the World Bank and others, the World Bank&amp;#x2019;s BOOST dataset, and other national or international sources as available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For total government expenditure:&lt;/strong&gt; the source of total government expenditure would be from a comparable source as the total amount of public expenditure on education. For example, if the expenditure amount is derived from national budget documents then total expenditure would also be derived from national budget documents. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that if governments have an official indicator for this SDG, then this would be the source.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;La source des données varie selon les pays en fonction de la disponibilité :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pour les dépenses publiques consacrées à l’éducation :&lt;/strong&gt; les ensembles de données sur les dépenses publiques, les rapports de dépenses dans les budgets nationaux et infranationaux, la base de données des statistiques de finances publiques du FMI, les revues des dépenses publiques publiées par la Banque mondiale et d’autres, l’ensemble de données « BOOST » de la Banque mondiale et d’autres sources nationales ou internationales disponibles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pour les dépenses publiques totales :&lt;/strong&gt; la source des dépenses publiques totales proviendrait d’une source comparable au montant total des dépenses publiques consacrées à l’éducation. Par exemple, si le montant des dépenses est dérivé des documents budgétaires nationaux, les dépenses totales seront également dérivées des documents budgétaires nationaux. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notez que si les gouvernements ont un indicateur officiel pour cet ODD, alors ce serait la source.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
