<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 1-a-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total general (local, regional and central) government expenditure on education (current, capital, and transfers), expressed as a percentage of total general government expenditure on all sectors (including health, education, social services, etc.). It includes expenditure funded by transfers from international sources to the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Government expenditure on education covers educational expenditure by all levels of government (local, regional, central) on the formal education system, from early childhood to tertiary education, in both public and private instructional and non-instructional institutions within the borders of a country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expenditure on education includes expenditure on core educational goods and services, such as teaching staff, school buildings, or school books and teaching materials, and peripheral educational goods and services such as ancillary services, general administration and other activities.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dépenses totales des administrations publiques (locales, régionales et centrales) en matière d&apos;éducation (dépenses courantes, dépenses en capital et transferts), exprimées en pourcentage des dépenses totales des administrations publiques dans tous les secteurs (y compris la santé, l&apos;enseignement, les services sociaux, etc.) Ceci inclut les dépenses financées par des transferts de sources internationales au gouvernement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les dépenses publiques en éducation couvrent les dépenses d&apos;éducation effectuées par tous les niveaux de gouvernement (local, régional, central) dans le système d&apos;éducation formel, de la petite enfance à l&apos;enseignement supérieur, dans les établissements publics et privés, scolaires et non scolaires, à l&apos;intérieur des frontières d&apos;un pays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les dépenses en éducation comprennent les dépenses pour les biens et services éducatifs de base, tels que le personnel enseignant, les bâtiments scolaires ou les livres et matériels pédagogiques, et les biens et services éducatifs périphériques, tels que les services auxiliaires, l&apos;administration générale et d&apos;autres activités.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
