<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COMPARABILITY field for indicator 6-4-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Differences might occur due to the following, amongst others: For national estimates incoming freshwater is counted as being part of the country&amp;#x2019;s available freshwater resources, while global estimates can only be done by adding up the internal renewable water resources (water generated within the country) of all countries in order to avoid double counting. Moreover, external freshwater resources are computed according to treaties, if present, which may lead to different values with respect to the actual freshwater resources assessed through hydrology.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Sources de divergences  :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des écarts pourraient se produire en raison, entre autres, des éléments suivants : pour les estimations nationales, l’eau entrante fait partie des ressources en eau disponibles dans le pays, tandis que les estimations mondiales ne peuvent être faites qu’en additionnant les ressources internes en eau renouvelable (eau produite dans le pays) de tous les pays afin d’éviter le double comptage.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Различия могут возникать, в частности, из-за следующего: для национальных оценок поступающая пресная вода считается частью имеющихся пресноводных ресурсов страны, в то время как глобальные оценки могут быть выполнены только путем суммирования внутренних возобновляемых водных ресурсов (водных ресурсов, образовавшихся в стране) всех стран во избежание двойного счета. Более того, внешние ресурсы пресной воды рассчитываются в соответствии с договорами, если таковые имеются, что может привести к различным значениям по сравнению с фактическими ресурсами пресной воды, оцененными с помощью гидрологических исследований. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
