<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_SOURCE field for indicator 6-4-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Data come from governmental sources. The institutions responsible for data collection at national level vary according to countries. However, in general data for this indicator are provided by the Ministry of Agriculture, Ministry of Water, Ministry of Environment and other line Ministries. In many cases data collection at country level is coordinated by the National Statistics office (NSO).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oficinas nacionales de estadística a través de los corresponsales nacionales de AQUASTAT. Las instituciones responsables de la recolección de datos a nivel nacional varían según los países. Sin embargo, en general, los datos para este indicador los proporcionan el Ministerio de Agricultura, el Ministerio del Agua y el Ministerio de Medio Ambiente, así como otros ministerios competentes.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Fournisseurs de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description :&lt;/h2&gt;
Les bureaux nationaux de statistiques par l&apos;intermédiaire des correspondants nationaux d&apos;AQUASTAT. Les institutions responsables de la collecte des données au niveau national varient selon les pays. Cependant, en général, les données pour cet indicateur sont fournies par le Ministère de l&apos;Agriculture, le Ministère de l&apos;Eau et le Ministère de l&apos;Environnement, et d&apos;autres ministères de tutelle.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Поставщики данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Национальные статистические управления через национальных корреспондентов AQUASTAT. Учреждения, ответственные за сбор данных на национальном уровне, различаются в зависимости от страны. Однако в целом данные по этому показателю предоставляются Министерством сельского хозяйства, Министерством водных ресурсов и Министерством окружающей среды, а также другими отраслевыми министерствами.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
