<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 6-4-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computation method:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Method of computation: The indicator is computed as the total freshwater withdrawn (TFWW) divided by the difference between the total renewable freshwater resources (TRWR) and the environmental flow requirements (EFR), multiplied by 100. All variables are expressed in km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;/year (10&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;/year).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stress (%) = TFWW / (TRWR - EFR) * 100&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the experience of the initial five years of application of the indicator, and consistent with the approach taken during the MDG program, the threshold of 25% has been identified as the upper limit for a full and unconditional safety of water stress as assessed by the indicator 6.4.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means on one hand, that values below 25% can be considered safe in any instance (no stress); on the other, that values above 25% should be regarded as potentially and increasingly problematic, and should be qualified and/or reduced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above 25% of water stress, four classes have been identified to signal different levels of stress severity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NO STRESS&amp;#xA0;&amp;lt;25%&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LOW 25% - 50%&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MEDIUM 50% - 75%&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HIGH 75-100%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CRITICAL &amp;gt;100%&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Méthodologie&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Méthode de calcul :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Méthode de calcul : L&apos;indicateur est calculé comme étant le total des prélèvements d&apos;eau douce (TWW) divisé par la différence entre le total des ressources renouvelables en eau douce (TRWR) et les besoins environnementaux en eau (Env.), multiplié par 100. Toutes les variables sont exprimées en km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;/an (10&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;/an).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stress (%) = TWW / (TRWR - Env.) * 100&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il est suggéré de classer le niveau de stress hydrique en trois grandes catégories (niveaux) : faible, élevé et très élevé. Les seuils de l&apos;indicateur pourraient être spécifiques à chaque pays, afin de refléter les différences de climat et les objectifs nationaux en matière de gestion de l&apos;eau. Alternativement, des seuils uniformes pourraient être proposés en utilisant la littérature existante et en tenant compte des exigences environnementales en matière d&apos;eau.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Показатель рассчитывается путем деления общего объема забора пресной воды (TWW) на разницу между общими возобновляемыми ресурсами пресной воды (TRWR) и экологическими потребности в воде (Env.), умноженного на 100.
Все переменные выражаются в кубических километрах в год.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Нагрузка (%) = TWW / (TRWR - Env.) * 100 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Предлагается классифицировать уровень нагрузки на воду по трем основным категориям (уровням): низкий, высокий и очень высокий. Пороговые значения показателя могут быть специфическими для каждой страны, чтобы отразить различия в климатических условиях и национальных целях использования водных ресурсов. В качестве альтернативы можно было бы предложить ввести единообразные пороговые значения, используя существующие публикации по этой теме и принимая во внимание экологические потребности в воде.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
