<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DOC_METHOD field for indicator 6-4-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="en">## Methods and guidance available to countries for the compilation of the data at the national level
This indicator provides an estimate of pressure by all sectors on the country’s renewable freshwater resources. A low level of water stress indicates a situation where the combined withdrawal by all sectors is marginal in relation to the resources, and has therefore little potential impact on the sustainability of the resources or on the potential competition between users. A high level of water stress indicates a situation where the combined withdrawal by all sectors represents a substantial share of the total renewable freshwater resources, with potentially larger impacts on the sustainability of the resources and potential situations of conflicts and competition between users.
The indicator is computed based on three components:

* Total renewable freshwater resources ($TRWR$)
* Total freshwater withdrawal ($TWW$)
* Environmental flow requirements ($EFR$)

$$Water\:Stress (\%) = {TWW \over {TRWR-EFR.}} \times 100$$

Several documents exist that can be used to support countries in the computation of this indicator. Among them:

## Understanding AQUASTAT - FAO&apos;s global water information system
This information note covers a twenty year history of the collection and analysis of water-related data and its dissemination as an international public good, freely available to all. The process of collecting and checking the data has resulted in the establishment of a unique network of collaborators who provide data, use data from other countries for comparative purposes, and exchange views and experiences on how best to measure and account for water-related use. Users range from international private companies to non-governmental organizations, and virtually all significant reports related to water depend on the data provided by AQUASTAT.
&lt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc817e.pdf&gt;

## Renewable Water Resources Assessment - 2015 AQUASTAT methodology review
&lt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc818e.pdf&gt;

## Global database on municipal wastewater production, collection, treatment, discharge and direct use in agriculture 
This paper describes the rationale and method to setup and feed the AQUASTAT database on municipal wastewater production, collection, treatment, discharge or direct use in agriculture. The best available sources of information have been reviewed, including peer-reviewed papers, proceedings of workshops, conferences and expert meetings, global or regional databases, as well as country briefs, national reports and direct communications by country government officials and experts
&lt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc823e.pdf&gt;

## Cooling water for energy generation and its impact on national-level water statistics 
This technical note, describing the issue of cooling water for energy generation and its impact on national-level water statistics, has two purposes: 1) to act as a general informational resource and 2) to encourage governmental agencies responsible for water usage to gather and report information disaggregated by sub-sector (keeping thermoelectric withdrawals separate from industrial and hydroelectric withdrawals), and to determine the point at which lower water withdrawal designs are more favourable, even if the required capital cost is higher.
&lt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc822e.pdf&gt;

## Municipal and industrial water withdrawal modelling for the years 2000 and 2005 using statistical methods 
This document describes the efforts to generate models that estimate the municipal and industrial water withdrawals for the years 2000 and 2005. 
&lt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc821e.pdf&gt;

## Disambiguation of water statistics 
The nomenclature surrounding water information is often confusing and gives rise to different interpretations and thus confusion. When discussing the way in which renewable water resources are utilized, the terms water use, usage, withdrawal, consumption, abstraction, extraction, utilization, supply and demand are often used without clearly stating what is meant. 
&lt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc816e.pdf&gt;

## Country survey on water use for agriculture and rural development
Questionnaire for water survey
These Guidelines and Questionnaire have been prepared for the updating of the data and country profiles in AQUASTAT.
&lt;http://www.fao.org/nr/water/aquastat/sets/aq-5yr-quest_eng.xls&gt;
&lt;http://www.fao.org/nr/water/aquastat/sets/aq-5yr-guide_eng.pdf&gt;

## International Recommendations for Water Statistics
The International Recommendations for Water Statistics (IRWS) were developed to help strengthen national information systems for water in support of design and evaluation of Integrated Water Resources Management (IWRM) policies.
&lt;https://unstats.un.org/UNSD/envaccounting/irws/&gt;

## UNSD/UNEP Questionnaire on Environment Statistics – Water Section
&lt;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/questionnaire.htm&gt;
&lt;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/qindicators.htm&gt;

## UNSD ‘National Accounts Main Aggregates Database’
&lt;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/snaama/selbasicFast.asp&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
