<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 6-4-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Traitement des valeurs manquantes :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Au niveau national :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Si des données partielles sont disponibles, une méthodologie sera développée en ce qui concerne l&apos;inter et l&apos;extrapolation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Aux niveaux régional et mondial :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour les OMD, les valeurs les plus récentes ont été utilisées pour obtenir des agrégats régionaux ou mondiaux, même si elles n&apos;étaient pas disponibles pour la même année. Il est prévu que grâce aux données qui seront produites pour le suivi des ODD, des données soient disponibles pour plus ou moins les mêmes années.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; На уровне страны: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; При наличии разрозненных данных будет разработана методология с учетом интерполяции и экстраполяции &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для ЦРТ использовались самые последние значения для получения региональных или глобальных агрегатов, даже если они отсутствовали за тот же год. Ожидается, что на основе эталона, который будет разработан для мониторинга ЦУР, станут доступны данные за более или менее один и тот же диапазон лет &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Treatment of missing values:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At country level:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three types of imputation are made at country level to fill in missing years in the timeseries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Linear imputation: between two available data-points&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Carry forward: after the last available data-points and up to 10 years&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Vertical imputation: in case of available total freshwater withdrawal but missing disaggregation by sources, and if existing disaggregation existed for previous years, the respective ratio by sources is applied to the available total.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At regional and global levels:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the imputation methods at country level, data will be available for the whole time series (unless the latest official value was obtained more than 10 years ago).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
