<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 6-4-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Treatment of missing values:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At country level:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three types of imputation are made at country level to fill in missing years in the timeseries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Linear imputation: between two available data-points&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Carry forward: after the last available data-points and up to 10 years&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Vertical imputation: in case of available total freshwater withdrawal but missing disaggregation by sources, and if existing disaggregation existed for previous years, the respective ratio by sources is applied to the available total.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At regional and global levels:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the imputation methods at country level, data will be available for the whole time series (unless the latest official value was obtained more than 10 years ago).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt; Tratamiento de valores faltantes: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; A nivel de país: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Se realizan tres tipos de imputación a nivel de país para completar los años que faltan en la serie temporal: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; Imputación lineal: entre dos puntos de datos disponibles &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; Transferencia hacia adelante: después de los últimos puntos de datos disponibles y hasta 10 años &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; Imputación vertical: en caso de que se disponga de la extracción total de agua dulce pero falte el desglose por fuentes, y si existe el desglose para los años anteriores, se aplica la proporción respectiva por fuentes al total disponible &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; A nivel regional y mundial: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Gracias a los métodos de imputación a nivel de país, se dispondrá de datos para toda la serie temporal (a menos que el último valor oficial se haya obtenido hace más de 10 años). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; На страновом уровне используются три типа условного исчисления для заполнения отсутствующих данных по годам во временных рядах: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; Линейное вменение: между двумя доступными элементами данных &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; Перенос на будущий период: после последних имеющихся данных и до периода в 10 лет &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; Вертикальное вменение: в случае имеющихся данных по общему забору пресной воды, но без разбивки по источникам, и если существующая разбивка имеется за предыдущие годы, то соответствующий коэффициент по источникам применяется к имеющемуся общему забору пресной воды. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Благодаря методам вменения на страновом уровне данные будут доступны для всех временных рядов (если только последнее официальное значение не было получено более 10 лет назад). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
