<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 6-4-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Freshwater withdrawal as a percentage of renewable freshwater resources is a good indicator of pressure on limited water resources, one of the most important natural resources. However, it only partially addresses the issues related to sustainable water management. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplementary indicators that capture the multiple dimensions of water management would combine data on water demand management, behavioural changes with regard to water use and the availability of appropriate infrastructure, and measure progress in increasing the efficiency and sustainability of water use, in particular in relation to population and economic growth. They would also recognize the different climatic environments that affect water use in countries, especially in agriculture, which is the main user of water. Sustainability assessment is also linked to the critical thresholds fixed for this indicator. Although there is no universal consensus on such thresholds, a proposal is presented below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trends in freshwater withdrawal show relatively slow patterns of change. Usually, three-five years are a minimum frequency to be able to detect significant changes, as it is unlikely that the indicator would show meaningful variations from one year to the other. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimation of water withdrawal by sector may represent a limitation to the computation of the indicator. Few countries publish water withdrawal data on a regular basis by sector. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no universally agreed method for the computation of incoming freshwater flows originating outside of a country&amp;apos;s borders. Nor is there any standard method to account for return flows, the part of the water withdrawn from its source and which flows back to the river system after use. In countries where return flow represents a substantial part of water withdrawal, the indicator tends to underestimate available water and therefore overestimate the level of water stress. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other limitations that affect the interpretation of the water stress indicator include: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;difficulty to obtain accurate, complete and up-to-date data; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;potentially large variation of sub-national data; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;lack of account of historical (e.g., due to climate change and population growth) and seasonal variations in water resources;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;lack of consideration to the distribution among water uses; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;lack of consideration of water quality and its suitability for use; and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the indicator can be higher than 100 percent when water withdrawal non-renewable freshwater (fossil groundwater), when annual groundwater withdrawal is higher than annual replenishment (over-abstraction) or when freshwater withdrawal includes part or all the water set aside for environmental flow requirements. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these issues can be solved through disaggregation of the indicator at the level of hydrological units and by distinguishing between different use sectors. However, due to the complexity of water flows, both within a country and between countries, care should be taken not to double-count.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt; Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La extracción de agua dulce como porcentaje de los recursos renovables de agua dulce es un buen indicador de la presión sobre los limitados recursos hídricos, uno de los recursos naturales más importantes. Sin embargo, sólo aborda parcialmente las cuestiones relacionadas con la gestión sostenible del agua. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Indicadores complementarios que captan las múltiples dimensiones de la gestión del agua combinarían datos sobre la gestión de la demanda de agua, los cambios de comportamiento con respecto al uso del agua y la disponibilidad de infraestructuras adecuadas, y medirían los avances en el aumento de la eficiencia y la sostenibilidad del uso del agua, en particular en relación con el crecimiento demográfico y económico. También reconocerían los diferentes entornos climáticos que afectan al uso del agua en los países, en particular en la agricultura, que es el principal usuario del agua. La evaluación de la sostenibilidad también está vinculada a los umbrales críticos fijados para este indicador. Aunque no existe un consenso universal sobre dichos umbrales, a continuación se presenta una propuesta. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Las tendencias en la extracción de agua dulce muestran patrones de cambio relativamente lentos. Por lo general, tres-cinco años son una frecuencia mínima para poder detectar cambios significativos, ya que es poco probable que el indicador muestre variaciones significativas de un año a otro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La estimación de la extracción de agua por sector puede representar una limitación para el cálculo del indicador. En realidad, pocos países publican regularmente datos sobre la extracción de agua por sector. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; No existe un método universalmente acordado para el cálculo de los flujos entrantes de agua dulce que se originan fuera de las fronteras de un país. Tampoco existe ningún método estándar para tener en cuenta los caudales de retorno, la parte del agua extraída de su fuente y que fluye de vuelta al sistema fluvial después de su uso. En los países donde el flujo de retorno representa una parte sustancial de la extracción de agua, el indicador tiende a subestimar el agua disponible y, por lo tanto, a sobrestimar el nivel de estrés hídrico. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Otras limitaciones que afectan la interpretación del indicador de estrés hídrico incluyen: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dificultad para obtener datos precisos, completos y actualizados; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;variación potencialmente grande de los datos subnacionales; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;falta de consideración de las variaciones estacionales de los recursos hídricos; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;falta de consideración de la distribución entre los usos del agua; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;falta de consideración de la calidad del agua y su idoneidad para el uso; y&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;el indicador puede ser superior al 100% cuando la extracción de agua no es renovable (aguas subterráneas fósiles), cuando la extracción anual de aguas subterráneas es superior a la reposición anual (sobreexplotación) o cuando la extracción de agua incluye parte o la totalidad del agua reservada para las necesidades hídricas medioambientales. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Algunas de estas cuestiones pueden resolverse mediante la desagregación del indicador a nivel de las unidades hidrológicas y la distinción entre los diferentes sectores de uso. Sin embargo, debido a la complejidad de los flujos de agua, tanto dentro de un país como entre países, se debe tener cuidado de no contar dos veces. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires et limites : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le prélèvement d&apos;eau en pourcentage des ressources renouvelables en eau est un bon indicateur de la pression exercée sur des ressources en eau limitées, l&apos;une des ressources naturelles les plus importantes. Cependant, le tout ne répond que partiellement aux enjeux liés à la gestion durable de l&apos;eau. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des indicateurs supplémentaires qui englobent les multiples dimensions de la gestion de l&apos;eau combineraient des données sur la gestion de la demande en eau, les changements de comportement en matière d&apos;utilisation de l&apos;eau et la disponibilité d&apos;infrastructures appropriées, et mesureraient les progrès réalisés dans l&apos;amélioration de l&apos;efficacité et de la durabilité de l&apos;utilisation de l&apos;eau, notamment en fonction de la croissance démographique et économique. Ils permettraient également de reconnaître les différents environnements climatiques qui affectent l&apos;utilisation de l&apos;eau dans chaque pays, et en particulier dans le secteur de l&apos;agriculture, le principal utilisateur d&apos;eau. L&apos;évaluation de la durabilité est également liée aux seuils critiques fixés pour cet indicateur, mais il n&apos;existe pas de consensus universel à ce chapitre. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les tendances en matière de prélèvement d&apos;eau montrent des changements relativement lents. Habituellement, une période de trois à cinq ans est la fréquence minimale pour pouvoir détecter des changements significatifs, car il est peu probable que l&apos;indicateur montre des variations significatives d&apos;une année à l&apos;autre. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;estimation des prélèvements d&apos;eau par secteur est la principale limite au calcul de l&apos;indicateur. En effet, peu de pays publient régulièrement des données sur l&apos;utilisation de l&apos;eau par secteur. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les ressources en eau renouvelables comprennent toutes les ressources en eau de surface et en eau souterraine qui sont disponibles sur une base annuelle, sans tenir compte de la capacité à récolter et à utiliser cette ressource. Les ressources en eau exploitables, qui désignent le volume d&apos;eau de surface ou d&apos;eau souterraine disponible 90 % du temps, sont considérablement inférieures aux ressources en eau renouvelables, mais il n&apos;existe aucune méthode universelle pour évaluer les ressources en eau exploitables. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il n&apos;existe pas de méthode universellement reconnue pour le calcul des débits d&apos;eau douce entrants provenant de l&apos;extérieur des frontières d&apos;un pays. Il n&apos;existe pas non plus de méthode standard pour comptabiliser les débits de retour, c&apos;est-à-dire la partie de l&apos;eau prélevée à la source qui retourne au système fluvial après utilisation. Dans les pays où le débit de retour représente une partie substantielle du prélèvement d&apos;eau, l&apos;indicateur tend à sous-estimer l&apos;eau disponible et donc à surestimer le niveau de stress hydrique. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parmi les autres limitations qui affectent l&apos;interprétation de cet indicateur, on retrouve : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;difficulté d&apos;obtenir des données exactes, complètes et à jour ; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;variation potentiellement importante des données infranationales ; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;manque de considération des variations saisonnières des ressources en eau
; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;manque de considération de la répartition entre les utilisations de l&apos;eau
; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;manque de considération de la qualité de l&apos;eau et de son adéquation à l&apos;utilisation
; et &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;l&apos;indicateur peut être supérieur à 100 % lorsque le prélèvement d&apos;eau comprend
de l&apos;eau douce secondaire (eau prélevée précédemment et retournée au système), de l&apos;eau non renouvelable (nappes fossiles), lorsque le prélèvement annuel d&apos;eaux souterraines est supérieur à la réalimentation annuelle (surexploitation) ou lorsque le prélèvement d&apos;eau comprend une partie ou la totalité de l&apos;eau mise en réserve pour les besoins environnementaux en eau. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certains de ces problèmes peuvent être résolus par la désagrégation  de l&apos;indice au niveau des unités hydrologiques et en distinguant les différents secteurs d&apos;utilisation. Cependant, en raison de la complexité des débits d&apos;eau, tant à l&apos;intérieur d&apos;un pays qu&apos;entre les pays, il faut veiller à ne pas faire de double comptage. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Забор пресной воды, выраженный в долях от возобновляемых ресурсов пресной воды, является хорошим показателем нагрузки на ограниченные водные ресурсы, являющихся одними из наиболее важных природных ресурсов. Однако он лишь частично решает вопросы, связанные с устойчивым управлением водными ресурсами. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Дополнительные показатели, охватывающие множество аспектов управления водными ресурсами, будут объединять данные об управлении спросом на воду, изменениях поведения в отношении водопользования и наличия соответствующей инфраструктуры, а также отражать прогресс в повышении эффективности и устойчивости водопользования, в частности в отношении населения и экономического роста. Они также будут выявлять различные климатические условия, которые влияют на водопользование в странах, в частности в сельском хозяйстве, которое является основным пользователем воды. Оценка устойчивости также связана с критическими порогами, установленными для этого показателя. Хотя универсального консенсуса по таким пороговым значениям нет, но предложение изложено ниже. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Тенденции забора пресной воды показывают относительно медленные изменения. Обычно период от трех до пяти лет - это минимальная периодичность, чтобы можно было обнаружить существенные изменения, поскольку маловероятно, что показатель будет демонстрировать значимые колебания от года к году.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Оценка забора воды по секторам может ограничивать расчет показателя. Немногие страны фактически публикуют данные по водозабору по секторам на регулярной основе. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Не существует универсально согласованного метода расчета входящих потоков пресной воды, возникающих за пределами границ страны. Также не существует стандартного метода учета возвратных стоков, части воды, забираемой из источника и возвращаемой в речную систему после использования. В странах, где возвратный сток составляет значительную часть забора воды, показатель имеет тенденцию занижать доступные водные ресурсы и, следовательно, переоценивать уровень нагрузки на водные ресурсы. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; К другим ограничениям, влияющим на интерпретацию показателя нагрузки на водные ресурсы, относятся:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; сложность получения точных, полных и актуальных данных; &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; потенциально большой разброс субнациональных данных; &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; отсутствие учета сезонных колебаний водных ресурсов; &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; недостаточное внимание к распределению воды между водопользователями; &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; отсутствие внимания к качеству воды и ее пригодности для использования;
и &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; показатель может быть выше 100 процентов, когда происходит водозабор невозобновляемой
воды (ископаемые подземные воды), когда годовой забор подземных вод превышает годовое пополнение (чрезмерный отбор) или когда водозабор включает часть или весь набор водных ресурсов, не беря в расчёт оптимальный экологический дебит воды. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Некоторые из этих проблем можно решить путем дезагрегирования показателя на уровне гидрологических единиц и проведения различия между различными секторами использования. Однако из-за сложности водных потоков, как внутри страны, так и между странами, следует проявлять осторожность, чтобы избежать двойного учета.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
