<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 6-4-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The level of water stress: freshwater withdrawal as a proportion of available freshwater resources is the ratio between total freshwater withdrawn by all major sectors and total renewable freshwater resources, after taking into account environmental flow requirements. Main sectors, as defined by ISIC standards, include agriculture; forestry and fishing; manufacturing; electricity industry; and services. This indicator is also known as water withdrawal intensity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator provides an estimate of pressure by all sectors on the country&amp;#x2019;s renewable freshwater resources. A low level of water stress indicates a situation where the combined withdrawal by all sectors is marginal in relation to the resources, and has therefore little potential impact on the sustainability of the resources or on the potential competition between users. A high level of water stress indicates a situation where the combined withdrawal by all sectors represents a substantial share of the total renewable freshwater resources, with potentially larger impacts on the sustainability of the resources and potential situations of conflicts and competition between users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total renewable freshwater resources (TRWR) are expressed as the sum of internal and external renewable water resources. The terms &amp;#x201C;water resources&amp;#x201D; and &amp;#x201C;water withdrawal&amp;#x201D; are understood here as freshwater resources and freshwater withdrawal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internal renewable water resources are defined as the long-term average annual flow of rivers and recharge of groundwater for a given country generated from endogenous precipitation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;External renewable water resources refer to the flows of water entering the country, taking into consideration the quantity of flows reserved to upstream and downstream countries through agreements or treaties. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total freshwater withdrawal (TFWW) is the volume of freshwater extracted from its source (rivers, lakes, aquifers) for agriculture, industries and services.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-1&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It is estimated at the country level for the following three main sectors: agriculture, services (including domestic water withdrawal) and industries (including cooling of thermoelectric plants). Freshwater withdrawal includes fossil groundwater. It does not include non-conventional water, i.e. direct use of treated wastewater, direct use of agricultural drainage water and desalinated water. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environmental flow requirements (EFR) are defined as the quantity and timing of freshwater flows and levels necessary to sustain aquarian ecosystems, which, in turn, support human cultures, economies, sustainable livelihoods, and wellbeing. Water quality and also the resulting ecosystem services are excluded from this formulation which is confined to water volumes. This does not imply that quality and the support to societies which are dependent on environmental flows are not important and should not be taken care of.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Methods of computation of EFR are extremely variable and range from global estimates to comprehensive assessments for river reaches. For the purpose of the SDG indicator, water volumes can be expressed in the same units as the TFWW, and then as percentages of the available water resources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; In AQUASTAT, service water withdrawal is reported as Municipal water withdrawal. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; They are indeed taken into account by other targets and indicators, such as 6.3.2, 6.5.1, and 6.6.1. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Définition : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Niveau de stress hydrique : le prélèvement d&apos;eau douce en proportion des ressources en eau douce disponibles est le rapport entre le total de l&apos;eau douce prélevée par tous les grands secteurs et le total des ressources renouvelables en eau douce, après avoir tenu compte des besoins environnementaux en eau. Les principaux secteurs, tels que définis par les normes de la Classification internationale type des industries (CITI), comprennent l&apos;agriculture, la sylviculture et la pêche, l&apos;industrie manufacturière, l&apos;industrie de l&apos;électricité et les services. Cet indicateur est également connu sous le nom d&apos;intensité des retraits d&apos;eau. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur fournit une estimation de la pression exercée par tous les secteurs sur les ressources renouvelables en eau douce d&apos;un pays. Un faible niveau de stress hydrique indique une situation où le prélèvement combiné de tous les secteurs est marginal par rapport aux ressources, et a donc peu d&apos;impact potentiel sur la durabilité des ressources ou sur la concurrence potentielle entre les utilisateurs. Un niveau élevé de stress hydrique indique une situation dans laquelle le prélèvement combiné de tous les secteurs représente une part substantielle de l&apos;ensemble des ressources renouvelables en eau douce, et a un impact potentiellement plus important sur la durabilité des ressources et sur des situations potentielles de conflits et de concurrence entre les utilisateurs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le total des ressources en eau douce renouvelables représente la somme des ressources en eau renouvelables internes et externes. Les termes &amp;#x201C;ressources en eau&amp;#x201D; et &amp;#x201C;prélèvements d&apos;eau&amp;#x201D; sont entendus ici comme ressources en eau douce et prélèvements d&apos;eau douce. &lt;/p&gt;
Les ressources en eau renouvelables internes sont définies comme le débit annuel moyen à long terme des rivières et la recharge des eaux souterraines pour un pays donné, générés par les précipitations endogènes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les ressources en eau renouvelables externes font référence aux débits d&apos;eau entrant dans le pays, en prenant en considération la quantité de débits réservés aux pays en amont et en aval selon les accords ou les traités. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le prélèvement total d&apos;eau douce est le volume d&apos;eau douce extrait de sa source (rivières, lacs, aquifères) pour l&apos;agriculture, les industries et les municipalités. Il est estimé au niveau national pour les trois principaux secteurs suivants : l&apos;agriculture, les municipalités (y compris le prélèvement d&apos;eau domestique) et les industries. Les prélèvements d&apos;eau douce comprennent l&apos;eau douce primaire (non prélevée auparavant), l&apos;eau douce secondaire (précédemment prélevée et retournée dans les rivières et les eaux souterraines, comme les eaux usées rejetées et les eaux de drainage agricole) et les nappes fossiles. Ils n&apos;incluent pas l&apos;eau non conventionnelle, c&apos;est-à-dire l&apos;utilisation directe des eaux usées traitées, l&apos;utilisation directe des eaux de drainage agricole et l&apos;eau dessalée. Le prélèvement total d&apos;eau douce est en général calculé comme étant la somme du prélèvement total d&apos;eau par secteur moins l&apos;utilisation directe des eaux usées, l&apos;utilisation directe des eaux de drainage agricole et l&apos;utilisation d&apos;eau dessalée. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les besoins environnementaux en eau correspondent aux quantités d&apos;eau nécessaires pour maintenir les écosystèmes d&apos;eau douce et estuariens. La qualité d&apos;eau et les services écosystémiques qui en résultent sont exclus de cette formulation, qui se limite aux volumes d&apos;eau. Cela ne signifie toutefois pas que la qualité et le soutien aux sociétés qui dépendent des débits environnementaux ne sont pas importants et ne doivent pas être pris en compte. Les méthodes de calcul des besoins environnementaux en eau sont extrêmement variables et vont des estimations mondiales aux évaluations complètes des tronçons de rivière. Pour les besoins de l&apos;indicateur des ODD, les volumes d&apos;eau peuvent être exprimés dans les mêmes unités que le prélèvement total d&apos;eau douce, puis en pourcentage des ressources en eau disponibles. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Уровень нагрузки на водные ресурсы: забор пресной воды, выраженный в виде доли доступных ресурсов пресной воды - это соотношение между общим объемом пресной воды, забранным всеми основными секторами, и общими возобновляемыми ресурсами пресной воды с учетом требований экологического стока. Основные секторы, определенные стандартами МСОК, включают сельское хозяйство, лесоводство и рыболовство; обрабатывающую промышленность; снабжение электроэнергией, газом, паром и кондиционированным воздухом; и услуги. Этот показатель также известен как интенсивность водозабора.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Этот показатель дает оценку воздействия всех секторов на возобновляемые ресурсы пресной воды в стране. Низкий уровень нагрузки на водные ресурсы указывает на ситуацию, когда совокупный забор всеми секторами является незначительным по отношению к ресурсам и, следовательно, оказывает незначительное потенциальное влияние на устойчивость ресурсов или на потенциальную конкуренцию между пользователями. Высокий уровень нагрузки на водные ресурсы указывает на ситуацию, когда совокупный водозабор всеми секторами представляет собой значительную долю от общего объема возобновляемых ресурсов пресной воды, что может оказать более значительное воздействие на устойчивость ресурсов и на создание потенциальных ситуаций, приводящих к конфликтам и конкуренции между пользователями.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Общие возобновляемые ресурсы пресной воды (ОВРПВ) выражаются как сумма внутренних и внешних возобновляемых ресурсов пресной воды. Термины &quot;ресурсы воды&quot; и &quot;водозабор&quot; понимаются здесь как ресурсы и забор пресной воды. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Внутренние возобновляемые водные ресурсы определяются как долгосрочный среднегодовой сток рек и пополнение для данной страны грунтовых вод эндогенного (глубинного) отложения. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Внешние возобновляемые водные ресурсы означают стоки воды, поступающие в страну, с учетом количества стоков, зарезервированных для стран, расположенных в верховьях и низовьях рек, на основании соглашений или договоров.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Общий забор пресной воды (ОЗПВ) - это объем пресной воды, извлеченной из ее источника (реки, озера, водоносные горизонты) для сельского хозяйства, промышленности и сферы услуг. &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href= &quot;#footnote-1&quot;id=&quot;footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;[1] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; Он оценивается на страновом уровне для следующих трех основных секторов: сельское хозяйство, услуги (включая водозабор для бытовых нужд) и промышленность (включая охлаждение ТЭЦ). Забор пресной воды включает ископаемые подземные воды. Он не включает нетрадиционные источники воды, т.е. прямое использование очищенных сточных вод, прямое использование сельскохозяйственных дренажных вод и опресненной воды. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Оптимальный экологический дебит (ОЭД) определяются как количество и время поступления пресной воды и уровни, необходимые для поддержания аквариальных экосистем, которые, в свою очередь, поддерживают человеческую культуру, экономику, устойчивые средства к существованию и благополучие. Качество воды, а также связанные с этим экосистемные услуги исключаются из этой формулировки, которая связана с объемами воды. Это не означает, что качество и поддержка обществ, зависящих от экологических потоков, не важны и о них не следует заботиться. &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot;id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt; [2] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; Методы расчета ОЭД чрезвычайно разнообразны и варьируются от глобальных оценок до всеобъемлющих оценок для участков рек. Для показателя ЦУР объемы воды могут быть выражены в тех же единицах, что и ОВРПВ, а также в долях от доступных водных ресурсов. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot;id=&quot;footnote-1&quot;&gt; 1 &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p&gt; В AQUASTAT забор воды для сектора услуг отражается как забор воды для муниципальных нужд. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot;id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt; 2 &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p&gt; Они несомненно учитываются в других целях и показателях, таких как 6.3.2, 6.5.1 и 6.6.1. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt; &amp;#x2191; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
