<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 10-a-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Rationale:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The calculation of this indicator will allow observing on how many products Developing countries and LDCs will have free access to Developed countries markets. When compared to the tariff rates applied to other countries, this indicator will allow assessing to which extent special and differential treatment has been accorded in terms of import tariffs. The evolution of this indicator will indicate progress on the phasing out of tariff rates on goods coming from Developing and LDCs.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El cálculo de este indicador permitirá observar sobre cuántos productos los países en desarrollo y los PMA tendrán libre acceso a los mercados de los países desarrollados. Si se compara con los tipos arancelarios aplicados a otros países, este indicador permitirá evaluar hasta qué punto se ha concedido un trato especial y diferenciado en términos de aranceles de importación. La evolución de este indicador indicará los avances en la eliminación progresiva de los tipos arancelarios sobre las mercancías procedentes de los países en desarrollo y de los PMA.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Justification : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le calcul de cet indicateur permettra d&apos;observer sur combien de produits les pays en développement et les PMA auront libre accès aux marchés des pays développés. Comparé aux taux tarifaires appliqués aux autres pays, cet indicateur permettra d&apos;évaluer dans quelle mesure un traitement spécial et différencié a été accordé en termes de tarifs d&apos;importation. L&apos;évolution de cet indicateur indiquera les progrès réalisés dans l&apos;élimination progressive des droits de douane sur les marchandises provenant des pays en développement et des PMA.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Расчет этого показателя позволит наблюдать, сколько товаров из развивающихся стран и наименее развитых стран будут иметь свободный доступ на рынки развитых стран. При сравнении с тарифными ставками, применяемыми к другим странам, этот показатель позволит оценить, в какой степени был предоставлен особый и дифференцированный режим с точки зрения импортных тарифов. Развитие этого показателя будет указывать на прогресс в поэтапной отмене тарифных ставок на товары, поступающие из развивающихся и наименее развитых стран. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
