<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 5-4-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;Time use statistics have been used for: (1) provide a measure of quality of life or general wellbeing of individuals and households; (2) offer a more comprehensive measurement of all forms of work, including unpaid household service work; (3) produce data relevant for monitoring gender equality and the empowerment of women and girls and are essential inputs for the policy and political dialogue on gender equality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International comparability of time-use statistics is limited by a number of factors, including: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Diary versus stylized time-use survey. Data on time-use can be collected through a 24-hour diary (light diary) or stylized questionnaire. With diaries, respondents are asked to report on what activity they were performing when they started the day, what activity followed, and the time that activity began and ended, and so forth through the 24 hours of the day. Stylized time-use questions ask respondents to recall the amount of time they allocated to a certain activity over a specified period, such as a day or week. Often, stylized time-use questions are attached as a module to a multipurpose household survey. The 24-hour diary method yields better results than the stylized method but is a more expensive mode of data collection. Data obtained from these two different data collection methods are usually not comparable, and even data collected with different stylized questions might not be comparable given that the level of details asked about activities performed might differ from one instrument to another, thus impacting the total time spent on a given activity. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time-use activity classification. Regional and national classifications of time-use activities may differ from ICATUS 2016, resulting in data that are not comparable across countries. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time-use data presented refer to the &amp;#x201C;main activity&amp;#x201D; only. Any &amp;#x201C;secondary activity&amp;#x201D; performed simultaneously with the main activity is not reflected in the average times shown. For instance, a woman may be cooking and looking after a child simultaneously. For countries reporting cooking as the main activity, time spent caring for children is not accounted for and reflected in the statistics. This may affect international comparability of data on time spent caring for children; it may also underestimate the time women spend on this activity. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Different target age population used by countries and age groups used also make time use data difficult to compare across countries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</data>
</root>
