<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 16-9-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UNICEF undertakes a wide consultative process of compiling and assessing data from national sources for the purposes of updating its global databases on the situation of children. Up until 2017, the mechanism UNICEF used to collaborate with national authorities on ensuring data quality and international comparability on key indicators of relevance to children was known as Country Data Reporting on the Indicators for the Goals (CRING).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;As of 2018, UNICEF launched a new country consultation process with national authorities on selected child-related global SDG indicators it is custodian or co-custodian to meet emerging standards and guidelines on data flows for global reporting of SDG indicators, which place strong emphasis on technical rigour, country ownership and use of official data and statistics. The consultation process solicited feedback directly from National Statistical Offices, as well as other government agencies responsible for official statistics, on the compilation of the indicators, including the data sources used, and the application of internationally agreed definitions, classification and methodologies to the data from that source. Once reviewed, feedback is made available to countries on whether or not specific data points are accepted, and if not, the reasons why. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Proceso de recolección:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNICEF lleva a cabo un amplio proceso consultivo de recopilación y evaluación de datos procedentes de fuentes nacionales con el fin de actualizar sus bases de datos mundiales sobre la situación de la infancia. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hasta 2017, el mecanismo que UNICEF utilizaba para colaborar con las autoridades nacionales en la garantía de la calidad de los datos y la comparabilidad internacional de los indicadores clave de relevancia para la infancia se conocía como Informe de Datos de País sobre los Indicadores para los Objetivos (CRING, por sus siglas en inglés).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A partir de 2018, UNICEF lleva a cabo una consulta anual con las autoridades gubernamentales sobre 10 de los indicadores de los ODS relacionados con la infancia en su papel de custodio único o conjunto, y en consonancia con su mandato de supervisión global y sus compromisos normativos para avanzar en la Agenda 2030 para la infancia. Esto incluye el indicador 16.9.1. A continuación se describen más detalles sobre el proceso de consulta a los países. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ЮНИСЕФ проводит широкий процесс консультаций по сбору и оценке данных из национальных источников в целях обновления своих глобальных баз данных о положении детей. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Вплоть до 2017 года механизм, который ЮНИСЕФ использовал для сотрудничества с национальными властями по обеспечению качества данных и международной сопоставимости ключевых показателей, актуальных для детей, назывался «Отчетность по странам, относящаяся к показателям для Целей» (CRING).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Начиная с 2018 года ЮНИСЕФ проводит ежегодные консультации с государственными органами по 10 показателям ЦУР, связанным с детьми, в качестве единоличного ответственного учреждения или как член совместного ответственного учреждения и в соответствии со своим глобальным мандатом в области мониторинга и нормативными обязательствами по продвижению Повестки дня в интересах детей на период до 2030 года. Сюда входит показатель 16.9.1. Более подробная информация о процессе консультации со страной изложена ниже.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
