<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 16-9-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Treatment of missing values:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At country level:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When data for a country are entirely missing, UNICEF does not publish any country-level estimate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At regional and global levels:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The regional average is applied to those countries within the region with missing values for the purposes of calculating regional aggregates only, but are not published as country-level estimates. Regional aggregates are only published when at least 50 per cent of the regional population for the relevant age group are covered by the available data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The global aggregate is a weighted average of all the SDG sub-regional aggregates that make up the world. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel de país:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cuando los datos de un país faltan por completo, UNICEF no publica ninguna estimación a nivel de país&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel regional y mundial:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La media regional se aplica a los países de la región con valores faltantes sólo a efectos de calcular los agregados regionales, pero no se publican como estimaciones a nivel de país. Los agregados regionales sólo se publican cuando al menos el 50% de la población regional para el grupo de edad correspondiente está cubierta por los datos disponibles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; El agregado mundial es una media ponderada de todos los agregados subregionales de los ODS que componen el mundo. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Когда данные по стране полностью отсутствуют, ЮНИСЕФ не публикует никаких оценок на страновом уровне&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Среднее значение по региону применяется к тем странам в регионе, у которых отсутствуют значения, только для целей расчета региональных агрегатов, но они не публикуются в качестве оценок на страновом уровне. Сводные данные по регионам публикуются только в том случае, если имеющиеся данные охватывают по крайней мере 50 процентов населения региона соответствующей возрастной группы. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Глобальный агрегат - это средневзвешенное значение всех субрегиональных агрегатов ЦУР, составляющих весь мир. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
