<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 16-9-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportion of children under 5 years of age whose births have been registered with a civil authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Birth registration&lt;/strong&gt;: Birth registration is defined as &amp;#x2018;the continuous, permanent and universal recording, within the civil registry, of the occurrence and characteristics of births in accordance with the legal requirements of a country&amp;#x2019;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Birth certificate&lt;/strong&gt;: A birth certificate is a vital record that documents the birth of a child. The term &amp;#x2018;birth certificate&amp;#x2019; can refer either to the original document certifying the circumstances of the birth, or to a certified copy or representation of the registration of that birth, depending on the practices of the country issuing the certificate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Civil authority&lt;/strong&gt;: Official authorized to register the occurrence of a vital event and to record the required details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Доля детей в возрасте до 5 лет, рождение которых было зарегистрировано в гражданском органе. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Регистрация рождений&lt;/strong&gt;: Регистрация рождений определяется
как непрерывная, постоянная и повсеместная запись в реестре актов гражданского состояния фактов и характеристик рождений в соответствии с требованиями законодательства страны.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Свидетельство о рождении&lt;/strong&gt;: Свидетельство о рождении - это
запись о рождении ребенка. Термин &quot;свидетельство о рождении&quot; может относиться либо к подлинному документу, подтверждающему обстоятельства рождения, либо к заверенной копии или к документу, заверяющему регистрацию этого рождения, в зависимости от практики страны, выдавшей свидетельство.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Гражданский орган&lt;/strong&gt;: Орган, официально уполномоченный регистрировать
жизненно важные события и фиксировать необходимые детали.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
