<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The CLASS_SYSTEM field for indicator 15-1-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;Protected Areas are defined as described above by IUCN (IUCN; Dudley 2008) and documented in the World Database on Protected Areas (WDPA). (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net&quot;&gt;www.protectedplanet.net&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importantly, a variety of specific management objectives are recognised within this definition, spanning conservation, restoration, and sustainable use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Category Ia: Strict nature reserve&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Category Ib: Wilderness area&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Category II: National park&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Category III: Natural monument or feature&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Category IV: Habitat/species management area&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Category V: Protected landscape/seascape&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Category VI: Protected area with sustainable use of natural resources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The status &amp;quot;designated&amp;quot; is attributed to a protected area when the corresponding authority, according to national legislation or common practice (e.g., by means of an executive decree or the like), officially endorses a document of designation. The designation must be made for the purpose of biodiversity conservation, not de facto protection arising because of some other activity (e.g., military).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data on protected areas are managed in the WDPA (www.protectedplanet.net) by UNEP-WCMC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OECMs are defined as described above by the Convention on Biological Diversity (CBD 2018) and documented in the World Database on Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures (WDOECM) (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net/en/thematic-areas/oecms&quot;&gt;www.protectedplanet.net/en/thematic-areas/oecms&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OECMs are defined by the Convention on Biological Diversity (CBD) as &amp;#x201C;A geographically defined area other than a Protected Area, which is governed and managed in ways that achieve positive and sustained long-term outcomes for the in-situ conservation of biodiversity, with associated ecosystem functions and services and where applicable, cultural, spiritual, socio&amp;#x2013;economic, and other locally relevant values&amp;#x201D; (CBD, 2018). Data on OECMs are managed in the WDOECM (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net/en/thematic-areas/oecms&quot;&gt;www.protectedplanet.net/en/thematic-areas/oecms&lt;/a&gt;) by UNEP-WCMC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Biodiversity Areas (KBAs) are defined as described below by IUCN (2016) and documented in the World Database of KBAs (WDKBA) (www.keybiodiversityareas.org/kba-data).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sites contributing significantly to the global persistence of biodiversity are identified following globally criteria set out in A Global Standard for the Identification of KBAs (IUCN 2016) applied at national levels. KBAs encompass (a) Important Bird &amp;amp; Biodiversity Areas, that is, sites contributing significantly to the global persistence of biodiversity, identified using data on birds, of which more than13,000 sites in total have been identified from all of the world&amp;#x2019;s countries (BirdLife International 2014, Donald et al. 2018); (b) Alliance for Zero Extinction sites (Ricketts et al. 2005), that is, sites holding effectively the entire population of at least one species assessed as Critically Endangered or Endangered on the IUCN Red List of Threatened Species, of which 853 sites have been identified for 1,483 species of mammals, birds, amphibians, reptiles, freshwater crustaceans, reef-building corals, conifers, cycads and other taxa; (c) KBAs identified under an earlier version of the KBA criteria (Langhammer et al. 2007), including those identified in Ecosystem Hotspot Profiles developed with support of the Critical Ecosystem Partnership Fund. These three subsets are being reassessed using the Global Standard, which unifies these approaches along with other mechanisms for identification of important sites for other species and ecosystems (IUCN 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data on KBAs are managed in the WDKBA (www.keybiodiversityareas.org/kba-data) by BirdLife International on behalf of the KBA Partnership.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
