<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COMPARABILITY field for indicator 3-3-3, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The estimated incidence can differ from the incidence reported by a Ministry of Health which can be affected by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the completeness of reporting: the number of reported cases can be lower than the estimated cases if the percentage of health facilities reporting in a month is less than 100%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the extent of malaria diagnostic testing (the number of slides examined or RDTs performed) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the use of private health facilities which are usually not included in reporting systems. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Sources des divergences : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;incidence estimée peut être différente de l&apos;incidence signalée par un ministère de la santé, qui peut être affectée par :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;l&apos;exhaustivité de la notification (le nombre de cas notifiés peut être inférieur aux cas estimés si le pourcentage d&apos;établissements de santé notifiant au cours d&apos;un mois est inférieur à 100%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;l&apos;étendue des tests de diagnostic du paludisme (nombre de lames examinées ou de TDR effectués) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;le recours à des établissements de santé privés qui ne sont généralement pas inclus dans les systèmes de déclaration. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Информация о предположительном уровне заболеваемости может отличаться от данных по уровню заболеваемости, содержащихся в отчете Министерства здравоохранения, на что могут влиять следующие факторы: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; полнота отчетности: количество зарегистрированных случаев может быть меньше
предположительного значения, если доля медицинских учреждений, представляющих отчеты за месяц, составляет менее 100% &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; объем диагностического тестирования малярии (количество исследованных мазков
или выполненных быстрых диагностических тестов (БДТ) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; пользование частными медицинскими учреждениями, которые обычно не включаются
в системы отчетности. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
