<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 3-3-3, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;To measure trends in malaria morbidity and to identify locations where the risk of disease is highest. With this information, programmes can respond to unusual trends, such as epidemics, and direct resources to the populations most in need. This data also serves to inform global resource allocation for malaria such as when defining eligibility criteria for Global Fund finance. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Justificación&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medir las tendencias de la morbilidad de la malaria e identificar los lugares donde el riesgo de enfermedad es mayor. Con esta información, los programas pueden responder a tendencias inusuales, como las epidemias, y dirigir los recursos a las poblaciones más necesitadas. Estos datos también sirven para informar sobre la asignación global de recursos para la malaria, como, por ejemplo, a la hora de definir los criterios de elegibilidad para la financiación del Fondo Mundial.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Justification &lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La justification est de mesurer l&apos;évolution de la morbidité liée au paludisme et identifier les endroits où le risque de maladie est le plus élevé. Grâce à ces informations, les programmes peuvent répondre à des tendances inhabituelles, telles que les épidémies, et orienter les ressources vers les populations qui en ont le plus besoin. Ces données servent également à éclairer l&apos;allocation des ressources mondiales pour le paludisme, par exemple lors de la définition des critères d&apos;éligibilité au financement du Fonds mondial.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Обоснование &lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Произвести оценку тенденций в заболеваемости малярией и определить места, где риск заболевания наиболее высок. Располагая этой информацией, программы могут реагировать на аномальные тенденции, такие как эпидемии, и направлять ресурсы наиболее нуждающимся группам населения. Эти данные также служат информационной основой в процессе глобального распределения ресурсов на борьбу с малярией, например, при определении критериев отбора для финансирования Глобального фонда. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
