<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 2-1-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;The indicator is computed at the population level. To this aim, the population is represented by an &amp;#x201C;average&amp;#x201D; individual for which a probability distribution of the habitual daily dietary energy intake levels is modelled through a parametric probability density function (pdf). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the pdf is characterized, the indicator is obtained as the cumulative probability that daily habitual dietary energy intakes (x) are below the lower bound of the range of normal dietary energy requirements for that representative, or average individual (MDER), as in the formula below: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PoU= &amp;#x222B;_(x&amp;lt;MDER) f(x | DEC; CV) dx &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where DEC and CV are the mean and coefficient of variation that characterize the distribution of habitual dietary energy consumption levels in the population. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A custom R function is available from the Statistics Division at FAO to compute the PoU, given the three parameters DEC, CV, and MDER. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different data sources can be used to estimate the different parameters of the model. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DEC &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mean of the distribution of dietary energy consumption levels for the average individual in a population (DEC) corresponds, by definition, to the average, daily per capita food consumption level in the population. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DEC can be estimated from data on food consumption obtained through surveys that are representative of the population of interest. Depending on the survey design, they can be used to estimate DEC at national and at sub national levels, either by geographic areas or by socio-economic population groups. Unfortunately, though the situation is rapidly improving, representative surveys that collect food consumption data are still not available for every country and every year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the national population only, DEC can be estimated also from accounts of the total supply and utilization of all food commodities in a country, where the contribution of each commodity to the availability of food for human consumption is expressed in their dietary energy content, and their total is divided by the size of the population. The major source of data on national food balances are the Food Balance Sheets (FBS) maintained by FAO for most countries in the world (see http://www.fao.org/economic/ess/fbs/en/), informed by official data reported by member countries, and disseminated through FAOSTAT (http://www.fao.org/faostat/en/#data) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CV &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surveys that contain information on food consumption at individual or household level are the only available source to directly estimate the CV of habitual food consumption for the representative individual in the population. Unfortunately, survey data on food consumption are fraught by many problems that complicate the reliable estimation of CV. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In principle, repeated observations of daily consumption for each individual in a sample would be needed to estimate levels of habitual consumption and to control for measurement errors. Moreover, data should be collected in different periods of the year on the same individuals or households to account for possible seasonal variation in levels of dietary energy consumption. Due to their cost, nationally representative individual dietary intake surveys with such characteristics are very rare, and virtually inexistent for most developing countries. As a consequence, the most common sources of data to estimate CV are multipurpose household surveys, such as Living Standard Measurement Surveys, Household Incomes and Expenditure Surveys (or Household Budgets Survey), that collect also information on food consumption. When using data collected at household level however, careful attention should be taken in distinguishing levels of food purchases or acquisitions from levels of actual utilization (consumption and wastage) during the identified reference period and in properly recording the number of individuals who participate in consumption; moreover, household level data will mask the variability due to intra-household allocation of food. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all these reasons, the coefficient of variation calculated on the series of average per capita daily dietary energy consumption levels recorded for each household included in a survey is never a reliable estimate of CV, which should reflect variability in the levels of habitual (and not occasional) daily dietary energy consumption level, at the individual (and not household) level. Empirical estimates of CV from household survey data are upward biased due to the spurious variability induced by measurement error, differences between occasional and habitual consumption, differences between acquisition and actual consumption and seasonality; moreover, they do not reflect the variability in dietary energy consumption in the population associated with individual characteristics of the household members (such as sex, age, body mass and physical activity levels). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When using data collected through household surveys, CV is thus best estimated indirectly, controlling for spurious variability, and adjusted to reflect inter-individuals (in addition to inter-households) variability. The simplest way to proceed is to classify households into homogeneous groups and to calculate the coefficient of variation of the average per capita dietary energy consumption across household groups. This yields an estimate of the inter-households component of CV, labelled CV_H. An estimate of the inter-individuals component of the CV, labelled CV_I, is obtained, for each population, from its structure by sex, age and body masses, and the two components are combined to obtain the needed estimate as: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CV^ = v[(CV_H)^2+(CV_I)^2 )]. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For countries and years when no data from household survey are available, an indirect estimate of the CV, CV_IND, is obtained via a regression that projects the values of per capita GDP, Gini coefficient of income, and an index of the relative price of food (FPI) on the CV, while controlling for a regional shifter (REG). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CV^_IND=&amp;#xDF;_0+&amp;#xDF;_1 GDP+ &amp;#xDF;_2 GINI+ &amp;#xDF;_3 FPI+&amp;#xDF;_4 REG. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coefficients of the regression are estimated from the set of data and years for which data on CV, GDP, GINI and FPI are available. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MDER &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human energy requirements are computed by multiplying normative requirements for basic metabolic rate (BMR, expressed per kg of body mass) by the ideal weight of a healthy person of given height, and then multiplied by a coefficient of physical activity level (PAL). Ranges of normal energy requirements are thus computed for each sex and age group of the population, observing that there exist a whole range of Body Mass Index (BMI) values &amp;#x2013; from 18.5 to 25 &amp;#x2013; that are compatible with health. This implies that any given attained height might correspond to a whole range of healthy body weights, and therefore to a range of values for energy requirement for BMR. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given information on the median height and the consideration that the group might contain individuals engaged in different levels of physical activity, the minimum, average and maximum dietary energy requirement can be computed for every sex and age class by taking into consideration special allowances for growth in individuals aged 0-21 and for pregnancy and lactation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(See ftp://ftp.fao.org/docrep/fao/007/y5686e/y5686e00.pdf for further details). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MDER for a given population group, including for the national population, is obtained as the weighted average of the minimums of the energy requirements ranges of each sex and age class, using the population size in each class as weights. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In computing the prevalence of dietary energy inadequacy in a population there has often been confusion between the concept of MDER and that of the Recommended Dietary Energy Intake, and regarding the appropriate threshold to be used to compute the probability of inadequacy. The reason why the probability of dietary energy inadequacy should be computed with reference to the MDER, and not the ADER (which, instead, can be used as an estimate of the average recommended dietary intake level for the whole population) is simply to recognize the fact that in any population there exists a certain range of normal variability in requirements; using the ADER as a threshold would greatly overestimate undernourishment as it would count also the proportion of the healthy population that consumes less than average, simply because of having less than average requirements. When needed, the ADER, or the average Recommended Dietary Energy Intake level in a population must be used instead to compute the dietary energy gap.&amp;quot; &lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
