<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SDG_RELATED_INDICATORS field for indicator 12-b-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;8.9.1 Tourism Direct GDP as a proportion of total GDP and in growth rate &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15.9.1 (a) Number of countries that have established national targets in accordance with or similar to Aichi Biodiversity Target 2 of the Strategic Plan for Biodiversity 2011&amp;#x2013;2020 in their national biodiversity strategy and action plans and the progress reported towards these targets; and (b) integration of biodiversity into national accounting and reporting systems, defined as implementation of the System of Environmental-Economic Accounting&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Indicadores relacionados&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.9.1 PIB directo del turismo (indicador derivado de la CST).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15.9.1 Progreso hacia las metas nacionales establecidas de acuerdo con la&amp;#xA0;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/sp/targets/rationale/target-2/&quot;&gt;Meta 2 de Aichi para la Diversidad Biológica&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#xA0;del Plan Estratégico para la Diversidad Biológica 2011-2020&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Indicateurs connexes &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.9.1 GDP direct du tourisme (indicateur dérivé du CST).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15.9.1 Progrès vers les objectifs nationaux établis conformément à &amp;#xA0;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/sp/targets/rationale/target-2/&quot;&gt;l&apos;objectif 2 d&apos;Aichi pour la biodiversité &lt;/a&gt;&amp;#xA0;du Plan stratégique pour la biodiversité 2011-2020.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Связанные показатели &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 8.9.1 8.9.1 Прямой вклад туризма в ВВП (показатель получен из вспомогательных счетов туризма). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 15.9.1Прогресс в достижении национальных целевых показателей, установленных в соответствии с Айтинской целевой задачей 2 по биоразнообразию в рамках Стратегического плана по биоразнообразию на 2011–2020 годы&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
