<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 16-7-1a, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Measuring representation&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The significance of descriptive representation has been challenged in different ways. First, there is the question of what and who should be mirrored in the representative body; why be attentive to some groups (women, young people, minorities etc) but not others (the poor, LGBTI, &amp;quot;ethnic&amp;quot; groups who might not be officially recognized etc)? Second, the mirror notion of descriptive representation may be deemed dangerous if it precludes citizens from choosing representatives who do not look like them. One of the base tenets of democracy is freedom of choice at the ballot box and if one is corralled into having to vote for a candidate of your own sex or ethnicity, then that intrinsic liberty is constrained. Third, descriptive representation has the danger of ultimately becoming an end in itself. Concerns about effective representation should not end once parliament has the appropriate number of members for each minority groups. Indeed at this stage concerns about adequate political representation should be just beginning. These members should be able to articulate minority concerns and have the same opportunities to influence policy as other members. Nevertheless, if a parliament includes none, or very few, women, young people, minorities etc., that is probably a worrying sign that their interests are not being heard. &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-10&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-10&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Representation needs to go hand in hand with participation, with both concepts being part of target 16.7. Without meaningful opportunities for citizens to participate in parliamentary decision-making, representation alone is unlikely to automatically lead to effective popular control of the government - one of the fundamental principles of democracy (International IDEA, 2013). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The age and sex of individuals holding decision-making positions in parliament provide an indication at the symbolic level of the way in which power is shared within this institution. However, there is no certainty that because a Speaker or committee Chair is young (or old), a woman (or a man), or belongs to a minority group, s/he will bring to the fore issues of interest to groups with the same socio-demographic profile.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tracking the age of MPs over time offers some measure of youth representation in parliament. However, in most parliaments around the world, leadership positions such as Speaker and permanent committee Chairs are considered senior functions which require considerable experience, and are awarded in recognition of parliamentary achievement. This means that such positions are by nature unlikely to be held by members below the &amp;#x2018;youth&amp;#x2019; age bracket of &amp;#x2018;45 years old and under&amp;#x2019;. As such, for the positions of Speaker and committee Chairs, more relevant insights will be generated on the basis of sex disaggregation. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IPU studies on women in parliaments&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-11&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-11&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; have found that committees representing the three &amp;#x2018;hard&amp;#x2019; policy portfolios of Foreign Affairs, Defence and Finance are traditionally male-dominated. The two other committees tracked by this indicator, representing cross-cutting portfolios of Human Rights and Gender Equality, are also of interest given their specific areas of focus. Although not found in every parliament, the very existence of these two committees suggests a particular commitment within parliament to safeguarding human rights and promoting gender equality. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In certain countries, particularly Small Island Developing States, the number of members of parliament may be very small. Consequently, there may not be a committee system, or the committee system may not contain the same distribution by areas of responsibility as observed in the majority of parliaments. In addition, in parliaments with a very small number of members, the addition or reduction of just one or two people to the number of women or the number of young MPs may have a significant impact on the overall percentage of representation of these groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Methodology&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As regards the scope of &amp;#x2018;population groups&amp;#x2019;, while representation of minorities and indigenous peoples may be more often tracked by national parliaments due to the availability of internationally accepted definitions, the indicator also invites reporting on any other tracked population groups, including, for instance, occupational groups.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An obvious limitation of this metadata is that it only considers members of parliament, in keeping with the focus of target 16.7 on &amp;#x2018;decision-making&amp;#x2019;. However, some parliaments may find it useful to also look at the composition of various staff categories such as clerks of the parliament, committee clerks or researchers, etc. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who holds the Chairs of parliamentary committees is largely tributary to the overall distribution of seats within the parliament. For example, parliaments with no members under the age of 30 will not have any committee Chairs under that age. Since committee chairs are typically awarded on the basis of experience and seniority,&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-12&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-12&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; higher age groups are expected to be common among committee Chairs and Speakers. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Data collection&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In between reporting dates, it may be difficult to maintain up-to-date information on the results of by-elections held in selected constituencies to fill vacancies arising from the death or resignation of members.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From one year to another during any given parliamentary term (typically 4 or 5 years), some Members may fall into a different age group amongst those considered for this indicator. For this reason, age of Members is collected at the time of their election to parliament &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Age of Speakers and permanent committee Chairs is collected at the time of their appointment to the position, then verified and updated as of 1 January each year. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Recommended approach to monitoring disability and population groups:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;1) Sensitivity of disability and population group data&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Efforts to promote inclusive parliaments presuppose recognition of ethno-cultural diversity&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-13&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-13&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. In certain contexts, population group status may prove to be a sensitive and politically charged variable. For example, several countries actively restrict or ban identification of ethnic or religious status, in order to protect vulnerable populations or discourage inter-ethnic conflict. In addition, definitions of groups that constitute a minority vary greatly between countries. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Furthermore, there is a strong human rights principle that individuals must be able to choose to identify themselves as members of a minority, or not. It would not be appropriate for parliaments (or any other body) to assume or to assign MPs&amp;#x2019; membership of a particular population group. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Similarly, discriminatory perceptions and implicit bias against disability can make the collection of data by parliaments on this characteristic equally sensitive. This is partly because parliamentarians with disabilities, like everyone else, have a right to privacy and therefore are not under an obligation to reveal a disability. Moreover, in many states, information concerning disability falls under the umbrella of health data and is therefore confidential, thus preventing parliaments to release this information even on an anonymous basis.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-14&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-14&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As a result, currently, next to no countries systematically collect data on disability among members of parliaments. As pointed out by the European Union Agency for Fundamental Rights (FRA), while collecting reliable and accurate statistical data regarding the experiences of persons with disabilities presents numerous challenges, the lack of comparable data hinders the understanding of barriers to political participation.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-15&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-15&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;2) Limitations of the descriptive representation approach to tracking disability and population group status &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unlike for sex and age, monitoring the descriptive representation of members of parliament based on disability or population group status would be neither feasible nor meaningful.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Considering how broad the concept of disability is, encompassing various types of impairments and various degrees of severity, it would be unrealistic and unwarranted to expect a one-to-one ratio of representation in parliament. Furthermore, since national-level disability statistics are not always up-to-date, let alone available, the comparison between the share of disabled in the national population and in parliament could be unsound, or difficult to establish. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are similar concerns with respect to monitoring the representation of various population groups. In countries whose populations are a mosaic of many diverse groups (some of which may account for less than 1 percent of the population) an exact reflection of such pluralism in the composition of parliament would be impossible and unnecessary. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For ethical reasons, data on disability and population group status of MPs could only be collected through individual surveys that meet required standards of confidentiality. Seeing that such practice is currently not in place, the testing of this approach will be explored in the future to establish whether surveying the world&amp;#x2019;s 46,000 parliamentarians is feasible. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;3) Adopting an incremental approach &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Given the perceived sensitivity of collecting data on disability and population group status and concerns related to the feasibility and usefulness of monitoring descriptive representation, it is proposed to take stock instead of electoral and constitutional provisions guaranteeing the representation of persons with disabilities and various population groups in national parliaments. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reserved seats and quotas&lt;/strong&gt; are among the most commonly utilized electoral means to ensure representation of certain groups in the political process. Above and beyond guaranteeing a minimum number of seats held by persons with disabilities and certain population groups, the existence of such provisions substantiates a country&amp;#x2019;s commitment to the right to equal participation in public and political life.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provisions on quotas can be found in countries&amp;#x2019; constitutions or electoral laws (i.e. legislated quotas).&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-16&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-16&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Such electoral measures are used to achieve equal or balanced access to political power by increasing access to political decision-making processes of certain sociodemographic groups. In 2010, the constitutions or electoral laws of more than 30 countries included electoral quotas for various groups (e.g. ethnic, religious) that commonly go under the name of &amp;#x2018;minority groups&amp;#x2019;. A few countries have similar provisions for persons with disabilities&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-17&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-17&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The impracticality of looking at descriptive representation does not mean there is no merit in producing statistics on disability or population groups in parliament. Even an indicative number of MPs self-reporting disability could help parliamentary administrations around the world to better accommodate their special needs. It could also provide valuable information on the actual exercise (and not only the legal status) of the human right to equal opportunity to participate in the public and political life. When supported by concrete figures, such information can be valuable to a broad range of actors trying to identify and address barriers to political participation, including civil society, community advocates, researchers, development partners and political institutions themselves. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In line with the proposed incremental approach, an &amp;#x2018;Inclusion Survey&amp;#x2019; (see Annex and Data Sources) was developed to facilitate the collection of self-reported data on disability (using the Short Set of Questions on&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Disability&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;elaborated by the Washington Group) and population group status by parliaments. This short survey module of 8 questions, developed specifically for the purpose of reporting on indicator 16.7.1(a), could be administered directly to all Members by a neutral sponsor such as a national statistical office or the IPU itself. Importantly, the introduction to the survey reassures respondents of the anonymity and confidentiality of their responses, which is essential to overcome individual reluctance to disclose sensitive personal information. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Recommendations for reporting also on the composition of local parliaments &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While at present the indicator looks only at national parliaments, broadening its scope to include legislative bodies of local governments could be considered in the future, in line with target 16.7 which calls for decision-making to be representative &amp;#x201C;at all levels&amp;#x201D;. Local councils or assemblies hold important decision-making powers, including the ability to issue by-laws that influence the lives of their respective local communities. While it is premature at this stage to propose a global methodology to report on representation in local legislatures due to the varying quality of data collection systems in place at the local level, and to a number of methodological complexities (notably with regards to the need for disaggregated population statistics to be available for each administrative division, in order to compute representation ratios in each local parliament), countries should nonetheless be encouraged to track diversity in local parliaments, using methodologies appropriate to their local context. As far as global SDG reporting is concerned, a recommendation for the future inclusion of local legislatures in indicator 16.7.1(a) can be found in Annex 1 to the Methodology Development Narrative. A custodian for this part of the indicator on local legislatures remains to be identified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-10&quot;&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; IPU and UNDP, &amp;#x201C;Frequently Asked Questions on the representation of minorities and indigenous peoples in parliament&amp;#x201D; (2008) in &amp;#x201C;Promoting inclusive parliaments: The representation of minorities and indigenous peoples in parliament&amp;#x201D; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-10&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-11&quot;&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; See, for example: IPU, &amp;#x201C;Gender-Sensitive Parliaments&amp;#x201D; (2011), &amp;#x201C;Equality in Politics: A Survey of Women and Men in Parliaments&amp;#x201D; (2008), &amp;#x201C;Women in Parliament: 20 Years in Review&amp;#x201D; (2016), &amp;#x201C;Women in Politics&amp;#x201D; (2017) &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-11&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-12&quot;&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; See e.g. IPU &amp;#x201C;Gender-sensitive Parliaments&amp;#x201D;, p. 18 (on committee chairs: &amp;#x201C;All leaders, irrespective of gender, need to demonstrate their capabilities before they can be accepted as credible and legitimate authority bearers&amp;#x201D;) &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-12&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-13&quot;&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; IPU and UNDP, &amp;#x201C;The representation of minorities and indigenous peoples in parliament: A global overview&amp;#x201D; (2010) &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-13&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-14&quot;&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; See, for example, the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR, 2016/679) which introduced a particularly broad definition of health data and a range of restrictions on processing it. GDPR took effect in all EU Member States in May 2018. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-14&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-15&quot;&gt;14&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; European Union Agency for Fundamental Rights, &amp;#x201C;The right to political participation for persons with disabilities: human rights indicators&amp;#x201D; (2014): &lt;a href=&quot;http://fra.europa.eu/en/publication/2014/right-political-participation-persons-disabilities-human-rights-indicators&quot;&gt;http://fra.europa.eu/en/publication/2014/right-political-participation-persons-disabilities-human-rights-indicators&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-15&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-16&quot;&gt;15&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Voluntary party quotas fall outside the scope of this indicator. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-16&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-17&quot;&gt;16&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Countries with constitutional or electoral provisions guaranteeing the representation of persons with disabilities in parliaments include Uganda, India, Afghanistan and Rwanda. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-17&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
