<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 16-7-1a, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The multiple data points pertaining to the parliamentary sub-component of indicator 16.7.1 will be compiled by the Inter-Parliamentary Union (IPU) based on information gathered in its New PARLINE database on national parliaments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Data on age and sex of Members and Speakers: &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IPU already collects data from secretariats of national parliaments on an ongoing basis for New PARLINE. The Platform already provides up-to-date and disaggregated data on the following positions: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Members&lt;/em&gt;: data disaggregated by sex and age. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Speakers&lt;/em&gt;: data disaggregated by sex and age. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chairs of permanent committees on Human Rights and Gender Equality: &lt;/em&gt;data disaggregated by sex and age. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Data on age and sex of Chairs of permanent committee &lt;/u&gt;on Foreign Affairs, Defense and Finance&lt;u&gt;: &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data on the sex and age of Chairs of permanent committees on Foreign Affairs, Defense and Finance New Parline, will be added to Parline in 2020 . This is building on the successful attempt made by the IPU in 2011 to collect sex-disaggregated data on committee Chairs, broken down by area of competence (see IPU, Gender-sensitive parliaments, 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Data on disability and population group status of Members:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the immediate future, data on the disability and population group status of individual members will not be collected. As explained above, (1) such characteristics are very rarely tracked by parliaments in a systematic way; (2) confidentiality and data protection concerns are likely to make such data collection challenging, if not legally impossible; (3) data on the representation of persons with disabilities or various population groups will likely be of limited potential use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, lists of electoral or constitutional provisions guaranteeing representation of persons with disabilities and various population groups in parliament are already compiled in the New PARLINE database (see &amp;#x2018;Reserved seats and quotas&amp;#x2019; section) and will be used to report on this indicator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future, it is recommended that the &amp;#x2018;Inclusion Survey&amp;#x2019; (see Annex) be considered by the IPU&amp;#x2019;s network of national parliaments. In this survey, each member is asked to self-report on (1) levels of difficulty in performing activities in five&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-7&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-7&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; core functional domains &amp;#x2013; namely seeing, hearing, walking, cognition and communication (the &amp;#x2018;Inclusion Survey&amp;#x2019; is an adapted version of the standardized Short Set of Questions on&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Disability&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;elaborated by the Washington Group), and (2) his/her affiliation to a national, ethnic, religious or linguistic minority group, or to an indigenous or occupational group, in keeping with the UN principle of self-identification with regards to indigenous peoples and minorities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the potential sensitivity of disclosing information on population groups and disability, declaring and being transparent as to who is the sponsor of the Inclusion Survey can make respondents more comfortable. It is important for the sponsor to be a neutral entity independent from the employer institution, and to be able to protect the confidentiality of survey respondents. In this regard, organisations such as IPU and National Statistical Offices are particularly well positioned to administer the Inclusion Survey in national parliaments, and to perform subsequent data analysis. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-7&quot;&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; It was advised by the Washington Group to omit the sixth domain of &amp;#x2018;self-care&amp;#x2019; from the Short Set of Questions on Disability, as this question does not capture additional disability cases but acts more like a &amp;#x2018;severity indicator&amp;#x2019;. Given the target population for this survey (members of parliament), this question was found unnecessary. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-7&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
