<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 16-10-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;h2&gt;Rationale:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As suggested by the Sustainable Development Solutions Network (SDSN) and UNESCO in earlier presentations to the UN Technical Support Team (UN TST), this is a relevant and measurable indicator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also responds to the growing number of UN member states that have already adopted legal guarantees, and many others that are currently considering relevant legislation or regulation in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rationale for assessing the implementation dimension is to assess the relevance of legal steps to practical information accessibility. It is not a composite indicator, but a logical linkage of laws and policies to practical impact that is relevant to SDG concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this indicator, the operative words are &amp;#x201C;adoption&amp;#x201D; and &amp;#x201C;implementation&amp;#x201D;. As such, it establishes: (a) whether a country (or at the global level, the number of countries) has constitutional, statutory and/or policy guarantees for public access to information; (b) the extent to which such national guarantees reflect &amp;#x2018;international agreements&amp;#x2019; (e.g. Universal Declaration of Human Rights, etc.); and (c) the implementation mechanisms in place for such guarantees, including the following variables:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Government efforts to publicly promote the right to information.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Citizens&amp;#x2019; awareness of their legal right to information and their ability to utilize it effectively.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The capacity of public bodies to provide information upon request by the public. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator thus collates data from multiple sources, including National Human Rights Institutions, national and international non-governmental organizations, academic institutions, and national media regulatory authorities, among others. Such information will be gathered, processed and checked by international organizations - UNESCO and World Bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNESCO collects some aspects of this data using the Media Development Indicators, in addition to the biennial World Trends in Freedom of Expression and Media Development report. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data on the existence of freedom of information laws are available for at least 195 countries.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
