<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 17-11-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Share of global trade is intended of a particular group of country fraction of total trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While for merchandise trade data are consistent through he time series (2000-current), for services trade there might be difficulties related to lack of harmonization for data previous to 2005. Before 2005 data are reported according the 5th Balance of Payments Manual. After 2005, data have been converted according to the categories and principles established by the 6th edition of the Balance of Payments Manual.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La participación en el comercio mundial se refiere a la fracción de un determinado grupo de países en el comercio total. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mientras que los datos del comercio de mercancías son coherentes a lo largo de la serie temporal (2000-actualidad), en el caso del comercio de servicios puede haber dificultades relacionadas con la falta de armonización de los datos anteriores a 2005. Los datos anteriores a 2005 se presentan de acuerdo con el 5º Manual de Balanza de Pagos. Después de 2005, los datos se han convertido según las categorías y los principios establecidos por la 6ª edición del Manual de Balanza de Pagos.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt;Методология&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Метод расчета:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Доля в мировой торговле подразумевает определенную часть, которая принадлежит стране в общем объеме торговли.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;В то время как данные по торговле товарами согласованы во временных рядах (с 2000 года по настоящее время), для торговли услугами могут возникнуть трудности, связанные с отсутствием гармонизации данных до 2005 года. До 2005 года данные представлялись в соответствии с 5-м изданием Руководства по платежному балансу. После 2005 года данные были преобразованы в соответствии с категориями и принципами, установленными 6-м изданием Руководства по платежному балансу.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
