<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DOC_METHOD field for indicator 9-1-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Methods and guidance available to countries for the compilation of the data at the national level:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aviation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Road/Rail/Inland waterways/Pipelines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metadata (explanations of coverage, breaks in series etc.) for the ITF and UNECE inland transport data are available through their respective online databases. The aforementioned Glossary for Transport Statistics provides definitions for passenger-km and tonne-km, but also for related terms such as what constitutes a passenger, the definitions and exclusions within each transport mode etc.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt; Méthodes et orientations à la disposition des pays pour la compilation des données au niveau national:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Aviation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Voies navigables routières/ferroviaires/intérieures/pipelines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Des métadonnées (explications de la couverture, ruptures en série, etc.) pour les données de transport intérieur de l’ITF et de l’CEE-ONU sont disponibles via leurs bases de données en ligne respectives. Le glossaire susmentionné pour les statistiques sur les transports fournit des définitions pour les passagers-km et les tonnes-km, mais aussi pour des termes connexes tels que ce qui constitue un passager, les définitions et exclusions dans chaque mode de transport, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Доступные странам методы и руководства для составления данных на национальном уровне: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Воздушный транспорт &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Автомобильный / железнодорожный / внутренний водный / трубопроводный транспорт &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Метаданные (объяснения охвата, разрывов в сериях и т. д.) для данных МТФ и ЕЭК ООН по внутреннему транспорту доступны по ссылке на соответствующие онлайн-базы данных. Вышеупомянутый Глоссарий по статистике транспорта содержит определения для пассажиро-километров и тонно-километров, а также для связанных терминов, таких как объяснение кто такой пассажир, определения и исключения для каждого вида транспорта и т. д. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
