<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 9-1-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At country level &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Aviation data are broadly complete.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;For inland transport statistics:&lt;/u&gt; In case of missing data for a country for which at least one data point is available since 2000, we calculate estimates based on the expected growth rate for the country. The growth rates are computed from other socio-economic variables, such as Gross Domestic Product (GDP), population or urbanization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;For road, rail, and inland waterways:&lt;/u&gt; For non-ITF/UNECE countries, countries that did not submit a response, or when there is uncertainty regarding the provided data, data points are estimated using the ITF models, which use several covariates such as GDP, population, transport network coverage and more. Currently there are four global models used for this analysis: the urban passenger model, the non-urban passenger model, the international freight model and the urban freight model. A description of the four models can be found in the ITF Transport Outlook 2021 or in the following resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ITF (2021) ITF Transport Outlook 2021, OECD Publishing &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ITF (2020) Decarbonising Transport in Europe, Project webpage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Maritime:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International maritime freight: In case of missing data for a country or a sub-region for which a data point is available since 2006, UNCTAD makes an estimate based on the expected growth rate of the volume of merchandise trade. If not available, use is made of the latest year for which data was available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Container port traffic: In case of missing data, UNCTAD makes an estimate by extrapolating from the liner shipping connectivity and ship capacity deployment data, which has shown to be highly correlated with container port traffic. Container ship deployment data are available for all container ships of the world, which thus allows for estimates on container port traffic to be generated even if no national data is available. In other cases, UNCTAD makes an estimate based on the expected growth rate of the volume of merchandise trade.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel de país:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aviación &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos son ampliamente completos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Estadísticas del transporte terrestre&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; En caso de que falten datos para un país del que se disponga de al menos una observación desde el año 2000, calculamos las estimaciones basándonos en la tasa de crecimiento prevista para el país. Las tasas de crecimiento se calculan a partir de otras variables socioeconómicas, como el Producto Interno Bruto (PIB), la población o la urbanización.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En el caso de los países no pertenecientes al ITF/UNECE, los puntos de datos se estiman utilizando el modelo de la ITF, que utiliza varias covariables como el PIB, la población y la cobertura de la red de transporte&amp;#x2026; Una descripción del modelo puede encontrarse en el informe ITF Transport Outlook 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ITF (2017) ITF Transport Outlook 2017, OECD Publishing &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Este modelo también utiliza varias otras fuentes de datos para que la calibración sea más sólida en las regiones en las que los datos del ITF no tienen una buena cobertura.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unión Internacional de Ferrocarriles (2015) Estadísticas ferroviarias &amp;#x2013; Sinopsis de 2015, UIC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Federación Internacional de Carreteras (2011) ITF World Road Statistics, IRF&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;De Bod, A., &amp;amp; Havenga, J. (2010). Sistema de transporte de mercancías por ferrocarril en el África subsahariana&amp;#x2019;: Potential impact of densification on cost. Journal of Transport and Supply Chain Management, Vol. 4, pp. 89-101&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt; Traitement des valeurs manquantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Au niveau national:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Aviation &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les données sont globalement complètes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Statistiques sur les transports intérieurs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; En cas de manque de données pour un pays pour lequel au moins un point de données est disponible depuis 2000, nous calculons les estimations en fonction du taux de croissance attendu pour le pays. Les taux de croissance sont calculés à partir d’autres variables socio-économiques, telles que le produit intérieur brut (PIB), la population ou l’urbanisation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Pour les pays non membres de l’ITF/CEE-ONU, les points de données sont estimés à l’aide du modèle ITF, qui utilise plusieurs covariés tels que le PIB, la population, la couverture des réseaux de transport&amp;#x2026; Une description du modèle se trouve dans les Perspectives des transports 2017 de l’ITF. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; ITF (2017) Perspectives des transports de l&apos;ITF 2017, Éditions de l&apos;OCDE
&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Ce modèle utilise également plusieurs autres sources de données pour rendre l’étalonnage plus robuste dans les régions où les données ITF n’ont pas une bonne couverture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Union internationale des chemins de fer (2015)Statistiques ferroviaires &amp;#x2013;
2015 synopsis, UIC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Fédération routière internationale (2011) Statistiques routières mondiales
de l&apos;ITF, FRI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; De Bod, A., &amp;amp; Havenga, J. (2010). Système de transport ferroviaire de
marchandises de l’Afrique subsaharienne&amp;#x2019; : Impact potentiel de la densification sur les coûts. Journal of Transport and Supply Chain Management, vol. 4, p. 89-101&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Воздушный транспорт &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные в целом полные. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Статистика внутреннего транспорта &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В случае отсутствия данных по стране, у которой имеется хотя бы один элемент данных с 2000 года, мы рассчитываем оценки на основе ожидаемых темпов роста для страны. Темпы роста рассчитываются на основе других социально-экономических переменных, таких как валовой внутренний продукт (ВВП), численность населения или степень урбанизации. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для стран, не входящих в МТФ / ЕЭК ООН, элементы данных оцениваются с использованием модели МТФ, которая использует несколько ковариаций, таких как ВВП, численность населения, охват транспортной сетью. Описание модели можно найти в Транспортном обзоре МТФ за 2017 год. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; МТФ (2017 год) Транспортный обзор МТФ за 2017 год, Публикация ОЭСР &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Эта модель также использует несколько других источников данных с тем, чтобы сделать калибровку более надежной в регионах, где данные МТФ не имеют хорошего охвата. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Международный союз железных дорог (2015 год) Статистика железных дорог &amp;#x2013; Краткий обзор за 2015 год, МСЖД &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Международная дорожная федерация (2011 год) Всемирная дорожная статистика МДФ, МДФ&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; De Bod, A., &amp;amp; Havenga, J. (2010). Sub-Saharan Africa&amp;#x2019;s rail freight transport system: Potential impact of densification on cost. Journal of Transport and Supply Chain Management, Vol. 4, pp. 89-101&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
