<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 9-1-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Treatment of missing values:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At country level:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aviation &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are broadly complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inland transport statistics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case of missing data for a country for which at least one data point is available since 2000, we calculate estimates based on the expected growth rate for the country. The growth rates are computed from other socio-economic variables, such as Gross Domestic Product (GDP), population or urbanization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For non-ITF/UNECE countries, data points are estimated using the ITF model, which uses several covariates such as GDP, population, transport network coverage&amp;#x2026; A description of the model can be found in the ITF Transport Outlook 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ITF (2017) ITF Transport Outlook 2017, OECD Publishing &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This model also uses several other data sources to make the calibration more robust in regions where ITF data does not have a good coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;International Union of Railways (2015) Railway Statistics &amp;#x2013; 2015 synopsis, UIC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;International Road Federation (2011) ITF World Road Statistics, IRF&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;De Bod, A., &amp;amp; Havenga, J. (2010). Sub-Saharan Africa&amp;#x2019;s rail freight transport system: Potential impact of densification on cost. Journal of Transport and Supply Chain Management, Vol. 4, pp. 89-101&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt; Traitement des valeurs manquantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Au niveau national:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Aviation &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les données sont globalement complètes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Statistiques sur les transports intérieurs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; En cas de manque de données pour un pays pour lequel au moins un point de données est disponible depuis 2000, nous calculons les estimations en fonction du taux de croissance attendu pour le pays. Les taux de croissance sont calculés à partir d’autres variables socio-économiques, telles que le produit intérieur brut (PIB), la population ou l’urbanisation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Pour les pays non membres de l’ITF/CEE-ONU, les points de données sont estimés à l’aide du modèle ITF, qui utilise plusieurs covariés tels que le PIB, la population, la couverture des réseaux de transport&amp;#x2026; Une description du modèle se trouve dans les Perspectives des transports 2017 de l’ITF. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; ITF (2017) Perspectives des transports de l&apos;ITF 2017, Éditions de l&apos;OCDE
&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Ce modèle utilise également plusieurs autres sources de données pour rendre l’étalonnage plus robuste dans les régions où les données ITF n’ont pas une bonne couverture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Union internationale des chemins de fer (2015)Statistiques ferroviaires &amp;#x2013;
2015 synopsis, UIC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Fédération routière internationale (2011) Statistiques routières mondiales
de l&apos;ITF, FRI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; De Bod, A., &amp;amp; Havenga, J. (2010). Système de transport ferroviaire de
marchandises de l’Afrique subsaharienne&amp;#x2019; : Impact potentiel de la densification sur les coûts. Journal of Transport and Supply Chain Management, vol. 4, p. 89-101&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
