<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 9-1-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Aviation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICAO Air Transport Reporting Forms approved by the Statistics Division of ICAO and its Member States has been used to define standards, methodologies and to collect aviation data since the 1950&amp;apos;s. ICAO definitions and metadata is also used by the Aviation Industry as the basis of collecting data and conducting analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Maritime:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UNCTAD secretariat collects and compiles the data from various websites and reports, including, by port and industry associations and authorities, national statistics offices, UN Monthly Bulletin of Statistics, governments, specialised agencies such as the International Energy Agency (IEA), the US Energy Information Administration (EIA), the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC), and, British Petroleum (BP). Data is also collected from reports issued by maritime specialised sources such as Drewry Maritime Research (DMR), Clarksons Research Services (CRS), Dynamar, and Lloyd&amp;#x2019;s List Intelligence (LLI).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Road, Rail, Inland waterways:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ITF runs transport models that are used to provide transport information for all regions.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aviación&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los formularios de notificación del transporte aéreo de la OACI, aprobados por la División de Estadística de la OACI y sus Estados miembros, se han utilizado para definir normas y metodologías y para recopilar datos sobre la aviación desde la década de 1950. Las definiciones y los metadatos de la OACI también son utilizados por la industria de la aviación como base para la recogida de datos y la realización de análisis.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt; Sources de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Aviation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les formulaires de déclaration du transport aérien de l’OACI approuvés par la Division des statistiques de l’OACI et de ses États membres ont été utilisés pour définir les normes, les méthodologies et recueillir des données sur l’aviation depuis les définitions et métadonnées de l’OACI de 1950&amp;apos;. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Воздушный транспорт &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Формы отчетности ИКАО по воздушному транспорту, утвержденные Статистическим отделом ИКАО и ее государствами-членами, используются для установления стандартов, методологий и процедуры сбора данных по воздушному транспорту с 1950-х годов. Определения и метаданные ИКАО также используются авиационной промышленностью в качестве основы для сбора данных и проведения анализа. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
