<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 2-2-3, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;Prevalence of anaemia and/or mean haemoglobin in women of reproductive age were obtained from 408 population-representative data sources from 124 countries worldwide. Data collected from 1995 to 2020 were used. Adjustment of data on blood haemoglobin concentrations for altitude and smoking was carried out whenever possible. Biologically implausible haemoglobin values (&amp;lt;25 g/L or &amp;gt;200 g/L) were excluded. A Bayesian hierarchical mixture model was used to estimate haemoglobin distributions and systematically addressed missing data, non-linear time trends, and representativeness of data sources. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full details on statistical methods may be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4547326/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;: Global, regional, and national trends in haemoglobin concentration and prevalence of total and severe anaemia in children and pregnant and non-pregnant women for 1995&amp;#x2013;2011: a systematic analysis of population-representative data (Stevens et al, 2013). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Briefly, the model calculates estimates for each country and year, informed by data from that country and year themselves, if available, and by data from other years in the same country and in other countries with data for similar time periods, especially countries in the same region. The model borrows data, to a greater extent, when data are non-existent or weakly informative, and to a lesser degree for data-rich countries and regions. The resulting estimates are also informed by covariates that help predict blood haemoglobin concentrations (e.g. socio-demographic index, meat supply (kcal/capita), mean BMI for women and log of under-five mortality for children). The uncertainty ranges (credibility intervals) reflect the major sources of uncertainty, including sampling error, non-sampling error due to issues in sample design/measurement, and uncertainty from making estimates for countries and years without data.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
