<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 6-6-1a, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator 6.6.1 tracks the extent to which different types of water-related ecosystems are changing in extent over time. The indicator is multifaceted capturing data on different types of freshwater ecosystems and to measure extent change the indicator considers spatial area changes, water quality and water quantity changes. The indicator uses satellite based Earth observations to globally monitor different freshwater ecosystems types Earth observation data series on surface area are available on permanent water, seasonal water, reservoirs, wetlands, mangroves; as well as generating data on water quality the using trophic state and turbidity of water bodies. Satellite images can be represented as numerical data, which in turn are aggregated into meaningful statistics of ecosystem change attributed to administrative areas such as national, sub-national (e.g. regions and provinces) and river basin boundaries. Global data products for river flows and groundwater level have not yet been produced at useful spatial and temporal resolutions to be incorporated into this SDG 6.6.1 methodology. Currently, these data should continue to be provided from modelling or from ground-based measurements and required from the countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SDG indicator 6.6.1 data derived from Earth observations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unit &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Features &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lakes &amp;amp; Rivers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;surface area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;annual and multi-annual changes in &lt;strong&gt;permanent water area&lt;/strong&gt; (1984-present)&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;statistics for new and lost permanent water (2000-2019)&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;statistics aggregated at national, sub-national &amp;amp; basin scales&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lakes &amp;amp; Rivers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;surface area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;annual and multi-annual changes in &lt;strong&gt;seasonal water area&lt;/strong&gt; (1984-present)&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;statistics for new and lost seasonal water (2000-2019)&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;annual seasonality statistics for periods: 0-1, 3-6, 7-11 months&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;statistics aggregated at national, sub-national &amp;amp; basin scales&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reservoirs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;surface area&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;water quality&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;annual and multi-annual changes in reservoir surface area (1984-prsent)&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;statistics for new and lost reservoir area (2000-2019)&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;statistics aggregated at national, sub-national &amp;amp; basin scales&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Monthly, annual and multi-annual measurements of trophic state and turbidity for 4,200 lakes and reservoirs globally (at 300m resolution)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mangroves&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;surface area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;annual and multi-annual changes in mangrove area (2000-2016)&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;statistics aggregated at national, sub-national &amp;amp; basin scales&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wetlands&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;surface area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;wetlands area (baseline area comprised of data btw 2016-2018)&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;statistics aggregated at national, sub-national &amp;amp; basin scales&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;wetlands area changes will be included starting in 2021/22&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lakes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;water quality&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Monthly, annual and multi-annual measurements of trophic state and turbidity for 4,200 lakes and reservoirs globally (at 300m resolution)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SDG indicator 6.6.1 data derived from national in-situ measurements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unit &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Features &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rivers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;flow &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;modelled natural runoff/streamflow&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;and/or&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;in-situ stream/river flow measurements, aggregated over time, of all major rivers&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Groundwater&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;level&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Changes to volume measurements, over time, of all major groundwater aquifers&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concepts and definitions used in the methodology have been based on existing international frameworks and glossaries unless where indicated otherwise below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water-related ecosystems&lt;/strong&gt; are a sub-set of all ecosystems. They contain the world&amp;#x2019;s freshwater resources and can be defined as &amp;#x201C;a dynamic complex of plant, animal, and micro-organism communities and the non-living environment dominated by the presence of flowing or still water, interacting as a functional unit.&amp;#x201D; (MEA, 2005; Dickens et al, 2019). The indicator is framed around the monitoring of different types of water-related ecosystems including lakes, rivers, wetlands, groundwater and artificial waterbodies such as reservoirs. These water-related ecosystems contain freshwater, with the exception of mangroves which contain brackish water (i.e. a combination of fresh and saltwater) however mangroves are still included within indicator 6.6.1. Reservoirs are also included as a category of water-related ecosystem within the indicator methodology; while it is recognized that reservoirs are not traditional water ecosystems which should necessarily warrant protection and restoration, in many countries they hold a noteworthy amount of freshwater and have thus been included. By including data on reservoirs, it is intended that countries can better understand changes occurring to artificial water bodies in conjunction with changes occurring to natural water bodies. Ecosystems that are not included under indicator 6.6.1 are: coral reefs and sea grass which are covered within Goal 14 (Oceans); and mountains, forests, and drylands which are covered within Goal 15 (Land). The extent to which each of the water-related ecosystems included under indicator 6.6.1 can be measured, uses one or more of the following physical parameters of change: spatial area, quantity (or volume) of water, and water quality. The full monitoring methodology for indicator 6.6.1 is available here. The extent to which each of the water-related ecosystems included under indicator 6.6.1 can be measured, uses one or more of the following physical parameters of change: spatial area, quantity (or volume) of water, and water quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inland vegetated wetlands&lt;/strong&gt; include areas of marshes, peatlands, swamps, bogs and fens, the vegetated parts of floodplains as well as rice paddies and flood recession agriculture. Inland vegetated wetlands do not include coastal mangroves. Data on mangroves which are produced separately to inland wetlands. This SDG indicator methodology is used for official reporting of SDG indicator 6.6.1 statistics. The SDG indicator 6.6.1 methodology does not apply the definition of wetlands defined by the Ramsar Convention on Wetlands, which is: &amp;#x201C;areas of marsh, fen, peatland or water, whether natural or artificial, permanent or temporary, with water that is static or flowing, fresh, brackish or salt, including areas of marine water the depth of which at low tide does not exceed six meters&amp;#x201D;. The Ramsar definition of wetlands may be interpreted to mean all water within a country including the marine environment. The SDG indicator 6.6.1 definition refers to only a specific group of inland vegetated wetlands typologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Permanent and seasonal water. A permanent water surface is underwater throughout the year whilst a seasonal water surface is underwater for less than 12 months of the year. Some locations don&amp;#x2019;t have observations for all 12 months of the year (for reasons such as polar night). In these cases, water is considered as seasonal if the number of months where water is present is less than the number of months where valid observations were acquired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second consideration is lakes and rivers that freeze for part of the year. During the frozen period water is still present under the ice (true both for rivers/lakes and the sea). If water is present throughout the observation period (i.e. unfrozen period), the water body is considered as a permanent water surface. If the area of the water body contracts during the unfrozen period, then the pixels along the borders of the lake or river are no longer water, and those pixels will be considered as a seasonal water surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reservoirs&lt;/strong&gt; are artificial (or human-made) bodies of freshwater, as opposed to lakes which are naturally occurring. The reservoirs dataset represents surface area data on artificial water bodies including reservoirs formed by dams, flooded areas such as opencast mines and quarries, flood irrigation areas, and water bodies created by hydro-engineering projects such as waterway and harbour construction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turbidity&lt;/strong&gt; is an indicator of water clarity, quantifying the haziness of the water and acting as an indicator of underwater light availability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trophic State&lt;/strong&gt; refers to the degree at which organic matter accumulates in the water body and is most commonly used in relation to monitoring eutrophication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surface Water refers to any area of surface water unobstructed by aquatic vegetation. This includes the following 3 water-related ecosystem categories: rivers and estuaries, lakes, and artificial waterbodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extent &amp;#x2013; has been expanded beyond spatial extent to capture additional basic parameters needed for the protection and restoration of water-related ecosystems. Extent includes three components: the spatial extent or surface area, the quality, and the quantity of water-related ecosystems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change means a shift from one condition of extent to another over time within a water-related ecosystem, measured against a point of reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Permanent and seasonal water concept definitions and data resolution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data on the spatial and temporal dynamics of naturally occurring surface water has been generated for the entire globe. A Global Surface Water dataset (Pekel et al., 2016) has been produced by the European Commission&amp;apos;s Joint Research Centre. The dataset documents different facets of the long term (since 1984 onward) water dynamics at 30x30 meter pixel resolution. The dataset documents permanent and seasonal surface water surfaces. All naturally occurring surface water larger in area than 30x30 meters has been mapped and at this 30 meter grid/pixel spatial resolution satellite imagery is predominantly capturing areas of lakes and wide rivers (ie rivers over 30meters wide). The data include land areas that are temporarily inundated. Smaller rivers and waterbodies are not captured as they are too narrow to detect or are masked by forest canopy. The data include individual full-resolution images acquired by the Landsat 5, 7 and 8 and Sentinel 1 satellites. These satellites capture images which are distributed publicly by the United States Geological Survey and by the European Union&amp;#x2019;s Copernicus space programme. Together they provide multispectral imagery at 30x30 meter resolution in six visible, near and shortwave infrared channels, plus thermal imagery at 60x60 meters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data includes land surfaces that are under water (e.g. a permanent water area) for all twelve months of a year. It also accounts for seasonal and climactic fluctuations of water, meaning lakes and rivers which freeze for part of the year are captured. Areas of permanent ice, such as glaciers and ice caps as well as permanently snow-covered land areas are not included. Areas of consistent cloud cover inhibit the observation of water surfaces in some areas and in these limited locations optical observations may not be available. A global shoreline mask has been applied to the data to prevent ocean water being included in the freshwater statistics and the methodology for this shoreline mask is published in the journal of operational oceanography, available here (Sayer et al. 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The accuracy of the Global Surface Water map was determined using over 40,000 control points from around the world and across the 36 years. The full validation methodology and results have been published in the scientific journal Nature, available here, (Pekel et al., 2016). The validation results show that the water detection expert system produced less than 1% of false water detections, and that less than 5% of water surfaces were missed. The provided maps are derived from the analysis of over four million images collected over 36 years which have been individually processed using an accurate expert system classifier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SDG 6.6.1 data portal (www.sdg661.app) documents various water transitions relating to permanent and seasonal surface water - these are changes in water state between two points in time (e.g. 2000 - 2019). Data is available for various transitions including new permanent water surfaces (i.e. conversion of a no water place into a permanent water place.); lost permanent water surfaces (i.e. conversion of a permanent water place into a no water place) as well as new and lost seasonal water. These allow monthly water presence or absence data to be captured. It is possible to identify specific months/years in which conditions changed, e.g. the date of filing of a new dam, or the month/year in which a lake disappeared. In addition, data on seasonality are provided, capturing changes resulting from intra and inter-annual variability or resulting from appearance or disappearance of seasonal or permanent water surfaces. The data separates &amp;apos;permanent&amp;apos; water bodies (those that are present throughout the period of observation) [nominally a year] from &amp;apos;seasonal&amp;apos; (those that are present for only part of the year).&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
