<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 2-a-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;Since the numerator of this data is based on financial and accounting systems and administrative sources, there is no confidence interval or standard error associated with government expenditure data. For the denominator, national accounts data typically do not provide any standard error or confidence interval information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key limitation with this indicator is that Consolidated General Government expenditure &amp;#x2013; the best measure for cross-country comparisons &amp;#x2013; is not available for all reporting countries. While most advanced economies &amp;#x2013; and many emerging market economies &amp;#x2013; do report these data, many smaller and/or low-income economies either do not have significant fiscal interventions in agriculture at the state/provincial and local/municipal levels; or do not have adequate source data to compile meaningful general government estimates for each subsector, as relevant. Given that in several countries, significant intervention in agriculture is implemented by sub-national governments, the Indicator 2.a.1 is calculated using the highest level of government available for the reporting country. For some countries, such as India, where the general government sector is defined for fiscal policy purposes as budgetary central government plus state government, the Indicator will take this into account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annex I lists the reporting countries, their M49 code, the latest year for which data are available and the level of government for which data has been reported. The level of government notation used is as follows: GG: Consolidated General Government; CG Consolidated Central Government (excluding Social Security Funds): CGI: Consolidated Central Government (including Social Security Funds); BA: Budgetary Central Government.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
