<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 10-7-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;Following the reclassification of SDG indicator 10.7.1 from tier III to tier II on October 2019, a number of countries have conducted activities to pilot the methodology and data collection strategy at national level. As of February 2022, these include: Bangladesh, Cambodia, Ghana, Indonesia, Lao PDR, Maldives, Mexico, Nepal, Philippines, South Korea, and Vietnam. Results for selected national pilot survey implementations are available in the ILO website at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilo.org/global/topics/fair-recruitment/WCMS_726736/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt;https://www.ilo.org/global/topics/fair-recruitment/WCMS_726736/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To complement official SDG 10.7.1 data, the ILO and the Global Knowledge Partnership on Migration and Development (KNOMAD), which is hosted at the World Bank, have supported several rounds of small scale Migration and Recruitment Costs Surveys for research and advocacy purposes. These surveys cover selected bilateral corridors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The datasets and documentation for these surveys can be found at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.knomad.org/data/recruitment-costs&quot;&gt;https://www.knomad.org/data/recruitment-costs&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desired disaggregation includes: sex, age group, education groups, and major destination countries (as recruitment costs have been documented to vary considerably by migration corridors).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional statistics may be presented by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;type of migration process (documented, undocumented migrant workers)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;occupation (ISCO-08): to assess skills levels such as high-skill and low-skill groups&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;major occupational groups: to assess which skills groups have the highest recruitment costs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;major industry (ISIC Rev.4): to assess main sectors where migrant workers are engaged and to assess recruitment costs in industries of key policy concern (e.g. agriculture, construction, retail, and domestic work)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</data>
</root>
