<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 2-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many sub-indicators for this indicator are already being collected in countries, either as part of existing farm surveys or through other data sources such as environmental monitoring systems, administrative data or household surveys. Yet they are not collected with a common set of criteria that fulfil the indicator requirements, guarantee the same quality or adherence to international comparability. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Time series:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SDG Indicator 2.4.1 measures progress towards more sustainable and productive agriculture over a three year periodicity because for many sub-indicators, it is likely that changes will be relatively limited from a year to another. Furthermore, the 3-year periodicity will enable countries to have three data points on the indicator before 2030.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator 2.4.1 is expected to be collected through farm surveys and the result expressed as a national value. However, the methodology is scale independent and can be adopted at any geographical level. In addition the indicator can be disaggregated according to type of farming system (crop, livestock or mixed) and other characteristics of the farm e.g. household/non-household sector, irrigated/non-irrigated or gender of the farm holder.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Disponibilité des données :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De nombreux sous-indicateurs de cet indicateur sont déjà recueillis dans les pays, soit dans le cadre d’enquêtes agricoles existantes, soit par le biais d’autres sources de données telles que les systèmes de surveillance de l’environnement, les données administratives ou les enquêtes auprès des ménages. Pourtant, ils ne sont pas recueillis avec un ensemble commun de critères qui répondent aux exigences de l’indicateur, garantissant la même qualité ou le respect de la comparabilité internationale. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Séries chronologiques :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’indicateur 2.4.1 des ODD mesure les progrès vers une agriculture plus durable et productive sur une périodicité de trois ans, car pour de nombreux sous-indicateurs, il est probable que les changements seront relativement limités d’une année à l’autre. En outre, la périodicité sur 3 ans permettra aux pays d’avoir trois points de données sur l’indicateur avant 2030. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Désagrégation :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’indicateur 2.4.1 devrait être recueilli au moyen d’enquêtes agricoles et le résultat devrait être exprimé en valeur nationale. Cependant, la méthodologie est indépendante de l’échelle et peut être adoptée à n’importe quel niveau géographique. En outre, l’indicateur peut être ventilé en fonction du type de système agricole (culture, bétail ou mixte) et d’autres caractéristiques de l’exploitation, par exemple le secteur des ménages/non-ménages, irrigué/non irrigué ou le sexe de l’exploitant. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
