<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 2-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partial non-response at individual level (farm holding) will be imputed using appropriate statistical techniques, such as nearest-neighbour algorithms. The decision on whether to impute or not and the choice of the method is a function of the nature of the variable to impute and the amount and type of data available for the imputation, such as the availability of auxiliary data coming from different sources (e.g. surveys, administrative information). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to clearly distinguish missing data from non-applicable events. As specified above and in the sub-indicator methodology sheets, some sub-indicators can be recorded as &amp;#x2018;not applicable&amp;#x2019; for a given farm. In this case, the farm will be considered sustainable from the perspective of the given sub-indicators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the country level, if and when data are provided using alternative sources for some of the sub-indicators, relevant notes to be provided by the country explaining the type, nature, source and time period of the data reported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No treatment of missing values will be carried out at the regional and global level. The regional and global estimates will be constructed using data of countries that have reported all 11 sub-indicators and/or those that have reported a sub-set of the 11 only if some of the sub-indicators are not applicable or irrelevant in the context of those country. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;La non-réponse partielle au niveau individuel (exploitation agricole) sera imputée à l&apos;aide de techniques statistiques appropriées, telles que les algorithmes du plus proche voisin. La décision d&apos;imputer ou non et le choix de la méthode sont fonction de la nature de la variable à imputer et de la quantité et du type de données disponibles pour l&apos;imputation, telles que la disponibilité de données auxiliaires provenant de différentes sources (par ex. enquêtes, informations administratives). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il est important de distinguer clairement les données manquantes des événements non applicables. Comme précisé ci-dessus et dans les fiches méthodologiques des sous-indicateurs, certains sous-indicateurs peuvent être enregistrés comme « sans objet » pour une exploitation donnée. Dans ce cas, l&apos;exploitation sera considérée comme durable du point de vue des sous-indicateurs donnés.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; &lt;strong&gt;Au niveau national :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; &lt;strong&gt;Aux niveaux régional et mondial :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
