<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 2-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scope of indicator 2.4.1 is the agricultural farm holding, and more precisely the agricultural land area of the farm holding, i.e. land used primarily to grow crops and raise livestock. This choice of scope is fully consistent with the intended use of a country&amp;#x2019;s agricultural land area as the denominator of the aggregate indicator. Specifically, the following are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Included within scope:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Intensive and extensive crops and livestock production systems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Subsistence agriculture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;State and common land when used exclusively and managed by the farm holding.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Food and non-food crops and livestock products (e.g. tobacco, cotton, and sheep wool). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Crops grown for fodder or for energy purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agro-forestry (trees on the agriculture areas of the farm).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aquaculture, to the extent that it takes place within the agricultural land area. For example, rice-fish farming and similar systems. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excluded from scope:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;State and common land not used exclusively by the farm holding.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nomadic pastoralism.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Production from gardens and backyards. Production from hobby farms&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Holdings focusing exclusively on aquaculture. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Holdings focusing exclusively on forestry.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Food harvested from the wild.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The literature review (Hayati, 2017) identified a large number of potential sustainability themes across the three dimensions of sustainability and, for each theme, usually a large number of possible sub-indicators. The key considerations in the selection of themes are relevance and measurability. In terms of relevance, the relationship between the associated sub-indicator and sustainable agriculture outcomes at farm level should be strong. Following this approach, only sub-indicators that are responsive to farm level policies aimed at improving sustainable agriculture are considered. In terms of measurability, only a &amp;#x201C;core&amp;#x201D; set of themes and sub-indicators for which measurement and reporting is expected in the majority of countries are selected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key aspect of all approaches to measuring sustainable agriculture is the recognition that sustainability is a multi-dimensional concept, and that these multiple dimensions need to be reflected in the construction of the indicator. This implies that SDG indicator 2.4.1 must be based on a set of sub-indicators that cover these three dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through a consultative process that has lasted over two years, 11 themes and sub-indicators have been identified, which make up SDG 2.4.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;No.&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;Sub-indicators&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Land productivity&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Farm output value per hectare&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Profitability&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Net farm income &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Resilience&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Risk mitigation mechanisms &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Soil health&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Prevalence of soil degradation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Water use&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Variation in water availability&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Fertilizer pollution risk&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Management of fertilizers&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;7&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Pesticide risk&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Management of pesticides &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;8&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Biodiversity&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Use of agro-biodiversity-supportive practices &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;9&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Decent employment&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Wage rate in agriculture&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;10&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Food security&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Food Insecurity Experience Scale (FIES)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;11&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Land tenure&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Secure tenure rights to land&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see the annex for a detailed description of the sub-indicators.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; The countries will define hobby farms as per their national criteria and remove these farms from the population of interest for 2.4.1 until an international definition is available. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le champ de l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1 est l&apos;exploitation agricole, et plus précisément la superficie agricole de l&apos;exploitation, c.-à-d. les terres utilisées principalement pour la culture et l&apos;élevage. Ce choix de champ est tout à fait cohérent avec l&apos;utilisation prévue de la superficie agricole d&apos;un pays comme dénominateur de l&apos;indicateur agrégé. Plus précisément, les éléments suivants sont inclus dans le champ de l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1 :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Systèmes de production de cultures et d&apos;élevage intensifs et extensifs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agriculture de subsistance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Terres de l&apos;État et communales lorsqu&apos;elles sont utilisées exclusivement et gérées par l&apos;exploitation agricole.&lt;/li&gt; 
  &lt;li&gt;Cultures alimentaires et non alimentaires et produits de l&apos;élevage (p. ex., tabac, coton et laine de mouton). &lt;/li&gt; 
  &lt;li&gt;Cultures destinées au fourrage ou à des fins énergétiques.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agroforesterie (arbres sur les zones agricoles de l&apos;exploitation). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aquaculture, dans la mesure où elle a lieu sur les terres agricoles (p. ex., la rizipisciculture et les systèmes similaires). &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les éléments suivants sont exclus du champ de l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1 :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Terres de l&apos;État et communales non utilisées exclusivement par l&apos;exploitation agricole.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pastoralisme nomade.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Production issue des jardins et arrière-cours. Production des fermes d&apos;agrément &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exploitations consacrées exclusivement à l&apos;aquaculture. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exploitations consacrées exclusivement à la sylviculture. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nourriture récoltée à l&apos;état sauvage. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La revue littéraire (Hayati, 2017) a identifié un grand nombre de thèmes potentiels de durabilité dans les trois dimensions de la durabilité et, pour chaque thème, généralement un grand nombre de sous-indicateurs possibles. Les considérations clés dans la sélection des thèmes sont la pertinence et la mesurabilité. En termes de pertinence, la relation entre le sous-indicateur associé et les résultats de l&apos;agriculture durable au niveau de l&apos;exploitation doit être forte. Suivant cette approche, seuls les sous-indicateurs qui répondent aux politiques au niveau des exploitations visant à améliorer l&apos;agriculture durable sont pris en compte. En termes de mesurabilité, seul un ensemble de thèmes et de sous-indicateurs « de base » pour lesquels des mesures et des rapports sont attendus dans la majorité des pays sont sélectionnés.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Un aspect essentiel de toutes les approches de la mesure de l&apos;agriculture durable est la reconnaissance du fait que la durabilité est un concept multidimensionnel, et que ces multiples dimensions doivent être reflétées dans la construction de l&apos;indicateur. Cela implique que l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1 des ODD doit être basé sur un ensemble de sous-indicateurs qui couvrent ces trois dimensions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Grâce à un processus consultatif qui a duré plus de deux ans, 11 thèmes et sous-indicateurs ont été identifiés et constituent l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1 des ODD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;No.&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;Thèmes&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;Sous-indicateurs&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Productivité des terres&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Valeur de production agricole par hectare&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Rentabilité&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Revenu net de la ferme&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Résilience&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Mécanismes d&apos;atténuation de risques&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Santé des sols&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Prévalence de détérioration des sols&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Utilisation de l&apos;eau&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Variation dans la disponibilité de l&apos;eau&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Risque de pollution par les engrais&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Gestion des engrais&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;7&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Risque des pesticides&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Gestion des pesticides&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;8&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Biodiversité&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Utilisation de pratiques propices à l&apos;agro-biodiversité&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;9&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Emploi décent&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Taux de rémunération en agriculture&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;10&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Sécurité alimentaire&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Échelle de sécurité alimentaire fondée sur l&apos;expérience (FIES)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;11&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Régime foncier&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Droits fonciers sûrs&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Veuillez consulter l&apos;annexe pour une description détaillée des sous-indicateurs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les pays définiront les fermes d&apos;agrément selon leurs critères nationaux et retireront ces exploitations de la population d&apos;intérêt pour l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1 jusqu&apos;à ce qu&apos;une définition internationale soit disponible. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
