<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 5-3-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;There are existing tools and mechanisms for data collection that countries have implemented to monitor the situation with regards to this indicator. The modules used to collect information on marital status among women and men of reproductive age (15-49 years) in the DHS and MICS have been fully harmonized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The measure of child marriage is retrospective in nature by design, capturing age at first marriage among a population that has completed the risk period (i.e., adult women). While it is also possible to measure the current marital status of girls under age 18, such measures would provide an underestimate of the level of child marriage, as girls who are not currently married may still do so before they turn 18. For more details on interpretation and common pitfalls for this indicator, see: &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.unicef.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/A-Generation-to-Protect-publication-English_2020.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Generation to Protect: Monitoring violence exploitation and abuse of children within the SDG framework&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;(UNICEF 2020).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt; Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Existen herramientas y mecanismos de recopilación de datos que los países han implementado para supervisar la situación con respecto a este indicador. Los módulos utilizados para recopilar información sobre el estado civil entre mujeres y hombres en edad reproductiva (15-49 años) en las DHS y las MICS han sido plenamente armonizados. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Il existe des outils et des mécanismes de collecte de données que les pays ont mis en place pour suivre la situation en ce qui concerne cet indicateur. Les modules utilisés pour recueillir des informations sur l’état matrimonial chez les femmes et les hommes en âge de procréer (15-49 ans) dans l&apos;EDS et le MICS ont été entièrement harmonisés. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La mesure du mariage d&apos;enfants est de nature rétrospective par conception, englobant l’âge au premier mariage chez une population qui a terminé la période de risque (c.-à-d. les femmes adultes). Bien qu’il soit également possible de mesurer l’état matrimonial actuel des filles de moins de 18 ans, de telles mesures permettraient de sous-estimer le niveau de mariage d&apos;enfants, car les filles qui ne sont pas actuellement mariées peuvent encore le faire avant l’âge de 18 ans. Pour plus de détails sur l’interprétation et les pièges courants de cet indicateur, consulter : &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.unicef.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/A-Generation-to-Protect-publication-English_2020.pdf&quot;&gt;(en anglais) &lt;em&gt;A Generation to Protect: Monitoring violence exploitation and abuse of children within the SDG framework&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (UNICEF 2020). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Существуют инструменты и механизмы сбора данных, которые страны внедрили для мониторинга ситуации, относящейся к этому показателю. Модули, используемые для сбора информации о семейном положении женщин и мужчин репродуктивного возраста (15–49 лет) в Обследовании демографических характеристик и состояния здоровья (DHS) и Кластерном обследовании по многим показателям (MICS), были полностью гармонизированы.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
