<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 6-5-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;The majority of the world&amp;#x2019;s water resources are shared: 468 transboundary aquifers have been identified in 2021 and 310 transboundary lake and river basins cover nearly one half of the Earth&amp;#x2019;s land surface and account for an estimated 60% of global freshwater. Approximately 40% of the world&amp;#x2019;s population lives in river and lake basins shared by two or more countries and over 90% lives in countries that share basins. Development of water resources has impacts across transboundary basins, potentially on countries sharing transboundary basins, and use of surface water or groundwater may affect the other resource, which are often interlinked. Intensive water use, flow regulation or pollution risks going as far as compromising the development aspirations of countries sharing transboundary basins and therefore transboundary cooperation is required. However, cooperation is in many cases not advanced. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specific agreements or other arrangements concluded between countries sharing transboundary basins are a key precondition to ensure long-term, sustainable cooperation. International customary water law (as reflected in the 1992 Water Convention, the 1997 Watercourses Convention, and the 2008 draft Articles on the Law of Transboundary Aquifers), as well as existing experience and good practices, all point to minimum requirements for operational cooperation. These minimum requirements are captured by the four criteria for operationality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the basis for the explicit call for transboundary water cooperation in the wording of target 6.5 and the importance of monitoring this indicator to complement indicator 6.5.1 which measures the advancement of Integrated Water Resources Management (IWRM).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Progress by a particular country towards the cooperation aspect of target 6.5, reflected by the value of indicator 6.5.2, can be achieved either by establishing new operational cooperation arrangements, or making existing arrangements operational by developing and regularizing activities, or expanding the coverage of cooperation arrangements with the ultimate objective to cover all surface waters and groundwaters.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
