<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 1-1-1b, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; Estimates are produced for countries and years for which no direct working poverty estimates are available based on household survey estimates, but for which total poverty estimates are available in the World Bank&amp;#x2019;s PovcalNet database. This is carried out through a multivariate regression model described in &amp;#x201C;Employment and economic class in the developing world&amp;#x201D; (Kapsos and Bourmpoula, 2013), available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; Following the step described directly above, missing data at the national level are estimated through a multivariate regression model for the purpose of producing global and regional estimations.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A nivel de país&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A nivel regional y mundial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;• Les estimations sont produites pour les pays et les années pour lesquels aucune estimation directe de la pauvreté des travailleurs, basée sur des estimations des enquêtes sur les ménages, n&apos;est disponible , mais pour lesquels des estimations de la pauvreté totale sont disponibles dans la base de données PovcalNet de la Banque mondiale. Ceci est effectué par le biais d&apos;un modèle de régression multivarié décrit dans &quot;Employment and economic class in the developing world&quot; (Kapsos et Bourmpoula, 2013), disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Suite à l&apos;étape décrite directement ci-dessus, les données manquantes au niveau national sont estimées par un modèle de régression multivarié dans le but de produire des estimations globales et régionales.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt;Обработка отсутствующих значений:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;На страновом уровне&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;На региональном и глобальном уровнях&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
