<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 1-1-1b, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proportion of the employed population below the international poverty line of US$1.90 per day, also referred to as the working poverty rate, is defined as the share of employed persons living in households with per-capita consumption or income that is below the international poverty line of US$1.90.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employment: All persons of working age who, during a short reference period (one week), were engaged in any activity to produce goods or provide services for pay or profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poverty Line: Threshold below which individuals in the reference population are considered poor and above which they are considered non-poor. The threshold is generally defined as the per-capita monetary requirements an individual needs to afford the purchase of a basic bundle of goods and services. For the purpose of this indicator, an absolute international poverty line of US$1.90 per day is used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Household in poverty: Households are defined as poor if their income or consumption expenditure is below the poverty line taking into account the number of household members and composition (e.g., number of adults and children).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working poor: Employed persons living in households that are classified as poor, that is, that have income or consumption levels below the poverty line used for measurement.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt; Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La proporción de la población empleada por debajo de la línea de pobreza internacional de 1,90 dólares estadounidenses por día, también conocida como la tasa de pobreza laboral, se define como la proporción de personas empleadas que viven en hogares con consumo o ingreso per cápita que está por debajo de la línea de pobreza internacional de 1,90 dólares estadounidenses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Empleo:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Todas las personas en edad de trabajar que, durante un breve período de referencia (una semana), se dedicaron a cualquier actividad para producir bienes o prestar servicios a cambio de una remuneración o beneficio. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Línea de Pobreza:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Umbral por debajo del cual los individuos de la población de referencia se consideran pobres y por encima del cual se consideran no pobres. El umbral se define generalmente como los requerimientos monetarios per cápita que un individuo necesita para poder comprar un conjunto básico de bienes y servicios. A efectos de este indicador, se utiliza un umbral de pobreza absoluta internacional de 1,90 dólares estadounidenses al día &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Hogares en situación de pobreza:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Los hogares se definen como pobres si sus ingresos o gastos de consumo están por debajo del umbral de pobreza teniendo en cuenta el número de miembros del hogar y la composición (por ejemplo, el número de adultos y niños). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Trabajadores pobres:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Personas empleadas que viven en hogares clasificados como pobres, es decir, que tienen niveles de ingresos o consumo por debajo del umbral de pobreza utilizado para la medición. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La proportion de la population active sous le seuil de pauvreté international de 1,90 $ américain par jour, également appelée taux de pauvreté des travailleurs, est définie comme la part des personnes actives vivant dans des ménages dont la consommation ou le revenu par habitant est inférieur au seuil de pauvreté international de 1,90 $ américain par jour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emploi : Toutes les personnes en âge de travailler qui, pendant une courte période de référence (une semaine), ont exercé une activité quelconque de production de biens ou de prestation de services contre rémunération ou profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seuil de pauvreté : Seuil en dessous duquel les individus de la population de référence sont considérés comme étant pauvres et au-dessus duquel ils sont considérés comme n&apos;étant pas pauvres. Le seuil est généralement défini comme les besoins monétaires par habitant dont un individu a besoin pour pouvoir faire l&apos;achat d&apos;un ensemble de biens et de services de base. Pour les besoins de cet indicateur, un seuil de pauvreté international absolu de 1,90 $ américain par jour est utilisé.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ménage en situation de pauvreté : Les ménages sont définis comme étant pauvres si leur revenu ou leurs dépenses de consommation sont inférieurs au seuil de pauvreté compte tenu du nombre de membres dans le ménage et de sa composition (p. ex., le nombre d&apos;adultes et d&apos;enfants).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travailleurs pauvres : Personnes actives vivant dans des ménages classés comme étant pauvres, c&apos;est-à-dire dont le revenu ou le niveau de consommation est inférieur au seuil de pauvreté utilisé pour la mesure.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt;Понятия и определения&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Определение:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Доля занятого населения, живущего ниже международной черты бедности, составляющей 1,90 долл. США в день, также называемой уровнем бедности среди работающего населения, определяется как доля занятого населения, живущего в домохозяйствах со среднедушевым потреблением или доходом, ниже международной черты бедности, составляющей 1,90 долл. США.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Понятия:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Занятость:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Все лица трудоспособного возраста, которые в течение короткого отчетного периода (одна неделя) занимались какой-либо деятельностью по производству товаров или оказанию услуг за плату или получение прибыли.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Черта бедности:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Порог, ниже которого люди в исследуемой группе населения считаются бедными и выше которого они не считаются бедными. Пороговый показатель обычно определяется как требуемые среднедушевые денежные средства, необходимые человеку для того, чтобы позволить себе приобрести базовый пакет товаров и услуг. Для целей этого показателя используется международная черта абсолютной бедности в размере 1,90 долл. США в день.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Бедное домохозяйство:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Домашние хозяйства определяются как бедные, если их доходы или потребительские расходы находятся ниже черты бедности с учетом количества членов домохозяйства и его состава (например, количества взрослых и детей)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Работающие бедняки:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Люди, работающие по найму, живущие в домохозяйствах, которые классифицируются как бедные, т.е. те, которые имеют уровни дохода или потребления, ниже используемой для оценки черты бедности.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
