<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 2-5-1b, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conservation of plant and animal genetic resources for food and agriculture (GRFA) in medium- or long-term conservation facilities (&lt;em&gt;ex situ&lt;/em&gt;, in genebanks) represents the most trusted means of conserving genetic resources worldwide. Plant and animal GRFA conserved in these facilities can be easily used in breeding programmes as well, even directly on-farm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The measure of trends in &lt;em&gt;ex situ&lt;/em&gt; conserved materials provides an overall assessment of the extent to which we are managing to maintain and/or increase the total genetic diversity available for future use and thus protected from any permanent loss of genetic diversity which may occur in the natural habitat, i.e. &lt;em&gt;in situ&lt;/em&gt;, or on-farm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two components of the indicator 2.5.1, plant (a) and animal (b) GRFA, are separately counted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Animal genetic resources&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The animal component is calculated as the number of local (i.e. being reported to exist only in one country) and transboundary (i.e. being reported to exist in more than one country) breeds with material stored within a genebank collection with an amount of genetic material which is required to reconstitute the breed in case of extinction (further information on &amp;#x201C;sufficient material stored to reconstitute a breed&amp;#x201D; can be found in the Guidelines on Cryoconservation of Animal Genetic Resources, FAO, 2012, accessible at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/docrep/016/i3017e/i3017e00.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/docrep/016/i3017e/i3017e00.htm&lt;/a&gt;). The guidelines have been endorsed by the FAO Commission on Genetic Resources for Food and Agriculture at its Thirteenth Regular Session (http://www.fao.org/docrep/meeting/024/mc192e.pdf).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Animal genetic resources&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breed: A breed is either a sub-specific group of domestic livestock with definable and identifiable external characteristics that enable it to be separated by visual appraisal from other similarly defined groups within the same species, or a group for which geographical and/or cultural separation from phenotypically similar groups has led to acceptance of its separate identity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medium- or long-term conservation facilities: Biological diversity is often conserved &lt;em&gt;ex situ&lt;/em&gt;, outside its natural habitat, in facilities called genebanks. In the case of domestic animal diversity, &lt;em&gt;ex situ&lt;/em&gt; conservation includes both the maintenance of live animals (&lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;) and cryoconservation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cryoconservation is the collection and deep-freezing of semen, ova, embryos or tissues for potential future use in breeding or regenerating animals.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La conservation des ressources génétiques végétales et animales pour l’alimentation et l’agriculture (RGAA) dans des installations de conservation à moyen ou long terme (&lt;em&gt;ex situ&lt;/em&gt;, dans les banques de gènes) représente le moyen le plus fiable de conserver les ressources génétiques dans le monde. Les RGAA végétales et animales conservées dans ces installations peuvent également être facilement utilisées dans les programmes de sélection, même directement à la ferme. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La mesure des tendances des matériaux conservés &lt;em&gt;ex situ&lt;/em&gt; fournit une évaluation globale de la mesure dans laquelle nous parvenons à maintenir et/ou à accroître la diversité génétique totale disponible pour une utilisation future et donc à la protéger de toute perte permanente de diversité génétique qui pourrait survenir dans l’habitat naturel, c’est-à-dire &lt;em&gt;in situ&lt;/em&gt;, ou à la ferme. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les deux composantes de l&apos;indicateur 2.5.1, les RGAA végétales (a) et animales (b), sont comptées séparément.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ressources zoogénétiques&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La composante animale est calculée comme le nombre de races locales (c’est-à-dire dont l’existence n’aurait été signalée que dans un seul pays) stockées dans une collection d&apos;une banque de gènes avec une quantité de matériel génétique stockée qui est nécessaire pour reconstituer la race en cas d’extinction (de plus amples informations sur le « matériel stocké en quantité suffisante pour reconstituer une race » peuvent être trouvées dans « Cryoconservation of animal genetic resources », FAO, 2012, accessible (en anglais) à l&apos;adresse http://www.fao.org/docrep/016/i3017e/i3017e00.htm). Ces lignes directrices ont été approuvées par la Commission des ressources génétiques pour l’alimentation et l’agriculture de la FAO à sa treizième session ordinaire ((en anglais) http://www.fao.org/docrep/meeting/024/mc192e.pdf). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ressources zoogénétiques&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Race : Une race est soit un groupe sous-spécifique d&apos;animaux domestiques présentant des caractéristiques externes définissables et identifiables qui lui permettent d’être séparée par évaluation visuelle d&apos;autres groupes de la même espèce définis de manière similaire, soit un groupe pour lequel la séparation géographique et/ou culturelle de groupes phénotypiquement similaires a conduit à l’acceptation de son identité distincte. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installations de conservation à moyen ou à long terme : La diversité biologique est souvent conservée &lt;em&gt;ex situ&lt;/em&gt;, en dehors de son habitat naturel, dans des installations appelées banques de gènes. Dans le cas de la diversité des animaux domestiques, la conservation &lt;em&gt;ex situ&lt;/em&gt; comprend à la fois le maintien d’animaux vivants (&lt;em&gt;in vivo&lt;/em&gt;) et la cryoconservation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La cryoconservation est la collecte et la congélation de sperme, d&apos;ovules, d&apos;embryons ou de tissus en vue d&apos;une utilisation potentielle future pour la reproduction ou la régénération des animaux.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
