<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 5-5-1a, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Collection process:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data are provided by national parliaments and updated after an election or parliamentary renewal. National parliaments also transmit their data to the IPU at least once a year and when the numbers change significantly. IPU member parliaments provide information on changes and updates to the IPU secretariat. After each general election or renewal a questionnaire is dispatched to parliaments to solicit the latest available data. If no response is provided, other methods are used to obtain the information, such as from the electoral management body, parliamentary web sites or Internet searches. Additional information gathered from other sources is regularly crosschecked with parliament. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt; Processus de collecte :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les données sont fournies par les parlements nationaux et mises à jour après une élection ou un renouvellement parlementaire. Les parlements nationaux transmettent également leurs données à l’UIP au moins une fois par an et lorsque les chiffres changent considérablement. Les parlements membres de l’UIP fournissent des informations sur les changements et les mises à jour au secrétariat de l’UIP. Après chaque élection générale ou renouvellement, un questionnaire est envoyé aux parlements pour solliciter les dernières données disponibles. Si aucune réponse n’est fournie, d’autres méthodes sont utilisées pour obtenir l’information, par exemple auprès de l’organisme de gestion électorale, des sites Web parlementaires ou des recherches sur Internet. Les informations supplémentaires recueillies auprès d’autres sources sont régulièrement recoupées avec le Parlement. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
