<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 5-5-1a, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The indicator measures the degree to which women have equal access to parliamentary decision making. Women&amp;#x2019;s participation in parliaments is a key aspect of women&amp;#x2019;s opportunities in political and public life, and is therefore linked to women&amp;#x2019;s empowerment. Equal numbers of women and men in lower chambers would give an indicator value of 50 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A stronger presence of women in parliament allows new concerns to be highlighted on political agendas, and new priorities to be put into practice through the adoption and implementation of policies and laws. The inclusion of the perspectives and interests of women is a prerequisite for democracy and gender equality, and contributes to good governance. A representative parliament also allows the different experiences of men and women to affect the social, political and economic future of societies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changes in the indicator have been tracked over time. Although the international community has supported and promoted women&amp;#x2019;s participation in political decision-making structures for several decades, improvement in women&amp;#x2019;s access to parliament has been slow. This has led to the introduction of special policy and legal measures to increase women&amp;#x2019;s shares of parliamentary seats in several countries. Those countries that have adopted special measures generally have greater representation of women in parliament than countries without special measures.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador mide el grado de igualdad de acceso de las mujeres a la toma de decisiones parlamentarias. La participación de las mujeres en los parlamentos es un aspecto clave de las oportunidades de las mujeres en la vida política y pública y, por lo tanto, está vinculada al empoderamiento de las mujeres. Un número igual de mujeres y hombres en las cámaras bajas daría un valor del indicador del 50%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Una mayor presencia de las mujeres en el parlamento permite que se destaquen nuevas preocupaciones en las agendas políticas, y que se pongan en práctica nuevas prioridades a través de la adopción y aplicación de políticas y leyes. La inclusión de las perspectivas e intereses de las mujeres es un requisito previo para la democracia y la igualdad de género, y contribuye a la buena gobernanza. Un parlamento representativo también permite que las diferentes experiencias de hombres y mujeres afecten al futuro social, político y económico de las sociedades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los cambios en el indicador se han seguido a lo largo del tiempo. Aunque la comunidad internacional ha apoyado y promovido la participación de las mujeres en las estructuras de toma de decisiones políticas durante varias décadas, la mejora del acceso de las mujeres al parlamento ha sido lenta. Esto ha llevado a la introducción de medidas políticas y legales especiales para aumentar la proporción de mujeres en los escaños parlamentarios en varios países. Los países que han adoptado medidas especiales suelen tener una mayor representación de mujeres en el parlamento que los países que no tienen medidas especiales.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt; Justification :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L’indicateur mesure dans quelle mesure les femmes ont un accès égal à la prise de décisions parlementaires. La participation des femmes aux parlements est un aspect clé des opportunités des femmes dans la vie politique et publique, et est donc liée à l’autonomisation des femmes. Un nombre égal de femmes et d’hommes dans les chambres basses donnerait une valeur indicative de 50 pour cent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Une présence plus forte des femmes au parlement permet de mettre en évidence de nouvelles préoccupations sur les agendas politiques, et de nouvelles priorités doivent être mises en pratique par l’adoption et la mise en œuvre de politiques et de lois. L’inclusion des perspectives et des intérêts des femmes est une condition préalable à la démocratie et à l’égalité des sexes et contribue à la bonne gouvernance. Un parlement représentatif permet également aux différentes expériences des hommes et des femmes d’influer sur l’avenir social, politique et économique des sociétés. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les changements dans l’indicateur ont été suivis au fil du temps. Bien que la communauté internationale ait soutenu et encouragé la participation des femmes aux structures décisionnelles politiques pendant plusieurs décennies, l’amélioration de l’accès des femmes au Parlement a été lente. Cela a conduit à l’introduction de mesures politiques et juridiques spéciales visant à accroître la part des femmes dans les sièges parlementaires dans plusieurs pays. Les pays qui ont adopté des mesures spéciales ont généralement une plus grande représentation des femmes au Parlement que les pays qui n’ont pas de mesures spéciales. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель отражает ситуацию, до какой степени женщины имеют равный доступ к принятию парламентских решений. Участие женщин в работе парламентов является ключевым аспектом возможностей женщин в политической и общественной жизни и, следовательно, связано с расширением прав и возможностей женщин. Значение показателя, равное 50 процентам, означало бы равное количество женщин и мужчин в нижних палатах. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Более широкое представительство женщин в парламенте позволяет обратить внимание на новые проблемы в политической повестке дня и воплощать в жизнь новые приоритеты посредством принятия и реализации политики и законов. Учет взглядов и интересов женщин является предпосылкой демократии и гендерного равенства и способствует эффективному управлению. Представительный парламент также делает возможным, используя различный опыт мужчин и женщин, оказывать влияние на социальное, политическое и экономическое будущее общества. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Изменения показателя отслеживаются с течением времени. Хотя международное сообщество уже в течение нескольких десятилетий поддерживало и поощряло участие женщин в структурах принятия политических решений, но положительные изменения в вопросе доступа женщин в парламент происходили медленно. Такая ситуация привела к принятию специальных политических и правовых мер, направленных на увеличение доли женщин в парламентах нескольких странах. Те страны, которые приняли специальные меры, обычно имеют большее представительство женщин в парламенте, чем страны, в которых специальные меры не были приняты. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
