<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 5-6-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sustainable Development Goal (SDG) Indicator 5.6.2 seeks to measure the extent to which countries have national laws and regulations that guarantee full and equal access to women and men aged 15 years and older to sexual and reproductive health care, information, and education. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is a percentage (%) scale of 0 to 100 (national laws and regulations exist to guarantee full and equal access), indicating a country&amp;#x2019;s status and progress in the existence of such National laws and regulations. Indicator 5.6.2 measures only the existence of laws and regulations; it does not measure their implementation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laws: laws and statutes are official rules of conduct or action prescribed, or formally recognized as binding, or enforced by a controlling authority that governs the behavior of actors (including people, corporations, associations, government agencies). They are adopted or ratified by the legislative branch of government and may be formally recognized in the Constitution or interpreted by courts. Laws governing sexual and reproductive health are not necessarily contained in one law. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regulations: are executive, ministerial, or other administrative orders or decrees. At the municipal level, regulations are sometimes called ordinances. Regulations and ordinances issued by governmental entities have the force of law, although circumscribed by the level of the issuing authority. Under this methodology, only regulations with the national-level application are considered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restrictions: many laws and regulations contain restrictions in the scope of their applicability. Such restrictions, which include, though are not limited to, those by age, sex, marital status, and requirement for third party authorization, represent barriers to full and equal access to sexual and reproductive health care, information, and education. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plural legal systems: are defined as legal systems in which multiple sources of law co-exist. Such legal systems have typically developed over a period because of colonial inheritance, religion, and other socio-cultural factors. Examples of sources of law that might co-exist under a plural legal system include English common law, French civil or other law, statutory law, and customary and religious law. The co-existence of multiple sources of law can create fundamental contradictions in the legal system, which result in barriers to full and equal access to sexual and reproductive health care, information, and education. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x201C;Guarantee&amp;#x201D; (access): for this methodology, &amp;#x201C;guarantee&amp;#x201D; is understood as a law or regulation that assures a particular outcome or condition. The methodology recognizes that laws can only guarantee &amp;#x201C;in principle&amp;#x201D;; for the outcomes to be fully realized in practice, additional steps, including policy and budgetary measures will need to be in place.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’indicateur 5.6.2 des objectifs de développement durable (ODD) vise à mesurer dans quelle mesure les pays disposent de lois et de réglementations nationales qui garantissent un accès complet et égal aux femmes et aux hommes âgés de 15 ans et plus aux soins de santé sexuelle et génésique, à l’information et à l’éducation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’indicateur est une échelle de pourcentage (%) de 0 à 100 (représentant des lois et réglementations nationales existant pour garantir un accès complet et égal), indiquant le statut et l’avancement d’un pays dans l’existence de ces lois et réglementations nationales. L’indicateur 5.6.2 ne mesure que l’existence de lois et de règlements; il ne mesure pas leur mise en œuvre. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lois : les lois et les statuts sont des règles officielles de conduite ou d’action prescrites, ou formellement reconnues comme contraignantes, ou appliquées par une autorité de contrôle qui régit le comportement des acteurs (y compris les personnes, les sociétés, les associations, les organismes gouvernementaux). Elles sont adoptées ou ratifiées par le pouvoir législatif du gouvernement et peuvent être officiellement reconnues dans la Constitution ou interprétées par les tribunaux. Les lois régissant la santé sexuelle et génésique ne sont pas nécessairement contenues dans une seule loi. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Règlements : les règlements sont des arrêtés, des ordonnances ou des décrets exécutifs, ministériels ou autres. Au niveau municipal, les règlements sont parfois appelés ordonnances. Les règlements et ordonnances pris par des entités gouvernementales ont force de loi, bien que circonscrits par le niveau de l’autorité d’émission. Dans le cadre de cette méthodologie, seuls les règlements ayant une application au niveau national sont pris en compte. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restrictions : de nombreuses lois et règlements contiennent des restrictions dans la portée de leur applicabilité. Ces restrictions, qui comprennent, sans toutefois s’y limiter, celles fondées sur l’âge, le sexe, l’état matrimonial et l’exigence d’une autorisation d’un tiers, constituent des obstacles à un accès complet et égal aux soins de santé sexuelle et génésique, à l’information et à l’éducation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Systèmes juridiques pluralistes : systèmes définis comme des systèmes juridiques dans lesquels coexistent de multiples sources de droit. Ces systèmes juridiques se sont généralement développés au fil du temps en raison de l’héritage colonial, de la religion et d’autres facteurs socioculturels. Voici des exemples de sources de droit qui pourraient coexister dans un système juridique pluraliste : la « common law » anglaise, le droit civil français ou autre, le droit statutaire et le droit coutumier et religieux. La coexistence de sources juridiques multiples peut créer des contradictions fondamentales dans le système juridique, qui se traduisent par des obstacles à l’accès complet et égal aux soins de santé sexuelle et génésique, à l’information et à l’éducation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;« Garantie » (accès) : aux fins de la présente méthodologie, la « garantie » s’entend comme une loi ou un règlement qui garantit un résultat ou une condition particulière. La méthodologie reconnaît que les lois ne peuvent garantir qu&apos;« en principe »; pour que les résultats soient pleinement réalisés dans la pratique, des mesures supplémentaires, y compris des mesures politiques et budgétaires, devront être mises en place. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
