<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 2-2-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;National estimates from primary sources (e.g., from household surveys) used to generate the JME country modelled estimates are based on standardized methodology using the WHO Child Growth Standards as described in &lt;em&gt;Recommendations for data collection, analysis and reporting on anthropometric indicators in children under 5 years old (&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.unicef.org/resources/data-collection-analysis-reporting-on-anthropometric-indicators-in-children-under-5/&quot;&gt;WHO/UNICEF 2019&lt;/a&gt;) and WHO Anthro Survey Analyser (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/tools/child-growth-standards/software&quot;&gt;WHO, 2019&lt;/a&gt;). The JME country modelled estimates are generated using smoothing techniques and covariates (&lt;a href=&quot;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30430613/&quot;&gt;McLain et al. 2018&lt;/a&gt;) applied to quality-assured national data to derive trends and up-to-date estimates. Worldwide and regional estimates are derived as the respective country averages weighted by the countries&amp;#x2019; under-five population estimates (UNPD-WPP latest available edition) using annual JME country modelled estimates. . &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las estimaciones de las encuestas se basan en una metodología estandarizada que utiliza los Patrones de Crecimiento Infantil de la OMS, tal y como se describe en otros documentos (Ref: manual del software Anthro). Las estimaciones mundiales y regionales se basan en la metodología descrita en UNICEF-OMS-Banco Mundial: Estimaciones conjuntas de la malnutrición infantil - Niveles y tendencias (UNICEF/OMS/BM 2012)&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Les estimations de l&apos;enquête sont basées sur une méthodologie standardisée utilisant les normes de croissance de l&apos;enfant de l&apos;OMS telles que décrites ailleurs (Réf : manuel du logiciel Anthro). Les estimations mondiales et régionales sont basées sur la méthodologie décrite dans le document de UNICEF-OMS-Banque mondiale : « Joint child malnutrition estimates - Levels and trends (UNICEF/WHO/WB 2012) ».&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Оценки обследований основаны на стандартизированной методологии с использованием Стандартов роста детей ВОЗ, как описано в другом документе (см. Руководство по программному обеспечению Anthro). Глобальные и региональные оценки основаны на методологии, подготовленной совместно ЮНИСЕФ, ВОЗ и Всемирным банком и изложенной в документе: Совместные оценки детского недоедания - уровни и тенденции (ЮНИСЕФ / ВОЗ / ВБ, 2012 г.)&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
