<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The QUALITY_ASSURE field for indicator 2-2-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The quality criteria established in the 2019 UNICEF/WHO guidance (&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.unicef.org/resources/data-collection-analysis-reporting-on-anthropometric-indicators-in-children-under-5/&quot;&gt;WHO/UNICEF, 2019&lt;/a&gt;)ewere used to update the JME primary data source review form. The JME review form is used to abstract key information including methodological details (e.g., sampling procedures, description of anthropometrical equipment), data quality outputs (e.g., response rates, weight and height distributions, percentage of cases that were flagged as having implausible anthropometry outcomes according to the WHO Child Growth Standards) and the malnutrition prevalence estimates from each primary data source (e.g., household survey) under review. One JME working group member fills in the review form for each data source and when information is missing or further details are required, the country teams are contacted. Once all information is available and the JME primary data source review form is completed, each data source is reviewed by the three agencies (UNICEF, WHO, WB) which form the JME working group. This allows for a thorough and efficient standard joint review of each data source by the three agencies prior to inclusion in the JME country database of primary sources (e.g., household surveys) that are used to generate the JME country modelled estimates. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Description des pratiques et des lignes directrices axées sur la qualité en général et traitant de la qualité des programmes statistiques de votre organisme, y compris les mesures visant à assurer l&apos;utilisation efficace des ressources.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
