<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REL_CAL_POLICY field for indicator 2-2-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Data release:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next planned release fo global/regional estimates as well as the updated country dataset is May 2017. Global and regional estimates are released annually every May starting in 2017. The country level dataset is updated and released more often than the global/regional estimates. Although a set schedule has not yet been established, there have been at least two annual updates (one coinciding with the annual release of the regional/global estimates and at least one other update at another time of the year).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Publicación de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La próxima publicación prevista para las estimaciones globales/regionales, así como el conjunto de datos actualizados por países, es mayo de 2017. Las estimaciones globales y regionales se publican anualmente en mayo a partir de 2017. El conjunto de datos a nivel de país se actualiza y se publica con más frecuencia que las estimaciones globales/regionales. Aunque todavía no se ha establecido un calendario fijo, ha habido al menos dos actualizaciones anuales (una coincidiendo con la publicación anual de las estimaciones regionales/globales y al menos otra actualización en otro momento del año).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Publication des données :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La prochaine publication des estimations mondiales/régionales et de l&apos;ensemble des données nationales actualisées est prévue pour mai 2017. Les estimations mondiales et régionales sont publiées chaque année en mai à partir de 2017. L&apos;ensemble de données nationales est mis à jour et publié plus souvent que les estimations mondiales/régionales. Bien qu&apos;un calendrier fixe n&apos;ait pas encore été établi, il y a eu au moins deux mises à jour annuelles (une coïncidant avec la publication annuelle des estimations régionales/mondiales et au moins une autre mise à jour à un autre moment de l&apos;année).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Выпуск данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Следующий запланированный выпуск глобальных / региональных оценок, а также обновленного набора страновых данных состоится в мае 2017 года. Глобальные и региональные годовые оценки публикуются ежегодно в мае, начиная с 2017 года. Набор данных на страновом уровне обновляется и публикуется чаще, чем глобальные / региональные оценки. Хотя график выпуска наборов данных еще не разработан, но было проведено, как минимум, два ежегодных обновления (одно совпало с ежегодным выпуском региональных / глобальных оценок и, как минимум, одно обновление состоялось в другое время года).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
