<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 9-b-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proportion of medium-high and high-tech industry (MHT hereafter) value added in total value added of manufacturing (MVA hereafter) is a ratio value between the value added of MHT industry and MVA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The value added of an industry (industry value added) is a survey concept that refers to the given industry&amp;#x2019;s net output derived from the difference of gross output and intermediate consumption. Manufacturing sector&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;is defined according to the International Standard Industrial Classification of all Economic Activities (ISIC) Revision 3 (1990) or Revision 4 (2008). It refers to industries belonging to sector D in Revision 3 or sector C in Revision 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology classification is based on research and development (R&amp;amp;D) expenditure relative to value added otherwise referred as R&amp;amp;D intensity. Data for R&amp;amp;D intensity are presented in a report (Galindo-Rueda and Verger, 2016) published by the OECD in 2016, which also proposes a taxonomy for industry groups with different ranges of R&amp;amp;D expenditure relative to their gross value added. MHT industries have traditionally been defined exclusively to manufacturing industries. However, there have been recent efforts (Galindo-Rueda and Verger, 2016) to extend the definition to non-manufacturing industries as well. Nevertheless, medium-high and high technology sectors also in new paper are primarily represented by manufacturing industries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;ISIC Rev.4&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;ISIC Rev.3 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;20&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Manufacture of chemicals and chemical products&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;24&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Manufacture of chemicals and chemical products&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;21&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Manufacture of basic pharmaceutical products and pharmaceutical preparations&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;29&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Manufacture of machinery and equipment n.e.c.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;252&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Manufacture of weapons and ammunition&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;30&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Manufacture of office, accounting and computing machinery&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;26&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Manufacture of computer, electronic and optical products&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;31&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Manufacture of electrical machinery and apparatus n.e.c.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;27&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Manufacture of electrical equipment&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;32&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Manufacture of radio, television and communication equipment and apparatus&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;28&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Manufacture of machinery and equipment n.e.c.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;33&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Manufacture of medical, precision and optical instruments, watches and clocks&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;29&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Manufacture of motor vehicles, trailers and semi-trailers&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;34&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Manufacture of motor vehicles, trailers and semi-trailers&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;30*&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Manufacture of other transport equipment &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;35**&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Manufacture of other transport equipment&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;325&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Manufacture of medical and dental instruments and supplies&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* &lt;/strong&gt;Excluding 301 (Building of ships and boats)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;** &lt;/strong&gt;Excluding 351 (Building and repairing of ships and boats)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MVA is the value added of manufacturing industry, which is Section C of ISIC Rev.4, and Section D of ISIC Rev.3. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La proporción del valor agregado de la industria de media y alta tecnología (MAT en adelante) en el valor agregado total de la industria manufacturera (VAM en adelante) es un valor de ratio entre el valor añadido de la industria MAT y el VAM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;El valor agregado de una industria (valor agregado de la industria) es un concepto de encuesta que se refiere a la producción neta de la industria derivada de la diferencia de la producción bruta y el consumo intermedio. El sector manufacturero&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;se define según la Clasificación Industrial Internacional Uniforme de todas las Actividades Económicas (CIIU) Revisión 3 (1990) o Revisión 4 (2008). Se refiere a las industrias pertenecientes al sector D en la Revisión 3 o al sector C en la Revisión 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La clasificación tecnológica se basa en el gasto en investigación y desarrollo (I+D) en relación con el valor agregado, también denominado intensidad de I+D. Los datos sobre la intensidad de la I+D se presentan en un informe (Galindo-Rueda y Verger, 2016) publicado por la OCDE en 2016, que también propone una taxonomía para los grupos industriales con diferentes rangos de gasto en I+D en relación con su valor agregado bruto. Tradicionalmente, las industrias MAT se han definido exclusivamente a las industrias manufactureras. Sin embargo, ha habido esfuerzos recientes (Galindo-Rueda y Verger, 2016) para ampliar la definición también a las industrias no manufactureras. No obstante, los sectores de tecnología media-alta y alta también en el nuevo papel están representados principalmente por las industrias manufactureras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
 &lt;tbody&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;CIIU Rev.4&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Descripción&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;ISIC Rev.3 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Descripción&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;20&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fabricación de productos químicos&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;24&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fabricación de sustancias químicas y productos químicos&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;21&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fabricación de productos farmacéuticos básicos y preparados farmacéuticos&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;29&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fabricación de maquinaria y equipo n.c.o.p.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;252&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fabricación de armas y municiones&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;30&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fabricación de máquinas de oficina, contabilidad e informática&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;26&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fabricación de productos informáticos, electrónicos y ópticos&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;31&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fabricación de máquinas y aparatos eléctricos n.c.o.p.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;27&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Fabricación de material eléctrico&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;32&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Fabricación de equipos y aparatos de radio, televisión y comunicaciones&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;28&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fabricación de maquinaria y equipo n.c.o.p.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;33&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Fabricación de instrumentos médicos, de precisión y ópticos, de relojes&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;29&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fabricación de vehículos de motor, remolques y semirremolques&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;34&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fabricación de vehículos de motor, remolques y semirremolques&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;30*&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fabricación de otro material de transporte &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;35**&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Fabricación de otro material de transporte&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;325&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Fabricación de instrumentos y suministros médicos y odontológicos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;* &lt;/strong&gt;Excluido el 301 (Construcción de buques y barcos)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;** &lt;/strong&gt;Excluida la 351 (Construcción y reparación de buques y embarcaciones)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El VAM es el valor añadido de la industria manufacturera, que es la Sección C de la CIIU Rev.4, y la Sección D de la CIIU Rev.3. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt; Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Définition :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La proportion de la valeur ajoutée de l’industrie de moyenne-haute et de haute technologie (MHT ci-après) dans la valeur ajoutée totale de la fabrication (MVA ci-après) est un rapport valeur ajoutée entre la valeur ajoutée de l’industrie MHT et MVA. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Concepts :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La valeur ajoutée d’une industrie (valeur ajoutée de l’industrie) est un concept d’enquête qui fait référence à la production nette de l’industrie donnée découlant de la différence entre la production brute et la consommation intermédiaire. Le secteur manufacturier&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;est défini selon la Classification industrielle standard internationale de toutes les activités économiques (CITI) Révision 3 (1990) ou révision 4 (2008). Il fait référence aux industries appartenant au secteur D dans la révision 3 ou au secteur C dans la révision 4. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La classification technologique est fondée sur les dépenses de recherche et développement (R&amp;amp;D) par rapport à la valeur ajoutée autrement appelée intensité R&amp;amp;D. Les données relatives à l’intensité de la R&amp;amp;D sont présentées dans un rapport (Galindo-Rueda et Verger, 2016) publié par l’OCDE en 2016, qui propose également une taxonomie pour les groupes industriels ayant des fourchettes différentes de dépenses de R&amp;amp;D par rapport à leur valeur ajoutée brute. Les industries MHT sont traditionnellement définies exclusivement aux industries manufacturières. Toutefois, des efforts récents ont été déployés (Galindo-Rueda et Verger, 2016) pour étendre la définition aux industries non manufacturières. Néanmoins, les secteurs de la moyenne-haute et de la haute technologie sont également représentés principalement par les industries manufacturières. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; CITI Rev.4&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Description&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; CITI Rev.3 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Description&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;20&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Fabrication de produits chimiques et chimiques&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;24&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Fabrication de produits chimiques et chimiques&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;21&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Fabrication de produits pharmaceutiques de base et préparations pharmaceutiques&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;29&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Fabrication de machines et d’équipement n.c.a.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;252&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Fabrication d’armes et de munitions&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;30&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Fabrication de machines de bureau, de comptabilité et d’informatique&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;26&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Fabrication de produits informatiques, électroniques et optiques&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;31&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Fabrication de machines et d’appareils électriques n.c.a.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;27&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Fabrication d’équipements électriques&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;32&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Fabrication d’équipements et d’appareils de radio, de télévision et
de communication&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;28&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Fabrication de machines et d’équipement n.c.a.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;33&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Fabrication d’instruments médicaux, de précision et optiques, de montres
et d’horloges&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;29&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Fabrication de véhicules automobiles, remorques et semi-remorques&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;34&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Fabrication de véhicules automobiles, remorques et semi-remorques&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;30*&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Fabrication d’autres équipements de transport &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;35**&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Fabrication d’autres équipements de transport&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;325&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Fabrication d’instruments et de fournitures médicaux et dentaires&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;* &lt;/strong&gt;À l’exclusion de 301 (Construction de navires et de bateaux)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;** &lt;/strong&gt;À l’exclusion de 351 (Construction et réparation de navires et de bateaux)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; MVA est la valeur ajoutée de l’industrie manufacturière, qui est la section C de la CITI Rev.4, et la section D de la CITI Rev.3. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
