<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 3-a-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Reports either downloaded from websites, submitted through the WHO FCTC reporting platform or emailed by national counterparts. WHO shares and makes public the methodologies for its estimates through the WHO global report on trends in tobacco use 2000-2025 and the WHO Report on the Global Tobacco Epidemic. The WHO estimates undergo country consultation prior to publication. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Proceso de recopilación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Informes descargados de sitios web o enviados por correo electrónico por sus homólogos nacionales. La OMS comparte y hace públicas las metodologías de sus estimaciones a través del Informe mundial de la OMS sobre las tendencias del consumo de tabaco 2000-2025 y el Informe de la OMS sobre la epidemia mundial de tabaquismo. Las estimaciones de la OMS se someten a consulta en los países antes de su publicación.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Processus de collecte : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les rapports téléchargés à partir de sites Web ou envoyés par courriel par des homologues nationaux. L&apos;OMS partage et rend publiques les méthodologies de ses estimations par le biais du Rapport mondial sur les tendances de l&apos;usage du tabac 2000-2025 de l&apos;OMS et du Rapport sur l&apos;épidémie mondiale de tabagisme de l&apos;OMS. Les estimations de l&apos;OMS font l&apos;objet d&apos;une consultation dans les pays avant leur publication. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Отчеты загружаются с веб-сайтов или отправляются по электронной почте национальными партнерами. ВОЗ распространяет и публикует методологии своих оценок в глобальном отчете ВОЗ о тенденциях в употреблении табака в 2000-2025 годах и в докладе ВОЗ о глобальной табачной эпидемии. Перед публикацией оценки ВОЗ проходят процесс консультаций со странами. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
