<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 3-a-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Rationale:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tobacco use is a major contributor to illness and death from non-communicable diseases (NCDs). There is no proven safe level of tobacco use or of second-hand smoke exposure. All daily and non-daily users of tobacco are at risk of a variety of poor health outcomes across the life-course, including NCDs. Reducing the prevalence of current tobacco use will make a large contribution to reducing premature mortality from NCDs (Target 3.4). Routine and regular monitoring of this indicator is necessary to enable accurate monitoring and evaluation of the impact of implementation of the WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control (WHO FCTC), or tobacco control policies in the countries that are not yet Parties to the WHO FCTC, over time. Tobacco use prevalence levels are an appropriate indicator of implementation of SDG Target 3.a &amp;#x201C;Strengthen the implementation of the World Health Organization Framework Convention on Tobacco Control in all countries, as appropriate&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt; Justification : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L&apos;usage du tabac est un facteur majeur de maladie et de décès dus aux maladies non transmissibles (MNT). Il n&apos;y a pas de niveau sûr prouvé de tabagisme ou d&apos;exposition à la fumée secondaire. Tous les utilisateurs quotidiens et non quotidiens de tabac sont exposés à divers problèmes de santé tout au long de leur vie, y compris les MNT. La réduction de la prévalence de l&apos;usage actuel du tabac contribuera largement à réduire la mortalité prématurée due aux MNT (objectif 3.4). Un suivi systématique et régulier de cet indicateur est nécessaire pour permettre un suivi et une évaluation précis de l&apos;impact de la mise en œuvre de la Convention-cadre de l&apos;OMS pour la lutte antitabac (OMS FCTC) ou des politiques de lutte antitabac dans les pays qui ne sont pas encore Parties à la Convention-cadre de l&apos;OMS, au fil du temps. Les niveaux de prévalence du tabagisme sont un indicateur approprié de la mise en œuvre de l&apos;objectif 3.a des ODD « Renforcer la mise en œuvre de la Convention-cadre de l&apos;Organisation mondiale de la santé pour la lutte antitabac dans tous les pays, le cas échéant ». &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
