<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COMPARABILITY field for indicator 9-2-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difference may arise due to: a) discrepancies in data sources; b) ISIC Revision used by a country; c) informal employment; d) coverage of data source (geographical coverage, economic activities covered, types of establishments covered, etc.); e) working-age population definition..&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Fuentes de discrepancias:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La diferencia puede surgir debido a: a) discrepancias en las fuentes de datos; b) Revisión CIIU utilizada por un país; c) empleo informal; d) cobertura de la fuente de datos (cobertura geográfica, actividades económicas cubiertas, tipos de establecimientos cubiertos, etc.); e) definición de población en edad de trabajar. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Sources des écarts : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La différence peut être due à : a) des divergences dans les sources de données ; b) la révision de la CITI utilisée par un pays ; c) l&apos;emploi informel ; d) la couverture de la source de données (couverture géographique, activités économiques couvertes, types d&apos;établissements couverts, etc. e) la définition de la population en âge de travailler.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Несовпадения могут возникнуть из-за: a) расхождений в источниках данных; б) использования странами различных редакций МСОК; в) наличия неформальной занятости; г) сферы охвата источника данных (географический охват, охватываемые виды экономической деятельности, типы охватываемых заведений и т. д.); д) различиях в определении населения трудоспособного возраста. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
