<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 3-1-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Numerator: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number of births attended by skilled health personnel (doctor, nurse or midwife) trained in providing quality obstetric care, including giving the necessary support and care to the mother and the newborn during childbirth and immediate postpartum period &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Denominator: The total number of live births in the same period. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Births attended by skilled health personnel = (number of births attended by skilled health personnel)/(total number of live births) x 100.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El número de mujeres de entre 15 y 49 años con un nacimiento vivo atendido por personal sanitario calificado (por ejemplo, médicos, personal de enfermería o matronería) durante el parto se expresa como porcentaje de las mujeres de entre 15 y 49 años con un nacimiento vivo en el mismo período.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Numérateur : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le nombre d&apos;accouchements assistés par du personnel de santé qualifié (médecin, infirmière ou sage-femme) formé à fournir des soins obstétriques de qualité, notamment à apporter le soutien et les soins nécessaires à la mère et au nouveau-né pendant l&apos;accouchement et la période post-partum immédiate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dénominateur : Le nombre total de naissances vivantes au cours de la même période. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Количество женщин в возрасте 15-49 лет, родивших живого ребенка под наблюдением квалифицированного медицинского персонала (например, врачей, медсестер или акушерок) во время родов, выражается как доля женщин в возрасте 15-49 лет, родивших живого ребенка за тот же период.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
