<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 3-1-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Having a skilled health care provider at the time of childbirth is an important lifesaving intervention for both women and newborns. Not having access to this key assistance is detrimental to women&amp;apos;s and newborns health because it could cause the death of the women and/or the newborn or long lasting morbidity Achieving universal coverage for this indicator is therefore essential for reducing maternal and newborn mortality. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contar con un asistente calificado en el momento del parto es una intervención importante para salvar la vida tanto de las mujeres como de los bebés. No tener acceso a esta asistencia clave es perjudicial para la salud de las mujeres porque podría causar la muerte de las mujeres o una morbilidad duradera, especialmente en entornos vulnerables.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;L&apos;accès à un prestataire de soins de santé qualifié au moment de l&apos;accouchement est une intervention importante pour sauver la vie des femmes et des nouveau-nés. Le fait de ne pas avoir accès à cette assistance clé est préjudiciable à la santé des femmes et des nouveau-nés, car cela peut entraîner le décès des femmes et/ou du nouveau-né ou une morbidité de longue durée. La couverture universelle de cet indicateur est donc essentielle pour réduire la mortalité maternelle et néonatale. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Наличие квалифицированного медицинского персонала во время родов - важное мероприятие, спасающее жизни как женщин, так и детей. Отсутствие доступа к этому ключевому виду помощи вредит здоровью женщин, поскольку может вызвать смерть женщины или длительную заболеваемость, особенно в уязвимых условиях.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
