<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 3-1-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Births attended by skilled health personnel is an indicator of health care utilization. It is a measure of the health system&amp;#x2019;s functioning and potential to provide adequate coverage for childbirth. On its own, however, this indicator does not provide insight into the availability or accessibility of services, for example in cases where emergency care if needed. Neither does this indicator capture the quality of care received.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data collection and data interpretation in many countries is challenged by lack of guidelines, standardization of professional titles and functions of the health care provider, and in some countries by task-shifting. In addition, many countries have found that there are large gaps between international standards and the competencies of existing of health care professionals providing childbirth care. Lack of training and an enabling environment often hinder evidence based management of common obstetric and neonatal complications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most commonly used denominator is the number of live births.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Les naissances assistées par du personnel de santé qualifié sont un indicateur de l&apos;utilisation des soins de santé. Il s&apos;agit d&apos;une mesure du fonctionnement et du potentiel du système de santé à fournir une couverture adéquate pour les accouchements. Cependant, à lui seul, cet indicateur ne donne pas une idée de la disponibilité ou de l&apos;accessibilité des services, par exemple dans les cas où des soins d&apos;urgence sont nécessaires. Cet indicateur ne rend pas non plus compte de la qualité des soins reçus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dans de nombreux pays, la collecte et l&apos;interprétation des données sont rendues difficiles par l&apos;absence de directives, de normalisation des titres professionnels et des fonctions du prestataire de soins de santé et, dans certains pays, par le transfert des tâches. En outre, de nombreux pays ont constaté qu&apos;il existe de grands écarts entre les normes internationales et les compétences des professionnels de la santé existants qui dispensent des soins d&apos;accouchement. Le manque de formation et un environnement favorable entravent souvent la prise en charge factuelle des complications obstétricales et néonatales courantes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le dénominateur le plus couramment utilisé est le nombre de naissances vivantes.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
