<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 3-9-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mortality rate attributable to the joint effects of household and ambient air pollution can be expressed as: crude death rate or age-standardized death rate. Crude rates are calculated by dividing the brut number of deaths by the total population (or indicated if a different population group is used, e.g. children under 5 years), while the age-standardized rates adjust for differences in the age distribution of the population by applying the observed age-specific mortality rates for each population to a standard population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evidence from epidemiological studies have shown that exposure to air pollution is linked, among others, to the important underlying causes of death taken into account in this estimate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Acute lower respiratory infections (estimated in all age groups; ICD-10: J09-J22, P23, U04 );&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Cerebrovascular diseases (stroke) in adults (estimated above 25 years; ICD-10: I60-I69);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Ischaemic heart diseases (IHD) in adults (estimated above 25 years; ICD-10: I20-I25);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) in adults (estimated above 25 years; ICD-10: J40-J44); and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Lung cancer in adults (estimated above 25 years; ICD-10: C33-C34).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mortality resulting from the exposure to ambient (outdoor) air pollution and household (indoor) air pollution from polluting fuels used for cooking and/or heating was assessed. Ambient air pollution results from emissions from industrial activity, households, cars and trucks which are complex mixtures of air pollutants, many of which are harmful to health. Of all these pollutants, fine particulate matter has the greatest effect on human health. By polluting fuels is understood kerosene, wood, coal, animal dung, charcoal, and crop wastes.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
