<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DOC_METHOD field for indicator 2-2-3, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;This indicator is part of the Global Nutrition Monitoring Framework (GNMF), for which operational guidance is offered to countries &amp;#x2013; the Global nutrition monitoring framework: Operational guidance for tracking progress in meeting targets for 2025 available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/nutrition/publications/operational-guidance-GNMF-indicators&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/nutrition/publications/operational-guidance-GNMF-indicators&lt;/a&gt; in the six UN official languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHO in collaborationg with UNICEF, the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and Nutrition International updated a Micronutrient Survey Manual, containing details about conducting and national nutrition survey and reporting results.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt;Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, World Health Organization, Nutrition International, UNICEF. Micronutrient survey manual. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2020. Licence: CC BY-NC-SA 3.0 IGO. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Métodos y directrices disponibles para los países para la recopilación de los datos a nivel nacional:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Este indicador forma parte del Marco Mundial de Vigilancia de la Nutrición (MMVN), para el que se ofrece a los países una orientación operativa &amp;#x2013; Marco Mundial de Vigilancia de la Nutrición: Orientación operativa para el seguimiento de los avances en el cumplimiento de las metas para 2025 disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/nutrition/publications/operational-guidance-GNMF-indicators&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/nutrition/publications/operational-guidance-GNMF-indicators&lt;/a&gt; en los seis idiomas oficiales de la ONU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La OMS también colabora con UNICEF, los Centros para el Control y la Prevención de Enfermedades de EE.UU. y Nutrición Internacional para actualizar un Manual de Encuesta sobre Micronutrientes, que contiene detalles sobre la realización de una encuesta nacional sobre nutrición y la presentación de los resultados&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-1&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mnsurveytoolkit.nutritionintl.org/&quot;&gt;http://mnsurveytoolkit.nutritionintl.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur fait partie du Cadre mondial de suivi de la nutrition (GNMF), pour lequel des conseils opérationnels sont proposés aux pays : Cadre mondial de suivi de la nutrition – Guide pratique pour le suivi des avancées par rapport aux cibles mondiales 2025, disponible à l&apos;adresse &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/handle/10665/272261/9789242513608-fre.pdf&quot;&gt; https://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/handle/10665/272261/9789242513608-fre.pdf &lt;/a&gt; (disponible dans les six langues officielles de l&apos;ONU).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;OMS en collaboration avec l&apos;UNICEF, les « Centers for Disease Control and Prevention » des États-Unis et « Nutrition International » ont mis à jour un manuel d&apos;enquête sur les micronutriments, qui contient des détails sur la conduite et la communication des résultats des enquêtes nationales sur la nutrition.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt;(en anglais) « Centers for Disease Control and Prevention », Organisation mondiale de la Santé, « Nutrition International », UNICEF. Micronutrient survey manual. Genève : Organisation mondiale de la Santé; 2020. Licence : CC BY-NC-SA 3.0 IGO. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Доступные странам методы и руководство для составления данных на национальном уровне: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Этот показатель является частью Глобальной основы мониторинга в области питания (ГОМП), в котором странам предлагается для работы оперативное руководство &quot;Глобальные основы мониторинга в области питания: оперативное руководство для отслеживания прогресса на пути достижения целей на 2025 год&quot; доступное по адресу &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/nutrition/publications/operational-guidance-GNMF-indicators&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/nutrition/publications/operational-guidance-GNMF-indicators&lt;/a&gt; на шести официальных языках ООН. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ВОЗ также сотрудничает с ЮНИСЕФ, Центрами США по контролю и профилактике заболеваний и Международным центром питания в целях обновления Руководства по обследованию питательных микроэлементов, содержащего подробную информацию о проведении и организации национального обследования в области питания и представлении результатов. &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href = &quot;# footnote -1 &quot;id =&quot; footnote-ref-1 &quot;&gt; [1] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class =&quot; footnotes &quot;&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class =&quot; footnote-number &quot;id = &quot;footnote-1&quot;&gt; 1 &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mnsurveytoolkit.nutritionintl.org/&quot;&gt; http://mnsurveytoolkit.nutritionintl.org/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href = &quot; # footnote-ref-1 &quot;&gt; &amp; # x2191; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
