<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 2-2-3, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Percentage of women aged 15&amp;#x2212;49 years with a haemoglobin concentration less than 120 g/L for non-pregnant women and lactating women, and less than 110 g/L for pregnant women, adjusted for altitude and smoking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anaemia: condition in which the concentration of blood haemoglobin concentration falls below established cut-off values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iron deficiency: state in which there is insufficient iron to maintain the normal physiological function of blood, brain and muscles (ICD-11, 5B5K.0 iron deficiency)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iron deficiency anaemia: (ICD-11, 3A00, iron deficiency anaemia)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blood haemoglobin concentration: concentration of haemoglobin in whole blood&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Porcentaje de mujeres de 15&amp;#x2212;49 años con una concentración de hemoglobina inferior a 120 g/L en el caso de las mujeres no embarazadas y lactantes, e inferior a 110 g/L en el caso de las embarazadas, ajustado por la altitud y el tabaquismo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anemia: estado en el que la concentración de hemoglobina en la sangre desciende por debajo de los valores de corte establecidos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estado de deficiencia de hierro en el que no hay suficiente hierro para mantener la función fisiológica normal de la sangre, el cerebro y los músculos (CIE-11, 5B5K.0 deficiencia de hierro)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anemia ferropénica: (CIE-11, 3A00, anemia ferropénica)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concentración de hemoglobina en sangre: concentración de hemoglobina en sangre total&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pourcentage de femmes âgées de 15 à 49 ans ayant une concentration d&apos;hémoglobine inférieure à 120 g/L pour les femmes non enceintes et les femmes allaitantes, et inférieure à 110 g/L pour les femmes enceintes, ajusté en fonction de l&apos;altitude et du tabagisme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anémie : état dans lequel la concentration d&apos;hémoglobine sanguine tombe en dessous des valeurs limites établies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;État de carence en fer dans lequel le fer est insuffisant pour maintenir la fonction physiologique normale du sang, du cerveau et des muscles (CIM-11, carence en fer 5B5K.0) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anémie ferriprive : (CIM-11, 3A00, anémie ferriprive)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concentration d&apos;hémoglobine dans le sang : concentration d&apos;hémoglobine dans le sang total &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Доля женщин в возрасте от 15 до 49 лет с концентрацией гемоглобина менее 120 г / л для небеременных и кормящих женщин и менее 110 г / л для беременных с поправкой на нахождение на определенной высоте над уровнем моря и курение.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Анемия: состояние, при котором концентрация гемоглобина в крови падает ниже установленных пороговых значений. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Состояние, вызванное дефицитом железа, при котором железа недостаточно для поддержания нормальной физиологической функции крови, мозга и мышц (МКБ-11, дефицит железа 5B5K.0) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Железодефицитная анемия: (МКБ-11, 3A00, железодефицитная анемия) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Концентрация гемоглобина в крови: концентрация гемоглобина в цельной крови&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
