<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 16-4-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;There are certain limitations to the methodology used in the calculation of indicator 16.4.2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The pilot study and consultations with Member States revealed that countries could not properly provide information on the circumstances of illicit manufacture or altered / erased markings for arms nor uniquely identifiable. Therefore, information on the establishment of the illicit origin for these arms is not available.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The values for indicator 16.4.2 may be affected by whether the country has a significant proportion of apprehended arms that are traceable, which is usually a consequence of the context of illicit arms trafficking in the country and is not related to its Law Enforcement efforts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The process of tracing firearms can be notably long, especially if several requests are involved. Therefore, the information on tracing results provided on the questionnaire for the reference year may be incomplete. While the fact that countries are requested to review the figures reported during the previous data collection cycle may partially correct for this, there may still be a bias in the calculation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to indicator 16.4.2 as defined in this document, other non-official indicators may be of assistance when interpreting the reporting values. In particular, information is collected on the number of international tracing requests placed and responded to, and the total number of arms seized, found and surrendered by whether they are uniquely marked or not, the total number of arms that have been marked, recorded or destroyed. In addition, data on the number of individuals in contact with the police, prosecuted and convicted, in relation to illicit trafficking of arms is available. All these indicators could help complete the picture regarding the extent of Law Enforcement activities at the national level to counter illicit trafficking in arms.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
