<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 17-17-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator based on WBG data:&lt;em&gt; &amp;#x201C;Amount of United States dollars committed to public-private partnerships in infrastructure&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator by the World Bank Group defines the term Public-Private Partnership (PPPs) as &amp;#x201C;&lt;em&gt;any contractual arrangement between a public entity or authority and a private entity, for providing a public asset or service, in which the private party bears significant risk and management responsibility&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;#x201D;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term infrastructure refers to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Energy: electricity generation, transmission, and distribution, and natural gas transmission and distribution pipelines&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Information and communications technology (ICT): ICT backbone infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transport: Airports, railways, ports, and roads.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Water: potable water treatment and distribution, and sewerage collection and treatment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PPPs is defined as &amp;#x201C;any contractual arrangement between a public entity or authority and a private entity, for providing a public asset or service, in which the private party bears significant risk and management responsibility.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term infrastructure refers to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; Energy: electricity generation, transmission, and distribution, and natural gas transmission and distribution pipelines&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; Information and communications technology (ICT): ICT backbone infrastructure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; Transport: Airports, railways, ports, and roads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; Water: potable water treatment and distribution, and sewerage collection and treatment.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
