<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 3-9-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Data availability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are available for practically all countries. They are, however, sometimes based on health statistics provided by international agencies as the national data are incomplete. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Actual country data for 2010 onwards period:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asia and Pacific - 27% of countries (16 out of 59 countries, including China and India sample systems)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Africa - 6% of countries (3 out of 54 countries)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Latin America and the Caribbean - 56% of countries (19 out of 34 countries)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe, North America, Australia, New Zealand and Japan - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;94% of countries (44 out of 47 countries, missing are mainly very small countries)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the period 2000-2009:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asia and Pacific - 27% of countries (16 out of 59 countries, including China and India sample systems)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Africa - 6% of countries (3 out of 54 countries)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Latin America and the Caribbean - 56% of countries (19 out of 34 countries)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe, North America, Australia, New Zealand and Japan - 94% of countries (44 out of 47 countries, missing are mainly very small countries)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web link to the database: &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.home%20&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.home&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator has been established and available for more than a decade. &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.INADEQUATEWSH?lang=en&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.INADEQUATEWSH?lang=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/gbd_poor_water/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/gbd_poor_water/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHO has been collating country figures and has been using these to produce global and regional estimates against this indicator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Time series:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limited time series data is available (comparable series for years 2012 and soon 2015; data for 2002 are also available but have more limited comparability)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this indicator is population-based, geographic location is the most natural disaggregation. Data also exists for age group and sex. Similar to JMP&amp;#x2019;s work on disaggregation by income groups (wealth quintile), data can further be disaggregated by wealth quintile.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se dispone de datos para prácticamente todos los países. Sin embargo, a veces se basan en estadísticas sanitarias proporcionadas por organismos internacionales, ya que los datos nacionales son incompletos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Datos reales de los países para el período 2010 en adelante:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asia y el Pacífico - 27% de los países (16 de 59 países, incluidos los sistemas de muestra de China e India)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;África - 6% de los países (3 de 54 países)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;América Latina y el Caribe - 56% de los países (19 de 34 países)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europa, América del Norte, Australia, Nueva Zelanda y Japón - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;94% de los países (44 de 47 países, faltan principalmente países muy pequeños)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Para el período 2000-2009:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asia y Pacífico - 27% de los países (16 de 59 países, incluidos los sistemas de muestra de China e India)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;África - 6% de los países (3 de 54 países)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;América Latina y el Caribe - 56% de los países (19 de 34 países)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europa, América del Norte, Australia, Nueva Zelanda y Japón - 94% de los países (44 de 47 países, los que faltan son principalmente países muy pequeños)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enlace web a la base de datos: &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.home%20&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.home&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador está establecido y disponible desde hace más de una década. &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.INADEQUATEWSH?lang=en&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.INADEQUATEWSH?lang=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/gbd_poor_water/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/gbd_poor_water/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La OMS ha cotejado las cifras de los países y las ha utilizado para elaborar estimaciones mundiales y regionales en relación con este indicador. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se dispone de datos de series temporales limitadas (series comparables para los años 2012 y próximamente 2015; también se dispone de datos para 2002, pero su comparabilidad es más limitada).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dado que este indicador se basa en la población, la ubicación geográfica es el desglose más natural. También existen datos por grupo de edad y sexo. Al igual que el trabajo del PCM sobre la desagregación por grupos de ingresos (quintil de riqueza), los datos pueden desagregarse aún más por quintil de riqueza.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilité des données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont disponibles pour presque tous les pays. Lorsque les données nationales sont incomplètes, les données reposent sur des statistiques fournies par des organisations internationales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Données nationales uniquement pour les années 2010 et suivantes :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asie et Pacifique - 27 % des pays (16 pays sur 59, incluant la Chine et l&apos;Inde (systèmes d&apos;enregistrement par échantillonnage))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afrique - 6 % des pays (3 pays sur 54)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amérique latine et Caraïbes - 56 % des pays (19 pays sur 34)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe, Amérique du Nord, Australie, Nouvelle-Zélande et Japon - 94 % des pays (44 pays sur 47, les trois manquants sont essentiellement de très petits pays)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pour la période 2000 à 2009 :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asie et Pacifique - 27 % des pays (16 pays sur 59, incluant la Chine et l&apos;Inde (systèmes d&apos;enregistrement par échantillonnage))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afrique - 6 % des pays (3 pays sur 54)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amérique latine et Caraïbes - 56 % des pays (19 pays sur 34)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe, Amérique du Nord, Australie, Nouvelle-Zélande et Japon - 94 % des pays (44 pays sur 47, les trois manquants sont essentiellement de très petits pays)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lien Internet à la base de données (en anglais) : &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.home%20&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.home&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur est utilisé et disponible depuis plus d&apos;une décennie. &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.INADEQUATEWSH?lang=en&quot;&gt;(en anglais) http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.INADEQUATEWSH?lang=fr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/gbd_poor_water/en/&quot;&gt;(en anglais) http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/gbd_poor_water/fr/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;OMS compile et utilise ces données pour produire des estimations régionales et mondiales pour cet indicateur. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Séries chronologiques :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des séries chronologiques sont disponibles (séries comparables pour 2012 et bientôt 2015; les données pour 2002 sont également disponibles, mais ne sont pas totalement comparables).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Désagrégation :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comme l&apos;indicateur est basé sur la population, la désagrégation au niveau géographique est la plus évidente. Les données sont également disponibles par sexe et par groupe d&apos;âge. Comme pour les données produites par le programme conjoint OMS/UNICEF « Joint Monitoring Programme for Water Supply, Sanitation and Hygiene » (JMP), les données peuvent également être désagrégées par quintile de richesse.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt;Доступность данных&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Описание:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Данные доступны практически по всем странам. Однако иногда они основаны на статистике здравоохранения, предоставленной международными агентствами, поскольку национальные данные являются неполными. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Конкретные страновые данные за период с 2010 года и далее:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Азиатско-Тихоокеанский регион - 27% стран (16 из 59 стран, включая Китай и Индию) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Африка - 6% стран (3 из 54 стран) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Латинская Америка и Карибский бассейн - 56% стран (19 из 34 стран) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Европа, Северная Америка, Австралия, Новая Зеландия и Япония - &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 94% стран (44 из 47 стран, отсутствуют в основном очень маленькие страны) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; За период 2000-2009 годов: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Азиатско-Тихоокеанский регион - 27% стран (16 из 59 стран, включая Китай и Индию) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Африка - 6% стран (3 из 54 стран) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Латинская Америка и Карибский бассейн - 56% стран (19 из 34 стран) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Европа, Северная Америка, Австралия, Новая Зеландия и Япония - 94% стран (44 из 47 стран, отсутствуют в основном очень маленькие страны)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Интернет-ссылка на базу данных: &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.home%20&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.home&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Показатель разработан и данные доступны уже более десяти лет. &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.INADEQUATEWSH?lang=en&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.INADEQUATEWSH?lang=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/gbd_poor_water/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/gbd_poor_water/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ВОЗ сопоставляет данные по странам и использует их для получения глобальных и региональных оценок по этому показателю. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Временные ряды:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Доступны ограниченные данные временных рядов (сопоставимые ряды за 2012 год и вскоре будут данные за 2015 год; данные за 2002 год также доступны, но имеют более ограниченную сопоставимость)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Дезагрегирование:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Поскольку этот показатель имеет в основе данные по численности населения, географическое положение представляет собой наиболее естественную дезагрегацию. Также существуют данные по возрастным группам и полу. Подобно тому, как Совместная программа мониторинга (СПМ) провела работу по дезагрегации данных по группам дохода (квинтиль благосостояния), данные также могут быть дополнительно дезагрегированы по квинтилям благосостояния.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
