<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 3-9-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At country level &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are available for practically all countries. They are, however, sometimes based on health statistics provided by international agencies as the national data are incomplete, which have been interpolated/ extrapolated, adjusted, and completed by additional data and cause-of-death models. A more detailed description of the methods is provided in http://www.who.int/healthinfo/global_burden_disease/GlobalCOD_method_2000_2012.pdf &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At regional and global levels &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NA &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel de país:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se dispone de datos para prácticamente todos los países. Sin embargo, a veces se basan en estadísticas sanitarias proporcionadas por organismos internacionales, ya que los datos nacionales están incompletos, y se han interpolado/extrapolado, ajustado y completado con datos adicionales y modelos de causa de muerte. Se ofrece una descripción más detallada de los métodos en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/global_burden_disease/GlobalCOD_method_2000_2012.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/global_burden_disease/GlobalCOD_method_2000_2012.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel regional y mundial:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NA.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Au niveau national :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont disponibles pour presque tous les pays. Toutefois, lorsque les données nationales sont incomplètes, les données reposent sur des statistiques fournies par des organisations internationales qui ont été interpolées, extrapolées, ajustées et complétées par des données supplémentaires et des modèles de cause de décès. Une description détaillée des méthodes utilisées est disponible (en anglais) à l&apos;adresse : http://www.who.int/healthinfo/global_burden_disease/GlobalCOD_method_2000_2012.pdf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aux niveaux régional et mondial :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sans objet&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt;Обработка отсутствующих значений:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;На страновом уровне:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Данные доступны практически по всем странам. Однако иногда они основаны на статистике здравоохранения, предоставляемой международными агентствами, поскольку национальные данные являются неполными, и их приходится интерполировать / экстраполировать, корректировать, привлекать дополнительные данные и строить модели причин смерти. Более подробное описание методов приведено в &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/global_burden_disease/GlobalCOD_method_2000_2012.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/global_burden_disease/GlobalCOD_method_2000_2012.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;На региональном и глобальном уровнях:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Не применимо&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
