<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 3-9-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Comments and limitations:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data rely on (a) statistics on WASH services (6.1, 6.2 and 6.3), which are well assessed in almost all countries, and (b) data on deaths. Data on deaths are also widely available from countries from death registration data or sample registration systems, which are certainly feasible systems. Such data are crucial for improving health and reducing preventable deaths in countries. The main limitation is that not all countries do have such registration systems to date, and data need to be completed with other type of information.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires et limites :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données reposent sur (a) des statistiques sur les services WASH (6.1, 6.2 et 6.3), qui sont disponibles pour presque tous les pays, et (b) des données sur les décès. Les données nationales sur les décès sont généralement disponibles à partir des enregistrements des décès ou des systèmes d&apos;enregistrement par échantillonnage. Ces données sont essentielles pour améliorer la santé et réduire les décès évitables. La principale limite est que tous les pays ne disposent pas encore de tels systèmes d&apos;enregistrement et que les données doivent être complétées par d&apos;autres types d&apos;informations.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt;Комментарии и ограничения:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Данные основаны на (а) статистике услуг ВССГ (6.1, 6.2 и 6.3), которые хорошо производятся почти во всех странах, и (б) данных по смертям. Также в широком доступе имеются данные по смертям, которые страны получают из систем регистрации смертей или выборочной регистрации, которые, безусловно, являются реализуемыми системами. Такие данные имеют решающее значение для улучшения здоровья и совершенствования ситуации с предотвратимыми смертями в странах. Основное ограничение заключается в том, что не все страны имеют на сегодняшний день такие системы регистрации, при этом данные приходится дополнять информацией из других источников.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
