<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 3-9-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mortality rate attributed to unsafe water, unsafe sanitation and lack of hygiene (exposure to unsafe Water, Sanitation and Hygiene for All (WASH) services) as defined as the number of deaths from unsafe water, unsafe sanitation and lack of hygiene (exposure to unsafe WASH services) in a year, divided by the population, and multiplied by 100,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deaths attributable to unsafe water, sanitation and hygiene focusing on inadequate WASH services, expressed per 100,000 population; The included diseases are the WASH attributable fractions of diarrhoea (ICD-10 code A00, A01, A03, A04, A06-A09), intestinal nematode infections (ICD-10 code B76-B77, B79) and protein-energy malnutrition (ICD-10 code E40-E46).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Définition :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le taux de mortalité attribuable à l&apos;insalubrité de l&apos;eau, aux déficiences du système d&apos;assainissement et au manque d&apos;hygiène (exposition à des services d&apos;eau, d&apos;assainissement et d&apos;hygiène insalubres (WASH)) est défini comme le nombre de décès attribuables à ces causes au cours d&apos;une année, divisé par la population, et multiplié par 100 000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Décès attribuables à une eau insalubre ou un assainissement ou une hygiène inadéquat (en particulier les services WASH), exprimés pour 100 000 habitants. Les maladies incluses sont les diarrhées (CIM-10 codes A00, A01, A03, A04, A06-A09), les infections intestinales à nématodes (CIM-10 codes B76-B77, B79) et la malnutrition protéino-énergétique (CIM-10 codes E40-E46) attribuables à des lacunes au niveau des services WASH.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Уровень смертности от доступа к небезопасным услугам в области водоснабжения, санитарии и гигиены для всех (ВССГ)), определяется как количество смертей в результате использования небезопасной воды, небезопасной санитарии и отсутствия гигиены (воздействие небезопасной воды, санитарии и отсутствия гигиены для всех) за год, поделенное на численность населения, и умноженное на 100000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Смертность, связанная с доступом к небезопасным услугам в области водоснабжения, санитарии и гигиены, с упором на неадекватные услуги ВССГ, в расчете на 100 000 населения; Включенные заболевания - это добавочные доли риска при отсутствии ВССГ от диареи (код ICD-10 A00, A01, A03, A04, A06-A09), кишечных нематодных инфекций (код ICD-10 B76-B77, B79) и белково-энергетической недостаточности (ICD- 10 код E40-E46). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
