<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 2-1-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;Definition: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prevalence of undernourishment (PoU) (French: pourcentage de sous-alimentation; Spanish: porcentaje de sub-alimentaci&amp;#xF3;n; Italian: prevalenza di sotto-alimentazione) is an estimate of the proportion of the population whose habitual food consumption is insufficient to provide the dietary energy levels that are required to maintain a normal active and healthy life. It is expressed as a percentage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concepts: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Undernourishment is defined as the condition by which a person has access, on a regular basis, to the amount of food that are insufficient to provide the energy required for conducting a normal, healthy and active life, given his or her own dietary energy requirements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though strictly related, &amp;#x201C;undernourishment&amp;#x201D; as defined here is different from the physical conditions of &amp;#x201C;malnutrition&amp;#x201D; and &amp;#x201C;undernutrition&amp;#x201D; as it refers to the condition of insufficient intake of food, rather than to the outcome in terms of nutritional status. In French, Spanish and Italian the difference is marked by the use of the terms alimentation, alimentaci&amp;#xF3;n, or alimentazione, instead of nutrition, nutrici&amp;#xF3;n or nutrizione, in the name of the indicator. A more appropriate expression in English that would render the precise meaning of the indicator might have been &amp;#x201C;prevalence of under-feeding&amp;#x201D; but by now the term &amp;#x201C;undernourishment&amp;#x201D; has long been associated with the indicator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the undernourishment condition applies to individuals, due to conceptual and data-related considerations, the indicator can only be referred to a population, or group of individuals. The prevalence of undernourishment is thus an estimate of the percentage of individuals in a group that are in that condition, but it does not allow for the identification of which individuals in the group are, in fact, undernourished. &lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
