<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 8-1-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;h2&gt;Treatment of missing values:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At country level:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a full set of official annual GDP data is not available, estimation procedures are employed to obtain estimates for the entire time series. When full data are not available, a hierarchy of other data sources is used to gather information on the national accounts of a country or area. The data gathered are then either used directly or estimation procedures are applied to obtain the annual GDP data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If official data are not available, the selection of data sources is based on following hierarchy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. Official publications and websites of national statistical offices, central banks or relevant government ministries;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Official statistics disseminated by Eurostat, European Central Bank and the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) for their members;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. Information provided by Permanent Missions to the United Nations;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. Economic surveys and estimates prepared by United Nations&amp;#x2019; Regional Economic Commissions (i.e. UNECE, ECLAC, ESCAP, UNECA and ESCWA);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e. Publications of international organizations with a strong focus on statistical data collection (including regional development banks). The most common sources used for their respective countries are listed below: Asia: Asian Development Bank, ASEAN, Arab Monetary Fund, Secretariat of the Pacific Community (SPC) Africa: African Development Bank, Afristat, Banque des Etats de l&amp;#x2019;Afrique Centrale (BEAC), Union Economique Monetaire Ouest Africain (UEMOA) Americas: CARICOM, Caribbean Development Bank, Eastern Caribbean Central Bank (ECCB) Other: OECD for non-member countries Statistical Committee of the Commonwealth of Independent States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;f. Estimates and indicators from other international organizations. The most common sources used are: the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and the World Bank;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;g. Publications or websites of specialized groups, the most common sources used are: the Gulf Cooperation Council, the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC), the Committee of Central Bank Governors in SADC; the Islamic Development Bank, and the Statistical Training Centre for Islamic Countries;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;h. Economic data from commercial providers and other sources, the most common sources used are: the Economic Intelligence Unit and the United States Central Intelligence Agency;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i. Information from neighbouring countries where no alternative source is available (Switzerland for Liechtenstein; France for Monaco; Italy for San Marino; Spain for Andorra; and some Pacific Islands for other Pacific Islands);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The estimation methods involved in preparing the GDP estimates using sources other than official data include trend extrapolation, using appropriate indices for inflating or deflating relevant data series, and share distribution of GDP. A hierarchical assessment is followed to determine which method should be used. Effort is made to keep data estimation methods consistent from year to year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At regional and global levels:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the missing real GDP country or area data are imputed using the methods as described above, they are summed up to derive the respective regional or global aggregates and then divided by the corresponding population data to obtain the regional or global real GDP per capita. After that, annual growth rates in regional or global real GDP per capita are calculated using the formula described above.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
