<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 5-2-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator measures the percentage of ever-partnered women and girls aged 15 years and older who have experienced physical, sexual or psychological violence by a current or former intimate partner, in the previous 12 months. Definition of violence against women and girls and of the forms of violence specified under this indicator are presented in the next section (Concepts).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;NOTE: &lt;/u&gt;We refer to &amp;#x201C;violence against women&amp;#x201D; throughout, and this also includes adolescent girls (15-19 years old).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the UN Declaration on the Elimination of Violence against Women (1993), violence against women is &amp;#x201C;Any act of gender-based violence that results in, or is likely to result in, physical, sexual or psychological harm or suffering to women, including threats of such acts, coercion or arbitrary deprivation of liberty, whether occurring in public or in private life. Violence against women shall be understood to encompass, but not be limited to, the following: Physical, sexual and psychological violence occurring in the family [&amp;#x2026;]&amp;#x201D;. See here for full definition: https://undocs.org/en/A/RES/48/104 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intimate partner violence against women includes any abuse perpetrated by a current or former partner within the context of marriage, cohabitation or any other formal or informal union.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;u&gt;different forms of violence&lt;/u&gt; included in the indicator are defined as follows: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Physical violence consists of acts aimed at physically hurting the victim and include, but are not limited to, acts like pushing, grabbing, twisting the arm, pulling hair, slapping, kicking, biting or hitting with a fist or object, trying to strangle or suffocate, burning or scalding on purpose, or threatening or attacking with some sort of weapon, gun or knife. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Sexual violence is defined as any sort of harmful or unwanted sexual behavior that is imposed on someone, whether by use of physical force, intimidation or coercion. It includes acts of abusive sexual contact, forced sexual acts, attempted or completed sexual acts (intercourse) without consent (rape or attempted rape), non-contact acts such as being forced to watch or participate in pornography, etc. In intimate partner relationships, sexual violence is commonly operationally defined in surveys as: being physically forced to have sexual intercourse, having sexual intercourse out of fear for what the partner might do or through coercion, and/or being forced to so something sexual that the woman considers humiliating or degrading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Psychological violence consists of any act that induces fear or emotional distress . It includes a range of behaviors that encompass acts of emotional abuse such as being frequently humiliated in public, intimidated or having things you care for destroyed, etc. These often coexist with acts of physical and sexual violence by intimate partners. In addition, surveys often measure controlling behaviours (e.g., being kept from seeing family or friends, or from seeking health care without permission). These are also considered acts of psychological abuse &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a more detailed definition of physical, sexual and psychological violence against women see &lt;em&gt;Guidelines for Producing Statistics on Violence against Women- Statistical Surveys&lt;/em&gt; (UN, 2014), and the &lt;em&gt;International Classification of Crime for Statistical Purposes&lt;/em&gt; ICCS (UNODC, 2015), and Violence against Women Prevalence Estimates, 2018. Global, regional and national prevalence estimates for intimate partner violence against women and global and regional prevalence estimates for non-partner sexual violence against women (WHO, 2021). . &lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
