<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 5-4-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator is defined as the proportion of time spent in a day on unpaid domestic and care work by men and women. Unpaid domestic and care work refers to activities related to the provision of services for own final use by household members, or by family members living in other households. These activities are listed in ICATUS 2016 under the major divisions &amp;#x201C;3. Unpaid domestic services for household and family members&amp;#x201D; and &amp;#x201C;4. Unpaid caregiving services for household and family members&amp;#x201D;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unpaid domestic and care work &lt;/em&gt;refers to activities including food preparation, dishwashing, cleaning and upkeep of the dwelling, laundry, ironing, gardening, caring for pets, shopping, installation, servicing and repair of personal and household goods, childcare, and care of the sick, elderly or disabled household and family members, among others. These activities are listed in ICATUS 2016 under the major divisions &amp;#x201C;3. Unpaid domestic services for household and family members&amp;#x201D; and &amp;#x201C;4. Unpaid caregiving services for household and family members&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concepts and definitions for this indicator are based on the following international standards:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;System of National Accounts 2008 (SNA 2008)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Resolution concerning statistics of work, employment and labour underutilization, adopted by the International Conference of Labour Statisticians (ICLS) at its 19th Session in 2013&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;International Classification of Activities for Time Use Statistics 2016 (ICATUS 2016)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relevant specific concepts are presented below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An activity is said to be productive or to fall within the &amp;#x201C;general production boundary&amp;#x201D; if it satisfies the third-person criterion (the activity can be delegated to another person and yield the same desired results).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Productive activities can be further classified based on the ILO framework for work statistics (included in the 19&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; ICLS resolution) into:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Own-use production work (activities to produce goods and services for own final use; the intended destination of the output is mainly for final use of the producer in the form of capital formation, or final consumption by household members or by family members living in other households; in the case of agricultural, fishing, hunting or gathering goods intended mainly for own consumption, a part or surplus may nevertheless be sold or bartered)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Employment (activities to produce goods or provide services for pay or profit)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unpaid trainee work (any unpaid activity to produce goods or provide services for others, in order to acquire workplace experience or skills in a trade or profession)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Volunteer work (any unpaid, non-compulsory activity to produce goods or provide services for others)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Other forms of work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The own-use production work can be differentiated based on whether goods or services are produced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Indicator 5.4.1 only considers the own-use production work of services, or in other words, the activities related to unpaid domestic services and unpaid caregiving services undertaken by households for their own use. These activities are listed in ICATUS 2016 under the major divisions &amp;#x201C;3. Unpaid domestic services for household and family members&amp;#x201D; and &amp;#x201C;4. Unpaid caregiving services for household and family members&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as possible, statistics compiled by UNSD are based on the International Classification of Activities for Time Use Statistics 2016 (ICATUS 2016), which classifies activities undertaken by persons during the survey period. ICATUS 2016 was adopted by the United Nations Statistical Commission for use as an international statistical classification at its 48th session, 7-10 March 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
