<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 1-1-1a, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;The World Bank typically receives data from National Statistical Offices (NSOs) directly. In other cases it uses NSO data received indirectly. For example, it receives data from Eurostat and from LIS (Luxemburg Income Study), who provide the World Bank NSO data they have received / harmonized. The Universidad Nacional de La Plata, Argentina and the World Bank jointly maintain the SEDLAC (Socio-Economic Database for Latin American and Caribbean) database that includes harmonized statistics on poverty and other distributional and social variables from 24 Latin American and Caribbean countries, based on microdata from household surveys conducted by NSOs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data is obtained through country specific programs, including technical assistance programs and joint analytical and capacity building activities. The World Bank has relationships with NSOs on work programs involving statistical systems and data analysis. Poverty economists from the World Bank typically engage with NSOs broadly on poverty measurement and analysis as part of technical assistance activities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The input data used are most often unit record data of welfare and occasionally grouped data, which is converted to a full distribution. The World Bank cannot take as input data a poverty rate published on an NSO website without the underlying distribution for a couple of reaons: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extrapolating or interpolating all country estimates to a common reference year, which is needed to calculate global poverty, requires a full distribution. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updates to poverty estimates in the face of revised PPPs and consumer price indices (CPIs) would not be possible to perform by the World Bank, imposing a higher burden on NSOs potentially becoming an obstacle for timely publication of updated data.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unit-record data allows for quality checking the data and ensuring that the choices used to create the welfare aggregate are as comparable as possible across countries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directly from National Statistical Offices (NSOs) or indirectly from others &amp;#x2013; see section on data sources.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
