<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_SOURCE field for indicator 17-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ru"># Поставщики данных

Агентством, отвечающим за подготовку статистики задолженности на национальном уровне, является Всемирный банк, данные которому поступают от государственных учреждений на основе данных о ссудах по займам. Национальным поставщиком данных по показателю &quot;Экспорт товаров и услуг&quot; является учреждение, ответственное за сбор и составление статистики платежного баланса. Эта ответственность варьируется и зависит от конкретной страны (т.е. Центрального банка). Оценки сотрудников Всемирного банка по данным &quot;Экспорт товаров и услуг&quot; используются для заполнения пробелов. &quot;Данные об экспорте товаров и услуг не направляются непосредственно Всемирному банку национальным поставщиком данных. Они представляются Международному валютному фонду (МВФ), который является учреждением, отвечающим за надзор за стабильностью платежного баланса в рамках своего институционального мандата.
			</language>
			<language lang="en"># Data providers

The agency in charge of producing the debt statistics at the national level is the World Bank with the data sourced by government agencies on a loan by loan basis. The national data provider of “Exports of Goods, and Services” is the institution in charge of the collection and compilation of the Balance of Payments statistics. This responsibility varies and is country specific (i.e. Central Bank). World Bank staff estimates for “Exports of Goods and Services” data are used for gap filling purposes. “Exports of Goods and Services” data are not reported directly to the World Bank from the national data provider. They are reported to the International Monetary Fund (IMF), which is the institution in charge of overseeing balance of payment stability as part of its institutional mandate.
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
