<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REG_AGG field for indicator 3-8-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Regional aggregates:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regional and global aggregates are computed by using national population sizes to compute a weighted average of country-specific values for the index. This is justified on the grounds that UHC is a property of countries, and the index of essential services is a summary measure of access to essential services for each country&amp;#x2019;s population.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los agregados regionales y mundiales se calculan utilizando los tamaños de la población nacional para calcular una media ponderada de los valores específicos de cada país para el índice. Esto se justifica por el hecho de que la CSU es una propiedad de los países, y el índice de servicios esenciales es una medida resumida del acceso a los servicios esenciales para la población de cada país.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt; Agrégats régionaux : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les agrégats régionaux et mondiaux sont calculés en utilisant la taille de la population nationale pour calculer une moyenne pondérée des valeurs spécifiques au pays pour l&apos;indice. Cela se justifie par le fait que la CSU est une propriété des pays et que l&apos;indice des services essentiels est une mesure sommaire de l&apos;accès aux services essentiels pour la population de chaque pays. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Региональные агрегаты: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Региональные и глобальные агрегированные показатели рассчитываются с использованием данных по численности населения страны для вычисления средневзвешенного значения индекса для конкретной страны. Это оправдано тем, что показатель всеобщего охвата услугами здравоохранения (ВОУЗ) является достоянием стран, а индекс основных услуг является суммарным показателем доступа к основным услугам для населения каждой страны. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
