<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 3-8-2, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of countries or territories with SDG 3.8.2 data increases over time as more surveys become available.. For more information and to get the latest updates, please use WHO and World Bank dedicated data portals: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/data/gho/data/themes/topics/financial-protection&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/data/gho/data/themes/topics/financial-protection&lt;/a&gt; and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://datatopics.worldbank.org/universal-health-coverage/&quot;&gt;https://datatopics.worldbank.org/universal-health-coverage/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The frequency of such data is similar to the frequency of the data used to produce SDG indicator 1.1.1. It varies across countries but on average, this ranges from an annual 1-year basis to 3 to 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following disaggregation is possible in so far as the survey has been designed to provide representative estimates and/or there are enough observations collected at such level:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Geographic location (rural/urban)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sex of the head of the household (male/female); &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Age and sex of the head of the household (below 60 years old/ 60 years or older; male/female);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Age composition of the household based on the following grouping: &amp;#x201C;Adults only (20-59 years old)&amp;#x201D; - households that consist of members aged between 20 and 59 years old; &amp;#x201C;Adults with children and adolescents (below 60 years old members)&amp;#x201D; - households that consist of members aged below 60 only as follows: at least one member below 20 years old AND at least one member aged between 20 and 59 years old; &amp;#x201C;Multigenerational households (all ages)&amp;#x201D; - households that include at least one person below 20 years old AND at least one person aged between 20 and 59 years old AND at least one person &amp;gt;= 60 years old; &amp;#x201C;Adults with older persons (from 20 years old)&amp;#x201D; - households that consist of members aged &amp;gt;=20 only as follows: at least one person aged between 20 and 59 years old AND at least one person &amp;gt;= 60 years old; &amp;#x201C;Only older adults (&amp;gt;=60 years old)&amp;#x201D; - households that consist of members aged &amp;gt;=60 years old only; &amp;#x201C;Only members below 20 years old&amp;#x201D; - households that consist of members aged below 20 years old only.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Geographic location (rural/urban)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Other possible disaggregation are possible such as by quintiles of the household welfare measures (total household consumption expenditure or income). See section 4.b on comments and limitations for the sensitivity of the disaggregation to the choice of the welfare measure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</data>
</root>
