<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 3-5-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;The two main challenges in terms of computing the SDG 3.5.1 indicator are the limited availability of household surveys on substance use and the under-reporting of use among survey respondents. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data reported from household surveys are one of the sources of information on of the number of people with substance use disorders. There are issues of under-reporting for certain psychoactive substances, in countries where stigma is associated to substance use and when a considerable proportion of the drug or alcohol using population is institutionalized, homeless or unreachable by population-based surveys. Additionally, being a relatively rare event, household surveys on substance use disorders require a large sample and can be costly. In order to address these issues, additional approaches (e.g. scale up methods) are increasingly used in household surveys to address undercount issues. These can be used in conjunction with special studies and/or additional information, in order to obtain reasonable estimates via indirect methods, such as benchmark/multiplier or capture-recapture methods. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An additional step in data validation and country capacity building for monitoring treatment coverage for substance use disorders will be implemented during the next couple of years for in-depth data generation in a sample of countries from different regions and representing different levels of health system development. A rapid assessment tool for in-depth data generation is in the process of development by WHO. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator stresses on type, availability and coverage of services but does not necessarily provide information on the actual quality of the interventions/services provided. To address this, at national level, the proposed treatment indicator will be accompanied with contextual information on availability coverage, i.e. treatment capacity for substance use disorders to provide additional information for interpretation of the contact coverage data. &lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
