<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 8-a-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aid for Trade commitments and disbursements is the gross disbursements and commitments of total Official Development Assistance (ODA) from all donors for aid for trade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DAC defines Official Development Assistance (ODA) as &amp;#x201C;those flows to countries and territories on the DAC List of ODA Recipients and to multilateral institutions which are i) provided by official agencies, including state and local governments, or by their executive agencies; and ii) each transaction is administered with the promotion of the economic development and welfare of developing countries as its main objective; and is concessional in character and conveys a grant element of at least 25 per cent (calculated at a rate of discount of 10 per cent). (See http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other official flows (OOF),excluding officially supported export credits, are defined as transactions by the official sector which do not meet the conditions for eligibility as ODA, either because they are not primarily aimed at development, or because they are not sufficiently concessional. See http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/documentupload/DCDDAC(2016)3FINAL.pdf, Para 24. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aid for Trade is captured in the CRS through sector codes in the 331 series and the aid for trade marker. see here: http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/purposecodessectorclassification.htm. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2018;All donors&amp;#x2019; refers to DAC donors, non-DAC donors and multilateral organisations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
