<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 15-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator Coverage by protected areas of important sites for mountain biodiversity shows temporal trends in the mean percentage of each important site for mountain biodiversity (i.e., those that contribute significantly to the global persistence of biodiversity) that is covered by designated protected areas and Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures (OECMs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protected areas, as defined by the IUCN (IUCN; Dudley 2008), are clearly defined geographical spaces, recognized, dedicated and managed, through legal or other effective means, to achieve the long-term conservation of nature with associated ecosystem services and cultural values. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Este indicador Cobertura por áreas protegidas de los lugares importantes para la biodiversidad de las montañas muestra las tendencias temporales del porcentaje medio de cada lugar importante para la biodiversidad de las montañas (es decir, aquellos que contribuyen significativamente a la persistencia global de la biodiversidad) que está cubierto por áreas protegidas designadas.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Этот показатель &quot;Доля охраняемых районов среди важных для горного биоразнообразия участков&quot; отражает временные тенденции в средней процентной доле каждого важного для горного биоразнообразия участка (т. е. вносящих значительный вклад в глобальное сохранение биоразнообразия), который покрывается уполномоченными охраняемыми территориями. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
