<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 3-4-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h1&gt;Data availability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around 70 countries currently provide WHO with regular high-quality data on mortality by age, sex and causes of death, and another 40 countries submit data of lower quality. However, comprehensive cause-of-death estimates are calculated by WHO systematically for all of its Member States (with a certain population threshold) every 3 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sex, age group&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En la actualidad, unos 70 países proporcionan a la OMS datos regulares de alta calidad sobre la mortalidad por edad, sexo y causas de muerte, y otros 40 países presentan datos de menor calidad. Sin embargo, la OMS calcula sistemáticamente estimaciones exhaustivas de las causas de muerte para todos sus Estados miembros (con un determinado umbral de población) cada 3 años.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sexo, grupo de edad&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilité des données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environ 70 pays fournissent actuellement à l&apos;OMS des données régulières de qualité sur la mortalité par âge, sexe et causes de décès, et 40 autres pays soumettent des données de moindre qualité. Cependant, des estimations complètes des causes de décès sont calculées par l&apos;OMS de manière systématique pour tous ses États membres (avec un certain seuil de population) tous les 3 ans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Désagrégation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sexe, tranche d&apos;âge &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Около 70 стран в настоящее время предоставляют в ВОЗ регулярные высококачественные данные по смертности в разбивке по возрасту, полу и причинам смерти, а еще 40 стран представляют данные более низкого качества. Тем не менее, всеобъемлющие оценки причин смерти рассчитываются ВОЗ систематически для всех ее государств-членов (с определенным пороговым значением численности населения) каждые 3 года. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; По полу, возрастным группам &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
