<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 3-4-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments and limitations&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complete recording of suicide deaths in death-registration systems requires good linkages with coronial and police systems, but can be seriously impeded by stigma, social and legal considerations, and delays in determining cause of death. Less than one half of WHO Member States have well-functioning death-registration systems that record causes of death.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El registro completo de las muertes por suicidio en los sistemas de registro de defunciones requiere una buena conexión con los sistemas forenses y policiales, pero puede verse seriamente obstaculizado por el estigma, las consideraciones sociales y jurídicas y los retrasos en la determinación de la causa de muerte. Menos de la mitad de los Estados miembros de la OMS cuentan con sistemas de registro de defunciones que funcionan bien y registran las causas de la muerte.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commentaires et limitations &lt;/strong&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;enregistrement complet des décès par suicide dans les systèmes d&apos;enregistrement des décès nécessite de bonnes liaisons avec les systèmes coronaux et policiers, mais peut être sérieusement entravé par la stigmatisation, les considérations sociales et juridiques, et les retards dans la détermination de la cause du décès. Moins de la moitié des États membres de l&apos;OMS disposent de systèmes d&apos;enregistrement des décès qui fonctionnent bien et qui enregistrent les causes de décès.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Комментарии и ограничения&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Полная регистрация самоубийств в системах регистрации смертей требует хороших связей с корональной и полицейской системами, но ей могут серьезно препятствовать стигматизация, социальные и правовые соображения и задержки в определении причин смерти. Менее половины государств-членов ВОЗ имеют хорошо функционирующие системы регистрации смерти, фиксирующие причины смерти.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
