<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The CLASS_SYSTEM field for indicator 5-2-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The &amp;#x2018;gold standard&amp;#x2019; and operational definitions applied to the generation of the 2018 global, regional and national estimates for intimate partner violence against women (WHO, 2021) reference the UN Guidelines for Producing Statistics on Violence against Women(UN, 2014) and the UNODC International Classification of Crime for Statistical Purposes ICCS (UNODC, 2015. These international standards on measurement and reporting include &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;standardized definitions of physical, sexual, and psychological IPV against women;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; measurement of these forms of violence using acts-based questions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Appropriate sample size &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;disaggregation by age groups&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;application of the appropriate denominator/target population (ever-partnered women)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reporting by type of perpetrator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;comprehensive interviewer training to administer violence against women questions, and following internationally agreed ethical and safety guidelines, including on privacy, confidentiality and support service information. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Survey measurement, should be guided by these international standards and documentation should report on all of the above to allow for an overall assessment of data quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, to date, individual studies and surveys use different measures, methodologies and reporting standards. This makes it challenging to compare the prevalence across studies and requires the use of adjusted estimates for international comparability (see section 4b).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;La « norme or » appliquée à la production de données et d’estimations fait référence aux documents (en anglais) « Guidelines for Producing Statistics on Violence against Women- Statistical Surveys » (NU, 2014) et « International Classification of Crime for Statistical Purposes ICCS » (ONUDC, 2015), et aux définitions opérationnelles de « Violence against Women Prevalence Estimates, 2018. Global, regional and national prevalence estimates for intimate partner violence against women and global and regional prevalence estimates for non-partner sexual violence against women » (OMS, 2021). Ces normes internationales sur la mesure et l’établissement de rapports comprennent : des définitions complètes et normalisées de la violence physique, sexuelle et psychologique à l’égard des femmes entre partenaires intimes, la mesure de ces formes de violence à l’aide de questions fondées sur les actes, la taille de l’échantillon, la désagrégation par groupe d’âge, l’application du dénominateur approprié ou de la population cible (femmes toujours en couple), la classification et le signalement par type d’agresseur, une formation complète des intervieweurs pour bien poser les questions reliées à la violence à l&apos;égard des femmes et en respectant les directives éthiques et de sécurité convenues à l’échelle internationale, y compris en ce qui concerne la protection de la vie privée, la confidentialité et l’information sur les services de soutien. La documentation de l’enquête devrait donc permettre d’évaluer la qualité globale des données. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cependant, les études et les enquêtes individuelles utilisent des mesures et des méthodologies différentes, ce qui rend difficile la comparaison de la prévalence de la violence entre partenaires intimes entre les études et nécessite l’utilisation d’estimations ajustées pour la comparabilité internationale (voir la section 4b). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
