<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The QUALITY_ASSURE field for indicator 5-2-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The Interagency Working Group on Violence against Women Data, which comprises all custodian agencies for this SDG indicator, thoroughly reviews all country data, including its primary source when deemed necessary, to assess quality and comparability based on exclusion/inclusion criteria agreed upon a priori. These criteria refer to, inter-alia, survey population coverage, operational definitions, methodology, and period. All data points have been discussed and a consensual decision made for every data point included/excluded from the current SDG Indicators Database. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2020, a country consultation and validation process of data compiled by custodian agencies for this indicator was undertaken, including with identified SDG indicators focal points and focal points in other relevant ministries. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Le Groupe de travail interinstitutions sur les données sur la violence à l’égard des femmes, qui comprend tous les organismes dépositaires de cet indicateur des ODD, examine minutieusement toutes les données nationales, y compris leur source principale lorsque cela est jugé nécessaire, afin d’évaluer la qualité et la comparabilité sur la base de critères d’exclusion/inclusion convenus a priori. Ces critères se réfèrent, entre autres, à la couverture de la population de l’enquête, aux définitions opérationnelles, à la méthodologie et à la période. Tous les points de données ont été discutés et une décision consensuelle a été prise pour chaque point de données inclus/exclu de la base de données actuelle sur les indicateurs des ODD. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En 2020, un processus national de consultation et de validation des données compilées par les organismes dépositaires de cet indicateur a été entrepris, y compris avec les points focaux identifiés pour les indicateurs des ODD et les points focaux dans d’autres ministères concernés. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
