<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 5-2-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The SDG 5.2.1 Indicator Database comprises data from population-based household surveys representative at the national and/or sub-national level and implementing a methodology that uses act-based questions. All sources date from 2000 to 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A significant proportion of data from low- and middle-income countries are obtained from the Domestic Violence Module of the Demographic and Health Surveys (DHS). Some data come from dedicated surveys on violence against women in countries that have implemented, for example, WHO&amp;#x2019;s violence against women survey methodology or other methodologies consistent with international guidelines and best practices. In the case of higher-income countries, data were obtained from Crime Victimisation Surveys (CVS) or dedicated surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;La base de données de l&apos;indicateur 5.2.1 des ODD comprend des données provenant d&apos;enquêtes auprès des ménages basées sur la population représentatives au niveau national et/ou infranational et mettant en œuvre une méthodologie qui utilise des questions basées sur des actes. Toutes les sources datent de 2000 à 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Une part importante des données des les pays à faible ou à moyen revenu, est obtenue à partir du module sur la violence domestique, des enquêtes démographiques et de santé (EDS). Certaines données proviennent d&apos;enquêtes dédiées à la violence à l&apos;égard des femmes dans des pays qui ont mis en œuvre, par exemple, la méthodologie d&apos;enquête de l&apos;OMS sur la violence à l&apos;égard des femmes ou d&apos;autres méthodologies conformes aux directives et meilleures pratiques internationales. Dans le cas des pays à revenu élevé, des données ont été obtenues à partir d&apos;enquêtes sur les victimes d&apos;actes criminels (EVC) ou d&apos;enquêtes spécialisées.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
