<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 5-a-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;If a country adopts the strategy of interviewing one randomly selected eligible respondent per agricultural household, this may result in a small sample size. Countries are recommended to take into consideration the impact on the expected sample size on the precision of the estimates. If necessary, countries may consider interviewing more than one eligible respondent per agricultural household, or all eligible respondents. Alternatively, countries may consider collecting information on all eligible respondents through a proxy respondent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is critical that the list of legally binding documents proposed above is customized in order to consider only documents that are enforceable before the law and that guarantee individual&amp;#x2019;s tenure rights in the national context. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Si un pays adopte la stratégie consistant à interroger un répondant éligible sélectionné au hasard par ménage agricole, cela peut se traduire par une petite taille d’échantillon. Il est recommandé aux pays de prendre en considération l’impact sur la taille attendue de l’échantillon sur la précision des estimations. Si nécessaire, les pays peuvent envisager d’interroger plus d’un répondant éligible par ménage agricole, ou tous les répondants éligibles. Alternativement, les pays peuvent envisager de recueillir des informations sur tous les répondants éligibles par l’intermédiaire d’un répondant substitut (proxy). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il est essentiel que la liste des documents juridiquement contraignants proposée ci-dessus soit personnalisée afin de ne prendre en compte que les documents qui sont exécutoires devant la loi et qui garantissent les droits fonciers des individus dans le contexte national. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
