<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 5-a-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;One recommendation is for countries to take into consideration the impact of the expected sample size on the precision of the estimates. One way of attaining a large enough sample size is to consider collecting information on all eligible respondents through a proxy respondent, as this can be relatively easily done using the household rosters in the surveys. However, it is important to keep in mind that when a proxy respondent provides the information for the member of the household, it is likely that some bias or response errors are introduced &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is critical that the list of legally binding documents of ownership proposed to be included in questions relating to proxy 1 in this document are customized to consider only documents that are enforceable before the law and that guarantee individual&amp;#x2019;s rights in the national context. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Si un pays adopte la stratégie consistant à interroger un répondant éligible sélectionné au hasard par ménage agricole, cela peut se traduire par une petite taille d’échantillon. Il est recommandé aux pays de prendre en considération l’impact sur la taille attendue de l’échantillon sur la précision des estimations. Si nécessaire, les pays peuvent envisager d’interroger plus d’un répondant éligible par ménage agricole, ou tous les répondants éligibles. Alternativement, les pays peuvent envisager de recueillir des informations sur tous les répondants éligibles par l’intermédiaire d’un répondant substitut ou par procuration (proxy). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il est essentiel que la liste des documents juridiquement contraignants proposée ci-dessus soit personnalisée afin de ne prendre en compte que les documents qui sont exécutoires devant la loi et qui garantissent les droits fonciers des individus dans le contexte national. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
