<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The DATA_COMP field for indicator 15-5-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computation method:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Red List Index is calculated at a point in time by first multiplying the number of species in each Red List Category by a weight (ranging from 1 for &amp;#x2018;Near Threatened&amp;#x2019; to 5 for &amp;#x2018;Extinct&amp;#x2019; and &amp;#x2018;Extinct in the Wild&amp;#x2019;) and summing these values. This is then divided by a maximum threat score which is the total number of species multiplied by the weight assigned to the &amp;#x2018;Extinct&amp;#x2019; category. This final value is subtracted from 1 to give the Red List Index value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathematically this calculation is expressed as: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RLIt = 1 &amp;#x2013; [(Ss Wc(t,s) / (WEX * N)]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where Wc(t,s) is the weight for category (c) at time (t) for species (s) (the weight for &amp;#x2018;Critically Endangered&amp;#x2019; = 4, &amp;#x2018;Endangered&amp;#x2019; = 3, &amp;#x2018;Vulnerable&amp;#x2019; = 2, &amp;#x2018;Near Threatened&amp;#x2019; = 1, &amp;#x2018;Least Concern&amp;#x2019; = 0. &amp;#x2018;Critically Endangered&amp;#x2019; species tagged as &amp;#x2018;Possibly Extinct&amp;#x2019; or &amp;#x2018;Possibly Extinct in the Wild&amp;#x2019; are assigned a weight of 5); WEX = 5, the weight assigned to &amp;#x2018;Extinct&amp;#x2019; or &amp;#x2018;Extinct in the Wild&amp;#x2019; species; and N is the total number of assessed species, excluding those assessed as Data Deficient in the current time period, and those considered to be &amp;#x2018;Extinct&amp;#x2019; in the year the set of species was first assessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The formula requires that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exactly the same set of species is included in all time periods, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The only Red List Category changes are those resulting from genuine improvement or deterioration in status (i.e., excluding changes resulting from improved knowledge or taxonomic revisions), and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Deficient species are excluded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many cases, species lists will change slightly from one assessment to the next (e.g., owing to taxonomic revisions). The conditions can therefore be met by retrospectively adjusting earlier Red List categorizations using current information and taxonomy. This is achieved by assuming that the current Red List Categories for the taxa have applied since the set of species was first assessed for the Red List, unless there is information to the contrary that genuine status changes have occurred. Such information is often contextual (e.g., relating to the known history of habitat loss within the range of the species). If there is insufficient information available for a newly added species, it is not incorporated into the Red List Index until it is assessed for a second time, at which point earlier assessments are retrospectively corrected by extrapolating recent trends in population, range, habitat and threats, supported by additional information. To avoid spurious results from biased selection of species, Red List Indices are typically calculated only for taxonomic groups in which all species worldwide have been assessed for the Red List, or for samples of species that have been systematically or randomly selected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The methods and scientific basis for the Red List Index were described by Butchart et al. (2004, 2005, 2007, 2010). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Butchart et al. (2010) also described the methods by which Red List Indices for different taxonomic groups are aggregated to produce a single multi-taxon Red List Index. Specifically, aggregated Red List Indices are calculated as the arithmetic mean of modelled Red List Indices. Red List Indices for each taxonomic group are interpolated linearly for years between data points and extrapolated linearly (with a slope equal to that between the two closest assessed points) to align them with years for which Red List Indices for other taxa are available. The Red List Indices for each taxonomic group for each year are modelled to take into account various sources of uncertainty: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Deficiency: Red List categories (from Least Concern to Extinct) are assigned to all Data Deficient species, with a probability proportional to the number of species in non-Data Deficient categories for that taxonomic group; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extrapolation uncertainty: although RLIs were extrapolated linearly based on the slope of the closest two assessed point, there is uncertainty about how accurate this slope may be. To incorporate this uncertainty, rather than extrapolating deterministically, the slope used for extrapolation is selected from a normal distribution with a probability equal to the slope of the closest two assessed points, and standard deviation equal to 60% of this slope (i.e., the CV is 60%); &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Temporal variability: the &amp;#x2018;true&amp;#x2019; Red List Index likely changes from year to year, but because assessments are repeated only at multi-year intervals, the precise value for any particular year is uncertain. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make this uncertainty explicit, the Red List Index value for a given taxonomic group in a given year is assigned from a moving window of five years, centred on the focal year (with the window set as 3-4 years for the first two and last two years in the series). Note that assessment uncertainty cannot yet be incorporated into the index. Practically, these uncertainties are incorporated into the aggregated Red List Indices as follows: Data Deficient species were allotted a category as described above, and a Red List Index for each taxonomic group was calculated interpolating and extrapolating as described above. A final Red List Index value was assigned to each taxonomic group for each year from a window of years as described above. Each such &amp;#x2018;run&amp;#x2019; produced a Red List Index for the complete time period for each taxonomic group, incorporating the various sources of uncertainty. Ten thousand such runs are generated for each taxonomic group, and the mean is calculated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods for generating national disaggregations of the Red List Index are described below.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
