<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The SOURCE_TYPE field for indicator 6-a-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;The UN-Water Global Analysis and Assessment of Sanitation and Drinking-Water (GLAAS) provides information on governance, monitoring, human resources, and financing in the water, sanitation, and hygiene (WASH) sector. The UN-Water GLAAS survey is currently conducted on a biennial basis, led by WHO, and collected data from 94 countries (predominantly low and lower-middle income countries) in the most recent cycle in 2013-2014. The scope of the question on external funding has been expanded beyond WASH for the 2016-17 GLAAS cycle to include wastewater and water quality, water efficiency, water resource management, and the status of water-related ecosystems. GLAAS has completed three full cycles (2009-2010, 2011-2012, and 2013-2014), as well as a pilot conducted in 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National governments participating in the GLAAS survey fill out the questionnaire, preferably supported by a multi-stakeholder review. Although one ministry leads the process, it is often the case that many different ministries and departments must be involved in the process in order to obtain the data required to complete the questionnaire. A GLAAS national focal person supports the lead ministry to coordinate data collection, to compile the national response to the questionnaire, and to lead on the process of data validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OECD Development Assistance Committee (DAC) has been collecting data on aid flows since 1973 through the OECD Creditor Reporting System based on a standard methodology and agreed definitions from member countries and other aid providers. The data are generally obtained on an activity level, and include numerous parameters to allow disaggregation by provider and recipient country, by type of finance, and by type of resources provided. Data are available for essentially all high-income countries as bilateral donors, and for an increasing number of middle-income aid providers, as well as multi-lateral lending institutions. Methodology on ODA data collection by OECD can be found here: http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data will be complemented by Integrated Water Resources Management (IWRM) reporting in SDG target 6.5 (for wastewater and water quality, water efficiency, water resource management, and the status of water-related ecosystems) (UNEP 2016). The analysis of IWRM has been done in the past by UN-Water in 2008 (led by UN-DESA) and in 2012 (led by UNEP, UNDP, GWP and SIWI) as requested by the UN Commission for Sustainable Development (UN-Water 2008, 2012).&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
