<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 12-3-1a, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the absence of food loss data at the country-commodity level, FAO developed a loss imputation model to estimate losses of all countries and commodities and compile the Food Loss Index for SDG regions and commodity groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The model builds on loss data provided by the countries to the FAO within the annual Agriculture Production Questionnaires, loss factors available in the scientific literature published in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/platform-food-loss-waste/flw-data/en/&quot;&gt;FLW database&lt;/a&gt; and from case studies, and a set of 200+ explanatory variables. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The model is a fixed effect model that selects the explanatory variables with a random forest algorithm. Where there is no information at all for a country-commodity combination, the model is applied to a cluster of commodities and the countries&amp;#x2019; estimated loss percentages will be equal to the cluster&amp;#x2019;s at global level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When loss data is insufficient to estimate even one country-commodity combination, the countries&amp;#x2019; estimated loss percentages will be equal to the cluster&amp;#x2019;s at global level for all the ten commodities in that country basket.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Au niveau des pays&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En l&apos;absence de données sur les pertes alimentaires au niveau des pays et des produits, la FAO a mis au point un modèle d&apos;imputation des pertes pour estimer les pertes de tous les pays et produits et compiler l&apos;indice de pertes alimentaires pour les régions SDG et les groupes de produits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/platform-food-loss-waste/flw-data/en/&quot;&gt;Le modèle s&apos;appuie sur les données relatives aux pertes fournies par les pays à la FAO dans le cadre des questionnaires annuels sur la production agricole, sur les facteurs de perte disponibles dans la littérature scientifique publiée dans la base de données FLW&lt;/a&gt; et dans des études de cas, ainsi que sur un ensemble de plus de 200 variables explicatives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le modèle est un modèle à effet fixe qui sélectionne les variables explicatives à l&apos;aide d&apos;un algorithme de forêt aléatoire. Lorsqu&apos;il n&apos;existe aucune information pour une combinaison pays/produit, le modèle est appliqué à un groupe de produits et les pourcentages de perte estimés pour les pays&amp;#x2019; seront égaux à ceux du groupe&amp;#x2019;au niveau mondial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aux niveaux régional et mondial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lorsque les données sur les pertes sont insuffisantes pour estimer ne serait-ce qu&apos;une seule combinaison pays/produit, les pourcentages de pertes estimés pour les pays&amp;#x2019; seront égaux au groupe&amp;#x2019;au niveau mondial pour les dix produits du panier de ce pays.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
