<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 15-5-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Red List Index has been classified by the IAEG-SDGs as Tier 1. Current data are available for all countries in the world, and these are updated annually. Index values for each country are available in the UN SDG Indicators Database &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/sdgs/indicators/database/&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/sdgs/indicators/database/&lt;/a&gt;. Red List Index graphs and underlying index data are available for each country, SDG regions, IPBES region, CMS region and various thematic disaggregations at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iucnredlist.org/search&quot;&gt;https://www.iucnredlist.org/search&lt;/a&gt;. Red List Index graphs are also available for each country in the BIP Indicators Dashboard (&lt;a href=&quot;https://bipdashboard.natureserve.org/bip/SelectCountry.html&quot;&gt;https://bipdashboard.natureserve.org/bip/SelectCountry.html&lt;/a&gt;), the Integrated Biodiversity Assessment Tool Country Profiles (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ibat-alliance.org/country_profiles&quot;&gt;https://ibat-alliance.org/country_profiles&lt;/a&gt;), and (for birds) on the BirdLife International Data Zone (http://datazone.birdlife.org/species/dashboard).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Red List Index can be downscaled to show national and regional Red List Indices, weighted by the fraction of each species&amp;#x2019; distribution occurring within the country or region, building on the method published by Rodrigues et al. (2014) PLoS ONE 9(11): e113934. These show an index of how well species are conserved in a country or region to its potential contribution to global species conservation (for the taxonomic groups of species included). The index is calculated as: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;L&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;msub&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;I&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mfenced separators=&quot;|&quot;&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;,&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/mfenced&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/msub&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;1&lt;/mn&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;-&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;&amp;#x3A3;&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
        &lt;mfenced separators=&quot;|&quot;&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;msub&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;W&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mfenced separators=&quot;|&quot;&gt;
                  &lt;mrow&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
                    &lt;mo&gt;,&lt;/mo&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
                  &lt;/mrow&gt;
                &lt;/mfenced&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/msub&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;*&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mfenced separators=&quot;|&quot;&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mfrac&gt;
                  &lt;mrow&gt;
                    &lt;msub&gt;
                      &lt;mrow&gt;
                        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
                      &lt;/mrow&gt;
                      &lt;mrow&gt;
                        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
                        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
                      &lt;/mrow&gt;
                    &lt;/msub&gt;
                  &lt;/mrow&gt;
                  &lt;mrow&gt;
                    &lt;msub&gt;
                      &lt;mrow&gt;
                        &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
                      &lt;/mrow&gt;
                      &lt;mrow&gt;
                        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
                      &lt;/mrow&gt;
                    &lt;/msub&gt;
                  &lt;/mrow&gt;
                &lt;/mfrac&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/mfenced&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/mfenced&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;W&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;E&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;X&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;*&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;&amp;#x3A3;&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
        &lt;mfenced separators=&quot;|&quot;&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mfrac&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;msub&gt;
                  &lt;mrow&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
                  &lt;/mrow&gt;
                  &lt;mrow&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
                  &lt;/mrow&gt;
                &lt;/msub&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;msub&gt;
                  &lt;mrow&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
                  &lt;/mrow&gt;
                  &lt;mrow&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
                  &lt;/mrow&gt;
                &lt;/msub&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/mfrac&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/mfenced&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where t is the year of comprehensive reassessment, u is the spatial unit (i.e. country), W_((t,s)) is the weight of the global Red List category for species s at time t (Least Concern =0, Near Threatened =1, Vulnerable =2, Endangered =3, Critically Endangered =4, Critically Endangered (Possibly Extinct) =5, Critically Endangered (Possibly Extinct in the Wild) =5, Extinct in the Wild =5 and Extinct =5), WEX = 5 is the weight for Extinct species, r_su is the fraction of the total range of species s in unit u, and R_s is the total range size of species s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The index varies from 1 if the country has contributed the minimum it can to the global RLI (i.e., if the numerator is 0 because all species in the country are Least Concern) to 0 if the country has contributed the maximum it can to the global RLI (i.e., if the numerator equals the denominator because all species in the country are Extinct or Possibly Extinct). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The taxonomic groups included are those in which all species have been assessed for the IUCN Red List more than once. Red List categories for years in which comprehensive assessments (i.e. those in which all species in the taxonomic group have been assessed) were carried out are determined following the approach of Butchart et al. 2007; PLoS ONE 2(1): e140, i.e. they match the current categories except for those taxa that have undergone genuine improvement or deterioration in extinction risk of sufficient magnitude to qualify for a higher or lower Red List category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator can also be disaggregated by ecosystems, habitats, and other political and geographic divisions (e.g., Han et al. 2014), by taxonomic subsets (e.g., Hoffmann et al. 2011), by suites of species relevant to particular international treaties or legislation (e.g., Croxall et al. 2012), by suites of species exposed to particular threatening processes (e.g., Butchart 2008), and by suites of species that deliver particular ecosystem services, or have particular biological or life-history traits (e.g., Regan et al. 2015). In each case, information can be obtained from The IUCN Red List of Threatened Species to determine which species are relevant to particular subsets (e.g., which occur in particular ecosystems, habitats, and geographic areas of interest). These disaggregations are available on the IUCN Red List website at https://www.iucnredlist.org/search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disaggregations of the Red List Index are also of particular relevance as indicators towards the following SDG targets (Brooks et al. 2015): SDG 2.4 Red List Index (species used for food and medicine); SDG 2.5 Red List Index (wild relatives and local breeds); SDG 12.2 Red List Index (impacts of utilisation) (Butchart 2008); SDG 12.4 Red List Index (impacts of pollution); SDG 13.1 Red List Index (impacts of climate change); SDG 14.1 Red List Index (impacts of pollution on marine species); SDG 14.2 Red List Index (marine species); SDG 14.3 Red List Index (reef-building coral species) (Carpenter et al. 2008); SDG 14.4 Red List Index (impacts of utilisation on marine species); SDG 15.1 Red List Index (terrestrial &amp;amp; freshwater species); SDG 15.2 Red List Index (forest-specialist species); SDG 15.4 Red List Index (mountain species); SDG 15.7 Red List Index (impacts of utilisation) (Butchart 2008); and SDG 15.8 Red List Index (impacts of invasive alien species) (Butchart 2008, McGeoch et al. 2010).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El Índice de la Lista Roja ha sido clasificado por el IAEG-SDG como Nivel 1. Se dispone de datos actuales para todos los países del mundo, que se actualizan periódicamente (aproximadamente una vez cada cuatro años).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desde 1980 (aproximadamente 35 años). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El Índice de la Lista Roja puede reducirse para mostrar los Índices de la Lista Roja nacionales y regionales, ponderados por la fracción de la distribución de cada especie que se da en el país o región, basándose en el método publicado por Rodrigues et al. (2014) PLoS ONE 9(11): e113934. Estos muestran un índice de probabilidad de supervivencia agregada (el inverso del riesgo de extinción) para todas las aves, mamíferos, anfibios, corales y cícadas que se dan en el país o región. El índice muestra el grado de conservación de las especies en un país o región en relación con su contribución potencial a la conservación global de las especies. El índice se calcula como: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RLI(t,u) = 1 &amp;#x2013; [(Ss(W(t,s) * (rsu/Rs)) / (WEX * Ss (rsu/Rs))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;donde t es el año de la reevaluación global, u es la unidad espacial (es decir país), W_((t,s)) es la ponderación de la categoría global de la Lista Roja para la especie s en el momento t (Preocupación mínima =0, Casi amenazada =1, Vulnerable =2, En peligro =3, En peligro crítico =4, En peligro crítico (posiblemente extinto) =5, En Peligro Crítico (Posiblemente Extinto en Estado Silvestre) =5, Extinto en Estado Silvestre =5 y Extinto =5), WEX = 5 es la ponderación de las especies Extintas, r_su es la fracción del área de distribución total de la especie s en la unidad u, y R_s es el tamaño total del área de distribución de la especie s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El índice varía de 1 si el país ha contribuido lo mínimo que puede al ILR global (es decir, si el numerador es 0 porque todas las especies en el país son LC) a 0 si el país ha contribuido lo máximo que puede al ILR global (es decir, si el numerador es igual al denominador porque todas las especies en el país están Extintas o Posiblemente Extintas). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los grupos taxonómicos incluidos son aquellos en los que todas las especies han sido evaluadas para la Lista Roja de la UICN más de una vez. Las categorías de la Lista Roja correspondientes a los años en los que se han realizado evaluaciones completas (es decir, aquellas en las que se han evaluado todas las especies del grupo taxonómico) se determinan siguiendo el enfoque de Butchart et al. 2007; PLoS ONE 2(1): e140, es decir, coinciden con las categorías actuales, excepto en el caso de aquellos taxones que han experimentado una auténtica mejora o deterioro del riesgo de extinción de magnitud suficiente como para optar a una categoría de la Lista Roja superior o inferior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador también se puede desglosar por ecosistemas, hábitats y otras divisiones políticas y geográficas (p. ej., Han et al. 2014), por subconjuntos taxonómicos (p. ej., Hoffmann et al. 2011), por conjuntos de especies relevantes para determinados tratados internacionales o legislación (p. ej, Croxall et al. 2012), por conjuntos de especies expuestas a determinados procesos de amenaza (p. ej., Butchart 2008) y por conjuntos de especies que prestan determinados servicios ecosistémicos o tienen determinados rasgos biológicos o vitales (p. ej., Regan et al. 2015). En cada caso, se puede obtener información de la Lista Roja de Especies Amenazadas de la UICN para determinar qué especies son relevantes para determinados subconjuntos (por ejemplo, las que se dan en determinados ecosistemas, hábitats y áreas geográficas de interés).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los desgloses del Índice de la Lista Roja también son de especial relevancia como indicadores para las siguientes metas de los ODS (Brooks et al. 2015): ODS 2.4 Índice de la Lista Roja (especies utilizadas para la alimentación y la medicina); ODS 2.5 Índice de la Lista Roja (parientes silvestres y razas locales); ODS 12.2 Índice de la Lista Roja (impactos de la utilización) (Butchart 2008); ODS 12.4 Índice de la Lista Roja (impactos de la contaminación); ODS 13.1 Índice de la Lista Roja (impactos del cambio climático); ODS 14.1 Índice de la Lista Roja (impactos de la contaminación en las especies marinas); ODS 14.2 Índice de la Lista Roja (especies marinas); ODS 14.3 Índice de la Lista Roja (especies de coral constructoras de arrecifes) (Carpenter et al. 2008); ODS 14.4 Índice de la Lista Roja (impactos de la utilización sobre las especies marinas) &amp;#x2013; un Grupo de Expertos Técnicos ad hoc FAO-UICN está trabajando actualmente para desarrollar recomendaciones acordadas sobre el uso y la interpretación de este indicador; ODS 15.1 Índice de la Lista Roja (especies terrestres y de agua dulce); ODS 15.2 Índice de la Lista Roja (especies forestales); ODS 15.4 Índice de la Lista Roja (especies de montaña); ODS 15.7 Índice de la Lista Roja (impactos de la utilización) (Butchart 2008); y ODS 15.8 Índice de la Lista Roja (impactos de las especies exóticas invasoras) (Butchart 2008, McGeoch et al. 2010).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Индекс Красной книги был классифицирован Межучрежденческой и экспертной группой по показателям достижения целей в области устойчивого развития (МЭГ-ЦУР) как Уровень 1. Текущие данные доступны по всем странам мира и обновляются на регулярной основе (примерно раз в четыре года). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; С 1980 года (примерно 35 лет). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Масштабность Индекса Красной книги может быть уменьшена для отображения национальных и региональных Индексов Красной книги, взвешенных на долю распространения каждого вида, находящегося в пределах страны или региона, основываясь на методе, опубликованном Rodrigues et al. (2014) PLoS ONE 9 (11): e113934. Они отражают индекс совокупной вероятности выживания (обратный риску исчезновения) для всех птиц, млекопитающих, амфибий, кораллов и саговников, встречающихся в стране или регионе. Индекс показывает, насколько хорошо виды сохраняются в стране или регионе по отношению к потенциальному вкладу в глобальное сохранение видов. Индекс рассчитывается как: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; RLI (t, u) = 1 &amp;#x2013; [(Ss (W (t, s) * (rsu / Rs)) / (WEX * Ss (rsu / RS)) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; где t - год всесторонней переоценки, u - пространственная единица (т.е. страна), W _ ((t, s)) - вес глобальной категории Красной книги для видов s в момент времени t (&quot;Находятся под наименьшей угрозой&quot; = 0 , &quot;Близки к уязвимому положению&quot; = 1, &quot;В уязвимом положении&quot; = 2,&quot; В опасности&quot; = 3, &quot;В критической опасности&quot; = 4, &quot;В критической опасности (возможно исчезнувшие)&quot; = 5, &quot;В критической опасности (возможно исчезнувшие в дикой природе)&quot; = 5, &quot;Исчезнувшие в дикой природе&quot; = 5 и &quot;Исчезнувший вид&quot; = 5 ), WEX = 5 - это вес исчезнувших видов, r_su - это доля от общего ареала видов s в единице u, а R_s - общий размер ареала видов s. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Индекс изменяется от 1, если страна внесла минимальный вклад в глобальный Индекс Красной книги (т. е. если числитель равен 0, поскольку все виды в стране являются находящимися под наименьшей угрозой) до 0, если страна внесла максимально возможный вклад в глобальный Индекс Красной книги (то есть, если числитель равен знаменателю, потому что все виды в стране считаются исчезнувшими или возможно исчезнувшими). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В таксономические группы включены виды, которые оценивались для включения в Красную книгу МСОП более одного раза. Категории Красной книги за годы, в которые проводились комплексные оценки (т. е. те, в которых были оценены все виды в таксономической группе), определяются в соответствии с подходом Butchart et al. 2007; PLoS ONE 2 (1): e140, т.е. они соответствуют текущим категориям, за исключением тех таксонов, которые подверглись действительному улучшению или ухудшению факторов риска исчезновения, достаточного для того, чтобы претендовать на более высокую или низкую категорию Красной книги.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Показатель также может быть дезагрегирован по экосистемам, средам обитания и другим политическим и географическим подразделениям (например, Han et al. 2014), по таксономическим подмножествам (например, Hoffmann et al. 2011), по группам видов, относящихся к конкретным международным договорам или законодательству (например, Croxall et al.2012), наборам видов, подверженных определенным угрожающим процессам (например, Butchart 2008), и наборам видов, которые предоставляют определенные экосистемные услуги или имеют определенные биологические или жизненные черты (например, Regan et al.2015). В каждом случае можно получить информацию из Красной книги МСОП угрожаемых видов, чтобы определить, какие виды относятся к определенным подмножествам (например, которые встречаются в определенных экосистемах, местообитаниях и географических районах, представляющих интерес). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Дезагрегирование Индекса Красной книги также имеет особое значение в качестве показателей для следующих задач ЦУР (Brooks et al. 2015): Индекс Красной книги ЦУР 2.4 (виды, используемые для производства продуктов питания и лекарств); Индекс Красной книги ЦУР 2.5 (дикие сородичи и местные породы); Индекс Красной книги ЦУР 12.2 (влияние использования) (Butchart 2008); Индекс Красной книги ЦУР 12.4 (воздействие загрязнения); Индекс Красной книги ЦУР 13.1 (последствия изменения климата); Индекс Красной книги ЦУР 14.1 (воздействие загрязнения на морские виды); Индекс Красной книги ЦУР 14.2 (морские виды); Индекс Красной книги ЦУР 14.3 (рифообразующие кораллы) (Карпентер и др., 2008); Индекс Красной книги ЦУР 14.4 (воздействие использования на морские виды); специальная совместная группа технических экспертов ФАО-МСОП в настоящее время работает над выработкой согласованных рекомендаций по использованию и интерпретации этого показателя; Индекс Красной книги ЦУР 15.1 (наземные и пресноводные виды); Индекс Красной книги ЦУР 15.2 (виды лесо-специалисты); Индекс Красной книги ЦУР 15.4 (горные виды); Индекс Красной книги ЦУР 15.7 (влияние использования) (Butchart 2008); и Индекс Красной книги ЦУР 15.8 (воздействие инвазивных чужеродных видов) (Butchart 2008, McGeoch et al. 2010). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
