<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REG_AGG field for indicator 15-5-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The Red List Categories and Criteria are applied for each species on The IUCN Red List of Threatened Species and are determined globally and provided principally by the Specialist Groups and stand-alone Red List Authorities of the IUCN Species Survival Commission, IUCN Secretariat-led initiatives, and Red List partner organizations. The staff of the IUCN Global Species Programme compile, validate, and curate these data, and are responsible for publishing and communicating the results. Each individual species assessment is supported by the application of metadata and documentation standards (IUCN 2013), including classifications of, for example, threats and conservation actions (Salafsky et al. 2008). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Red List assessments are undertaken through either open workshops or through open-access web-based discussion fora. Assessments are reviewed by the appropriate Red List Authority (an individual or organization appointed by the IUCN Species Survival Commission to review assessments for specific species or groups of species) to ensure standardisation and consistency in the interpretation of information and application of the criteria. A Red List Technical Working Group and the IUCN Red List Unit work to ensure consistent categorization between species, groups and assessments. Finally, a Standards and Petitions Sub-committee monitors the process and resolves challenges and disputes over Red List assessments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, IUCN publishes guidelines on applying the IUCN Red List Categories and Criteria at regional or national scales (IUCN 2012b). Based on these, many countries have initiated programmes to assess the extinction risk of species occurring within their borders. These countries will be able to implement the Red List Index based on national extinction risk, once they have carried out at least two national Red Lists using the IUCN system in a consistent way (Bubb et al. 2009). An increasing number of countries have now completed national Red List Indices for a range of taxa (e.g., G&amp;#xE4;rdenfors 2010, Pihl &amp;amp; Flensted 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While global Red List Indices can be disaggregated to show trends for species at smaller spatial scales, the reverse is not true. National or regional Red List Indices cannot be aggregated to produce Red List Indices showing global trends. This is because a taxon&amp;#x2019;s global extinction risk has to be evaluated at the global scale and cannot be directly determined from multiple national scale assessments across its range (although the data from such assessments can be aggregated for inclusion in the global assessment).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods for generating regional disaggregations of the Red List Index are described below in section 5 on Data availability and disaggregation.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las categorías y los criterios de la Lista Roja se aplican a cada una de las especies de la Lista Roja de Especies Amenazadas de la UICN y se determinan a nivel mundial y las proporcionan principalmente los Grupos Especialistas y las Autoridades independientes de la Lista Roja de la Comisión de Supervivencia de Especies de la UICN, las iniciativas dirigidas por la Secretaría de la UICN, la asociación BirdLife International y las demás organizaciones asociadas a la Lista Roja de la UICN. El personal del Programa Mundial de Especies de la UICN recopila, valida y conserva estos datos, y es responsable de publicar y comunicar los resultados. Cada evaluación individual de las especies se apoya en la aplicación de metadatos y normas de documentación (UICN 2013), incluyendo clasificaciones de, por ejemplo, amenazas y acciones de conservación (Salafsky et al. 2008). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las evaluaciones de la Lista Roja se realizan a través de talleres abiertos o de foros de debate de libre acceso en la web. Las evaluaciones son revisadas por la Autoridad de la Lista Roja correspondiente (una persona u organización designada por la Comisión de Supervivencia de Especies de la UICN para revisar las evaluaciones de especies o grupos de especies específicos) para garantizar la normalización y la coherencia en la interpretación de la información y la aplicación de los criterios. Un Grupo de Trabajo Técnico de la Lista Roja y la Unidad de la Lista Roja de la UICN trabajan para garantizar una categorización coherente entre especies, grupos y evaluaciones. Por último, un Subcomité de Normas y Peticiones supervisa el proceso y resuelve las impugnaciones y disputas sobre las evaluaciones de la Lista Roja.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Además, la UICN publica directrices sobre la aplicación de las categorías y criterios de la Lista Roja de la UICN a escala regional o nacional (UICN 2012b). Basándose en ellas, muchos países han iniciado programas para evaluar el riesgo de extinción de las especies que se encuentran dentro de sus fronteras. Estos países podrán aplicar el Índice de la Lista Roja basado en el riesgo de extinción nacional, una vez que hayan realizado al menos dos Listas Rojas nacionales utilizando el sistema de la UICN de forma coherente (Bubb et al. 2009). Un número cada vez mayor de países ha completado los Índices de la Lista Roja nacional para una serie de taxones (por ejemplo, G&amp;#xE4;rdenfors 2010, Pihl &amp;amp; Flensted 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mientras que los Índices de la Lista Roja globales pueden desglosarse para mostrar las tendencias de las especies a escalas espaciales más pequeñas, lo contrario no es cierto. Los Índices de la Lista Roja nacionales o regionales no pueden agregarse para producir Índices de la Lista Roja que muestren las tendencias globales. Esto se debe a que el riesgo de extinción global de un taxón debe evaluarse a escala global y no puede determinarse directamente a partir de múltiples evaluaciones a escala nacional en su área de distribución (aunque los datos de dichas evaluaciones pueden agregarse para incluirlos en la evaluación global).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Региональные агрегаты: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Категории и критерии Красной книги применяются для каждого вида из Красной книги МСОП видов, находящихся под угрозой исчезновения, и устанавливаются на глобальном уровне, а также предлагаются к использованию в основном группами специалистов и отдельными органами Комиссии Красной книги МСОП по выживанию видов, инициативными группами под руководством Секретариата МСОП, партнерством Международной ассоциации по защите птиц (BLI) и другими партнерскими организациями Красной книги МСОП. Сотрудники Глобальной программы МСОП по видам собирают, проверяют и обрабатывают эти данные, а также несут ответственность за публикацию и распространение результатов. Оценка каждого отдельного вида обеспечивается путем применения стандартов метаданных и документации (IUCN 2013), включая классификации, например, угроз и природоохранных мероприятий (Salafsky et al. 2008). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Оценка Красной книги проводится либо на открытых семинарах, либо на открытых дискуссионных форумах в Интернете. Оценки проверяются соответствующим органом Красной книги (лицо или организация, назначенные Комиссией МСОП по выживанию видов для проверки оценок по конкретным видам или группам видов) для обеспечения стандартизации и согласованности в интерпретации информации и применении критериев. Техническая рабочая группа по Красной книге и Группа Красной книги МСОП работают над обеспечением последовательной категоризации между видами, группами и оценками. Наконец, Подкомитет по стандартам и петициям контролирует процесс и решает проблемы и споры, связанные с оценками из Красной книги.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Кроме того, МСОП публикует рекомендации по применению категорий и критериев Красной книги МСОП в региональном или национальном масштабе (МСОП 2012b). Исходя из этого, многие страны инициировали программы по оценке риска исчезновения видов, встречающихся внутри их границ. Эти страны смогут применять Индекс Красной книги, рассчитанный на основе национального риска исчезновения после того, как они составят по крайней мере две национальных Красных книги с использованием системы МСОП согласованным образом (Bubb et al. 2009). Все большее число стран в настоящее время производят национальные Индексы Красной книги для ряда таксонов (например, G&amp;#xE4;rdenfors 2010, Pihl &amp;amp; Flensted 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Хотя глобальные Индексы Красной книги можно дезагрегировать, чтобы показать тенденции для видов в меньших пространственных масштабах, но в обратную сторону процесс не производится. Национальные или региональные Индексы Красной книги не могут быть агрегированы для создания Индексов Красной книги, отражающих глобальные тенденции. Это связано с тем, что глобальный риск исчезновения таксона должен оцениваться в глобальном масштабе и не может быть напрямую определен из нескольких оценок в национальном масштабе по всему его ареалу (хотя данные таких оценок могут быть агрегированы для включения в глобальную оценку).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
