<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 9-5-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The UNESCO Institute for Statistics (UIS) sends out a questionnaire every year to collect research and experimental development (R&amp;amp;D) data from all countries (around 125 countries), which are not covered by the data collections of the other partner organizations such as the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD), Eurostat (Statistical Office of the European Union) and the Network on Science and Technology Indicators &amp;#x2013; Ibero-American and Inter-American (RICYT). In agreement with these three organisations, their data (which were collected from their member states/associated member states &amp;#x2013; around 65 countries-) are directly obtained from the respective databases (in the case of the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development - OECD and Statistical Office of the European Union - Eurostat) or received from the partner (in the case of the Network on Science and Technology Indicators &amp;#x2013; Ibero-American and Inter-American - RICYT). There is also collaboration in Africa with the African Science, Technology and Innovation (STI) Indicators Initiative (ASTII) of the African Union Development Agency-NEPAD (AUDA-NEPAD). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the countries to which the UNESCO Institute for Statistics (UIS) sends a questionnaire, the process is the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A questionnaire is sent to focal points in countries, generally within the Ministry of Science and Technology or the national statistical office.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The UNESCO Institute for Statistics (UIS) processes the questionnaires, communicating with the countries in case of questions, calculates indicators and releases the data and indicators on its website. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Countries are requested to complete the questionnaire using the standard international classifications, therefore adjustments are generally not needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other agencies have similar procedures.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Proceso de recolección:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El IEU envía todos los años un cuestionario para recoger los datos de I+D de todos los países (alrededor de 125 países), que no están cubiertos por las recopilaciones de datos de las otras organizaciones asociadas, como la Organización para la Cooperación y el Desarrollo Económico (OCDE), Eurostat (Oficina de Estadística de la Unión Europea) y la Red de Indicadores de Ciencia y Tecnología &amp;#x2013; Iberoamericana e Interamericana (RICYT). De acuerdo con estas tres organizaciones, sus datos (recogidos en sus estados miembros/estados miembros asociados &amp;#x2013; alrededor de 65 países-) se obtienen directamente de las respectivas bases de datos (en el caso de la OCDE y Eurostat) o se reciben del socio (en el caso de la RICYT). También existe una colaboración en África con la Iniciativa Africana de Indicadores de CTI (ASTII) de la UA/NEPAD, que puede conducir a una recopilación conjunta de datos en el futuro. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para los datos a los que el IEU envía un cuestionario, el proceso es el siguiente:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Se envía un cuestionario a los puntos focales de los países, generalmente dentro del Ministerio de Ciencia y Tecnología o de la oficina nacional de estadística.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;El IEU procesa los cuestionarios, se comunica con los países en caso de dudas, calcula los indicadores y publica los datos e indicadores en su página web. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Se pide a los países que rellenen el cuestionario utilizando las clasificaciones internacionales estándar, por lo que generalmente no es necesario realizar ajustes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt; Processus de collecte:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L’ISU envoie chaque année un questionnaire pour recueillir des données de R&amp;amp;D de tous les pays (environ 125 pays), qui ne sont pas couvertes par les collectes de données des autres organisations partenaires telles que l’Organisation de coopération et de développement économiques (OCDE), Eurostat (Office statistique de l’Union européenne) et le Réseau sur les indicateurs scientifiques et technologiques &amp;#x2013; Ibéro-Américain et interaméricain (RICYT). En accord avec ces trois organisations, leurs données (qui ont été collectées auprès de leurs États membres/États membres associés &amp;#x2013; autour de 65 pays-) sont directement obtenues à partir des bases de données respectives (dans le cas de l’OCDE et d’Eurostat) ou reçues du partenaire (dans le cas du RICYT). Il y a également une collaboration en Afrique avec l’Initiative africaine pour les indicateurs des ITS (ASTII) de l’UA/NEPAD, qui pourrait conduire à une collecte conjointe de données à l’avenir. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Pour les données à qui l’ISU envoie un questionnaire, le processus est le suivant :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Un questionnaire est envoyé aux points focaux dans les pays, généralement
au sein du Ministère des sciences et de la technologie ou de l’Office national de la statistique. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; L’ISU traite les questionnaires, communique avec les pays en cas de questions,
calcule les indicateurs et publie les données et les indicateurs sur son site Web. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Les pays sont priés de remplir le questionnaire à l’aide des classifications
internationales standard, c’est pourquoi des ajustements ne sont généralement pas nécessaires. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt;Процесс сбора:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Статистический институт ЮНЕСКО (СИЮ) ежегодно рассылает вопросник для сбора данных по НИОКР от всех стран (около 125 стран), которые не охватываются процедурой сбора данных другими партнерскими организациями, такими как Организация экономического сотрудничества и развитие (ОЭСР), Евростат (Статистическое управление Европейского союза) и Сеть по показателям науки и технологий - Иберо-американская и Межамериканская (RICYT). По согласованию с этими тремя организациями их данные (которые были собраны в их государствах-членах / ассоциированных государствах-членах - около 65 стран-) получаются напрямую из соответствующих баз данных (в случае ОЭСР и Евростата) или получаются от партнера (в случае RICYT). В Африке также осуществляется сотрудничество с Африканской инициативой по показателям науки, техники и инноваций (ASTII) Африканского Единства (АЕ)/ Нового партнерства в целях развития в Африке (НЕПАД), что может привести в будущем к совместному сбору данных.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Процесс сбора данных, по которым СИЮ направляет вопросник, выглядит следующим образом:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Вопросник направляется координаторам в странах, как правило, в министерства науки и технологий или национальные статистические управления.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;СИЮ обрабатывает вопросники, связывается со странами в случае возникновения вопросов, рассчитывает показатели и публикует данные и показатели на своем сайте. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Странам предлагается заполнять вопросник, используя стандартные международные классификации, поэтому корректировки обычно не требуются.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
