<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 16-6-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Data availability:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This indicator needs to be measured on the basis of data collected by NSOs through official household surveys.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description and time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is no existing globally comparable official dataset on the &amp;#x201C;Proportion of the population satisfied with their last experience of public services.&amp;#x201D; While a large number of countries have experience with measuring citizen satisfaction with public services, there is large variability in the ways NSOs and government agencies in individual countries collect data on citizen satisfaction with public services, in terms of the range of services included, the specific attributes examined, question wording and response formats, etc. This variability poses a significant challenge for cross-country comparability of such data.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A number of global and regional sources provide comparable data on some measures of citizen satisfaction with public services. For instance, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gallup.com/analytics/232838/world-poll.aspx&quot;&gt;Gallup World Poll&lt;/a&gt; (not publicly available, but data collected for more than 150 countries) asks people how satisfied they are with education and healthcare public services in their local area. However, the Gallup World Poll questions do not ask specifically about satisfaction &lt;em&gt;with the last experience of public services&lt;/em&gt;, and does not refer to specific attributes of public services to be considered by respondents when providing their assessment. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At regional level, the Afrobarometer&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-22&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-22&quot;&gt;[21]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; has collected data on citizens&amp;#x2019; satisfaction with healthcare and education services across Africa over seven survey rounds (from 1999/2001 to 2016/18), using the question &amp;#x201C;&lt;em&gt;How well or badly would you say the current government is handling the following matters, or haven&amp;#x2019;t you heard enough to say: Addressing educational needs?&lt;/em&gt; Improving basic health services? with the following answer categories: &lt;em&gt;1=Very badly, 2=Fairly badly, 3=Fairly well, 4=Very well&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-23&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-23&quot;&gt;[22]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Also at the regional (European) level, eight waves of the biennial European Social Survey&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-24&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-24&quot;&gt;[23]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (from 2002 to 2016) provide time series data on perception of education and health services in Europe. The relevant survey questions are: &lt;em&gt;What do you think overall about the state of health (education) services in [country] nowadays?&lt;/em&gt;, using a scale of 0 (extremely bad) to 10 (extremely good). Once again, these survey questions do not ask specifically about satisfaction &lt;em&gt;with the last experience of public services&lt;/em&gt;, and do ask respondents to consider specific attributes of public services when providing their assessment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The fourth edition of the European Quality of Life Survey&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-25&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-25&quot;&gt;[24]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (EQLS) in 2016 had a specific focus on the quality of public services, with questions on &lt;em&gt;both &lt;/em&gt;overall satisfaction levels with healthcare and education services, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; satisfaction with specific attributes of service provision, several of which match the attributes selected for global reporting on 16.6.2. This focus on the quality of public service provision is expected to remain in future iterations of the EQLS survey, and this survey could therefore become an appropriate source of data for reporting on SDG 16.6.2 for 33 participating countries &amp;#x2013; namely the 28 EU Member States and 5 candidate countries (Albania, the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia, Montenegro, Serbia and Turkey). More specifically, the following corresponding questions in the EQLS have been identified, jointly with Eurofound experts, to report on SDG 16.6.2: &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Healthcare services&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-26&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-26&quot;&gt;[25]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attributes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SDG 16.6.2 questions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corresponding EQLS questions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q 4.1 It was easy to get to the place where I received medical treatment. (0-3)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Q61 - Thinking about the last time you needed to see or be treated by a GP, family doctor or health centre, to what extent did any of the following make it difficult or not for you to do so? [Very difficult (1); a little difficult (2); not difficult at all (3)]: &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;a. Distance to GP/doctor&amp;#x2019;s office / health centre&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;b. Delay in getting appointment&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;c. Waiting time to see doctor on day of appointment&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Affordability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q 4.2 Expenses for healthcare services were affordable to you/your household. (0-3)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Q61 &amp;#x2013; Same as above: &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;d. Cost of seeing the doctor&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quality of facilities &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q 4.3 The healthcare facilities were clean and in good condition. (0-3)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Q62 - You mentioned that you used GP, family doctor or health centre services. On a scale of 1 to 10 where 1 means very dissatisfied and 10 means very satisfied, tell me how satisfied or dissatisfied you were with each of the following aspects the last time that you used the service. &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Quality of the facilities (building, room, equipment)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equal treatment for everyone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q 4.4 All people are treated equally in receiving healthcare services in your area.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;(0-3)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Q63 - To what extent do you agree or disagree with the following about GP, family doctor or health centre services in your area? [on a scale of 1 to 10, where 1 means completely disagree and 10 means completely agree]: &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;a. All people are treated equally in these services in my area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Courtesy and treatment (Doctor&amp;#x2019;s attitude) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The doctor or other healthcare staff you saw spent enough time with you [or a child in your household] during the consultation. (0-3)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Q62 - Satisfaction with the following aspects [on a scale of 1 to 10 where 1 means very dissatisfied and 10 means very satisfied]: &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;c. Personal attention you were given, including staff attitude and time devoted&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall satisfaction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Overall, how satisfied or dissatisfied were you with the quality of the healthcare services you [or a child in your household] received on that last consultation? (i.e. the last time you [or a child in your household] had a medical examination or treatment in the past 12 months)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Very dissatisfied (0) - Dissatisfied (1) &amp;#x2013; Satisfied (2) &amp;#x2013; Very satisfied (3)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Q58 - In general, how would you rate the quality of each of the following public services in [COUNTRY]? [on a scale of one to 10, where 1 means very poor quality and 10 means very high quality]&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;a. Health services&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Education services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attributes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SDG 16.6.2 questions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corresponding EQLS questions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q. 9.1 The school can be reached by public or private transportation, or by walk, in less than 30 minutes and without difficulties. (0-3)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;No relevant EQLS question &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Affordability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q. 9.2 School-related expenses (including administrative fees, books, uniforms and transportation) are affordable to you/your household. (0-3)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;No relevant EQLS question&lt;/u&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-27&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-27&quot;&gt;[26]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quality of facilities &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q. 9.3 School facilities are in good condition. (0-3)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Q85 - You mentioned that your child or someone in your household attended school. On a scale of 1 to 10 where 1 means very dissatisfied and 10 means very satisfied, please tell me how satisfied or dissatisfied you were with each of the following aspects. &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;a. Quality of the facilities (building, room, equipment)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equal treatment for everyone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q. 9.4 All children are treated equally in the school attended by the child/children in your household. (0-3)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Q86 - To what extent do you agree or disagree with the following statements about school services in your area? Please tell me on a scale of 1 to 10, where 1 means completely disagree and 10 means completely agree.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;a. All people are treated equally in these services in my area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Effective delivery of service (Quality of teaching)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q. 9.5 The quality of teaching is good. (0-3)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Q85 - You mentioned that your child or someone in your household attended school. On a scale of 1 to 10 where 1 means very dissatisfied and 10 means very satisfied, please tell me how satisfied or dissatisfied you were with each of the following aspects.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;b. Expertise and professionalism of staff/teachers&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;e. The curriculum and activities&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall satisfaction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q 10. Overall, how satisfied or dissatisfied are you with the quality of education services provided by the primary and/or secondary public schools attended by this child/children in your household? &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you reporting on: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Primary school in your area ___&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Secondary school in your area ___&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Very dissatisfied (0) - Dissatisfied (1) &amp;#x2013; Satisfied (2) &amp;#x2013; Very satisfied (3)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Q58 - In general, how would you rate the quality of each of the following public services in [COUNTRY]? [on a scale of one to 10, where one means very poor quality and 10 means very high quality]&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;b. Education system &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation categories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator 16.6.2 aims to measure how access to services and how the quality of services differs across various demographic groups. Empirical analysis to identify the strongest demographic determinants of citizen satisfaction with public services reveals that the most relevant disaggregation categories for SDG indicator 16.6.2 are (1) income, (2) sex and (3) place of residence (urban/rural, and by administrative region e.g. by province, state, district, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a minimum, results &lt;em&gt;for each one of the three service areas&lt;/em&gt; covered by this indicator (healthcare, education and government services)&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;should be disaggregated by these three variables:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Income:&lt;/strong&gt; Income (or expenditure) quintiles &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sex:&lt;/strong&gt; Male/Female&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Place of residence:&lt;/strong&gt; Living in urban/rural areas and/or living in which administrative region (province, state, district, etc.)&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-28&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-28&quot;&gt;[27]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the extent possible, all efforts should be made to also disaggregate results by disability status and by &amp;#x2018;nationally relevant population groups&amp;#x2019;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disability status:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#x2018;Disability&amp;#x2019; is an umbrella term covering long-term physical, mental, intellectual or sensory impairments which in interaction with various barriers may hinder the full and effective participation of disabled persons in society on an equal basis with others&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-29&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-29&quot;&gt;[28]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. If possible, NSOs are encouraged to add the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtongroup-disability.com/washington-group-question-sets/short-set-of-disability-questions/&quot;&gt;Short Set of Questions on Disability developed by the Washington Group&lt;/a&gt; to the survey vehicle used to administer the 16.6.2 batteries to disaggregate results by disability status.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nationally relevant population groups&lt;/strong&gt;: groups with a distinct ethnicity, language, religion, indigenous status, nationality or other characteristics.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-30&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-30&quot;&gt;[29]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Age:&lt;/strong&gt; Empirical analysis shows that there is no statistically significant association between the age of respondents and satisfaction levels. However, if countries choose to also disaggregate results by age, it is recommended to follow UN standards for the production of age-disaggregated national population statistics, using the following age groups: (1) below 25 years old, (2) 25-34, (3) 35-44, (4) 45-54, (5) 55-64 and (6) 65 years old and above. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-22&quot;&gt;21&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; The Afrobarometer is a pan-African, non-partisan research network that conducts public attitude surveys on democracy, governance, economic conditions, and related issues in more than 35 countries in Africa. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-22&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-23&quot;&gt;22&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; While the fifth round (2011/13) of the Afrobarometer survey included several attributes-based question on healthcare and education services, subsequent rounds only include a few: &amp;#x201C;if there is a school or a health Clinic within easy walking distance&amp;#x201D;; and &amp;#x201C;how easy or difficult was it to obtain the medical care or services from teachers or school officials&amp;#x201D;. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-23&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-24&quot;&gt;23&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; The European Social Survey (ESS) is a biennial cross-national survey of attitudes and behaviour established in 2001. In total, 37 countries have taken part in at least one round of the ESS since its inception. Surveys are conducted by leading academics and social research professionals. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-24&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-25&quot;&gt;24&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Eurofound&amp;#x2019;s European Quality of Life Survey (EQLS) documents living conditions and people&amp;#x2019;s social situation, and explores issues pertinent to the lives of European citizens. In operation since 2003, the EQLS 2016 &amp;#x2013; the fourth survey in the series &amp;#x2013; covered 33 countries &amp;#x2013; the 28 EU Member States and 5 candidate countries (Albania, the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia, Montenegro, Serbia and Turkey). provides detailed information on the quality of public services, including healthcare and education services. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-25&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-26&quot;&gt;25&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;u&gt;Note&lt;/u&gt;: For healthcare services, EQLS data would allow for the separate reporting of results (across all questions) on (1) primary care services (GP / doctor&amp;#x2019;s office / health centre) and (2) hospital or medical specialist services. Separate reporting on these two types of health care would be particularly relevant for the &amp;#x2018;affordability&amp;#x2019; attribute, given in European countries, primary care services typically cost little; more relevant would be to assess the affordability of hospital or medical specialist services, using question 67.e. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-26&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-27&quot;&gt;26&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; However, question HC100 on &amp;#x2018;Affordability of formal education&amp;#x2019; could be used in the European Union Statistics on Income and Living Conditions (EU-SILC) ad hoc module 2016. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-27&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-28&quot;&gt;27&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Based on the premise that decentralization efforts are aimed at extending local rights and responsibilities across the national territory, indicator 16.6.2 can help detect unequal access to services and disparities in the quality of services across localities. There is a risk for erroneous conclusions to be drawn from national aggregates unable to detect variations at sub-national level. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-28&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-29&quot;&gt;28&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; UN General Assembly, Convention on the Rights of Persons with Disabilities: resolution / adopted by the General Assembly, 24 January 2007, A/RES/61/106, available at: http://www.refworld.org/docid/45f973632.html &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-29&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-30&quot;&gt;29&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; The population of a country is a mosaic of different population groups that can be identified according to racial, ethnic, language, indigenous or migration status, religious affiliation, or sexual orientation, amongst other characteristics. For the purpose of this indicator, particular focus is placed on minorities. &lt;em&gt;Minority groups are &lt;/em&gt;groups that are numerically inferior to the rest of the population of a state, in a non-dominant position, whose members&amp;#x2014;being nationals of the state&amp;#x2014;possess ethnic, religious or linguistic characteristics differing from those of the rest of the population and show, even if only implicitly, a sense of solidarity directed towards preserving their culture, traditions, religion or language. While the nationality criterion included in the above definition has often been challenged, the requirement to be in a non-dominant position remains important (OHCHR, 2010). Collecting survey data disaggregated by population groups should be subject to the legality of compiling such data in a particular national context and to a careful assessment of the potential risks of collecting such data for the safety of respondents. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-30&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
