<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 16-6-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommended set of complementary questions to address selection 16.6.2 bias towards &amp;#x2018;&lt;em&gt;users&amp;#x2019;&lt;/em&gt; of public services &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Since SDG 16.6.2 refers to people&amp;#x2019;s &amp;#x2018;last experience&amp;#x2019; with public services, the indicator needs to focus on user experiences rather than on non-user perceptions. The experience of users is important, but it is equally important to understand the experiences and perceptions of those who turn elsewhere for services, or who do not access services altogether. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For each service area, NSOs are therefore strongly encouraged to administer three complementary questions (see Methodology section) &lt;em&gt;prior &lt;/em&gt;to the two &amp;#x2018;priority questions&amp;#x2019; to be used for global 16.6.2 reporting. These additional questions will help capture the experience of &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; users &lt;em&gt;and &lt;/em&gt;non-users of public services. They will help identify which population sub-groups who needed healthcare, education and government services did &lt;em&gt;not &lt;/em&gt;access the services they needed, and what barriers prevented them from doing so. While the information generated by these additional questions is critical for policymakers to design service provision programmes that &amp;#x2018;leave no one behind&amp;#x2019;, it is left to the discretion of each country to integrate them or not, as some may already be collecting similar information through existing surveys.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, the selection bias inherent in SDG 16.6.2, with its focus on users, can result in mismeasurement due to underlying inequalities in the propensity of various groups to interact with state institutions. In other words, a focus on &amp;#x2018;the last experience with public services&amp;#x2019; implicitly means that this indicator includes only those respondents who were privileged enough to access public services in the past year. This means that those (such as ethnic minorities, migrants, the elderly, undocumented workers) who have &lt;em&gt;not &lt;/em&gt;been able &amp;#x2013; or willing &amp;#x2013; to access the healthcare, education or government services they needed in the past 12 months, often as a consequence of multiple social and economic barriers arising from overlapping forms of marginalization will be undercounted by this indicator. There is a risk therefore that overall satisfaction levels reported on 16.6.2 will over-represent the experience of more privileged groups for whom access to public services is easier, because they have the financial, logistical and intellectual means to do so, and they trust that it is in their interest to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer scales:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To ensure the consistency of measurement in an international context, a standardised approach to response format is required. Available evidence from piloting and other NSO experiences suggests that a four-point Likert-scale with verbal scale anchors is preferable over the alternatives. A four-point scale offers the optimal range of response options for the concepts at hand, in terms of capturing as much meaningful variation between responses as there exists, while remaining understandable for respondents who are not very numerate or literate. Piloting experiences have revealed that offering too few response options (such as a &amp;#x2018;yes/no&amp;#x2019; binary response format) would not reveal much variation and might even frustrate some respondents, who might feel their satisfaction level cannot be accurately expressed. Furthermore, the Guidelines on Measuring Subjective Well-Being (OECD, 2013) caution against using &amp;#x201C;agree/disagree, true/false, and yes/no response formats in the measurement of subjective well-being due to the heightened risk of acquiescence and socially desirable responding&amp;#x201D;. Meanwhile, piloting experiences have shown that respondents would be equally burdened by too many response categories (such a 7- or 10-point scale), especially if the categories are too close to distinguish between them cognitively. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are different schools of thought on whether an odd or even number of categories is best when using Likert scales. While taking away the middle category forces respondents to voice a positive or negative opinion, and some respondents might find this approach frustrating, several NSOs in developing country contexts favor a Likert scale &lt;em&gt;without &lt;/em&gt;a neutral value (such as &amp;#x201C;neither satisfied nor dissatisfied&amp;#x201D;). Their preference is motivated by their long-standing survey experience which has shown that when a neutral value is provided, a large proportion (often a majority) of respondents will refrain from expressing their opinion &amp;#x2018;hiding&amp;#x2019; behind this middle-point. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The survey methodology for 16.6.2 therefore uses a 4-point bipolar Likert scale for all questions (for internal consistency), with the following scale labels: &amp;#x201C;strongly agree, agree, disagree, strongly disagree&amp;#x201D; for attributes-based questions, and &amp;#x201C;very satisfied, satisfied, dissatisfied, very dissatisfied&amp;#x201D; for overall satisfaction questions. &amp;#x201C;Don&amp;#x2019;t know&amp;#x201D; and &amp;#x201C;refuse to answer&amp;#x201D; options are also available, but &lt;em&gt;should not be read out loud&lt;/em&gt;, so as to not provide an easy way for respondents to disengage from the subjects of the various questions. When respondents say they &amp;#x201C;don&amp;#x2019;t know&amp;#x201D;, enumerators should repeat the question and simply ask them to provide their best guess. The &amp;#x201C;don&amp;#x2019;t know&amp;#x201D; and &amp;#x201C;refuse to answer&amp;#x201D; options should be used only as a last resort.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr"/>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
