<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The RATIONALE field for indicator 1-4-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;h2&gt;Rationale:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poverty has many dimensions. It is not only a lack of material well-being but also a lack of opportunities to live a tolerable life. The international extreme poverty line was updated in 2015 to 1.90 USD per day using 2011 purchasing power parity (WB 2015). Living under the extreme poverty line often encompasses deprivations of safe drinking water, proper sanitation, access to modern energy, sustainable mobility to economic resources, information technology, healthcare, education, etc. Poverty is also a manifestation of hunger and malnutrition, limited access to education and other basic services, social discrimination and exclusion as well as the lack of participation in decision-making. In other words, poverty is multidimensional and covers many aspects of life ranging from access to opportunities, livelihoods and means of survival. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the different aspects of poverty, this indicator focuses on &amp;#x2018;access to basic services&amp;#x2019;. Providing access to basic services such as safe drinking water, sanitation facilities, sustainable energy and mobility, housing, education, healthcare etc, helps to improve the quality of life of the poor. The lack of basic services provision and the lack of empowerment and involvement of local governments in basic service delivery undermine the economic growth and quality of life in any community. Adequate basic service delivery systems promote socio-economic improvements and help to achieve economic growth, social inclusion, poverty reduction and equality. More specifically, improved basic services can help to raise well-being and productivity of communities, create jobs, save time and human effort in transporting water, support food security, better use of energy, production of essential commodities, improve health (by making medical care, clean water or solid waste collection available) or enhance the level of education. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Quito implementation plan for the New Urban Agenda adopted in Habitat III conference, member states commit to &amp;#x201C;promoting equitable and affordable access to sustainable basic physical and social infrastructure for all, without discrimination, including affordable serviced land, housing, modern and renewable energy, safe drinking water and sanitation, safe, nutritious and adequate food, waste disposal, sustainable mobility, health care and family planning, education, culture, and information and communications technologies&amp;#x201D; . They further commit to &amp;#x201C;ensuring that these services are responsive to the rights and needs of women, children and youth, older persons and persons with disabilities, migrants, indigenous peoples and local communities, as appropriate, and to those of others in vulnerable situations&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic service delivery must move towards a demand-driven approach, which is appropriate for the local needs &amp;#x2013; and hence able to respond to the concept of &amp;#x201C;Access for all&amp;#x201D; &amp;#x2013; as stated in the NUA. Basic services are fundamental to improving living standards. Governments have the responsibility for their provision. This indicator will measure levels of accessibility to basic services and guide the efforts of governments for provision of equitable basic services for all to eradicate poverty.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
