<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 3-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Comments and limitations:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cause of death estimates have large uncertainty ranges for some causes and some regions. Data gaps and limitations in high-mortality regions reinforce the need for caution when interpreting global comparative cause of death assessments, as well as the need for increased investment in population health measurement systems. The use of verbal autopsy methods in sample registration systems, demographic surveillance systems and household surveys provides some information on causes of death in populations without well-functioning death registration systems, but there remain considerable challenges in the validation and interpretation of such data, and in the assessment of uncertainty associated with diagnoses of underlying cause of death.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires et limitations : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les estimations des causes de décès présentent de grandes incertitudes pour certaines causes et certaines régions. Les lacunes et les limites des données dans les régions à forte mortalité renforcent la nécessité de faire preuve de prudence dans l&apos;interprétation des évaluations comparatives des causes de décès au niveau mondial, ainsi que la nécessité d&apos;accroître les investissements dans les systèmes de mesure de la santé des populations. L&apos;utilisation de méthodes d&apos;autopsie verbale dans les systèmes d&apos;enregistrement d&apos;échantillons, les systèmes de surveillance démographique et les enquêtes sur les ménages fournit certaines informations sur les causes de décès dans les populations qui ne disposent pas de systèmes d&apos;enregistrement des décès fonctionnant bien, mais il reste des défis considérables à relever en ce qui concerne la validation et l&apos;interprétation de ces données, ainsi que l&apos;évaluation de l&apos;incertitude associée aux diagnostics des causes de décès sous-jacentes. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
