<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 2-3-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data is available for over 40 countries, including all 27 EU countries, 12 countries in Africa and two countries each in Asia and the Americas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A maximum of three data points is available for some countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator 2.3.1 must be disaggregated by classes of farming/pastoral/forestry enterprise size. The overall SDG Target 2.3 requires specific focus on women, indigenous peoples, family farmers, pastoralists and fishers. For this reason, the indicator must be disaggregated by sex, type of enterprise and by community of reference.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disponibilité des données :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont disponibles pour plus de 40 pays, dont les 27 pays de l’UE, 12 pays d’Afrique et deux pays d’Asie et des Amériques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Séries chronologiques :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D&apos;ici 2030.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Désagrégation :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur 2.3.1 doit être désagrégé par classes de taille d&apos;entreprise agricole/pastorale/forestière. La cible de l&apos;ODD global 2.3 exige que l&apos;on se concentre spécifiquement sur les femmes, les peuples autochtones, les agriculteurs familiaux, les pasteurs et les pêcheurs. Pour cette raison, l&apos;indicateur doit être ventilé par sexe, par type d&apos;entreprise et par communauté de référence.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
