<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 2-3-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volume of agricultural production of small-scale food producer in crop, livestock, fisheries, and forestry activities per number of days worked. The indicator is computed as a &lt;em&gt;ratio of annual output to the number of working days in one year&lt;/em&gt;. As the indicator is referred to a set of production units &amp;#x2013; those of a small scale &amp;#x2014; the denominator needs to summarize information on the entire production undertaken in each unit. This requires that volumes of production are reported in a common numeraire, given that it is impossible to sum up physical units. The most convenient numeraire for aggregating products in the numerator is a vector of constant prices. When measured at different points in time, as required by the monitoring of the SDG indicators, changes in constant values represent aggregated volume changes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO proposes to define small-scale food producers as producers who: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;operate an amount of land falling in the first two quintiles (the bottom 40 percent) of the cumulative distribution of land size at national level (measured in hectares); and &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;operate a number of livestock falling in the first two quintiles (the bottom 40 percent) of the cumulative distribution of the number of livestock per production unit at national level (measured in Tropical Livestock Units &amp;#x2013; TLUs); and &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;obtain an annual economic revenue from agricultural activities falling in the first two quintiles (the bottom 40 percent) of the cumulative distribution of economic revenues from agricultural activities per production unit at national level (measured in Purchasing Power Parity Dollars) not exceeding 34,387 Purchasing Power Parity Dollars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The following concepts are adopted for the computation of indicators 2.3.1:&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Small-scale food producers are defined as those falling in the intersection of the bottom 40 percent of the cumulative distribution of land, livestock and revenues.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tropical Livestock Units are a conversion scale used for standardization and measurement of the number of livestock heads. One TLU is the metabolic weight equivalent of one cattle in North America. The complete list of conversion factors can be found in the Guidelines for the preparation of livestock sector Reviews &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The concept of productivity is standardized by OECD&amp;#x2019;s Manual for Measuring Productivity. This defines productivity as &amp;#x201C;a ratio of a volume measure of outputs to a volume measure of input use.&amp;#x201D; More information on possible definitions can be found in &amp;#x201C;Productivity and Efficiency Measurement in Agriculture: Literature Review and Gaps Analysis&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volume de la production agricole des petits producteurs alimentaires dans les activités agricoles, d’élevage, de pêche et forestières par nombre de jours travaillés. L’indicateur est calculé comme un &lt;em&gt;ratio de la production annuelle sur le nombre de jours ouvrables au cours d’une année&lt;/em&gt;. Comme on désigne l’indicateur comme un ensemble d’unités de production – celles d’une petite échelle –, le dénominateur doit résumer les informations sur l’ensemble de la production entreprise dans chaque unité. Cela nécessite que les volumes de production soient déclarés en chiffre commun, étant donné qu’il est impossible de résumer les unités physiques. Le numéraire le plus pratique pour agréger les produits dans le numérateur est un vecteur de prix constants. Lorsqu’elles sont mesurées à différents moments dans le temps, comme l’exige le suivi des indicateurs des ODD, les variations des valeurs constantes représentent des variations de volume agrégées. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La FAO propose de définir les petits producteurs alimentaires comme des producteurs qui : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;exploitent une quantité de terres se situant dans les deux premiers quintiles (les 40 % inférieurs) de la répartition cumulative de la superficie des terres au niveau national (mesurée en hectares); et qui &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;exploitent un certain nombre de têtes de bétail se situant dans les deux premiers quintiles (les 40 % inférieurs) de la répartition cumulative du nombre de têtes de bétail par unité de production au niveau national (mesuré en unités de bétail tropical – UBT); et qui &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;obtiennent un revenu économique annuel provenant des activités agricoles se situant dans les deux premiers quintiles (les 40 % inférieurs) de la distribution cumulative des revenus économiques provenant des activités agricoles par unité de production au niveau national (mesuré en dollars de parité de pouvoir d’achat) ne dépassant pas 34 387 dollars de parité de pouvoir d’achat. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les concepts suivants sont adoptés pour le calcul des indicateurs 2.3.1 :&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les petits producteurs alimentaires sont définis comme ceux qui se trouvent dans l’intersection des 40 % inférieurs de la distribution cumulative des terres, du bétail et des revenus. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les unités de bétail tropical sont une échelle de conversion utilisée pour la normalisation et la mesure du nombre de têtes de bétail. Une UBT est l’équivalent en poids métabolique d’un bovin en Amérique du Nord. La liste complète des facteurs de conversion se trouve dans les Lignes directrices pour la préparation des examens du secteur de l’élevage &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Le concept de productivité est normalisé par le Manuel de mesure de la productivité de l’OCDE. Cela définit la productivité comme « un rapport entre une mesure en volume des extrants et une mesure en volume de l’utilisation des intrants ». Vous trouverez de plus amples renseignements sur les définitions possibles dans (en anglais) « Productivity and Efficiency Measurement in Agriculture: Literature Review and Gaps Analysis ». &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
