<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COVERAGE field for indicator 8-6-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data for this indicator is available for 157 countries and territories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Country data for this indicator is available as of 2000 in the SDG Indicators Global Database, but longer time series are available in ILOSTAT. Regional data in this submission covers a period of 2005 to 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No disaggregation is specifically required for this indicator, although having it disaggregated by sex is desirable, as is disaggregation by detailed age groups within the youth age band. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos de este indicador están disponibles a partir del año 2000 en la base de datos global de los indicadores de los ODS, pero hay series temporales más largas en ILOSTAT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No se requiere un desglose específico para este indicador, aunque es deseable tenerlo desglosado por sexo, así como el desglose por grupos de edad detallados dentro de la franja de edad de los jóvenes.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilité des données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Séries chronologiques :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données pour cet indicateur sont disponibles à partir de 2000 dans la base de données mondiale des indicateurs des ODD, mais des séries chronologiques plus longues sont disponibles dans ILOSTAT&lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;h2&gt;Désagrégation :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aucune désagrégation n&apos;est spécifiquement requise pour cet indicateur, bien qu&apos;une désagrégation par sexe soit souhaitable, tout comme une désagrégation par groupes d&apos;âge détaillés dans la tranche d&apos;âge des jeunes.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные по этому показателю доступны по состоянию на 2000 год в Глобальной базе данных показателей ЦУР, но в ILOSTATдоступны более длинные временные ряды. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для этого показателя не требуется специально дезагрегирования, хотя желательно его дезагрегирование по полу, как и дезагрегирование по детальным возрастным группам в пределах молодежной возрастной группы. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
