<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 8-6-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;The calculation of this indicator requires to have reliable information on both the labour market status and the participation in education or training of young persons. The quality of such information is heavily dependent on the questionnaire design, the sample size and design and the accuracy of respondents&amp;apos; answers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of the analysis of the indicator, in order to avoid misinterpreting it, it is important to bear in mind that it is composed of two different sub-groups (unemployed youth not in education or training and youth outside the labour force not in education or training). The prevalence and composition of each sub-group would have policy implications, and thus should also be considered when analysing the NEET rate. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h2&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El cálculo de este indicador requiere disponer de información fiable tanto sobre la situación del mercado laboral como sobre la participación en la educación o la formación de los jóvenes. La calidad de dicha información depende en gran medida del diseño del cuestionario, del tamaño y diseño de la muestra y de la precisión de las respuestas de los encuestados.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En cuanto al análisis del indicador, para evitar interpretaciones erróneas, es importante tener en cuenta que se compone de dos subgrupos diferentes (jóvenes desempleados que no cursan estudios o formación y jóvenes fuera de la población activa que no cursan estudios o formación). La prevalencia y la composición de cada subgrupo tendrían implicaciones políticas y, por tanto, también deberían tenerse en cuenta al analizar la tasa de NiNis.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires et limites :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le calcul de cet indicateur nécessite de disposer d&apos;informations fiables sur la situation des jeunes sur le marché du travail et sur leur participation à l&apos;éducation ou à la formation. La qualité de ces informations dépend fortement de la conception du questionnaire, de la taille et de la conception de l&apos;échantillon et de l&apos;exactitude des réponses des répondants. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En ce qui concerne l&apos;analyse de l&apos;indicateur, afin d&apos;éviter toute interprétation erronée, il est important de garder à l&apos;esprit qu&apos;il est composé de deux sous-groupes différents (les jeunes sans emploi ne suivant pas d&apos;enseignement ou de formation et les jeunes hors de la population active ne suivant pas d&apos;enseignement ou de formation). La prévalence et la composition de chaque sous-groupe ont des implications politiques et doivent donc être prises en compte lors de l&apos;analyse du taux de NEET.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Расчет этого показателя требует наличия надежной информации как о состоянии рынка труда, так и об участии молодежи в образовании или приобретении профессиональных навыков. Качество такой информации во многом зависит от структуры вопросника, объема и плана выборки, а также точности ответов респондентов. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; С точки зрения анализа показателя, чтобы избежать его неправильного толкования, важно помнить, что он состоит из двух разных подгрупп (безработная молодежь, не получающая образование или не приобретающая профессиональных навыков, и молодежь, не входящая в рабочую силу и не получающая образование или не приобретающая профессиональных навыков). Распространенность и состав каждой подгруппы будут иметь политические последствия и, следовательно, также должны учитываться при анализе уровня NEET-показателя. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
