<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The IMPUTATION field for indicator 12-a-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At country level:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the country level, electricity capacity data are sometimes missing for two reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delays in responding to IRENA questionnaires or publication of official data. In such cases, estimates are made so that global and regional totals can be calculated. The most basic treatment is to repeat the value of capacity from the previous year. However, IRENA also checks unofficial data sources and collects data about investment projects (see Indicator 7.a.1). These other sources can be used to identify if any new power plants have been commissioned in a year and are used where available to update the capacity value at the end of a year. Any such estimates are eventually replaced by official or questionnaire data when that becomes available.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Off-grid capacity data are frequently missing from national energy statistics or is presented in non-standard units (e.g. numbers of mini-hydro plants in a country rather than their capacity in MW). Where official data are not available, off-grid capacity figures are collected by IRENA from a wide variety of other official and unofficial sources in countries (e.g. development agencies, government departments, NGOs, project developers and industry associations) and this information is added to the capacity database to give a more complete picture of developments in the renewable energy sector in a country. These data are peer reviewed each year through an extensive network of national correspondents (the REN21 Network) and is checked with IRENA country focal points when they attend IRENA meetings and training workshops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When capacity data are missing, mostly in non-state territories, these are excluded from the dataset. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At regional and global levels:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See above. Regional and global totals are only estimated to the extent that figures for some countries may be estimated in each year. (See also data availability below). &lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
