<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 1-1-1b, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar">اخر تحديث
			</language>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 1: End poverty in all its forms everywhere&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 1.1: By 2030, eradicate extreme poverty for all people everywhere, currently measured as people living on less than $1.25 a day&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 1.1.1: Proportion of the population living below the international poverty line by sex, age, employment status and geographic location (urban/rural)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Employed population below international poverty line (%)&lt;/p&gt;2022-03-31&lt;p&gt;1.3.1, 8.2.1, 8.3.1, 8.5.1, 8.5.2, 10.4.1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;International Labour Organization (ILO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;International Labour Organization (ILO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proportion of the employed population below the international poverty line of US$1.90 per day, also referred to as the working poverty rate, is defined as the share of employed persons living in households with per-capita consumption or income that is below the international poverty line of US$1.90.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employment: All persons of working age who, during a short reference period (one week), were engaged in any activity to produce goods or provide services for pay or profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poverty Line: Threshold below which individuals in the reference population are considered poor and above which they are considered non-poor. The threshold is generally defined as the per-capita monetary requirements an individual needs to afford the purchase of a basic bundle of goods and services. For the purpose of this indicator, an absolute international poverty line of US$1.90 per day is used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Household in poverty: Households are defined as poor if their income or consumption expenditure is below the poverty line taking into account the number of household members and composition (e.g., number of adults and children).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working poor: Employed persons living in households that are classified as poor, that is, that have income or consumption levels below the poverty line used for measurement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Percent (%)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The series is disaggregated by sex and age, for which there are no standard international classifications. The age groups refer to all persons (aged 15+), youth (aged 15-24) and adults (aged 25+).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The preferred data source is a household survey with variables that can reliably identify both the poverty status of households and the economic activity of the household&amp;#x2019;s members. Examples include household income and expenditure surveys (HIES), living standards measurement surveys (LSMS) with employment modules, or labour force surveys (LFS) that collect information on household income. Such surveys offer the benefit of allowing the employment status and income (or consumption expenditure) variables to be derived from the same sampled households ideally for the same observation period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Employment estimates derived from a household survey other than a labour force survey may, however, not be the most robust due to questionnaire design. Similarly, a labour force survey may not be the best instrument for collecting household income or consumption expenditure data, although an attached income module can be designed to achieve statistically reliable results, including ensuring an overlap in the observation period between household income (or consumption expenditure) and employment status. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another possibility is to combine data from a household income and expenditure survey and from a separate labour force survey when the respondent households can be matched and consistency in the long observation period between the surveys can be obtained.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ILO processes national household survey microdatasets in line with internationally-agreed indicator concepts and definitions set forth by the International Conference of Labour Statisticians (ICLS). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuous&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National data are updated weekly on ILOSTAT. Global and regional estimates are updated once per year (in November or December).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mainly National Statistical Offices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;International Labour Organization (ILO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ILO is the UN focal point for labour statistics. It sets international standards for labour statistics through the International Conference of Labour Statisticians (ICLS). It also compiles and produces labour statistics with the goal of disseminating internationally-comparable datasets, and provides technical assistance and training to ILO member States to support their efforts to produce high quality labour market data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to eradicate poverty, we must understand the root causes of poverty. The working poverty rate reveals the proportion of the employed population living in poverty despite being employed, implying that their employment-related incomes are not sufficient to lift them and their families out of poverty and ensure decent living conditions. The adequacy of earnings is a fundamental aspect of job quality, and these deficits in job quality could be keeping workers and their families in poverty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proportion of working poor in total employment (that is, the working poverty rate) combines data on household income or consumption with labour force framework variables measured at the individual level and sheds light on the relationship between employment and household poverty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the country level, comparisons over time may be affected by such factors as changes in survey types or data collection methods. The use of Purchasing Power Parity (PPP) rather than market exchange rates ensures that differences in price levels across countries are taken into account. However, it cannot be categorically asserted that two people in two different countries, living below US$1.90 a day at PPP, face the same degree of deprivation or have the same degree of need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poverty in the context of this indicator is a concept that is applied to households, and not to individuals, based on the assumption that households pool their income. This assumption may not always be true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the poverty status of a household is a function of the wage and other employment-related income secured by those household members in employment, income derived from asset ownership, plus any other available income such as transfer payments and the number of household members. Whether a worker is counted as working poor therefore depends on his or her own income, the income of other household members and the number of household members who need to be supported. It is thus often valuable to study household structure in relation to working poverty. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;W&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;k&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;g&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;v&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;y&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;E&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;m&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;y&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;v&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;g&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;U&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;S&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;$&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mn&gt;1&lt;/mn&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;.&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;mn&gt;90&lt;/mn&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;y&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;T&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;m&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;y&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;m&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;&amp;#xD7;&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;100&lt;/mn&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ILO engages in annual consultations with member States through the ILOSTAT questionnaire and related Statistics Reporting System (StaRS). National data providers receive a link to the portal where they can review all national SDG data available on ILOSTAT.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through the ILO Harmonized Microdata initiative, the ILO strives to produce internationally comparable labour statistics based on the indicator concepts and definitions adopted by the International Conference of Labour Statisticians (ICLS).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; Estimates are produced for countries and years for which no direct working poverty estimates are available based on household survey estimates, but for which total poverty estimates are available in the World Bank&amp;#x2019;s PovcalNet database. This is carried out through a multivariate regression model described in &amp;#x201C;Employment and economic class in the developing world&amp;#x201D; (Kapsos and Bourmpoula, 2013), available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; Following the step described directly above, missing data at the national level are estimated through a multivariate regression model for the purpose of producing global and regional estimates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ILO produces global and regional estimates of employment by economic class (and thus, of working poverty rates) using the ILO&amp;#x2019;s Employment by Class (EbyC) model. These estimates are part of the ILO Estimates and Projections series, analysed in the ILO&amp;apos;s World Employment and Social Outlook reports. For more information, on the model used to derive these estimates, refer to the ILO paper &amp;#x201C;Employment and economic class in the developing world&amp;#x201D; (Kapsos and Bourmpoula, 2013), available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National poverty estimates will differ from this SDG indicator. This SDG indicator uses the international poverty line, currently set at US$1.90 at purchasing power parity. For further information, see: Decent Work and the Sustainable Development Goals: A Guidebook on SDG Labour Market Indicators (ILO) https://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The processes of compilation, production, and publication of data, including its quality control, are carried out following the methodological framework and standards established by the ILO Department of Statistics, in compliance with the information technology and management standards of the ILO.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data consistency and quality checks are regularly conducted for validation of the data before dissemination in the ILOSTAT database. These checks consist of data and metadata revision of all the relevant inputs applying protocols to ensure that international comparability and time-series consistency are maintained. For the resulting modelled estimates, both statistical and judgmental assessments of the output data are carried out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The final assessment of the quality of information is carried out by the Data Production and Analysis Unit of the ILO Department of Department. If any issues encountered cannot be clarified, the respective information is not published. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data for this indicator is available for 117 countries and territories. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This submission covers country data from 2000 to 2020. Global and regional aggregates are available from 2000 to 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The working poverty rate (proportion of employed persons living in poverty) is disaggregated by sex and age.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National poverty estimates will differ from this SDG indicator. This SDG indicator uses the international poverty line, currently set at US$1.90 at purchasing power parity. For further information, see: Decent Work and the Sustainable Development Goals: A Guidebook on SDG Labour Market Indicators (ILO) https://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decent Work and the Sustainable Development Goals: A Guidebook on SDG Labour Market Indicators (ILO) https://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ILOSTAT (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;ILOSTAT&amp;#x2019;s topic page on working poverty (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/topics/working-poor/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/topics/working-poor/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Employment and economic class in the developing world (Kapsos and Bourmpoula, 2013) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decent Work Indicators Manual &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---integration/documents/publication/wcms_229374.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---integration/documents/publication/wcms_229374.pdf&lt;/a&gt; (second version, page 70). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 1: Poner fin a la pobreza en todas sus formas y en todo el mundo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 1.1: De aquí a 2030, erradicar para todas las personas y en todo el mundo la pobreza extrema (actualmente se considera que sufren pobreza extrema las personas que viven con menos de 1,25 dólares de los Estados Unidos al día)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Indicador 1.1.1: Proporción de la población que vive por debajo del umbral de pobreza internacional por sexo, edad, situación laboral y ubicación geográfica (urbana/rural)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Última actualización: marzo de 2020 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Indicadores relacionados a febrero de 2020&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Información institucional &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Organización (es): &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; OIT &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La proporción de la población empleada por debajo de la línea de pobreza internacional de 1,90 dólares estadounidenses por día, también conocida como la tasa de pobreza laboral, se define como la proporción de personas empleadas que viven en hogares con consumo o ingreso per cápita que está por debajo de la línea de pobreza internacional de 1,90 dólares estadounidenses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Empleo:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Todas las personas en edad de trabajar que, durante un breve período de referencia (una semana), se dedicaron a cualquier actividad para producir bienes o prestar servicios a cambio de una remuneración o beneficio. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Línea de Pobreza:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Umbral por debajo del cual los individuos de la población de referencia se consideran pobres y por encima del cual se consideran no pobres. El umbral se define generalmente como los requerimientos monetarios per cápita que un individuo necesita para poder comprar un conjunto básico de bienes y servicios. A efectos de este indicador, se utiliza un umbral de pobreza absoluta internacional de 1,90 dólares estadounidenses al día &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Hogares en situación de pobreza:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Los hogares se definen como pobres si sus ingresos o gastos de consumo están por debajo del umbral de pobreza teniendo en cuenta el número de miembros del hogar y la composición (por ejemplo, el número de adultos y niños). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Trabajadores pobres:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Personas empleadas que viven en hogares clasificados como pobres, es decir, que tienen niveles de ingresos o consumo por debajo del umbral de pobreza utilizado para la medición. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La fuente de datos preferida es una encuesta de hogares con variables que pueden identificar de manera confiable tanto el estado de pobreza de los hogares como la actividad económica de los miembros del hogar. Algunos ejemplos son las encuestas de ingresos y gastos de los hogares (EIGH), las encuestas de medición de los niveles de vida (EMNV) con módulos de empleo o las encuestas de la fuerza laboral (EFL) que recopilan información sobre los ingresos de los hogares. Dichas encuestas ofrecen el beneficio de permitir que las variables de situación laboral e ingresos (o gastos de consumo) se deriven de los mismos hogares incluidos en la muestra, idealmente para el mismo período de observación. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Sin embargo, las estimaciones de empleo derivadas de una encuesta de hogares distintas de una encuesta de la fuerza laboral pueden no ser las más sólidas debido al diseño del cuestionario. Del mismo modo, una encuesta de la fuerza laboral puede no ser el mejor instrumento para recopilar los datos de ingresos o gastos de consumo de los hogares, aunque un módulo de ingresos adjunto puede diseñarse para lograr resultados estadísticamente fiables, incluso garantizar una superposición en el período de observación entre los ingresos de los hogares (o los gastos de consumo) y la situación del empleo. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Otra posibilidad es combinar los datos de una encuesta de ingresos y gastos de los hogares y de una encuesta separada de la fuerza laboral cuando se pueda igualar a los hogares encuestados y obtener coherencia en el largo período de observación entre las encuestas. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Proceso de recolección: &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Calendario&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Recopilación de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Publicación de datos: &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Principalmente Oficinas Nacionales de Estadística. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; OIT&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para erradicar la pobreza, debemos comprender sus causas fundamentales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La tasa de pobreza laboral revela la proporción de la población ocupada que vive en la pobreza a pesar de estar empleada, lo que implica que sus ingresos relacionados con el empleo no son suficientes para sacarlos a ellos y a sus familias de la pobreza y garantizarles unas condiciones de vida dignas. La suficiencia de los ingresos es un aspecto fundamental de la calidad del empleo, y estos déficits de calidad del empleo podrían estar manteniendo a los trabajadores y a sus familias en la pobreza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La proporción de trabajadores pobres en el empleo total (es decir, la tasa de pobreza de los trabajadores) combina datos sobre ingresos o consumos de los hogares con variables del marco laboral medidas a nivel individual y arroja luz sobre la relación entre el empleo y la pobreza de los hogares.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A nivel de país, las comparaciones a lo largo del tiempo pueden verse afectadas por factores como los cambios en los tipos de encuesta o los métodos de recogida de datos. El uso de las PPA en lugar de los tipos de cambio de mercado garantiza que se tengan en cuenta las diferencias en los niveles de precios entre países. Sin embargo, no se puede afirmar categóricamente que dos personas de dos países diferentes, que viven por debajo de 1,90 dólares al día en PPA, se enfrentan al mismo grado de privación o tienen el mismo grado de necesidad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La pobreza en el contexto de este indicador es un concepto que se aplica a los hogares, y no a los individuos, basándose en el supuesto de que los hogares ponen en común sus ingresos. Esta suposición puede no ser siempre cierta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Además, la situación de pobreza de un hogar es una función del salario y otros ingresos relacionados con el empleo obtenidos por los miembros del hogar que tienen un empleo, los ingresos derivados de la propiedad de activos, más cualquier otro ingreso disponible, como los pagos de transferencias, y el número de miembros del hogar. Por lo tanto, el hecho de que un trabajador se contabilice como trabajador pobre depende de sus propios ingresos, de los ingresos de otros miembros del hogar y del número de miembros del hogar que necesitan ser mantenidos. Por lo tanto, suele ser valioso estudiar la estructura del hogar en relación con la pobreza laboral. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tasa de pobreza laboral&amp;#xA0;= ((Personas empleadas que viven con menos de 1,90 dólares al día) / (Empleo total)) x 100&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A nivel de país&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A nivel regional y mundial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La OIT elabora estimaciones mundiales y regionales del empleo por clase económica (y, por tanto, de las tasas de pobreza de los trabajadores) utilizando el modelo de la OIT Employment by Class (EbyC). Estas estimaciones forman parte de la serie de Estimaciones y Proyecciones de la OIT, analizadas en los informes de la OIT sobre el Empleo Mundial y las Perspectivas Sociales. Para más información, sobre el modelo utilizado para obtener estas estimaciones, consulte el documento de la OIT &amp;#x201C;Empleo y clase económica en el mundo en desarrollo&amp;#x201D; (Kapsos y Bourmpoula, 2013), disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Métodos y lineamientos disponibles para los países para la recopilación de los datos a nivel nacional:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Garantía de calidad:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Serie temporal:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; El Banco Mundial está trabajando en la elaboración de estimaciones de pobreza desagregadas &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Fuentes de discrepancias:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Trabajo Decente y los Objetivos de Desarrollo Sostenible: Una Guía sobre los Indicadores del Mercado Laboral de los ODS (OIT) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ILOSTAT (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Página temática de ILOSTAT&amp;#x2019;)&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/topics/working-poor/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/topics/working-poor/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Empleo y clase económica en el mundo en desarrollo (Kapsos y Bourmpoula, 2013) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Manual de indicadores de trabajo decente &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---integration/documents/publication/wcms_229374.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---integration/documents/publication/wcms_229374.pdf&lt;/a&gt; (segunda versión, página 70). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 1 : Éliminer la pauvreté sous toutes ses formes et partout dans le monde&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 1.1 : D’ici 2030, éliminer complètement l’extrême pauvreté dans le monde entier (s’entend actuellement du fait de vivre avec moins de 1,25 $ (dollar américain) par jour)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 1.1.1 : Proportion de la population vivant en dessous du seuil de pauvreté fixé au niveau international, par sexe, âge, situation d’emploi et lieu de résidence (zone urbaine/zone rurale)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2021-01-01&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.3.1, 8.2.1, 8.3.1, 8.5.1, 10.4.1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organisation internationale du travail (OIT)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;OIT&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La proportion de la population active sous le seuil de pauvreté international de 1,90 $ américain par jour, également appelée taux de pauvreté des travailleurs, est définie comme la part des personnes actives vivant dans des ménages dont la consommation ou le revenu par habitant est inférieur au seuil de pauvreté international de 1,90 $ américain par jour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emploi : Toutes les personnes en âge de travailler qui, pendant une courte période de référence (une semaine), ont exercé une activité quelconque de production de biens ou de prestation de services contre rémunération ou profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seuil de pauvreté : Seuil en dessous duquel les individus de la population de référence sont considérés comme étant pauvres et au-dessus duquel ils sont considérés comme n&apos;étant pas pauvres. Le seuil est généralement défini comme les besoins monétaires par habitant dont un individu a besoin pour pouvoir faire l&apos;achat d&apos;un ensemble de biens et de services de base. Pour les besoins de cet indicateur, un seuil de pauvreté international absolu de 1,90 $ américain par jour est utilisé.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ménage en situation de pauvreté : Les ménages sont définis comme étant pauvres si leur revenu ou leurs dépenses de consommation sont inférieurs au seuil de pauvreté compte tenu du nombre de membres dans le ménage et de sa composition (par exemple, le nombre d&apos;adultes et d&apos;enfants).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travailleurs pauvres : Personnes actives vivant dans des ménages classés comme étant pauvres, c&apos;est-à-dire dont le revenu ou le niveau de consommation est inférieur au seuil de pauvreté utilisé pour la mesure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pourcentage&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;La source de données privilégiée est une enquête auprès des ménages contenant des variables pouvant identifier de manière fiable à la fois le statut de pauvreté des ménages et l&apos;activité économique des membres du ménage. Les exemples comprennent les enquêtes sur les revenus et les dépenses des ménages, les enquêtes de mesure du niveau de vie avec des modules sur l&apos;emploi et les enquêtes sur la population active qui recueillent des informations sur le revenu des ménages. Ces enquêtes présentent l&apos;avantage de permettre que les variables relatives à la situation d&apos;emploi et au revenu (ou aux dépenses de consommation) soient dérivées des mêmes ménages échantillonnés, idéalement pour la même période d&apos;observation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les estimations de l&apos;emploi dérivées d&apos;une enquête auprès des ménages autre qu&apos;une enquête sur la population active peuvent toutefois ne pas être les plus robustes en raison de la conception du questionnaire. De même, une enquête sur la population active peut ne pas être le meilleur instrument de collecte pour des données sur les revenus ou les dépenses de consommation des ménages, bien qu&apos;un module de revenu puisse être conçu pour obtenir des résultats statistiquement fiables, notamment en assurant un chevauchement de la période d&apos;observation entre les revenus (ou les dépenses de consommation) des ménages et la situation d&apos;emploi. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Une autre possibilité consiste à combiner les données d&apos;une enquête sur les revenus et les dépenses des ménages et d&apos;une enquête distincte sur la population active lorsque les ménages répondants peuvent être appariés et que la cohérence sur une longue période d&apos;observation entre les enquêtes peut être obtenue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;OIT traite les ensembles de microdonnées des enquêtes nationales aurpès des ménages conformément aux concepts et définitions des indicateurs convenus au niveau international et définis par la Conférence internationale des statisticiens du travail. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;En continu&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les données nationales sont mises à jour chaque semaine sur la plateforme ILOSTAT. Les estimations mondiales et régionales sont mises à jour une fois par an (en novembre ou en décembre). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Principalement les Bureaux nationaux de statistique.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;OIT&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L&apos;OIT est le point focal des Nations Unies pour les statistiques du travail. Elle établit des normes internationales pour les statistiques du travail par le biais de la Conférence internationale des statisticiens du travail. Elle compile et produit également des statistiques du travail dans le but de diffuser des ensembles de données comparables au niveau international, et fournit une assistance technique et une formation aux états membres de l&apos;OIT afin de soutenir leurs efforts pour produire des données sur le marché du travail de haute qualité. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pour éradiquer la pauvreté, nous devons en comprendre les causes profondes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le taux de pauvreté des travailleurs révèle la proportion de la population active qui vit dans la pauvreté en dépit d&apos;être employée, ce qui implique que leurs revenus liés à l&apos;emploi ne sont pas suffisants pour les sortir, eux et leurs familles, de la pauvreté et leur assurer des conditions de vie décentes. L&apos;adéquation des revenus est un aspect fondamental de la qualité de l&apos;emploi, et ces déficits contribuent à maintenir les travailleurs et leurs familles dans la pauvreté.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La proportion de travailleurs pauvres (c&apos;est-à-dire le taux de pauvreté des travailleurs) combine les données sur le revenu ou la consommation des ménages avec les variables du cadre de la population active mesurées au niveau individuel et met en lumière la relation entre l&apos;emploi et la pauvreté des ménages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Au niveau national, les comparaisons dans le temps peuvent être affectées par des facteurs tels que les changements de types d&apos;enquêtes ou de méthodes de collecte de données. L&apos;utilisation des PPA plutôt que des taux de change du marché garantit la prise en compte des différences de niveaux de prix entre les pays. Toutefois, on ne peut pas affirmer de manière catégorique que deux personnes dans deux pays différents, vivant avec moins de 1,90 $ américain par jour en PPA, sont confrontées au même degré de privation ou ont le même niveau de besoins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La pauvreté dans le contexte de cet indicateur est un concept qui s&apos;applique aux ménages, et non aux individus, et part du principe que les ménages mettent leurs revenus en commun. Cette hypothèse n&apos;est pas toujours vraie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En outre, le statut de pauvreté d&apos;un ménage est fonction du salaire et des autres revenus liés à l&apos;emploi obtenus par les membres du ménage qui ont un emploi, des revenus tirés de la possession d&apos;actifs, plus tout autre revenu disponible tel que les paiements de transfert ainsi que du nombre de membres dans le ménage. Le fait qu&apos;un travailleur soit considéré comme un travailleur pauvre dépend donc de son propre revenu, du revenu des autres membres du ménage et du nombre de membres qui doivent être soutenus dans le ménage. Il est donc souvent utile d&apos;étudier la structure des ménages par rapport à la pauvreté des travailleurs. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;T&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;x&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;v&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;é&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;v&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;P&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;v&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;v&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;v&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;v&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;m&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mn&gt;1&lt;/mn&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;,&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;mn&gt;90&lt;/mn&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;$&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;(&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;U&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;S&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;D&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;)&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;j&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;E&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;m&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;&amp;#xD7;&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;100&lt;/mn&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L&apos;OIT procède à des consultations annuelles avec les Etats membres par le biais du questionnaire d&apos;ILOSTAT et du système de rapports statistiques (« Statistics Reporting System » (StaRS)). Les fournisseurs de données nationaux reçoivent un lien vers le portail où ils peuvent examiner toutes les données nationales sur les ODD disponibles dans ILOSTAT.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dans le cadre de l’initiative de l’OIT sur les microdonnées harmonisées, l’OIT s’efforce de produire des statistiques du travail comparables au niveau international en se basant sur des concepts et définitions d’indicateurs adoptés par la Conférence internationale des statisticiens du travail. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Les estimations sont produites pour les pays et les années pour lesquels aucune estimation directe de la pauvreté des travailleurs, basée sur des estimations d&apos;enquêtes auprès des ménages, n&apos;est disponible, mais pour lesquels des estimations de la pauvreté totale sont disponibles dans la base de données PovcalNet de la Banque mondiale. Ceci est effectué par le biais d&apos;un modèle de régression multivarié décrit dans le document (en anglais) « Employment and economic class in the developing world » (Kapsos et Bourmpoula, 2013), disponible à l&apos;adresse &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Suite à l&apos;étape décrite directement ci-dessus, les données manquantes au niveau national sont estimées par un modèle de régression multivarié dans le but de produire des estimations globales et régionales.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L&apos;OIT produit des estimations mondiales et régionales de l&apos;emploi par classe économique (et donc, des taux de pauvreté des travailleurs) en utilisant le modèle de l&apos;emploi par classe de l&apos;OIT. Ces estimations font partie de la série des Estimations et Prévisions de l&apos;OIT, analysées dans les rapports de l&apos;OIT sur les Perspectives mondiales de l&apos;emploi et de la société. Pour plus d&apos;informations sur le modèle utilisé pour obtenir ces estimations, il est possible de consulter le document de l&apos;OIT (en anglais) « Employment and economic class in the developing world » (Kapsos et Bourmpoula, 2013), disponible à l&apos;adresse suivante : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les estimations nationales de la pauvreté différeront de cet indicateur des ODD. Cet indicateur des ODD utilise le seuil de pauvreté international, actuellement fixé à 1,90 $ (dollar américain) à parité de pouvoir d’achat. Pour plus d’informations, consulter le document (en anglais) « Decent Work and the Sustainable Development Goals: A Guidebook on SDG Labour Market Indicators » (OIT) &lt;a href=&quot;https://labordoc.ilo.org/discovery/delivery/41ILO_INST:41ILO_V2/1257239980002676&quot;&gt;https://labordoc.ilo.org/discovery/delivery/41ILO_INST:41ILO_V2/1257239980002676&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Des contrôles de cohérence et de qualité des données sont régulièrement effectués pour valider les données avant leur diffusion dans la base de données d&apos;ILOSTAT. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disponibilité des données :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données pour cet indicateur sont disponibles pour 117 pays et territoires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Séries chronologiques :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ceci couvre les années 2000 à 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Désagrégation :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le taux de pauvreté des travailleurs (proportion des travailleurs pauvres) est désagrégé par sexe et par âge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les estimations nationales de la pauvreté différeront de cet indicateur des ODD. Cet indicateur des ODD utilise le seuil de pauvreté international, actuellement fixé à 1,90 $ (dollar américain) à parité de pouvoir d’achat. Pour plus d’informations, consulter le document (en anglais) « Decent Work and the Sustainable Development Goals: A Guidebook on SDG Labour Market Indicators » (OIT) &lt;a href=&quot;https://labordoc.ilo.org/discovery/delivery/41ILO_INST:41ILO_V2/1257239980002676&quot;&gt;https://labordoc.ilo.org/discovery/delivery/41ILO_INST:41ILO_V2/1257239980002676&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(En anglais) « Decent Work and the Sustainable Development Goals: A Guidebook on SDG Labour Market Indicators » (OIT) &lt;a href=&quot;https://labordoc.ilo.org/discovery/delivery/41ILO_INST:41ILO_V2/1257239980002676&quot;&gt;https://labordoc.ilo.org/discovery/delivery/41ILO_INST:41ILO_V2/1257239980002676&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ILOSTAT (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/fr/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/fr/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Page sur la pauvreté des travailleurs de l&apos;ILOSTAT (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/fr/topics/working-poor/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/fr/topics/working-poor/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(En anglais) « Employment and economic class in the developing world » (Kapsos et Bourmpoula, 2013) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(En anglais) « Decent Work Indicators Manual » &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---integration/documents/publication/wcms_229374.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---integration/documents/publication/wcms_229374.pdf&lt;/a&gt; (deuxième version, page 70).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt">&lt;p&gt;Objectivo 1: Erradicar a proreza em todas as suas formas, em todos os lugares&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 1.1: Até 2030, erradicar a pobreza extrema em todos os lugares, atualmente medida como pessoas que vivem com menos de 1,25 dólares por dia&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 1: Повсеместная ликвидация нищеты во всех ее формах&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 1.1: К 2030 году ликвидировать крайнюю нищету для всех людей во всем мире (в настоящее время крайняя нищета определяется как проживание на сумму менее чем 1,25 долл. США в день)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 1.1.1: Доля населения, живущего за международной чертой бедности, в разбивке по полу, возрасту, статусу занятости и месту проживания (городское/сельское)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Последнее обновление: март 2020 года &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Связанные показатели по состоянию на февраль 2020 года&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Институциональная информация&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Организация(и):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;МОТ&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Понятия и определения&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Определение:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Доля занятого населения, живущего ниже международной черты бедности, составляющей 1,90 долл. США в день, также называемой уровнем бедности среди работающего населения, определяется как доля занятого населения, живущего в домохозяйствах со среднедушевым потреблением или доходом, ниже международной черты бедности, составляющей 1,90 долл. США.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Понятия:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Занятость:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Все лица трудоспособного возраста, которые в течение короткого отчетного периода (одна неделя) занимались какой-либо деятельностью по производству товаров или оказанию услуг за плату или получение прибыли.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Черта бедности:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Порог, ниже которого люди в исследуемой группе населения считаются бедными и выше которого они не считаются бедными. Пороговый показатель обычно определяется как требуемые среднедушевые денежные средства, необходимые человеку для того, чтобы позволить себе приобрести базовый пакет товаров и услуг. Для целей этого показателя используется международная черта абсолютной бедности в размере 1,90 долл. США в день.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Бедное домохозяйство:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Домашние хозяйства определяются как бедные, если их доходы или потребительские расходы находятся ниже черты бедности с учетом количества членов домохозяйства и его состава (например, количества взрослых и детей)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Работающие бедняки:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Люди, работающие по найму, живущие в домохозяйствах, которые классифицируются как бедные, т.е. те, которые имеют уровни дохода или потребления, ниже используемой для оценки черты бедности.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Источники данных&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Описание&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Предпочтительным источником данных является обследование домохозяйств, содержащее переменные, которые могут надежно определять как статус бедности домохозяйств, так и экономическую активность членов домохозяйства. Примерами могут служить обследования доходов и расходов домохозяйств (ОДРД), обследования оценки уровня жизни (ООУЖ), включающие в себя модули занятости или обследования рабочей силы (ОРС), при проведении которых собирается информация о доходах домохозяйства. Такие обследования обладают тем преимуществом, что позволяют получать переменные о статусе занятости и доходах (или расходах на потребление) из одних и тех же отобранных домохозяйств, в идеале в течение одного и того же периода наблюдения.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Оценки занятости, полученные из какого-либо обследования домохозяйства, но не из обследования рабочей силы, могут, однако, быть не самыми надежными из-за проблем со структурой вопросника. Точно так же обследование рабочей силы может быть не лучшим инструментом для сбора данных по доходам или расходам на потребление домохозяйств, хотя прилагаемый модуль дохода может быть спроектирован для достижения статистически достоверных результатов, включая обеспечение совпадения в период наблюдения доходов домохозяйств (или потребительских расходов) и статуса занятости.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Другой возможностью является объединение данных из обследования доходов и расходов домохозяйств и из отдельного обследования рабочей силы, когда можно сопоставить домохозяйства респондентов и добиться согласованности между обследованиями в течение длительного периода наблюдения.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Процесс сбора:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Календарь&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Сбор данных:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Выпуск данных: &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Поставщики данных&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;В основном национальные статистические управления.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Составители данных&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;МОТ&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Обоснование:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Для того, чтобы искоренить нищету, мы должны понять причины, лежащие в ее основе.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Уровень бедности среди работающих показывает долю занятого населения, живущего в бедности, несмотря на то, что они являются занятыми, что означает, что их доходов, получаемых в связи с занятостью, недостаточно для того, чтобы вытащить их и их семьи из бедности и обеспечить достойные условия жизни. Достаточность доходов является основополагающим аспектом качества рабочего места, и этот недостаток в качестве рабочего места может удерживать работников и их семьи в бедности.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Доля бедных среди работающих в общей численности занятого населения (т.е. уровень бедности среди работающих) объединяет данные о доходе или потреблении домохозяйств с концептуальными переменными рабочей силы, оцениваемыми на уровне работника, и проливает свет на взаимосвязь между занятостью и бедностью домохозяйств.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Комментарии и ограничения:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;На страновом уровне на сопоставления в динамике по времени могут влиять такие факторы, как изменения в типах обследований или методах сбора данных. Использование данных по ППС, а не рыночных обменных курсов, обеспечивает уверенность, что учтены различия в уровнях цен в разных странах. Однако нельзя категорически утверждать, что два человека в двух разных странах, живущие ниже черты в 1,90 доллара США в день по ППС, сталкиваются с одинаковой степенью обездоленности или испытывают одинаковую степень нужды.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Бедность в контексте этого показателя - это понятие, которое применяется к домашним хозяйствам, а не к отдельным лицам, основываясь на предположении о том, что в домашних хозяйствах доходы объединяются. Но это предположение не всегда может быть верным.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Более того, статус бедности какого-либо домохозяйства зависит от заработной платы и других доходов, связанных с занятостью, которые обеспечиваются членами домохозяйства, работающими по найму, доходов, получаемых от владения активами, а также от любых других имеющихся доходов, таких как трансфертные платежи, а также от количества членов домохозяйства. Поэтому вопрос о том, считается ли работник работающим бедняком, зависит от его или ее собственного дохода, дохода других членов домохозяйства и числа членов домохозяйства, нуждающихся в поддержке. Таким образом, часто бывает полезно изучить структуру домохозяйств в вопросе бедности среди работающих. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Уровень бедности среди работающих &amp;#xA0; = ((Занятые лица, живущие менее чем на 1,90 доллара США в день) / (Общая занятость)) x 100 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Обработка отсутствующих значений:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;На страновом уровне&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;На региональном и глобальном уровнях&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Региональные агрегаты&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;МОТ производит глобальные и региональные оценки занятости по экономическим классам (и, следовательно, уровням бедности среди работающих) с использованием модели Занятости по Классам (ЗпК) Международной организации труда (МОТ). Эти оценки являются частью рядов данных по оценкам и прогнозам МОТ, анализируемым в докладах МОТ о мировой занятости и социальных перспективах. Для получения дополнительной информации о модели, используемой для получения этих оценок, см. статью МОТ &quot;Занятость и экономический класс в развивающемся мире&quot; (Kapsos and Bourmpoula, 2013), доступную на 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&gt;
http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Доступные странам методы и руководства для составления данных на национальном уровне:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обеспечение качества: &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Наличие данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Всемирный банк проводит работу по дезагрегированным оценкам бедности. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Источники расхождений:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Ссылки&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Достойная работа и Цели в области устойчивого развития: Руководство по показателям ЦУР рынка труда (МОТ)
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/langen/index.htm&quot;&gt;
https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;ILOSTAT (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ILOSTAT&amp;#x2019;тематическая страница о бедности среди работающих (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/topics/working-poor/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/topics/working-poor/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Занятость и экономический класс в развивающемся мире (Kapsos and Bourmpoula, 2013) 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&quot;&gt;
http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---inst/documents/publication/wcms_216451.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Руководство по показателям достойного труда &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---integration/documents/publication/wcms_229374.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---integration/documents/publication/wcms_229374.pdf&lt;/a&gt; (вторая версия, стр. 70).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
