<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 10-5-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 10: Reduce inequality within and among countries&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 10.5: Improve the regulation and monitoring of global financial markets and institutions and strengthen the implementation of such regulations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 10.5.1: Financial Soundness Indicators (FSIs)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;03 December 2018&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Linkages with any other Goals and Targets: Recommendation II.2 of G-20 Data Gap Initiative &amp;#x2013; 2 concerns FSIs. Its target is by 2021, G-20 economies to report the seven FSIs expected from the Special Data Dissemination Standards Plus (SDDS Plus) adherent economies on a quarterly frequency, with a timeliness of one quarter. The seven SDG FSIs are the same as the FSIs under SDDS, but with one exception under SDDS Plus, where resident real estate price index is used instead of net open position in foreign exchange to capital.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;International Monetary Fund&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;International Monetary Fund&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seven FSIs are included as SDG indicators for 10.5.1 and expressed as percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 - Regulatory Tier 1 capital to assets &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 - Regulatory Tier 1 capital to risk- weighted assets &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 - Nonperforming loans net of provisions to capital &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 - Nonperforming loans to total gross loans &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 - Return on assets &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6 - Liquid assets to short-term liabilities &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7 - Net open position in foreign exchange to capital &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regulatory Tier 1 capital to assets&lt;/strong&gt;: This is the ratio of the core capital (Tier 1) to total (balance sheet) assets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regulatory Tier 1 capital to risk- weighted assets&lt;/strong&gt;: It is calculated using total regulatory Tier 1 capital as the numerator and risk-weighted assets as the denominator. The data for this FSI are compiled in accordance with the guidelines of either Basel I, Basel II, or Basel III. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nonperforming loans net of provisions to capital&lt;/strong&gt;: This FSI is calculated by taking the value of nonperforming loans (NPLs) less the value of specific loan loss provisions as the numerator and capital as the denominator. Capital is measured as total regulatory capital. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nonperforming loans to total gross loans&lt;/strong&gt;: This FSI is calculated by using the value of NPLs as the numerator and the total value of the loan portfolio (including NPLs, and before the deduction of specific loan- loss provisions) as the denominator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Return on assets&lt;/strong&gt;: This FSI is calculated by dividing annualized net income before extraordinary items and taxes (as recommended in the FSI Guide) by the average value of total assets (financial and nonfinancial) over the same period. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liquid assets to short-term liabilities&lt;/strong&gt;: This FSI is calculated by using the core measure of liquid assets as the numerator and short-term liabilities as the denominator. The ratio can also be calculated by taking the broad measure of liquid assets as the numerator. For jurisdictions that have implemented Basel III, this indicator could be supplemented with the liquidity coverage ratio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Net open position in foreign exchange to capital&lt;/strong&gt;: The net open position in foreign exchange should be calculated based on the recommendation of the Basel Committee for Banking Supervision (BCBS). Capital should be total regulatory capital as net open position in foreign exchange is a supervisory concept. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regulatory Tier 1 capital to assets&lt;/strong&gt;: Regulatory Tier 1 capital is calculated based on Basel I, II, or III depending on countries&amp;#x2019; supervisory practices. Denominator is total balance sheet (non-risk weighted) assets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regulatory Tier 1 capital to risk- weighted assets&lt;/strong&gt;: Regulatory Tier 1 capital is calculated based on Basel I, II, or III depending on countries&amp;#x2019; supervisory practices. Denominator is risk-weighted assets also calculated based on Basel standards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nonperforming loans (NPLs) net of provisions to capital&lt;/strong&gt;: A loan is classified as NPL when payment of principal or interest is past due by 90 days or more, or evidence exists that a full or partial amount of a loan is not going to be recovered. Only specific loan loss provisions are used in this calculation and they refer charges against the value of specific loans. Data exclude accrued interest in NPLs. Capital is measured as total regulatory capital calculated based on Basel I, II, or III depending on countries&amp;#x2019; supervisory practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nonperforming loans to total gross loans&lt;/strong&gt;: A loan is classified as NPL when payment of principal or interest is past due by 90 days or more, or evidence exists that a full or partial amount of a loan is not going to be recovered. The denominator is the total value of the loan portfolio (including NPLs, and before the deduction of specific loan- loss provisions). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Return on assets&lt;/strong&gt;: The numerator is annualized net income before extraordinary items and taxes. The denominator is the average value of total assets (financial and nonfinancial) over the same period. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liquid assets to short-term liabilities&lt;/strong&gt;: Core measure of liquid assets includes currency and deposits and other financial assets available on demand or within three months. Broad measures equal core measure plus securities traded in liquid markets that can be converted into cash with minimal change in value. The denominator is short-term elements of debt liabilities plus net (short-term) market value of financial derivatives position. The latter is calculated as financial derivatives liability position minus financial derivative asset position. Short-term refers to three months and should be defined on a remaining maturity basis. If remaining maturity is not available, original maturity can be used as an alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Net open position in foreign exchange to capital&lt;/strong&gt;: The net open position in foreign exchange equals the foreign-currency and foreign-currency linked element of balance sheet assets and off-balance sheet exposures minus the foreign-currency and foreign-currency linked element of balance sheet liabilities and off-balance sheet exposures. Foreign-currency-linked instruments refer to accounts denominated in national currency, but their payments are linked to exchange rates, thus subject to foreign exchange risk. The denominator is total regulatory capital as defined above. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The common source data are data reported by banks for supervisory purposes. They include balance sheet, income statement, and supervisory series (such as Tier 1 capital, Tier 2 capital, risk-weighted assets).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The national central banks or supervisory agencies collect these data for supervisory purposes, and these data are used for FSI compilation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are no predetermined deadlines. Countries report new FSIs as soon as they are ready&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data are disseminated on the IMF website as soon as they are ready.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The national central banks or bank supervisory agencies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The FSIs are compiled at national level, but not at region or global level. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regulatory Tier 1 capital to assets&lt;/strong&gt;: It is a more stringent version of the leverage ratio and indicates the extent to which assets are funded by other than own funds and is a measure of capital adequacy of the deposit-taking sector. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regulatory Tier 1 capital to risk- weighted assets&lt;/strong&gt;: It measures the capital adequacy of deposit takers based on the core capital concept of the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision (BCBS). Capital adequacy and availability ultimately determine the degree of robustness of financial institutions to withstand shocks to their balance sheets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nonperforming loans net of provisions to capital&lt;/strong&gt;: This FSI is a capital adequacy ratio and is an important indicator of the capacity of bank capital to withstand losses from NPLs that are not covered by specific loan loss provisions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nonperforming loans to total gross loans&lt;/strong&gt;: This FSI is often used as a proxy for asset quality and is intended to identify problems with asset quality in the loan portfolio. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Return on assets&lt;/strong&gt;: It is an indicator of bank profitability and is intended to measure deposit takers&amp;#x2019; efficiency in using their assets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liquid assets to short-term liabilities&lt;/strong&gt;: It is a liquid asset ratio and is intended to capture the liquidity mismatch of assets and liabilities and provides an indication of the extent to which deposit takers can meet the short-term withdrawal of funds without facing liquidity problems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Net open position in foreign exchange to capital&lt;/strong&gt;: This FSI is an indicator of sensitivity to market risk, which is intended to gauge deposit takers&amp;#x2019; exposure to exchange rate risk compared with capital. It measures the mismatch of foreign currency asset and liability positions to assess the vulnerability to exchange rate movements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data for most countries are reported on a monthly or quarterly basis; a few countries report data on a semi-annual basis and with a lag of more than a quarter. As of end-December 2018, there were 138 FSI reporters. Some countries&amp;#x2019; compilation practices deviate from the FSI Guide methodology in certain areas and are documented in the FSI metadata also posted on the IMF&amp;#x2019;s FSI website. Reporting countries provide all or most core FSIs and some encouraged FSIs that can be used to support the interpretation of these seven SDG indicators. FSI data and metadata reported by countries are available at http://data.imf.org/FSI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The calculation of the seven FSIs is detailed in section on &amp;#x201C;Definition&amp;#x201D; above. The common source data are data reported by banks to supervisory authorities, which are usually the FSI compilers. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; At country level&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not relevant to the seven FSIs. Source data are collected by banks&amp;#x2019; supervisory authorities and complete reporting is usually mandated by law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; At regional and global levels&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FSIs are not compiled at regional or global levels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The FSIs are not aggregated at regional levels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The FSI Compilation Guide (206) available at http://data.imf.org/FSI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The common source data are data reported by banks for supervisory purposes. National supervisors check and validate the data that are used by national FSI compilers. IMF staff check the FSIs reported by countries before posting on the FSI website and address data issues in collaboration with the national compilers whenever such issues are flagged by the validation and consistency checks implemented in the IMF data processing system.. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data availability:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of end-December 2018, there were 138 FSI reporters. All countries report all or most core FSIs and some encouraged FSIs that can be used to support the interpretation of these seven SDG indicators. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time series:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data for most countries are reported on a monthly or quarterly basis; a few countries report data on a semi-annual basis and with a lag of more than a quarter. Data are available as far back as 2005 for some countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FSIs disseminated by the IMF are weighted averages for the sector as a whole (e.g., deposit takers, other financial corporations, nonfinancial corporations). Data for parent banks, their branches, and relevant subsidiaries are consolidated; if this consolidation is not possible or not applicable, an explanation is provided in the metadata. There are no disaggregated breakdowns of the FSIs reported to the IMF.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data calculated by other sources could be different from the FSIs disseminated by the IMF due to the use of different compilation methodology and/or institutional coverage. The FSIs disseminated by the IMF are compiled based on the &lt;em&gt;FSI Compilation Guide&lt;/em&gt;, which provides the guidance on the concepts and definitions, and sources and techniques for the compilation of cross-country comparable data to support national and international surveillance of financial systems. To facilitate identification of possible discrepancies across countries, reporters provide metadata to the IMF that detail departures from recommendations in the &lt;em&gt;FSI Guide&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; http://data.imf.org/FSI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 10: Reducir la desigualdad en los países y entre ellos&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 10.5: Mejorar la reglamentación y vigilancia de las instituciones y los mercados financieros mundiales y fortalecer la aplicación de esos reglamentos&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 10.5.1: Indicadores de solidez financiera&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 3 de diciembre de 2018 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vínculos con otros objetivos y metas: La recomendación II.2 de la Iniciativa sobre la Brecha de Datos del G-20 &amp;#x2013; 2 se refiere a los ISF. Su objetivo es que, para 2021, las economías del G-20 informen sobre los siete ISF que se esperan de las economías adheridas a las Normas Especiales para la Divulgación de Datos Plus (NEDD Plus) con una frecuencia trimestral, con una puntualidad de un trimestre. Los siete ISF de las NEDD son los mismos que los de las NEDD, pero con una excepción en las NEDD Plus, en las que se utiliza el índice de precios de los bienes inmuebles residentes en lugar de la posición abierta neta en divisas al capital.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fondo Monetario Internacional&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Fondo Monetario Internacional&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se incluyen siete ISF como indicadores de los ODS para el 10.5.1 y se expresan en porcentaje.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Capital reglamentario de nivel 1 en relación con los activos &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Capital reglamentario de nivel 1 en relación con los activos ponderados en función del riesgo &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Créditos morosos netos de provisiones sobre capital &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Créditos morosos sobre el total de créditos brutos &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rendimiento de los activos &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Activos líquidos sobre pasivos a corto plazo &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Posición abierta neta en divisas sobre capital &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Capital reglamentario de nivel 1 sobre activos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Se trata de la relación entre el capital básico (Tier 1) y los activos totales (de balance). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Capital reglamentario de nivel 1 en relación con los activos ponderados por riesgo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; Se calcula utilizando el capital reglamentario total de nivel 1 como numerador y los activos ponderados por riesgo como denominador. Los datos de este ISF se compilan de acuerdo con las directrices de Basilea I, Basilea II o Basilea III. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Préstamos morosos netos de provisiones sobre el capital &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Este ISF se calcula tomando el valor de los préstamos morosos (NPL) menos el valor de las provisiones específicas para pérdidas de préstamos como numerador y el capital como denominador. El capital se mide como capital reglamentario total. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Préstamos morosos sobre el total de préstamos brutos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; Este ISF se calcula utilizando el valor de los préstamos morosos como numerador y el valor total de la cartera de préstamos (incluidos los préstamos morosos y antes de deducir las provisiones específicas para pérdidas de préstamos) como denominador. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rendimiento de los activos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; Este ISF se calcula dividiendo los ingresos netos anualizados antes de partidas extraordinarias e impuestos (como se recomienda en la Guía de los ISF) por el valor medio de los activos totales (financieros y no financieros) durante el mismo período. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Activos líquidos sobre pasivos a corto plazo &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: Este ISF se calcula utilizando la medida básica de los activos líquidos como numerador y los pasivos a corto plazo como denominador. El coeficiente también puede calcularse tomando como numerador la medida amplia de los activos líquidos. Para las jurisdicciones que han implementado Basilea III, este indicador podría complementarse con el ratio de cobertura de liquidez.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Posición abierta neta en divisas sobre capital&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: La posición abierta neta en divisas debe calcularse sobre la base de la recomendación del Comité de Supervisión Bancaria de Basilea (BCBS). El capital debe ser el capital reglamentario total, ya que la posición abierta neta en divisas es un concepto de supervisión. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Capital regulatorio de nivel 1 en relación con los activos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; El capital regulatorio de nivel 1 se calcula sobre la base de Basilea I, II o III, dependiendo de las prácticas de supervisión de los países. El denominador es el total de activos del balance (no ponderados por el riesgo). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Capital reglamentario de nivel 1 en relación con los activos ponderados por riesgo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: El capital reglamentario de nivel 1 se calcula sobre la base de Basilea I, II o III, dependiendo de las prácticas de supervisión de los países. El denominador son los activos ponderados por riesgo, también calculados según las normas de Basilea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Préstamos morosos (NPLs) netos de provisiones al capital&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; Un préstamo se clasifica como NPL cuando el pago del principal o de los intereses está vencido por 90 días o más, o existe evidencia de que un monto total o parcial de un préstamo no va a ser recuperado. En este cálculo sólo se utilizan las provisiones para pérdidas de préstamos específicos y se refieren a los cargos contra el valor de préstamos específicos. Los datos excluyen los intereses devengados en los préstamos morosos. El capital se mide como capital reglamentario total calculado sobre la base de Basilea I, II o III, dependiendo de las prácticas de supervisión de los países.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Préstamos morosos sobre el total de préstamos brutos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; Un préstamo se clasifica como moroso cuando el pago del principal o de los intereses está vencido desde hace 90 días o existe evidencia de que no se va a recuperar la totalidad o parte del préstamo. El denominador es el valor total de la cartera de préstamos (incluida la morosidad, y antes de deducir las provisiones específicas para préstamos). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rendimiento de los activos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: El numerador es el resultado neto anualizado antes de partidas extraordinarias e impuestos. El denominador es el valor medio de los activos totales (financieros y no financieros) durante el mismo periodo. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Activos líquidos sobre pasivos a corto plazo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; La medida básica de los activos líquidos incluye el efectivo y los depósitos y otros activos financieros disponibles a la vista o en un plazo de tres meses. La medida amplia es igual a la medida básica más los valores negociados en mercados líquidos que pueden convertirse en efectivo con un cambio de valor mínimo. El denominador son los elementos a corto plazo de los pasivos de deuda más el valor de mercado neto (a corto plazo) de la posición de los derivados financieros. Este último se calcula como la posición de pasivo de derivados financieros menos la posición de activo de derivados financieros. El corto plazo se refiere a tres meses y debe definirse sobre la base del vencimiento restante. Si no se dispone del plazo de vencimiento restante, puede utilizarse el plazo de vencimiento original como alternativa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Posición abierta neta en divisas sobre capital&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: La posición abierta neta en divisas es igual al elemento en moneda extranjera y vinculado a la moneda extranjera de los activos del balance y las exposiciones fuera de balance menos el elemento en moneda extranjera y vinculado a la moneda extranjera de los pasivos del balance y las exposiciones fuera de balance. Los instrumentos vinculados a divisas se refieren a cuentas denominadas en moneda nacional, pero sus pagos están vinculados a los tipos de cambio, por lo que están sujetos al riesgo de cambio. El denominador es el capital reglamentario total, tal como se ha definido anteriormente. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Descripción:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La fuente de datos común son los datos comunicados por los bancos con fines de supervisión. Incluyen el balance, los estados de resultados y las medidas de supervisión (como el capital Tier 1, el capital Tier 2 y los activos ponderados por riesgo).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Proceso de recopilación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los bancos centrales nacionales o las agencias de supervisión recopilan estos datos con fines de supervisión, y estos datos se utilizan para la compilación de FSI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendario&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recopilación de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No hay plazos predeterminados. Los países comunican los nuevos ISF en cuanto están listos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publicación de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos se difunden en el sitio web del FMI en cuanto están listos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los bancos centrales nacionales o las agencias de supervisión bancaria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los ISF se recopilan a nivel nacional, pero no a nivel regional o mundial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Capital reglamentario de nivel 1 en relación con los activos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Es una versión más estricta del ratio de apalancamiento e indica el grado en que los activos se financian con fondos distintos de los propios y es una medida de la adecuación del capital del sector de la captación de depósitos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Capital reglamentario de nivel 1 en relación con los activos ponderados por el riesgo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Mide la adecuación del capital de las instituciones de depósito basándose en el concepto de capital básico del Comité de Supervisión Bancaria de Basilea (BCBS). La adecuación y la disponibilidad de capital determinan, en última instancia, el grado de solidez de las instituciones financieras para resistir las perturbaciones en sus balances. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Créditos morosos netos de provisiones sobre capital&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; Este ISF es un coeficiente de adecuación del capital y es un indicador importante de la capacidad del capital bancario para soportar las pérdidas derivadas de los créditos morosos que no están cubiertas por las provisiones específicas para créditos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Créditos morosos sobre el total de créditos brutos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Este ISF se utiliza a menudo como indicador de la calidad de los activos y tiene por objeto identificar los problemas de calidad de los activos en la cartera de préstamos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rendimiento de los activos&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Es un indicador de la rentabilidad de los bancos y pretende medir la eficiencia de las entidades de depósito en el uso de sus activos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Activos líquidos sobre pasivos a corto plazo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Es un ratio de activos líquidos y pretende captar el desajuste de liquidez de los activos y los pasivos y proporciona una indicación de la medida en que las instituciones de depósito pueden hacer frente a la retirada de fondos a corto plazo sin enfrentarse a problemas de liquidez. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Posición abierta neta en divisas respecto al capital&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; Este ISF es un indicador de la sensibilidad al riesgo de mercado, que pretende medir la exposición de las instituciones de depósito al riesgo de tipo de cambio en comparación con el capital. Mide el desajuste de las posiciones activas y pasivas en moneda extranjera para evaluar la vulnerabilidad a los movimientos del tipo de cambio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos de la mayoría de los países se informan con carácter mensual o trimestral; unos pocos países informan los datos con carácter semestral y con un desfase de más de un trimestre. A finales de diciembre de 2018, había 138 informadores de ISF. Las prácticas de compilación de algunos países&amp;#x2019; se desvían de la metodología de la Guía de los ISF en ciertas áreas y se documentan en los metadatos de los ISF que también se publican en el sitio web de los ISF del FMI&amp;#x2019;. Los países informantes proporcionan todos o la mayoría de los ISF básicos y algunos ISF recomendados que pueden utilizarse para apoyar la interpretación de estos siete indicadores de los ODS. Los datos y metadatos de los ISF notificados por los países están disponibles en &lt;a href=&quot;http://data.imf.org/FSI.&quot;&gt;http://data.imf.org/FSI.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El cálculo de los siete ISF se detalla en la sección &amp;#x201C;Definición&amp;#x201D; anterior. La fuente de datos común son los datos comunicados por los bancos a las autoridades de supervisión, que suelen ser los compiladores de los ISF. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel de país:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No es relevante para los siete ISF. Las autoridades supervisoras de los bancos recopilan los datos de las fuentes&amp;#x2019; y la información completa suele ser obligatoria por ley&lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel regional y mundial:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los ISF no se recopilan a nivel regional ni mundial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los ISF no están agregados a nivel regional.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Métodos y directrices a disposición de los países para la compilación de los datos a nivel nacional:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La guía de compilación de los ISF (206), disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://data.imf.org/FSI&quot;&gt;http://data.imf.org/FSI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Garantía de calidad:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La fuente de datos común son los datos comunicados por los bancos a efectos de supervisión. Los supervisores nacionales comprueban y validan los datos que utilizan los compiladores nacionales de los ISF. El personal del FMI comprueba los ISF notificados por los países antes de publicarlos en el sitio web de los ISF y aborda los problemas de los datos en colaboración con los compiladores nacionales cuando los controles de validación y coherencia implementados en el sistema de procesamiento de datos del FMI señalan dichos problemas. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Descripción:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A finales de diciembre de 2018, había 138 informadores de ISF. Todos los países informan todos o la mayoría de los ISF básicos y algunos ISF fomentados que pueden utilizarse para apoyar la interpretación de estos siete indicadores de los ODS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Los datos de la mayoría de los países se comunican con carácter mensual o trimestral; algunos países comunican los datos con carácter semestral y con un desfase de más de un trimestre. Los datos de algunos países se remontan a 2005.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desglose:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Los ISF difundidos por el FMI son promedios ponderados para el sector en su conjunto (por ejemplo, instituciones de depósito, otras sociedades financieras, sociedades no financieras). Los datos de las casas matrices de los bancos, sus sucursales y las filiales pertinentes se consolidan; si esta consolidación no es posible o no es aplicable, se brinda una explicación en los metadatos. No existen desgloses de los ISF notificados al FMI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Fuentes de discrepancia:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos calculados por otras fuentes podrían ser diferentes de los ISF difundidos por el FMI debido al uso de una metodología de compilación diferente y/o a la cobertura institucional. Los ISF difundidos por el FMI se compilan sobre la base de la &lt;em&gt;Guía de compilación de los ISF&lt;/em&gt;, que ofrece orientación sobre los conceptos y definiciones, y las fuentes y técnicas para la compilación de datos comparables entre países en apoyo de la supervisión nacional e internacional de los sistemas financieros. Para facilitar la identificación de posibles discrepancias entre países, los informadores proporcionan al FMI metadatos que detallan las desviaciones de las recomendaciones de la &lt;em&gt;Guía de los ISF&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://data.imf.org/FSI&quot;&gt;http://data.imf.org/FSI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Referencias: &lt;/h2&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 10 : Réduire les inégalités dans les pays et d’un pays à l’autre&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 10.5 : Améliorer la réglementation et la surveillance des institutions et marchés financiers mondiaux et renforcer l’application des règles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 10.5.1 : Indicateurs de solidité financière&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dernière mise à jour : 03 Décembre 2018 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicateurs connexes &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liens avec d&apos;autres objectifs et cibles : La recommandation II.2 de l&apos;Initiative du G-20 sur le déficit de données &amp;#x2013; 2 concerne les ISF. Son objectif est que, d&apos;ici 2021, les économies du G-20 communiquent les sept ISF attendus des économies adhérant aux Normes spéciales de diffusion des données Plus (SDDS Plus) selon une fréquence trimestrielle, avec une actualité d&apos;un trimestre. Les sept ISF des SDG sont les mêmes que les ISF de la SDDS, à une exception près dans la SDDS Plus, où l&apos;indice des prix de l&apos;immobilier résident est utilisé à la place de la position ouverte nette en devises étrangères au capital.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Informations institutionnelles &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organisation(s) :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fonds monétaire international&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Définition : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sept ISF sont inclus en tant qu&apos;indicateurs des ODD pour 10.5.1 et exprimés en pourcentage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fonds propres réglementaires de catégorie 1 par rapport aux actifs &lt;/li&gt;.
&lt;li&gt;Fonds propres réglementaires de catégorie 1 par rapport aux actifs pondérés en fonction des risques &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prêts non productifs nets de provisions sur les fonds propres &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prêts non performants sur le total des prêts bruts &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rendement des actifs &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Liquidités sur passif à court terme &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Position ouverte nette en devises étrangères sur capital &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Fonds propres réglementaires de catégorie 1 sur l&apos;actif &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; : Il s&apos;agit du rapport entre les fonds propres de base (Tier 1) et le total des actifs (bilan). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Fonds propres réglementaires de catégorie 1 par rapport aux actifs pondérés en fonction des risques &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; : &lt;/em&gt; Il est calculé en utilisant le total des fonds propres réglementaires de catégorie 1 comme numérateur et les actifs pondérés en fonction des risques comme dénominateur. Les données de cet ISF sont compilées conformément aux directives de Bâle I, Bâle II ou Bâle III. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Prêts non performants nets de provisions par rapport au capital &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; : &lt;/em&gt; Cet ISF est calculé en prenant la valeur des prêts non performants (PNP) moins la valeur des provisions spécifiques pour pertes sur prêts comme numérateur et le capital comme dénominateur. Le capital est mesuré en tant que capital réglementaire total. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prêts non performants par rapport au total des prêts bruts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; :&lt;/em&gt; Cet ISF est calculé en utilisant la valeur des NPL comme numérateur et la valeur totale du portefeuille de prêts (y compris les NPL, et avant la déduction des provisions spécifiques pour pertes sur prêts) comme dénominateur. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Rendement des actifs &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; : &lt;/em&gt; Cet ISF est calculé en divisant le bénéfice net annualisé avant éléments extraordinaires et impôts (comme recommandé dans le Guide de l&apos;ISF) par la valeur moyenne du total des actifs (financiers et non financiers) sur la même période. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Actifs liquides sur passifs à court terme &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; : Cet ISF est calculé en utilisant la mesure de base des actifs liquides comme numérateur et les engagements à court terme comme dénominateur. Le ratio peut également être calculé en prenant la mesure large des actifs liquides comme numérateur. Pour les juridictions qui ont mis en œuvre Bâle III, cet indicateur pourrait être complété par le ratio de couverture des liquidités.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Position nette ouverte en devises étrangères par rapport au capital &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; : La position ouverte nette en devises devrait être calculée sur la base de la recommandation du Comité de Bâle sur le contrôle bancaire (CBCB). Le capital devrait être le capital réglementaire total car la position nette ouverte en devises étrangères est un concept de supervision. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fonds propres réglementaires de catégorie 1 par rapport aux actifs &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; :&lt;/em&gt; Les fonds propres réglementaires de catégorie 1 sont calculés sur la base de Bâle I, II ou III selon les pratiques de supervision des pays. Le dénominateur est le total des actifs du bilan (non pondérés en fonction des risques). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Fonds propres réglementaires de catégorie 1 par rapport aux actifs pondérés en fonction des risques&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; : Les fonds propres réglementaires de catégorie 1 sont calculés sur la base de Bâle I, II ou III, selon les pratiques de surveillance des pays. Le dénominateur est l&apos;actif pondéré en fonction des risques, également calculé sur la base des normes de Bâle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Prêts non performants (PNP) nets des provisions au capital &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; :&lt;/em&gt; Un prêt est classé comme PNP lorsque le paiement du principal ou des intérêts est en retard de 90 jours ou plus, ou lorsqu&apos;il existe des preuves qu&apos;un montant total ou partiel d&apos;un prêt ne sera pas recouvré. Seules les provisions spécifiques pour pertes sur prêts sont utilisées dans ce calcul et elles font référence à des charges contre la valeur de prêts spécifiques. Les données excluent les intérêts courus dans les NPL. Le capital est mesuré en tant que capital réglementaire total calculé sur la base de Bâle I, II ou III, selon les pratiques de supervision des pays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Prêts non performants par rapport au total des prêts bruts&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; :&lt;/em&gt; Un prêt est classé comme NPL lorsque le paiement du principal ou des intérêts est en retard de 90 jours ou plus, ou lorsqu&apos;il existe des preuves qu&apos;un montant total ou partiel d&apos;un prêt ne sera pas recouvré. Le dénominateur est la valeur totale du portefeuille de prêts (y compris les NPL, et avant la déduction des provisions spécifiques pour pertes sur prêts). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Rendement des actifs &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; : Le numérateur est le bénéfice net annualisé avant éléments exceptionnels et impôts. Le dénominateur est la valeur moyenne de l&apos;actif total (financier et non financier) sur la même période. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Actifs liquides sur passifs à court terme &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; : &lt;/em&gt; La mesure de base des actifs liquides comprend la monnaie fiduciaire et les dépôts et autres actifs financiers disponibles sur demande ou dans les trois mois. La mesure large est égale à la mesure de base plus les titres négociés sur des marchés liquides qui peuvent être convertis en espèces avec une variation de valeur minimale. Le dénominateur est constitué des éléments à court terme des dettes plus la valeur de marché nette (à court terme) de la position en produits financiers dérivés. Cette dernière est calculée comme étant la position de passif des dérivés financiers moins la position d&apos;actif des dérivés financiers. Le court terme fait référence à trois mois et doit être défini sur la base de l&apos;échéance restante. Si l&apos;échéance résiduelle n&apos;est pas disponible, l&apos;échéance initiale peut être utilisée comme alternative. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Position nette ouverte en devises par rapport au capital &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; : La position ouverte nette en devises étrangères est égale à l&apos;élément en devises étrangères et lié à des devises étrangères de l&apos;actif du bilan et des expositions hors bilan moins l&apos;élément en devises étrangères et lié à des devises étrangères du passif du bilan et des expositions hors bilan. Les instruments liés à des devises étrangères font référence à des comptes libellés en monnaie nationale, mais dont les paiements sont liés à des taux de change, et donc soumis à un risque de change. Le dénominateur est le total des fonds propres réglementaires tels que définis ci-dessus. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Sources de données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données de source commune sont des données déclarées par les banques à des fins de surveillance. Elles comprennent le bilan, le compte de résultat et les séries prudentielles (telles que les fonds propres de catégorie 1, les fonds propres de catégorie 2, les actifs pondérés en fonction des risques).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Processus de collecte :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les banques centrales nationales ou les agences de surveillance collectent ces données à des fins de surveillance, et ces données sont utilisées pour la compilation de l&apos;ISF.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendrier &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Collecte de données : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il n&apos;y a pas de dates limites prédéterminées. Les pays rapportent les nouveaux ISF dès qu&apos;ils sont prêts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Diffusion des données :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont diffusées sur le site Internet du FMI dès qu&apos;elles sont prêtes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Les fournisseurs de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les banques centrales nationales ou les agences de contrôle bancaire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compilateurs de données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les ISF sont compilés au niveau national, mais pas au niveau régional ou mondial. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justification : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fonds propres réglementaires de catégorie 1 par rapport aux actifs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; : Il s&apos;agit d&apos;une version plus stricte du ratio de levier et indique la mesure dans laquelle les actifs sont financés par des fonds autres que les fonds propres et constitue une mesure de l&apos;adéquation des fonds propres du secteur des dépôts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fonds propres réglementaires de catégorie 1 par rapport aux actifs pondérés en fonction des risques&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; : Il mesure l&apos;adéquation des fonds propres des preneurs de dépôts sur la base du concept de fonds propres de base du Comité de Bâle sur le contrôle bancaire (CBCB). L&apos;adéquation et la disponibilité des fonds propres déterminent en définitive le degré de robustesse des institutions financières à résister aux chocs subis par leurs bilans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Prêts non performants nets de provisions par rapport au capital &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; : &lt;/em&gt; Cet ISF est un ratio d&apos;adéquation des fonds propres et constitue un indicateur important de la capacité du capital bancaire à résister aux pertes dues aux PNL qui ne sont pas couvertes par des provisions spécifiques pour pertes sur prêts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Prêts non performants par rapport au total des prêts bruts &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; : Cet ISF est souvent utilisé comme un indicateur de la qualité des actifs et vise à identifier les problèmes de qualité des actifs dans le portefeuille de prêts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Rendement des actifs &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; : Il s&apos;agit d&apos;un indicateur de la rentabilité des banques qui vise à mesurer l&apos;efficacité des preneurs de dépôts dans l&apos;utilisation de leurs actifs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Actifs liquides sur passifs à court terme &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; : Il s&apos;agit d&apos;un ratio d&apos;actifs liquides qui vise à capturer l&apos;inadéquation de la liquidité de l&apos;actif et du passif et fournit une indication de la mesure dans laquelle les preneurs de dépôts peuvent faire face au retrait de fonds à court terme sans être confrontés à des problèmes de liquidité. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Position ouverte nette en devises étrangères par rapport au capital &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; : &lt;/em&gt; Cet ISF est un indicateur de sensibilité au risque de marché, qui vise à évaluer l&apos;exposition des preneurs de dépôts au risque de change par rapport au capital. Il mesure la non-concordance des positions de l&apos;actif et du passif en devises étrangères afin d&apos;évaluer la vulnérabilité aux fluctuations du taux de change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires et limites :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données de la plupart des pays sont déclarées sur une base mensuelle ou trimestrielle ; quelques pays déclarent des données sur une base semestrielle et avec un décalage de plus d&apos;un trimestre. À la fin décembre 2018, il y avait 138 déclarants d&apos;ISF. Les pratiques de compilation de certains pays s&apos;écartent de la méthodologie du Guide de l&apos;ISF dans certains domaines et sont documentées dans les métadonnées de l&apos;ISF également publiées sur le site Web de l&apos;ISF du FMI. Les pays déclarants fournissent tous ou la plupart des ISF de base et certains ISF encouragés qui peuvent être utilisés pour soutenir l&apos;interprétation de ces sept indicateurs des ODD. Les données et métadonnées de l&apos;ISF communiquées par les pays sont disponibles à l&apos;adresse &lt;a href=&quot;http://data.imf.org/FSI.&quot;&gt;http://data.imf.org/FSI.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Méthodologie &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Méthode de calcul : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le calcul des sept ISF est détaillé dans la section &amp;#x201C;Définition&amp;#x201D; ci-dessus. Les données de base communes sont les données déclarées par les banques aux autorités de surveillance, qui sont généralement les compilateurs de l&apos;ISF. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Traitement des valeurs manquantes : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Au niveau national :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il n&apos;est pas pertinent pour les sept ISF. Les données sources sont collectées par les autorités de surveillance des banques et une déclaration complète est généralement imposée par la loi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Aux niveaux régional et mondial :&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les ISF ne sont pas compilés aux niveaux régional et mondial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agrégats régionaux : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les ISF ne sont pas agrégés aux niveaux régionaux.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Méthodes et instructions à la disposition des pays pour la compilation des données au niveau national :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le guide de compilation de l&apos;ISF (206) disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://data.imf.org/FSI&quot;&gt;http://data.imf.org/FSI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Assurance qualité : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données de source commune sont les données déclarées par les banques à des fins de surveillance. Les superviseurs nationaux vérifient et valident les données qui sont utilisées par les compilateurs nationaux d&apos;ISF. Le personnel du FMI vérifie les ISF déclarés par les pays avant de les publier sur le site Internet de l&apos;ISF et traite les problèmes de données en collaboration avec les compilateurs nationaux lorsque ces problèmes sont signalés par les contrôles de validation et de cohérence mis en œuvre dans le système de traitement des données du FMI. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilité des données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;À la fin décembre 2018, il y avait 138 déclarants d&apos;ISF. Tous les pays déclarent tous ou la plupart des ISF de base et certains ISF encouragés qui peuvent être utilisés pour soutenir l&apos;interprétation de ces sept indicateurs des ODD. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Séries chronologiques :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données de la plupart des pays sont communiquées sur une base mensuelle ou trimestrielle ; quelques pays communiquent des données sur une base semestrielle et avec un décalage de plus d&apos;un trimestre. Les données sont disponibles jusqu&apos;en 2005 pour certains pays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Désagrégation :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les ISF diffusés par le FMI sont des moyennes pondérées pour le secteur dans son ensemble (par exemple, les preneurs de dépôts, les autres sociétés financières, les sociétés non financières). Les données des banques mères, de leurs succursales et des filiales concernées sont consolidées ; si cette consolidation n&apos;est pas possible ou n&apos;est pas applicable, une explication est fournie dans les métadonnées. Il n&apos;existe pas de ventilation désagrégée des ISF déclarés au FMI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sources de divergences :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données calculées par d&apos;autres sources peuvent être différentes des ISF diffusés par le FMI en raison de l&apos;utilisation d&apos;une méthodologie de compilation et/ou d&apos;une couverture institutionnelle différentes. Les ISF diffusés par le FMI sont compilés sur la base du &lt;em&gt;Guide de compilation des ISF&lt;/em&gt;, qui fournit des indications sur les concepts et les définitions, ainsi que sur les sources et les techniques de compilation de données comparables entre pays pour soutenir la surveillance nationale et internationale des systèmes financiers. Pour faciliter l&apos;identification d&apos;éventuelles divergences entre pays, les déclarants fournissent au FMI des métadonnées qui détaillent les écarts par rapport aux recommandations du &lt;em&gt;Guide ISF&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Références &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://data.imf.org/FSI&quot;&gt;http://data.imf.org/FSI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Références : &lt;/h2&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 10: Сокращение неравенства внутри стран и между ними&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 10.5: Совершенствовать методы регулирования и мониторинга глобальных финансовых рынков и учреждений и более последовательно применять такие методы&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 10.5.1: Показатели финансовой устойчивости&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Последнее обновление: 03 декабря 2018 года&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Связанные индикаторы &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Связь с любыми другими целями и задачами: Рекомендация II.2 второй фазы Инициативы Группы 20-ти/МВФК в отношении пробелов в данных касается показателей финансовой устойчивости (ПФУ). Рекомендация нацелена на то, чтобы к 2021 г. страны &quot;Большой двадцатки&quot; ежеквартально представляли отчеты по семи ПФУ, которые, как ожидается, будут представляться странами, присоединившимися к Специальному стандарту распространения данных - плюс (ССРД-плюс), при этом своевременность представления отчетов должна составлять один квартал. Семь ПФУ в ЦУР такие же, как ПФУ в ССРД, но с одним исключением в ССРД-плюс, где индекс цен на жилую недвижимость используется вместо чистой открытой позиции в иностранной валюте по отношению к собственному капиталу. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Институциональная информация &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Организация (и): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Международный валютный фонд &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Семь ПФУ включены как показатели ЦУР для показателя 10.5.1 и выражены в процентах. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Отношение нормативного капитала первого уровня к активам &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Отношение нормативного капитала 1 уровня к активам, взвешенным с учетом риска
&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Отношение необслуживаемых кредитов за вычетом резервов к капиталу &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Отношение необслуживаемых кредитов к общей сумме кредитов &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Прибыль на активы &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Отношение ликвидных активов к краткосрочным обязательствам &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Отношение чистой открытой позиции в иностранной валюте к капиталу &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение нормативного капитала первого уровня к активам &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: Это отношение основного капитала (уровень 1) к совокупным (балансовым) активам. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение нормативного капитала 1 уровня к активам, взвешенным с учетом риска &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Показатель рассчитывается с использованием общего нормативного капитала уровня 1 в качестве числителя и активов, взвешенных с учетом риска, в качестве знаменателя. Данные для этого ПФУ составлены в соответствии с руководящими принципами Базель I, Базель II или Базель III. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение необслуживаемых кредитов за вычетом резервов к капиталу &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Этот ПФУ рассчитывается путем использования стоимости необслуживаемых кредитов (НОК) за вычетом стоимости специального резерва для покрытия убытков по ссудам в числителе и капитала в качестве знаменателя. Капитал оценивается как общий нормативный капитал. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение необслуживаемых кредитов к общей сумме кредитов &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Этот ПФУ рассчитывается путем использования стоимости необслуживаемых кредитов (НОК) в качестве числителя и общей стоимости кредитного портфеля (включая необслуживаемые кредиты и до вычета специальных резервов для покрытия убытков по ссудам) в качестве знаменателя. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Прибыль на активы &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Этот ПФУ рассчитывается путем деления чистой прибыли в годовом исчислении до вычета чрезвычайных обстоятельств и налогов (как рекомендовано в Руководстве по показателям финансовой устойчивости) на среднюю стоимость общих активов (финансовых и нефинансовых) за тот же период. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение ликвидных активов к краткосрочным обязательствам &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: Этот ПФУ рассчитывается с использованием базовой оценки ликвидных активов в качестве числителя и краткосрочных обязательств в качестве знаменателя. Соотношение также можно рассчитать, взяв в качестве числителя широкую оценку ликвидных активов. Для юрисдикций, которые внедрили Базель III, этот показатель может быть дополнен коэффициентом покрытия ликвидности. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение чистой открытой позиции в иностранной валюте к капиталу &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: Чистая открытая позиция в иностранной валюте должна рассчитываться на основании рекомендации Базельского комитета по банковскому надзору (BCBS). Капитал должен составлять совокупный нормативный капитал, поскольку чистая открытая позиция в иностранной валюте является надзорной концепцией. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Отношение нормативного капитала первого уровня к активам &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Нормативный капитал первого уровня рассчитывается на основе Базеля I, II или III в зависимости от надзорной практики страны. Знаменатель - это общая сумма балансовых (без взвешенных с учетом риска) активов. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение нормативного капитала 1 уровня к активам, взвешенным с учетом риска &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: Нормативный капитал первого уровня рассчитывается на основе Базеля I, II или III в зависимости от надзорной практики страны. Знаменатель - это активы, взвешенные с учетом риска, также рассчитанные на основе стандартов Базеля. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение необслуживаемых кредитов за вычетом резервов к капиталу &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Заем классифицируется как НОК, если выплата основной суммы или процентов просрочена на 90 дней или более, или есть доказательства того, что полная или частичная сумма кредита не будет возмещена. В этом расчете используются только специальные резервы для покрытия убытков по ссудам, и они соотносят расходы со стоимостью конкретных ссуд. Данные не включают начисленные проценты по необслуживаемым кредитам. Капитал оценивается как совокупный нормативный капитал, рассчитанный на основе Базеля I, II или III в зависимости от надзорной практики страны. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение необслуживаемых кредитов к общей сумме кредитов &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Заем классифицируется как НОК, если выплата основной суммы или процентов просрочена на 90 дней или более, или есть доказательства того, что полная или частичная сумма кредита не будет возмещена. Знаменатель - это общая стоимость кредитного портфеля (включая необслуживаемые кредиты, и до вычета специальных резервов для покрытия убытков по ссудам). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Прибыль на активы &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: В числителе указывается чистая прибыль до вычета чрезвычайных обстоятельств и налогов в годовом выражении. Знаменатель - это средняя стоимость совокупных активов (финансовых и нефинансовых) за тот же период. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение ликвидных активов к краткосрочным обязательствам &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Базовая оценка ликвидных активов включает валюту, депозиты и другие финансовые активы, доступные по требованию или в течение трех месяцев. Широкие оценки равны базовой оценке плюс ценные бумаги, торгуемые на ликвидных рынках, которые могут быть конвертированы в наличные с минимальным изменением стоимости. Знаменатель представляет собой краткосрочные элементы долговых обязательств плюс чистая (краткосрочная) рыночная стоимость позиции по производным финансовым инструментам. Последний рассчитывается как позиция по обязательствам по производным финансовым инструментам за вычетом позиции по активам по производным финансовым инструментам. Определение &quot;краткосрочный&quot; - это три месяца, и его следует устанавливать на основе оставшегося срока погашения. Если оставшийся срок погашения недоступен, в качестве альтернативы можно использовать первоначальный срок погашения. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение чистой открытой позиции в иностранной валюте к капиталу &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: Чистая открытая позиция в иностранной валюте равна иностранной валюте и связанному с иностранной валютой элементу балансовых активов и внебалансовых рисков, за вычетом иностранной валюты и связанного с иностранной валютой элемента балансовых обязательств и внебалансовых рисков. Связанные с иностранной валютой инструменты относятся к счетам, деноминированным в национальной валюте, но платежи по ним привязаны к обменным курсам, таким образом, подвержены валютному риску. Знаменатель — это совокупный нормативный капитал, как определено выше. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Описание: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Общие исходные данные - это данные, предоставляемые банками в надзорных целях. Они включают баланс, отчет о прибылях и убытках и ряды данных банковского надзора (например, капитал первого уровня, капитал второго уровня, активы, взвешенные с учетом риска). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Национальные центральные банки или надзорные органы собирают эти данные для целей надзора и эти данные используются для составления ПФУ. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Календарь &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Сбор данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Нет заранее установленных сроков. Страны отчитываются о новых показателях финансовой устойчивости по мере их готовности. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Выпуск данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные размещаются на веб-сайте МВФ по мере их готовности. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Поставщики данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Национальные центральные банки или органы банковского надзора. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Составители данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ПФУ составляются на национальном уровне, но не на региональном или глобальном уровне. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение нормативного капитала 1-го уровня к активам &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: это более строгая версия коэффициента левериджа, указывающая на пределы, в которых активы финансируются скорее другими, а не собственными средствами, а также мера достаточности капитала сектора привлечения депозитов. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение нормативного капитала 1 уровня к активам, взвешенным с учетом риска &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: Показатель оценивает достаточность капитала депозитариев на основе концепции базового капитала Базельского комитета по банковскому надзору (BCBS). Достаточность и доступность капитала в итоге определяют степень устойчивости финансовых учреждений к потрясениям в их балансах. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение необслуживаемых кредитов за вычетом резервов к капиталу &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Этот ПФУ представляет собой коэффициент достаточности капитала и является важным показателем способности банковского капитала противостоять убыткам от необслуживаемых кредитов, которые не покрываются специальным резервом для покрытия убытков по ссудам. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение необслуживаемых кредитов к общей сумме кредитов &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: Этот ПФУ часто используется в качестве замещающего показателя качества активов и предназначен для выявления проблем с качеством активов в кредитном портфеле.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Прибыль на активы &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: Это показатель рентабельности банка, предназначенный для оценки эффективности депозитариев в использовании своих активов.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Отношение ликвидных активов к краткосрочным обязательствам &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: Это отношение ликвидности к активам и предназначено для выявления несоответствия ликвидности активов и пассивов, а также показывает, до какой степени депозитарии могут исполнить краткосрочный вывод средств, не столкнувшись с проблемами ликвидности. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Отношение чистой открытой позиции в иностранной валюте к капиталу &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Этот ПФУ является показателем чувствительности к рыночному риску, который предназначен для оценки подверженности депозитариев риску изменения валютного курса по сравнению с капиталом. Он измеряет несоответствие позиций активов и пассивов в иностранной валюте для оценки уязвимости к колебаниям обменного курса. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные по большинству стран предоставляются ежемесячно или ежеквартально; несколько стран представляют данные раз в полгода и с задержкой более, чем в квартал. По состоянию на конец декабря 2018 года 138 лиц направляли данные по ПФУ. В некоторых странах методы составления данных отличаются от методологии Руководства ПФУ в определенных областях и задокументированы в метаданных ПФУ, также размещенных на веб-сайте ПФУ МВФ. Отчитывающиеся страны предоставляют все или большинство основных ПФУ, а также некоторые рекомендуемые ПФУ, которые можно использовать для поддержки интерпретации этих семи показателей ЦУР. Данные ПФУ и метаданные, представленные странами, доступны на &lt;a href=&quot;http://data.imf.org/FSI.&quot;&gt; http://data.imf.org/FSI. &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Расчет семи ПФУ подробно описан выше в разделе &amp;#x201C; Определение &amp;#x201D;. Общие исходные данные - это данные, сообщаемые банками надзорным органам, которые обычно являются составителями ПФУ. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Это не применимо к семи ПФУ. Исходные данные собираются органами банковского надзора и полная отчетность обычно требуется по закону. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ПФУ не составляются на региональном или глобальном уровнях. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Региональные агрегаты: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ПФУ не агрегируются на региональных уровнях. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Доступные странам методы и руководства для составления данных на национальном уровне: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Руководство по составлению ПФУ (206) доступно по адресу &lt;a href=&quot;http://data.imf.org/FSI&quot;&gt; http://data.imf.org/FSI &lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обеспечение качества: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Общие исходные данные - это данные, предоставляемые банками для надзорных целей. Национальные надзорные органы проверяют и подтверждают данные, которые используются национальными составителями ПФУ. Персонал МВФ проверяет ПФУ, представленные странами, прежде чем размещать их на веб-сайте ПФУ, и решает проблемы с данными в сотрудничестве с национальными составителями, когда такие проблемы возникают в ходе проверок достоверности и согласованности, которые осуществляются в системе обработки данных МВФ. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Описание:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; По состоянию на конец декабря 2018 года 138 лиц направляли данные по ПФУ. Все страны предоставляют все или большинство основных ПФУ, а также некоторые рекомендуемые ПФУ, которые можно использовать для поддержки интерпретации этих семи показателей ЦУР. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные по большинству стран предоставляются ежемесячно или ежеквартально; несколько стран представляют данные раз в полгода и с задержкой более чем в квартал. По некоторым странам данные доступны за 2005 год. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ПФУ, распространяемые МВФ, представляют собой средневзвешенные значения по сектору в целом (например, депозитариев, других финансовых корпораций, нефинансовых корпораций). Данные по материнским банковским компаниям, их филиалам и соответствующим дочерним компаниям консолидируются; если такое объединение невозможно или неприменимо, пояснение приводится в метаданных. Дезагрегированные данные по ПФУ не представляются в МВФ. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные, рассчитанные из других источников, могут отличаться от ПФУ, распространяемых МВФ, из-за использования другой методологии составления и / или институционального охвата. ПФУ, распространяемые МВФ, составлены на основе &lt;em&gt; Руководства по составлению ПФУ &lt;/em&gt;, в котором содержатся рекомендации по понятиям и определениям, а также источникам и методам составления сопоставимых данных по странам для поддержки национальных и международных наблюдений за финансовыми системами. Чтобы облегчить выявление возможных расхождений между странами, лица, направляющие отчеты, предоставляют МВФ метаданные, в которых подробно описываются отклонения от рекомендаций, содержащихся в &lt;em&gt; Руководстве ПФУ &lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://data.imf.org/FSI&quot;&gt; http://data.imf.org/FSI &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Ссылки: &lt;/h2&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
