<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 14-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 14: Conserve and sustainably use the oceans, seas and marine resources for sustainable development&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 14.4: By 2020, effectively regulate harvesting and end overfishing, illegal, unreported and unregulated fishing and destructive fishing practices and implement science-based management plans, in order to restore fish stocks in the shortest time feasible, at least to levels that can produce maximum sustainable yield as determined by their biological characteristics&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 14.4.1: Proportion of fish stocks within biologically sustainable levels&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Proportion of fish stocks within biologically sustainable levels (not overexploited) (%) ER_H2O_FWTL&lt;/p&gt;2022-03-31&lt;p&gt;Indicator 14.7.1: Sustainable fisheries as a percentage of GDP in small island developing States, least developed countries and all countries&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator, &amp;quot;Proportion of marine fish stocks within biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot;, measures the sustainability of the world&amp;apos;s marine capture fisheries by the abundance of the exploited fish stocks with respect to MSY levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each level of reporting (National, Regional, Global) the indicator is calculated as the ratio between the number of exploited fish stocks classified as &amp;quot;within biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot; and the total number of stocks in the Reference List that were classified with a determined status (within/not within &amp;quot;biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;msub&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;P&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/msub&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;x&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;100&lt;/mn&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;x&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;100&lt;/mn&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where Ps is the percentage of stocks classified as &amp;quot;within biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot; for the Reference List of stocks. Ns is the number of stocks in the Reference List classified as &amp;quot;within biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot;, Nu is the number of stocks in the Reference List classified as &amp;quot;outside biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot; and N = Ns + Nu is the total number of stocks in the Reference List that have been classified as within or outside &amp;quot;biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Classifying individual stocks as within/outside &amp;quot;biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to keep consistency with the 14.4 target (&amp;quot;at least to levels that can produce maximum sustainable yield as determined by their biological characteristics&amp;quot; and other earlier international agreements, including the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS), a fish stock is classified as &amp;quot;within biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot; if its abundance is estimated (considering uncertainty) to be equal to or greater than the level that can produce the Maximum Sustainable Yield (MSY). In contrast, when abundance falls below the MSY level, the stock is classified as &amp;quot;outside biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A wide array of methods and approaches (including documented expert opinion) is used to classify stock status relative to the abundance producing MSY. This varies among countries, regions and stocks. Nevertheless, the reliability of the classification is assessed by FAO as part of the process of producing the index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maximum Sustainable Yield (MSY)&lt;/strong&gt; is commonly defined as the greatest average amount of catch that can be harvested in the long-term from a stock under constant and current environmental conditions (e.g., habitat, water conditions, species composition and interactions, and anything that could affect birth, growth, or death rates of the stock), without affecting the long-term productivity of the stock. A stock can produce MSY if its abundance is above a certain level, usually around 50% of its unexploited abundance (but actual value can vary around that level, depending on the biological characteristics of the stock). See more at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fao.org/faoterm/en/?defaultCollId=21&quot;&gt;https://www.fao.org/faoterm/en/?defaultCollId=21&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MSY-based reference points are the most common type of reference points used in fisheries management today. This is primarily because, for decades, reference points from surplus production models have most often been set based on the concept of MSY and they are the basic benchmarks for the sustainability of fisheries set by the UN Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS, Article 61(3)). For more on Reference Points in Fish Stock Assessment, see Caddy and Mahon (1995), Cadima (2003) or Haddon (2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BMSY&lt;/strong&gt;: Biomass corresponding to Maximum Sustainable Yield from a production model or from an age-based analysis using a stock recruitment model. Often used as a biological reference point in fisheries management, it is the calculated long-term average biomass value expected if fishing at FMSY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A population is:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#x201C;A group of individuals of the same species living in the same area at the same time and sharing a common gene pool, with little or no immigration or emigration.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A biological stock is: &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#x201C;A subpopulation of a species inhabiting a particular geographic area, having similar biological characteristics (e.g. growth, reproduction, mortality) and negligible genetic mixing with other adjacent subpopulations of the same species.&amp;quot; (FAO, 2004-2021).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Reference List of Stocks: i&lt;/strong&gt;t is not possible to classify the sustainability of exploitation for all the exploited stocks from a country, region or the world. Therefore, the indicator must be calculated based on a subset of these stocks. The list of the stocks that are classified for status and used to calculate the indicators is called the &amp;quot;Reference List of Stocks&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Reference List of Stocks is built differently for the Regional/Global and the National levels. The process of building the Reference List of Stocks for regional and global level are described in FAO (2011). At National level, countries are requested to define a list of stocks, based on an agreed set of criteria (Appendix 1). National and shared stocks can be included, but not straddling stocks (stocks that are distributed both in national EEZ and Areas Beyond National Jurisdiction).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this moment, there is not a direct correspondence between the national level Reference Lists (that are defined by each country) and the regional and global Reference lists (that are defined by FAO).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;move956633181111111111111111&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The detailed description of all necessary concepts can be found in the e-learning course (FAO 2019-2021).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Percent (%)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FAO Major Fishing Areas for Statistical Purposes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ASFIS List of Species for Fishery Statistics Purposes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNFSA Stock Jurisdictional distribution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FIRMS typology of stock units&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The classification of the status of exploited stocks relatively to the abundance that can produce MSY is often established through a formal stock assessment process. The data to inform stock assessments can come from many different sources, including fishery-dependent and fishery-independent sources. Fishery-dependent data are collected from the fishery itself, using both commercial and recreational sources through reporting or sample-based surveys at sea, at landing sites, or within fishing communities. They can include information on removals of fish from the sea, which can include landings and discards, and information on the fleet such as number of boats, number of tows, time spent on the sea, as well as economic and social information like fish prices, fuel expenditures, total sales, employment or other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fishery-independent data are obtained in ways not related to any fishing activity and are typically collected by scientists via surveys (often scientific cruises) designed to estimate species abundance and biomass over long time series, and over consistent seasons and geographic areas. Typically, fisheries-independent data also include biological information on the species (age, length, weight, maturity, etc.), and habitat and environmental information (temperature, salinity, depth, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These data and other information are used by Stock Assessment scientists to classify the stock status. References on the methods most commonly used can be found in Cadima (2003), Haddon (2011), Sparre and Venema (1998) and other publications dealing with the methods of stock assessment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The information used for the indicator at the Global/Regional level is based on a different process and data sources than that used for the national level &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global/Regional:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the high data demands of classical stock assessment methods, only a limited number of fish stocks have been assessed. These species account for ca 50 percent of the global catch (Hilborn et al., 2020), and most are caught by industrial fisheries in developed countries . To balance the global representativeness of the assessment results and the goal of using the best available information, the FAO uses a wide spectrum of data and methods to extend its assessment to the fish stocks that account for the majority (70-80 percent) of the global catch (FAO, 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The national level indicator, on the other hand, is based exclusively on the stock status reported by countries. A multiplicity of methods are used to classify the stock status, including model-based estimates, empirical indicators and documented expert opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For country reporting, a questionnaire was sent out to all FAO member States with marine boundaries (i.e. 165 States) in 2019, and will be resent in 2021, and then on a two-year basis. For the complete list of questions used to inform this indicator, please refer to Appendix 2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At this moment, data collection is separate for the national and regional/global levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global/regional level: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fish stocks that FAO has monitored since 1974 represent a wide spectrum of data availability, ranging from data-rich and formally assessed stocks to those that have very little information apart from catch statistics by FAO major fishing area and those with no stock assessment at all. For the purposes of using the best available data and information and maintaining consistency among stocks and assessors, a procedure has been defined to identify relevant stock status information (FAO 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National level: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO collects national data through a questionnaire sent to the Principal Focal Point (PFP) of each country. The PFP organises an institutional set-up which identifies the competent authorities to develop a reference list of stocks and completes the questionnaire. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the initial stages of national data reporting, the information or data collected through the questionnaire from a country will initially only inform the indicator for the individual countries, also acknowledging the need for a learning curve along the few first questionnaire inquiries. As a result, the global/regional indicator remains during these initial stages separate from the national indicators. However, FAO is working on a convergence (where possible) of the two processes, and good-quality stock status assessments reported by countries for the national indicators will be included in the regional/global indicator calculations, depending on the evolution and further standardization of country reporting over the next 3-5 years..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this effort, due to the heterogeneity of reporting from countries in the same FAO Major Fishing Area, and the necessary inclusion of straddling and highly migratory stocks and fisheries in the regional and global indicator, it is unlikely that a full convergence will be achieved in a short time-frame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National : Reporting every 2 years beginning in 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global/regional: every 2 years since 2013The data collection calendar for the national level may be adjusted in the future according to requirements for a convergence between National and Global/regional processes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National: biennially. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global/regional: biennially&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FAO provides global and regional data. National-level data are generally reported by the National Statistics Office or the Ministry of Fisheries and/or Agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO) is the lead United Nations agency for agriculture, forestry, fisheries and rural development. As part of its mandate, it fosters global, regional and national sustainable development initiatives to secure responsible fisheries worldwide, which in turn requires maintaining fish stocks at biologically sustainable levels, so that they can contribute fully, and in a sustainable way, to the food and nutrition security, as well as to social and economic development, of Humankind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, the mission of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/fishery-aquaculture/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FAO Fisheries and Aquaculture Division (NFI)&lt;/a&gt; is stated as &amp;quot;To strengthen global governance and the managerial and technical capacities of members and to lead consensus-building towards improved conservation and utilization of aquatic resources&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of its mandate, FAO is also tasked with collecting and disseminating data and information for improved planning and management of fisheries, aquaculture and the other food-producing sectors of the economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Article I of the FAO constitution requires that the organization collect, analyses, interpret and disseminate information relating to nutrition, food and agriculture (the term &amp;#x201C;agriculture&amp;#x201D; and its derivatives includes forestry, fisheries and aquaculture, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/K8024E/K8024E.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/K8024E/K8024E.pdf&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first session of the FAO Conference in 1945 provided the basis and rationale for the FAO mandate as a custodian agency of this indicator: &amp;#x201C;If FAO is to carry out its work successfully it will need to know where and why hunger and malnutrition exist, what forms they take, and how widespread they are. Such data will serve as a basis for making plans, determining the efficacy of measures used, and measuring progress from time to time.&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The United Nations (UN) Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS), the United Nations Fish Stocks Agreement (UNFSA [UN, 1995]) and the FAO Code of Conduct for Responsible Fisheries (FAO, 1995a) all require maintaining or restoring fish stocks at levels that are capable of producing their maximum sustainable yield (MSY). To fulfil the objectives of these international treaties, fishery management authorities need to undertake assessment of the state of fish stocks and develop effective policies and management strategies. As a UN Agency with a mandate for fisheries, FAO endeavours to provide the international community with the best information on the state of marine fishery resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 1974, FAO has been periodically assessing and reporting the state of marine fishery resources using a wide spectrum of methods from numerical models to data poor approaches. FAO global and regional estimates were also used as an MDG indicator for Goal 7 on environment during the period 2000-2015. This facilitated its approval as a Tier I SDG indicator by the 2nd IAEG-SDG in October 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator has a peculiar nature compared to more conventional SDG indicators. The indicator estimates the sustainability of fish stocks that often move across national boundaries. This led the indicator to be initially reported only at global and regional levels, with regions not corresponding to continental MDG or SDG regions but to marine regions termed &amp;#x201C;FAO Major Fishing Areas&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Global SDG Indicator Framework is a voluntary mechanism, but countries are required to report if data are available. As a custodian agency, the FAO works to put in action the 2030 Agenda&amp;#x2019;s emphasis on country ownership and higher the incentive to take actions at country, regional and global levels. FAO has developed, since 2018, a questionnaire approach to allow individual countries to report on the sustainability of fish stocks. The approach 1) provides a framework for meaningful country-level reporting that complements but does not alter the core methodology of SDG indicator 14.4.1 at the global/regional levels (FAO, 2011), and 2) provides countries with simplified methods to carry out fish stock assessment in data-limited contexts, to some extent overcoming the technical barriers that traditional methods presented. This is because country-level reporting will be limited to the assessment of stocks that are found only within a country&amp;#x2019;s EEZ and/or shared with neighbouring countries&amp;#x2019; EEZs, and therefore do not include straddling stocks, highly migratory species, or stocks in Areas Beyond National Jurisdiction (ABNJ). As a result, national data alone cannot be meaningfully aggregated at global/regional levels, but it can be used to inform country progress on fish stock sustainability within the EEZ. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2019, the FAO began sending a questionnaire to countries to collect national data with the aim to help countries in the reporting process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The indicator measures the sustainability of fishery resources, and as an end-result is a measure of Target 14.4. Its derivation requires catch and fishing effort data and/or other biological or technical data and parameters as well together with scientific expertise necessary to perform stock assessment correctly. The indicator at global level is estimated by the FAO based on the methodology developed in the 1980s. Although regular updates were carried out to incorporate technical advances and changes in major fish species, some discrepancies between regions may occur in the representativeness of the reference list in practical fisheries. However, this will not pose a large impact on the reliability of the indicator&amp;#x2019;s temporal trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the national level, the composition of stocks within the reference list of stocks and the selection criteria used to develop the list will vary between countries, making the indicator suitable for checking countries&amp;#x2019; own progress over time. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FAO currently reports the global and regional indicators calculated from FAO&amp;#x2019;s assessment of a selected list of fish stocks around the world. The methodology is described in the FAO Technical Paper (FAO 2011). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO has been developing the new approach for country-level reporting since 2017, and has consulted with countries in three dedicated expert consultation workshops: In November 2017, FAO convened a workshop to exchange views with national practitioners on the new proposed analytical methods to produce Indicator 14.4.1 at country level&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-1&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. In February 2019, FAO convened an expert consultation workshop&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; on development of the methodologies for the global assessment of fish stock status, with participants from countries and regional fisheries organizations. In order to help countries reporting on the indicator, FAO then organized a series of capacity development workshops on stock status assessment and estimation methods of SDG Indicator 14.4.1 for various regions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November 2019, FAO dispatched the first SDG14.4.1 questionnaire calling countries to report on their national indicator. Eighty-three countries submitted their questionnaire and three reported independently. FAO has reported the full results of this first inquiry through UNSD in February 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each level of reporting (National, Regional, Global) the indicator is calculated as the ratio between the number of exploited fish stocks classified as &amp;quot;within biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot; and the total number of stocks in the Reference List that were classified with a determined status (within/not within &amp;quot;biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;msub&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;P&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/msub&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;x&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;100&lt;/mn&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;x&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;100&lt;/mn&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where Ps is the percent of stocks classified as &amp;quot;within biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot; for the Reference List of stocks. Ns is the number of stocks in the Reference List classified as &amp;quot;within biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot;, Nu is the number of stocks in the Reference List classified as &amp;quot;outside biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot; and N = Ns + Nu is the total number of stocks in the Reference List that have been classified as within or outside &amp;quot;biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Classifying individual stocks as within/outside &amp;quot;biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to keep consistency with the 14.4 target (&amp;quot;at least to levels that can produce maximum sustainable yield as determined by their biological characteristics&amp;quot; and other earlier international agreements, including the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS)), a fish stock is classified as &amp;quot;within biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot; if its abundance is estimated to be (considering uncertainty) at or greater than the level that can produce the Maximum Sustainable Yield (MSY). In contrast, when abundance falls below the MSY level, the stock is classified as &amp;quot;outside biologically sustainable levels&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A wide array of methods and approaches (including documented expert opinion) is used to classify stock status relative to the abundance producing MSY. This varies among countries, regions and stocks. Nevertheless, the reliability of the classification is assessed by FAO as part of the process of producing the index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global/Regional:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global and regional estimates of stock sustainability have been performed for 584 fish stocks around the world since 1974, representing 70% of global landings. The status of each stock is estimated using the methodology described in the FAO Technical Paper (FAO, 2011). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Countries are requested to report the status of a reference list of fish stocks defined by each country on the basis of the criteria presented in Appendix 1.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Full report accessible here: http://www.fao.org/documents/card/en/c/I8714EN/ &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Full report accessible here: http://www.fao.org/3/ca4355en/ca4355en.pdf &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;FAO carries out a series of validations to assure that the data and information are provided by countries in line with the questionnaire instructions. The validation process consists of: (i) identification of errors, mistakes and missing value in the data and, (ii) correcting errors, mistakes and missing values in close consultation with the countries concerned. Each country is asked either to confirm that the data provided are correct or to provide remarks and / or revise data accordingly if they identify any errors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No adjustments were applied for the time series.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x25CF; At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure completeness of regional and global information on stocks, FAO gathers additional information outside of what is provided by each country, in particular concerning the highly migratory and straddling fishing stocks. For shared stocks, FAO may consult with Regional Fisheries Bodies (RFBs), who are mandated to assess and manage stocks with their contracting parties, in order to receive information and data and conduct stock assessment when necessary. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x25CF; At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator examines marine fish stocks. If a country has no marine capture fisheries, then the indicator is not calculated for that country and FAO reports it to UNSD with the flag &amp;#x201C;N&amp;#x201D; (Not relevant). When data is missing at national level, no imputation is performed to derive estimates. The estimation of the indicator at regional and global levels was estimated not based on country questionnaires, but by the FAO through a systematic assessment of a reference list selected globally. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As explained in the &amp;#x201C;Rationale&amp;#x201D; section, national data alone cannot be meaningfully aggregated at global/regional level because country-level reporting will be limited to the assessment of stocks that are found only within a country&amp;#x2019;s EEZ (including stocks shared with neighbouring countries&amp;#x2019; EEZs), and therefore not include straddling stocks, highly migratory species, or stocks in Areas Beyond National Jurisdiction (ABNJ). Therefore, regional &amp;#x201C;aggregates&amp;#x201D; by FAO Major Fishing Area and the global indicator value are calculated with a specific approach, as described in the FAO Technical Paper (FAO 2011)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In each country, the data available for each stock and expertise level to conduct different types of assessments will differ. Some countries may have classic stock assessments already conducted for many of their stocks, while others may have very few or no assessments available. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some countries, little stock assessment has been done. To help these countries and to facilitate their reporting, FAO prepared online materials and tools, including a selection of methods that can be used to evaluate stock status with data limited methods such as length-based and catch-only methods and an online platform for hands-on practice. The strengths and limitations of these methods are discussed in an eLearning course (Lesson 4), and caveats were also provided to avoid misuse and exercise cautions in practice. Furthermore, capacity development workshops have been organised to provide support to countries in stock assessment and reporting on the SDG 14.4.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;eLearning course: &lt;a href=&quot;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=502&quot;&gt;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=502&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FAO has in place the necessary frameworks and procedures for quality assurance of the SDG indicators data, according to the Fundamental Principles of Official Statistics and the FAO Statistics Quality Assurance Framework (SQAF) available at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/docrep/019/i3664e/i3664e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/docrep/019/i3664e/i3664e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO is systematically carrying out quality assessments to ensure the quality of the SDG indicator data sets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this indicator, a systematic cross-checking of the various source data was carried out during the overall compilation process of national and regional data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The FAO carries out a quality assurance review to help with consistency and correctness of this reporting process. The review is performed in two steps to quantify the level of confidence that can be attributed to national reporting: 1) to verify that the questionnaire has been correctly and sufficiently filled out and complies with the reporting guidelines, and 2) to assess the reliability of the responses relative to the supporting information reported by the country. Reliability is based on the compliance to the guidelines in developing the reference list of stocks, the proportion of stocks with official assessments, the source of stock assessments (e.g. RFB, peer-reviewed, expert knowledge), the amount of data available at the stock level, and the consistency with regional assessments (for shared stocks). FAO provides feedback to respondents, who have an opportunity to adjust their submission. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quality assessment reveals that quality is highly dependent on the primary data which undergoes the applicable validation procedures before dissemination. The outcomes of the calculations are also controlled and compared inside and among FAO fishing areas. Global and regional aggregates are assessed by considering and evaluating the contributions of regional fisheries bodies while ensuring consistency of the entire time series for the global indicator, with reference to the published methodology (FAO, 2011). In addition, an internal summary report on the annual assessment of the quality of country data is also produced.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global/regional: the indicator has global and regional data from 1974 to 2019. Regional breakdown is by FAO major fishing area. The regional and global indicators were calculated based on the reference list of fish stocks FAO established in 1974. Countries are not directly involved in the computation of the indicator at global/regional level. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National: the national-level questionnaire was dispatched for the first time in November 2019; FAO identifies 165 countries with a marine border, and three countries with Caspian Sea border, as being eligible, in principle, to report. As the result of the first questionnaire call, ninety-eight countries expressed interest in the indicator (59%), of which eighty-three replied with completed questionnaires while three countries reported the indicator separately (52%), 11 countries stated that they could not report due to lack of data or time, and one responded with some catch data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global/regional level: from 1974 to 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National level: First questionnaire dispatched in November 2019, considered a trial/testing phase. Upon comprehensive Quality Assurance analysis, FAO reported the full results of this first inquiry through UNSD in February 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By FAO major marine fishing areas for statistical purposes&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-3&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taxonomically, FAO publishes the indicator separately for straddling stocks (mostly tuna and tuna like).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fao.org/fishery/en/area/search&quot;&gt;https://www.fao.org/fishery/en/area/search&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fao.org/cwp-on-fishery-statistics/handbook/general-concepts/main-water-areas/en/&quot;&gt;https://www.fao.org/cwp-on-fishery-statistics/handbook/general-concepts/main-water-areas/en/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is estimated by the FAO based on the methodology developed in the 1980s (FAO, 2011). Although regular updates were carried out to incorporate technical advances and changes in major fish species, some discrepancies between regions may occur in the representativeness of the reference list in practical fisheries. However, this will not pose a large impact on the reliability of the Global indicator&amp;#x2019;s temporal trends which covers 75% of global landings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;FAO 2016-2021. Sustainable Development Goals. Indicator 14.4.1 - Proportion of fish stocks within biologically sustainable levels. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/sustainable-development-goals/indicators/1441/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/sustainable-development-goals/indicators/1441/en/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO 2019-2021. SDG 14.4.1 eLearning course. &lt;a href=&quot;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=502&quot;&gt;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=502&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO 2015-2021. CWP handbook of fishery statistical standards. Fishing areas for statistical purpose. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fao.org/cwp-on-fishery-statistics/handbook/general-concepts/main-water-areas/en/&quot;&gt;https://www.fao.org/cwp-on-fishery-statistics/handbook/general-concepts/main-water-areas/en/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO 2015-2021. CWP handbook of fishery statistical standards. Identifiers for aquatic animals and plants: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/cwp-on-fishery-statistics/handbook/general-concepts/identifiers-for-aquatic-animals-and-plants/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/cwp-on-fishery-statistics/handbook/general-concepts/identifiers-for-aquatic-animals-and-plants/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO 2004-2021. FIRMS Information Management Policy - Annex 1.2 - List of reference terms for Marine Resources. Updated June 2019. http://www.fao.org/3/a-ax530e.pdf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Branch, T.A., Jensen, O.P., Ricard, D., Ye, Y. &amp;amp; Hilborn, R. (2011) Contrasting global trends in marine fishery status obtained from catches and from stock assessments. Conservation Biology, 25: 777&amp;#x2013;783. doi: 10.1111/j.1523-1739.2011.01687.x.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caddy, J.R. and Mahon, R. (1995). Reference Points for fisheries management. FAO Fisheries Technical Paper. No. 337. Rome, FAO. 83p.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cadima, E.L. (2003) Fish stock assessment manual. FAO Fisheries Technical Paper. No. 393. Rome, FAO. 161p.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO (1995) Code of conduct for responsible fisheries. 41 pp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO (2005) Review of the state of world marine fishery resources. FAO Fisheries Technical Paper No. 457. Rome. 235 pp&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO (2011) Review of the state of world marine fishery resources. FAO technical paper 569: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/docrep/015/i2389e/i2389e00.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/docrep/015/i2389e/i2389e00.htm&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haddon, M. (2011). Modelling and Quantitative Methods in Fisheries 2nd Edition. Chapman and Hall/CRC. 465 p.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hilborn, R., R.O. Amoroso, C.M. Anderson, J.K. Baum, T.A. Branch, C. Costello, C.L. de Moor, et al. 2020. &amp;#x201C;Effective Fisheries Management Instrumental in Improving Fish Stock Status.&amp;#x201D; Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America 117 (4): 2218&amp;#x2013;24. &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1073/&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1073/&lt;/a&gt; pnas.1909726116.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sparre P. &amp;amp; Venema, S.C. (1998). Introduction to tropical fish stock assessment. Part 1. Manual. FAO Fisheries Technical Paper. No. 306.1, Rev. 2. Rome, FAO. 407p.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UN (1995) Agreement for the implementation of the provisions of the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea of 10 December 1982 relating to the conservation and management of straddling fish stocks and highly migratory fish stocks. 40 pp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appendix 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guidelines to establish reference list of stocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reference list compiles a list of fish stocks based on data from the considered area, i.e. a country&amp;#x2019;s EEZ and/or territorial waters and/or possibly the competence area of a regional fisheries management organization. This list of fish stocks will ideally include existing Assessment units or Management units, and also possibly other unassessed fish stocks that are fished in a given country. The list will exclude stocks straddling in the high seas, mostly tuna and tuna-like species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This list should:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Represent at least 60% (a higher percent is preferred when possible) of the national total landed and/or reported catch (Total in Tonnes excluding landings from straddling stocks). Information should be provided on all of the stocks that contribute to this top 60% (or more) of landings regardless of whether their status is known. Stocks should be input from left to right on the spreadsheet in the order of the largest to smallest total landings for each stock, by Tonnes. Species with multiple different stocks should be input as separate stocks. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contain stocks of major importance in terms of catch, ecosystem role, economic value, and social/cultural considerations. If possible, the list should represent stocks of each of these categories for a given country. For example, care should be taken to include fish stocks that are important to small-scale fisheries as well as large-scale industrial fisheries. Consideration for these different categories will vary between countries.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remain unchanged (i.e. for at least 5 years) to better reflect changes in stock status at the national level and minimize the effect of changing the reference list of stocks (i.e., adding, deleting, merging stocks) into the SDG indicator. This will ensure consistency in the indicator calculation and better reflect fish stock sustainability over time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appendix 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complete list of questions to countries to inform the indicator. Pink cells are mandatory, white cells are optional. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. REFERENCE LIST OF FISH STOCKS &amp;amp; STATUS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.1 Stock Name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.2 Stock Jurisdictional distribution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Please type &amp;quot;X&amp;quot; in the relevant box)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shared between Nations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.3 For shared stocks only, please list the exploiting countries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.4 Please indicate whether the stock is Assessed (Yes) or Unassessed (No)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.5 Method of assessment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If &amp;quot;Yes&amp;quot; assessed, please indicate which approach was used: (1) Classic; (2) Data-limited ; (3) Unspecified&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If &amp;quot;No&amp;quot; please indicate best available knowledge used to define stock status (e.g. trends over catch rates or abundance index)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.6 Current stock status&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indicate whether the stock is biologically sustainable (Yes or No)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assessment year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indicate source references of the official stock assessment or other information, including web links to online documents when available&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.7 Total landings for the entire stock&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Landings (in tonnes)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reference year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proportion of total landings from the total national landings (excluding landings from straddling stocks) (in percentage)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1 STOCK INDIVIDUAL INFORMATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.1 Stock name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Name of the individual stock&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.2 Scientific name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Species scientific name, preferably according to ASFIS List of Species for Fishery Statistics Purposes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.3 Common name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Species common name in English (if available)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Species common name in local language (list more than one if relevant)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.4 FAO Major Fishing Area/ with sub-levels when appropriate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indicate the code of the FAO major fishing area&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indicate the code of the area sub-levels where appropriate&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.5 Stock is considered as ...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(possible to select multiple answers, place &amp;quot;X&amp;quot; in the relevant cell(s))&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;... Assessment Unit (for stocks with an available official stock assessment)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2026; Management Unit (Unit that is used to implement management measures based on a stock assessment or not)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2026; Other (i.e., Species x Area) unit (if none of the above)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.8 Management Agency/Advisory Body&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Management agency or advisory body responsible for assessment (if assessment unit) or management (if management unit)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2 ASSESSMENT INFORMATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.1 Assessment status (Yes, No)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indicate whether the stock is Assessed (Yes) or Unassessed (No)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.2 Overfished (Yes, No, Unknown)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The official stock assessment concludes &amp;quot;Overfished&amp;quot; with respect to abundance reference points (Yes, No, Unknown). Note: if stock is overfished then is not biologically sustainable (please answer NO in question Line 15, Section 1). When possible, support your answer with information on Section 2.3 (for example, current biomass is less than biomass target reference point)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.3 Overfishing (Yes, No, Unknown)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The official stock assessment concludes &amp;quot;Overfishing&amp;quot; with respect to fishing mortality reference points (Yes, No, Unknown). Note: see e-learning course on how to link fishing mortality reference points to biological sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.4 Assessment method/software&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;If there is an official stock assessment available please indicate which method or software used. For example: stock synthesis; ASPIC, MULTIFAN-CL; VIT, CPUE trends, catch trends, size/length trends, none, others&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.5 Assessment availability (Yes, No)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The assessment is publicly available (Yes or No)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.6 Source references&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;List of Source references used to collect information, including web links to online documents when available&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.7 Reliability (L/M/H)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;High (H) &amp;#x2013; Formal stock assessment at the regional, national or local levels forms the foundation of the classification of stock status;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Medium (M) &amp;#x2013; Grey data/information and catch trend analysis provide the basis for the classification of stock status;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Low (L) &amp;#x2013; Black data/information and qualitative assessment (e.g. experts judgement) were used for the classification of stock status&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3 INPUT DATA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability (Yes, No)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Input data needed for the stock assessment&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3.1 Abundance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Current Biomass&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Most recent biomass or abundance in tonnes (NA if not available)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Virgin/pristine stock biomass (B0)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Value of the biomass or abundance target reference point in tonnes (i.e. prime stock biomass)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Target Reference Point type&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Type of biomass or abundance reference point used (e.g. 0.4B0; BMSY, etc. )&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Reference year&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Last year of input data used in the assessment (i.e. year of Current Biomass)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3.2 Fishing mortality&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Current F&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Most recent fishing mortality (F) or exploitation rate (U)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;F Reference Point&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Value of the fishing mortality reference point&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Reference Point type&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Type of fishing mortality reference point used (e.g. FMSY, F01, etc. )&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Reference year&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Last year of input data used in the assessment (i.e. year of Current F)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3.3 CPUE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Current CPUE&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Current value of catch per unit of effort&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Units of CPUE&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Unit (e.g. kg/trap), in case CPUE is not standardized&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Year of current CPUE&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Year of current CPUE&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3.4 Catches&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Current catch&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Current value of catch (in tonnes)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Reference year&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Year of current catch&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Average Catch Max&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Value of maximum catch in the time series (in tonnes) (after 5 years smoothing)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. SUPPORTING TIME SERIES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Time series are optional but recommended to be reported by stock for all available years&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fish Stock ID&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Landings (in tonnes)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Catches (in tonnes)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abundance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CPUE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exploitation rate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fishing Effort&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obs_measure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obs_measure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obs_measure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obs_measure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;METADATA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The reference list of stocks represent at least 60% of the current total national landed and/or reported catch statistics?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1a. If answered &amp;quot;No&amp;quot;, please specify&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The reference list of stocks contains all stocks of major importance in terms of catch, ecosystem role, economic value, and social/cultural considerations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Please indicate the frequency of stock assessment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3a. If answered &amp;quot;Other&amp;quot;, please specify&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. If the SDG indicator 14.4.1 is reported in the national SDG portal, database, or other please indicate the address&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2a. Please provide additional addresses if available&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Any additional information:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 14: Conservar y utilizar sosteniblemente los ocanos, los mares y los recursos marinos para el desarrollo sostenible&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 14.4: De aqu a 2020, reglamentar eficazmente la explotacin pesquera y poner fin a la pesca excesiva, la pesca ilegal, no declarada y no reglamentada y las prcticas pesqueras destructivas, y aplicar planes de gestin con fundamento cientfico a fin de restablecer las poblaciones depeces en el plazo ms breve posible, al menos alcanzando niveles que puedan producir el mximo rendimiento sostenible de acuerdo con sus caractersticas biolgicas&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 14.4.1: Proporcin de poblaciones de peces cuyos niveles son biolgicamente sostenibles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Febrero de 2021 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicadores relacionados&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicador 14.7.1: La pesca sostenible como porcentaje del PIB en los pequeos Estados insulares en desarrollo, los pases menos desarrollados y todos los pases &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Informacin institucional&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organizacin(es):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organizacin de las Naciones Unidas para la Agricultura y la Alimentacin (FAO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definicin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador Proporcin de las poblaciones de peces marinos dentro de niveles biolgicamente sostenibles mide la sostenibilidad de las pesqueras de captura marina del mundo por su abundancia. Una poblacin de peces cuya abundancia es igual o superior al nivel que puede producir el rendimiento mximo sostenible (RMS) se clasifica como biolgicamente sostenible. Por el contrario, cuando la abundancia cae por debajo del nivel de RMS, la poblacin se considera biolgicamente insostenible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El RMS se define como la mayor cantidad de capturas que puede obtenerse de forma continua de una poblacin en condiciones ambientales constantes y actuales (por ejemplo, el hbitat, las condiciones del agua, la composicin y las interacciones de las especies y todo lo que pueda afectar a las tasas de natalidad, crecimiento o mortalidad de la poblacin) sin afectar a la productividad a largo plazo de la poblacin. El indicador mide la sostenibilidad de los recursos pesqueros basndose en un buen equilibrio entre el uso humano y la conservacin ecolgica.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los puntos de referencia basados en el RMS son el tipo ms comn de puntos de referencia utilizados en la gestin de la pesca hoy en da. Esto se debe principalmente a que, durante dcadas, los puntos de referencia de los modelos de produccin de excedentes se han establecido con mayor frecuencia basndose en el concepto de RMS y son los puntos de referencia bsicos para la sostenibilidad de las pesqueras establecidos por la Convencin de las Naciones Unidas sobre el Derecho del Mar (UNCLOS, artculo 61(3)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Poblacin de peces&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;se refiere a un grupo de individuos de una sola especie o a veces de especies combinadas que viven en una zona definida de la que se obtienen capturas en una pesquera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cada pas debe establecer una &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;lista de referencia de poblaciones&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; que consiste en una lista de poblaciones seleccionadas segn las directrices de la FAO, con respecto a las cuales se informar del indicador (Apndice 1). La lista de referencia debe incluir las poblaciones nacionales y compartidas, pero no las poblaciones transzonales, tal y como se definen a continuacin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Las poblaciones nacionales&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; se encuentran completamente dentro de una ZEE y/o aguas territoriales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Poblaciones compartidas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;estn distribuidas dentro de la ZEE y/o las aguas territoriales de dos o ms pases adyacentes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Las poblaciones transzonales&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; se desplazan a travs de las fronteras entre las aguas de la ZEE o entre la ZEE y alta mar (por ejemplo, las poblaciones de atn), y que son capturadas por mltiples pases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se pide a los pases que informen sobre las poblaciones que figuran en su lista de referencia, incluidas las que son objeto de seguimiento mediante &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;evaluaciones oficiales de las poblaciones&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; por parte de un organismo autorizado, mediante un proceso cientfico y utilizando los mejores datos y datos cientficos disponibles. Estas evaluaciones podran basarse en mtodos clsicos o con datos limitados. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La evaluacin de poblaciones utiliza informacin biolgica, datos pesqueros como las estadsticas de capturas y el esfuerzo pesquero, y datos de estudios cientficos para estimar la dinmica de las poblaciones de peces con fines de gestin. Los mtodos de evaluacin de poblaciones incluyen modelos dinmicos biolgicos, modelos estructurados por edad, mtodos basados en la talla y modelos de reclutamiento de poblaciones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripcin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El punto de referencia basado en el RMS suele establecerse mediante un proceso formal de evaluacin de las poblaciones. Los datos que sirven de base a las evaluaciones de las poblaciones pueden proceder de muchas fuentes diferentes, incluidas las dependientes e independientes de la pesca. Los datos dependientes de la pesquera se recolectan de la propia pesquera, utilizando tanto fuentes comerciales como recreativas a travs de informes o encuestas por muestreo en el mar, en los lugares de desembarque o en las comunidades pesqueras. Los datos de estas fuentes se suelen compilar en las estadsticas de pesca. Pueden incluir informacin sobre las extracciones de pescado del mar, que pueden incluir los desembarques y los descartes, e informacin sobre la flota, como el nmero de barcos, el nmero de remolques y el tiempo de permanencia en el mar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos independientes de la pesca se obtienen de forma no relacionada con ninguna actividad pesquera y suelen ser recolectados por los cientficos a travs de estudios (a menudo cruceros cientficos) diseados para muestrear la abundancia y la biomasa de las especies en series temporales largas y en temporadas y zonas geogrficas coherentes. Normalmente, los datos independientes de la pesca recolectan informacin biolgica sobre la especie (edad, longitud, peso, madurez, etc.), as como informacin sobre el hbitat y el medio ambiente (temperatura, salinidad, profundidad, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para la evaluacin de las poblaciones se requieren tres categoras principales de datos, que incluyen datos sobre los rasgos del ciclo vital y series temporales de capturas y esfuerzo pesquero. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;La abundancia de la poblacin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; a menudo no se conoce y la abundancia relativa o los ndices se utilizan a menudo para reflejar los cambios histricos en el tamao de la poblacin. Estos datos pueden proceder de estudios independientes de la pesquera, por ejemplo, muestreos acsticos o basados en redes de arrastre, o de estimaciones dependientes de la pesquera que utilizan datos de captura y esfuerzo. Los parmetros del ciclo vital proporcionan informacin sobre el crecimiento individual y la productividad de la poblacin, por ejemplo, el tamao de los peces, la edad, las tasas de reproduccin y la mortalidad natural. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Captura&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; es la cantidad de peces extrados de una poblacin por todos los tipos de pesca.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global/Regional:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debido a la gran demanda de datos de los mtodos clsicos de evaluacin de poblaciones, solo se ha evaluado un nmero limitado de poblaciones de peces. Estas especies representan el 17&amp;#x2013;25 por ciento de las capturas mundiales (Branch et al., 2011), y la mayora son capturadas por pesqueras de pases desarrollados. Para equilibrar la representatividad mundial de los resultados de la evaluacin y el objetivo de utilizar la mejor informacin disponible, la FAO utiliza un amplio espectro de datos y mtodos para ampliar su evaluacin a las poblaciones de peces que representan la mayor parte (70-80 por ciento) de las capturas mundiales (FAO, 2005).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nacional:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para la presentacin de informes nacionales, se envi un cuestionario a todos los Estados miembros de la FAO con lmites marinos en 2019, y se volver a enviar en 2020, 2021 y, posteriormente, cada dos aos. Para la lista completa de preguntas utilizadas para informar este indicador, consulte el Apndice 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Proceso de recoleccin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global/regional: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las poblaciones de peces que la FAO ha supervisado desde 1974 representan un amplio espectro de disponibilidad de datos, que van desde las poblaciones con muchos datos y evaluadas formalmente hasta las que tienen muy poca informacin, aparte de las estadsticas de capturas por zona de pesca principal de la FAO, y las que no tienen ninguna evaluacin de las poblaciones. Con el fin de utilizar los mejores datos e informacin disponibles y mantener la coherencia entre las poblaciones y los evaluadores, se ha definido un procedimiento para identificar la informacin sobre el estado de las poblaciones (FAO 2011). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nacional: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La FAO recopila los datos nacionales a travs de un cuestionario enviado al Punto Focal Principal (PFP) de cada pas. El PFP organiza un dispositivo institucional que identifica a las autoridades competentes para elaborar una lista de referencia de las existencias y completa el cuestionario. La informacin o los datos recolectados a travs del cuestionario de un pas solo servirn inicialmente para informar de los avances de cada pas. Dependiendo de la evolucin y de la mayor normalizacin de los informes de los pases en los prximos 3-5 aos, los datos nacionales podrn utilizarse para informar de las estimaciones globales/regionales.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendario&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recopilacin de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global/regional: cada 2 aos (es decir, 2013, 2015, 2017, 2019, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nacional: Informes cada 2 aos (es decir, 2019, 2021, 2023, 2025, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publicacin de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nacional: bienal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global/regional: bienal&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La FAO proporciona datos mundiales y regionales. Los datos a nivel nacional suelen ser comunicados por la Oficina Nacional de Estadstica o el Ministerio de Pesca y/o Agricultura.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justificacin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Convencin de las Naciones Unidas (ONU) sobre el Derecho del Mar (UNCLOS), el Acuerdo de las Naciones Unidas sobre Poblaciones de Peces (UNFSA [ONU, 1995]) y el Cdigo de Conducta para la Pesca Responsable de la FAO (FAO, 1995a) exigen el mantenimiento o la recuperacin de las poblaciones de peces en niveles capaces de producir su rendimiento mximo sostenible (RMS). Para cumplir los objetivos de estos tratados internacionales, las autoridades encargadas de la gestin de la pesca deben evaluar el estado de las poblaciones de peces y desarrollar polticas y estrategias de gestin eficaces. Como organismo de las Naciones Unidas con un mandato en materia de pesca, la FAO se esfuerza por proporcionar a la comunidad internacional la mejor informacin sobre el estado de los recursos pesqueros marinos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desde 1974, la FAO evala peridicamente el estado de los recursos pesqueros marinos e informa al respecto utilizando un amplio espectro de mtodos, desde modelos numricos hasta enfoques con pocos datos. Las estimaciones mundiales y regionales de la FAO tambin se utilizaron como indicador de los ODM para el Objetivo 7 sobre medio ambiente durante el perodo 2000-2015. Esto facilit su aprobacin como indicador de nivel I de los ODS por parte del 2. IAEG-ODS en octubre de 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador tiene una naturaleza peculiar en comparacin con los indicadores ms convencionales de los ODS. El indicador estima la sostenibilidad de las poblaciones de peces que a menudo se mueven a travs de las fronteras nacionales. Esto llev a que el indicador se comunicara inicialmente solo a nivel mundial y regional, con regiones que no se corresponden con las regiones continentales de los ODM o de los ODS, sino con las regiones marinas denominadas &amp;#x201C;Principales zonas de pesca de la FAO&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El Marco Global de Indicadores de los ODS es un mecanismo voluntario, pero los pases estn obligados a informar si disponen de datos. Como organismo custodio, la FAO trabaja para poner en marcha el nfasis de la Agenda 2030 en la apropiacin por parte de los pases y el mayor incentivo para tomar medidas a nivel nacional, regional y mundial. La FAO ha desarrollado, desde 2018, un enfoque de cuestionario para permitir que los pases individuales informen sobre la sostenibilidad de las poblaciones de peces. El enfoque 1) proporciona un marco para la presentacin de informes significativos a nivel de pas que complementa, pero no altera, la metodologa bsica del indicador 14.4.1 de los ODS a nivel mundial/regional, y 2) proporciona a los pases mtodos simplificados para llevar a cabo la evaluacin de las poblaciones de peces en contextos con datos limitados, superando en cierta medida las barreras tcnicas que presentaban los mtodos tradicionales. Esto se debe a que los informes a nivel de pas se limitarn a la evaluacin de las poblaciones que se encuentran nicamente dentro de la ZEE de un pas y, por lo tanto, no incluirn las poblaciones transzonales, las especies altamente migratorias ni las poblaciones de las Zonas Fuera de la Jurisdiccin Nacional (ABNJ). En consecuencia, los datos nacionales por s solos no pueden agregarse de manera significativa a nivel mundial/regional, pero pueden utilizarse para informar sobre los avances de los pases en materia de sostenibilidad de las poblaciones de peces dentro de la ZEE. La FAO ha desarrollado una plataforma en lnea para facilitar la estimacin y el informe propio de un pas del indicador. La plataforma ofrece un curso de aprendizaje electrnico que ayuda a los pases a comprender el indicador, la metodologa de estimacin y el proceso de elaboracin del informe, as como algunos mtodos sencillos de evaluacin de las poblaciones que pueden utilizarse para estimar el estado de las poblaciones cuando solo se dispone de datos limitados para ayudar a abordar la insuficiencia de capacidad a la que se enfrentan muchos pases en desarrollo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En 2019, la FAO comenz a enviar un cuestionario a los pases para recopilar datos nacionales con el objetivo de ayudar a los pases en el proceso de presentacin de informes. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador mide la sostenibilidad de los recursos pesqueros y es una medida de resultado final de la meta 14.4. Su derivacin requiere los datos y los conocimientos tcnicos necesarios para realizar la evaluacin de las poblaciones. El indicador a nivel mundial es estimado por la FAO basndose en la metodologa desarrollada en los aos 80. Aunque se han realizado actualizaciones peridicas para incorporar los avances tcnicos y los cambios en las principales especies de peces, pueden producirse algunas discrepancias entre las regiones en cuanto a la representatividad de la lista de referencia en las pesqueras prcticas. Sin embargo, esto no supondr un gran impacto en la fiabilidad de las tendencias temporales del indicador.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En el mbito nacional, la composicin de las poblaciones dentro de la lista de referencia de poblaciones y los criterios de seleccin utilizados para elaborar la lista variarn entre los pases, lo que hace que el indicador sea adecuado para comprobar el progreso propio de los pases a lo largo del tiempo. Sin embargo, esto reduce la comparabilidad de los niveles de sostenibilidad entre pases. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Metodologa&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mtodo de clculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actualmente, la FAO informa de los indicadores mundiales y regionales calculados a partir de la evaluacin de la FAO de una lista seleccionada de poblaciones de peces en todo el mundo. La metodologa se describe en el documento tcnico de la FAO (FAO 2011). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La FAO ha estado desarrollando el nuevo enfoque para la presentacin de informes a nivel nacional desde 2017, y ha consultado con los pases en tres talleres de consulta de expertos dedicados: En noviembre de 2017, la FAO convoc un taller para intercambiar opiniones con los profesionales nacionales sobre los nuevos mtodos analticos propuestos para elaborar el indicador 14.4.1 a nivel de pas&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-1&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. En febrero de 2019, la FAO convoc un taller de consulta de expertos&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; sobre el desarrollo de las metodologas para la evaluacin mundial del estado de las poblaciones de peces, con participantes de los pases y las organizaciones regionales de pesca. En octubre de 2019, la FAO organiz un taller de desarrollo de capacidades sobre mtodos de evaluacin y estimacin del estado de las poblaciones del indicador 14.4.1 de los ODS para la regin de Asia y el Pacfico, con participantes de 17 pases.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Sin embargo, hasta ahora muy pocos pases han comenzado su propia estimacin y presentacin de informes del indicador 14.4.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global/Regional:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se han realizado estimaciones globales y regionales de la sostenibilidad de las poblaciones para 584 poblaciones de peces de todo el mundo desde 1974, que representan el 70% de los desembarcos mundiales. Cada poblacin se estima utilizando la metodologa descrita en el documento tcnico de la FAO (FAO, 2011). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nacional:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador se calcula como el nmero de poblaciones con estado sostenible dividido por el nmero de poblaciones con estado conocido en la lista de referencia. Esta proporcin se calcula a partir del nmero de poblaciones, sin ponderar por su volumen de produccin ni por su abundancia; es decir, se considera que cada poblacin de peces tiene la misma importancia. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se pide a los pases que informen de la situacin de una lista de referencia de poblaciones de peces, que debe determinarse en funcin de la importancia de una poblacin especfica en una sociedad, ya sea en los desembarcos, la contribucin econmica a la sociedad o los valores culturales y tradicionales, y no en funcin de la existencia de una evaluacin de la poblacin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Informe completo accesible aqu: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/documents/card/en/c/I8714EN/%20%20&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/documents/card/en/c/I8714EN/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Informe completo accesible aqu&lt;a href=&quot;:%20http:/www.fao.org/3/ca4355en/ca4355en.pdf%20%20&quot;&gt;: http://www.fao.org/3/ca4355en/ca4355en.pdf &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel de pas:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Este indicador examina las poblaciones de peces marinos. Si un pas no tiene pesca de captura marina, el indicador no se calcula para ese pas. En ese caso, no se realiza ninguna imputacin para obtener las estimaciones. En el caso de los pases que comunican datos limitados sobre las poblaciones de peces marinos, se recopilan datos adicionales de grupos de trabajo cientficos y se revisan y analizan sobre la base de los conocimientos de los expertos de la FAO. Sin embargo, la estimacin del indicador a nivel regional y mundial no se bas en los cuestionarios de los pases, sino que fue realizada por la FAO mediante una evaluacin sistemtica de una lista de referencia seleccionada a nivel mundial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel regional y mundial:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para garantizar la exhaustividad de la informacin regional y mundial sobre las poblaciones, la FAO recopila informacin adicional al margen de la proporcionada por cada pas, en particular en lo que respecta a las poblaciones de peces altamente migratorios y transzonales. En el caso de las poblaciones compartidas, la FAO puede consultar a los rganos Regionales de Pesca (ORP), que tienen el mandato de evaluar y gestionar las poblaciones con sus partes contratantes, con el fin de recibir informacin y datos y realizar la evaluacin de las poblaciones cuando sea necesario. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Como se explica en la seccin &amp;#x201C;Justificacin&amp;#x201D;,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;los datos nacionales por s solos no pueden agregarse de forma significativa a nivel global/regional porque los informes a nivel de pas se limitarn a la evaluacin de las poblaciones que se encuentran nicamente dentro de la ZEE de un pas y, por lo tanto, no incluirn las poblaciones transzonales, las especies altamente migratorias ni las poblaciones de las Zonas Fuera de la Jurisdiccin Nacional (ABNJ). Por lo tanto, los &amp;#x201C;agregados&amp;#x201D; regionales por Zona Principal de Pesca de la FAO y el valor del indicador mundial se calculan con un enfoque especfico, como se describe en el Documento Tcnico de la FAO (FAO 2011).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Mtodos y directrices a disposicin de los pases para la compilacin de los datos a nivel nacional:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En cada pas, los datos disponibles para cada poblacin y el nivel de conocimientos para realizar los distintos tipos de evaluaciones sern diferentes. Algunos pases pueden tener evaluaciones clsicas de sus poblaciones ya realizadas, mientras que otros pueden tener muy pocas o ninguna evaluacin disponible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En algunos pases se han realizado pocas evaluaciones de los stocks. Para ayudar a estos pases y facilitarles la presentacin de informes, la FAO prepar materiales y herramientas en lnea, incluida una seleccin de mtodos que pueden utilizarse para evaluar el estado de las poblaciones con mtodos de datos limitados, como los basados en la talla y los de solo captura. Los puntos fuertes y las limitaciones de estos mtodos se discuten en un curso de aprendizaje electrnico (Leccin 4), y tambin se proporcionaron advertencias para evitar su uso incorrecto y tomar precauciones en la prctica. Adems, se han organizado talleres de desarrollo de capacidades para proporcionar apoyo a los pases en la evaluacin de las poblaciones y la presentacin de informes sobre el ODS 14.4.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Curso de aprendizaje en lnea:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=502&quot;&gt;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=502&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Garanta de calidad:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NA&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripcin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador tiene datos globales desde 1974 hasta 2017. El desglose regional es por zona pesquera principal de la FAO. Los indicadores regionales y mundiales se calcularon a partir de la lista de referencia de poblaciones de peces que la FAO estableci en 1974.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global/regional: el indicador tiene datos globales y regionales desde 1974 hasta 2017. El desglose regional es por zona pesquera principal de la FAO. Los pases no participan directamente en el clculo del indicador a nivel mundial/regional. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nacional: el cuestionario a nivel nacional se envi por primera vez en noviembre de 2019; la FAO identifica 165 pases con una frontera marina, y tres pases con frontera en el Mar Caspio, como elegibles, en principio, para informar. Como resultado de la primera convocatoria del cuestionario, noventa y siete pases expresaron su inters en el indicador (57%), de los cuales 81 respondieron con cuestionarios completos, 11 pases declararon que no podan informar por falta de datos o de tiempo, uno respondi con algunos datos de capturas y tres pases informaron su indicador por separado. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De 1974 a 2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nivel global/regional: de 1974 a 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nivel nacional: No disponible an (primer cuestionario enviado en noviembre de 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregacin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Por principales zonas de pesca marina de la FAO con fines estadsticos&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-3&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desde el punto de vista taxonmico, la FAO publica el indicador por separado para las poblaciones transzonales (sobre todo atn y similares).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/cwp-on-fishery-statistics/handbook/general-concepts/fishing-areas-for-statistical-purposes/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/cwp-on-fishery-statistics/handbook/general-concepts/fishing-areas-for-statistical-purposes/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Fuentes de discrepancia:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador es estimado por la FAO basndose en la metodologa desarrollada en los aos 80. Aunque se han realizado actualizaciones peridicas para incorporar los avances tcnicos y los cambios en las principales especies de peces, pueden producirse algunas discrepancias entre las regiones en cuanto a la representatividad de la lista de referencia en las pesqueras prcticas. Sin embargo, esto no supondr un gran impacto en la fiabilidad de las tendencias temporales del indicador.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ODS 14.4.1:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/sustainable-development-goals/indicators/1441/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/sustainable-development-goals/indicators/1441/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Curso en lnea: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=502&quot;&gt;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=502&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Referencias:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Branch, T.A., Jensen, O.P., Ricard, D., Ye, Y. y Hilborn, R. (2011) Contrastando las tendencias globales del estado de las pesqueras marinas obtenidas de las capturas y de las evaluaciones de las poblaciones. &lt;em&gt;Conservation Biology&lt;/em&gt;, 25: 777&amp;#x2013;783. doi: 10.1111/j.1523-1739.2011.01687.x.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO (1995) Cdigo de conducta para la pesca responsable. 41 pp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO (2005) Examen del estado de los recursos pesqueros marinos mundiales. Documento tcnico de pesca de la FAO n 457. Roma. 235 pp&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO (2011) Examen del estado de los recursos pesqueros marinos mundiales. Documento tcnico de la FAO 569: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/docrep/015/i2389e/i2389e00.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/docrep/015/i2389e/i2389e00.htm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONU (1995) Acuerdo para la aplicacin de las disposiciones de la Convencin de las Naciones Unidas sobre el Derecho del Mar de 10 de diciembre de 1982 relativas a la conservacin y ordenacin de las poblaciones de peces transzonales y las poblaciones de peces altamente migratorios. 40 pp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Apndice 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directrices para establecer la lista de referencia de las poblaciones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La lista de referencia recopila una lista de poblaciones de peces basada en los datos de la zona considerada, es decir, la ZEE y/o las aguas territoriales de un pas y/o posiblemente la zona de competencia de una organizacin regional de gestin de la pesca. Esta lista de poblaciones de peces incluir idealmente unidades de evaluacin o unidades de gestin existentes, y tambin posiblemente otras poblaciones de peces no evaluadas que se pescan en un pas determinado. La lista excluir las poblaciones que se encuentran en alta mar, principalmente los atunes y especies afines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Esta lista debera:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Representar al menos el 60% (se prefiere un porcentaje mayor cuando sea posible) del total nacional de capturas desembarcadas y/o declaradas (Total en toneladas, excluyendo los desembarques de los stocks transzonales). Debe proporcionarse informacin sobre todas las poblaciones que contribuyen a este 60% (o ms) de los desembarques, independientemente de que se conozca su situacin. Las poblaciones deben introducirse de izquierda a derecha en la hoja de clculo en el orden de mayor a menor de los desembarques totales de cada poblacin, en toneladas. Las especies con varios stocks diferentes deben introducirse como stocks separados. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contener los stocks de mayor importancia en trminos de capturas, funcin del ecosistema, valor econmico y consideraciones sociales/culturales. Si es posible, la lista debe representar los stocks de cada una de estas categoras para un pas determinado. Por ejemplo, se debe tener cuidado de incluir las poblaciones de peces que son importantes para la pesca a pequea escala, as como para la pesca industrial a gran escala. La consideracin de estas diferentes categoras variar segn los pases.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Permanecer sin cambios (es decir, durante al menos 5 aos) para reflejar mejor los cambios en el estado de las poblaciones a nivel nacional y minimizar el efecto de cambiar la lista de referencia de las poblaciones (es decir, aadir, eliminar, fusionar poblaciones) en el indicador de los ODS. Esto garantizar la coherencia en el clculo del indicador y reflejar mejor la sostenibilidad de las poblaciones de peces a lo largo del tiempo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Apndice 2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lista completa de preguntas a los pases para elaborar el indicador. Las celdas rosas son obligatorias, las blancas son opcionales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. LISTA DE REFERENCIA DE LAS POBLACIONES DE PECES Y ESTADO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.1 Nombre de la poblacin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.2 Distribucin jurisdiccional de la accin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Escriba &amp;quot;X&amp;quot; en la casilla correspondiente)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nacional&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compartido entre naciones&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.3 Solo para las poblaciones compartidas, enumere los pases explotadores&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.4 Indique si la poblacin est evaluada (S) o no (No)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.5 Mtodo de evaluacin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Si &amp;quot;S&amp;quot; se evalu, indique qu mtodo se utiliz: (1) Clsico; (2) Limitado por datos; (3) No especificado&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Si &amp;quot;No&amp;quot; indique el mejor conocimiento disponible utilizado para definir el estado de la poblacin (por ejemplo, tendencias sobre las tasas de captura o ndice de abundancia)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.6 Estado actual de la poblacin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indique si la poblacin es biolgicamente sostenible (S o No)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ao de evaluacin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indique las referencias de la fuente de la evaluacin oficial de la poblacin u otra informacin, incluidos los enlaces web a los documentos en lnea cuando estn disponibles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.7 Desembarcos totales de toda la poblacin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Desembarcos (en toneladas)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ao de referencia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proporcin de los desembarques totales con respecto al total de desembarques nacionales (excluidos los desembarques de poblaciones transzonales) (en porcentaje)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1 INFORMACIN INDIVIDUAL SOBRE ACCIONES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.1 Nombre de la accin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Nombre de la accin individual&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.2 Nombre cientfico&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Nombre cientfico de la especie, preferiblemente segn la Lista de especies para fines de estadsticas pesqueras del ASFIS&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.3 Nombre comn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Nombre comn de la especie en ingls (si est disponible)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Nombre comn de la especie en el idioma local (enumere ms de uno si es pertinente)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.4 Zona principal de pesca de la FAO/ con subniveles cuando corresponda&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indique el cdigo de la zona principal de pesca de la FAO&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indique el cdigo de los subniveles de la zona, cuando proceda&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.5 Las existencias se consideran ...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(es posible seleccionar varias respuestas, coloque &amp;quot;X&amp;quot; en la(s) celda(s) correspondiente(s))&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;... Unidad de evaluacin (para poblaciones con una evaluacin oficial disponible)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2026; Unidad de gestin (Unidad que se utiliza para aplicar medidas de gestin basadas o no en una evaluacin de la poblacin)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &amp;#x2026;Otra unidad (es decir, Especie x rea) (si no hay ninguna de las anteriores)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.8 Agencia de gestin/organismo asesor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Agencia de gestin u organismo asesor responsable de la evaluacin (si se trata de una unidad de evaluacin) o de la gestin (si se trata de una unidad de gestin)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2 INFORMACIN SOBRE LA EVALUACIN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.1 Estado de la evaluacin (S, No)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indique si la poblacin est evaluada (S) o no evaluada (No)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.2 Sobrepesca (S, No, Desconocido)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;La evaluacin oficial de la poblacin concluye &amp;quot;Sobrepesca&amp;quot; con respecto a los puntos de referencia de abundancia (S, No, Desconocido). Nota: si la poblacin est sobreexplotada, entonces no es biolgicamente sostenible (responda NO en la lnea 15 de la pregunta, seccin 1). Cuando sea posible, apoye su respuesta con la informacin de la Seccin 2.3 (por ejemplo, la biomasa actual es inferior al punto de referencia de la biomasa objetivo)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.3 Sobrepesca (S, No, Desconocido)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;La evaluacin oficial de la poblacin concluye &amp;quot;Sobrepesca&amp;quot; con respecto a los puntos de referencia de mortalidad por pesca (S, No, Desconocido). Nota: vase el curso de aprendizaje en lnea sobre cmo relacionar los puntos de referencia de mortalidad por pesca con la sostenibilidad biolgica.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.4 Mtodo/software de evaluacin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Si existe una evaluacin oficial de la poblacin, indique qu mtodo o programa informtico se ha utilizado. Por ejemplo: sntesis de la poblacin; ASPIC, MULTIFAN-CL; VIT, tendencias de la CPUE, tendencias de las capturas, tendencias de la talla/talla, ninguno, otros&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.5 Disponibilidad de la evaluacin (S, No)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;La evaluacin est disponible pblicamente (S o No)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.6 Referencias de fuentes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Lista de referencias de fuentes utilizadas para recopilar la informacin, incluidos los enlaces web a los documentos en lnea cuando estn disponibles&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.7 Fiabilidad (L/M/H)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Alta (H) &amp;#x2013;La evaluacin formal de la poblacin a nivel regional, nacional o local constituye la base de la clasificacin del estado de la poblacin;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Media (M) &amp;#x2013;Los datos/informacin grises y el anlisis de las tendencias de las capturas constituyen la base de la clasificacin del estado de la poblacin;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Baja (L) &amp;#x2013;Para la clasificacin del estado de la poblacin se utilizaron datos/informacin en negro y una evaluacin cualitativa (por ejemplo, el juicio de los expertos)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3 DATOS DE ENTRADA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disponibilidad de datos (S, No)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Datos de entrada necesarios para la evaluacin de la poblacin&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3.1 Abundance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Biomasa actual&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Biomasa o abundancia ms reciente en toneladas (NA si no est disponible)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Biomasa virgen/pristina (B0)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Valor del punto de referencia de la biomasa o de la abundancia en toneladas (es decir, biomasa del stock primario)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tipo de punto de referencia objetivo&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tipo de punto de referencia de biomasa o abundancia utilizado (por ejemplo, 0,4B0; BMSY, etc. )&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Ao de referencia&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;ltimo ao de los datos de entrada utilizados en la evaluacin (es decir, el ao de la biomasa actual)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3.2 Mortalidad por pesca&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;F actual&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Mortalidad por pesca (F) o tasa de explotacin (U) ms recientes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Punto de referencia F&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Valor del punto de referencia de mortalidad por pesca&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tipo de punto de referencia&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tipo de punto de referencia de mortalidad por pesca utilizado (por ejemplo, FMSY, F01, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Ao de referencia&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;ltimo ao de los datos de entrada utilizados en la evaluacin (es decir, el ao de la F actual)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3.3 CPUE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;CPUE actual&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Valor actual de las capturas por unidad de esfuerzo&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Unidades de CPUE&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Unidad (por ejemplo, kg/trampa), en caso de que la CPUE no est estandarizada&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Ao de la CPUE actual&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Ao de la CPUE actual&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3.4 Capturas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Captura actual&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Valor actual de las capturas (en toneladas)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Ao de referencia&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Ao de la captura actual&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Media de capturas mximas&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Valor de la captura mxima en la serie temporal (en toneladas) (despus de 5 aos de suavizacin)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. SERIES TEMPORALES DE APOYO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;Las series temporales son opcionales, pero se recomienda que se comuniquen por poblacin para todos los aos disponibles&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identificacin de la poblacin de peces&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ao&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Desembarcos (en toneladas)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capturas (en toneladas)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abundancia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CPUE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tasa de explotacin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Esfuerzo de pesca&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medicin_obs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unidad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medicin_obs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unidad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medicin_obs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unidad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medicin_obs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unidad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;METADATOS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. La lista de referencia de las poblaciones representa al menos el 60% del total nacional actual de las estadsticas de capturas desembarcadas y/o notificadas...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1a. Si contest &amp;quot;No&amp;quot;, por favor especifique&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. La lista de referencia de las poblaciones contiene todas las poblaciones de mayor importancia en trminos de capturas, funcin del ecosistema, valor econmico y consideraciones sociales/culturales&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Por favor, indique la frecuencia de la evaluacin de la poblacin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3a. Si contest &amp;quot;Otros&amp;quot;, por favor especifique&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Si el indicador 14.4.1 de los ODS se recoge en el portal nacional de los ODS, en la base de datos o en otro lugar, indique la direccin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2a. Por favor, indique otras direcciones si las tiene&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Cualquier informacin adicional:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 14: Conserver et exploiter de manire durable les ocans, les mers et les ressources marines aux fins dudveloppement durable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 14.4: Dici  2020, rglementer efficacement la pche, mettre un terme  la surpche,  la pche illicite, non dclare et non rglemente et aux pratiques de pche destructrices et excuter des plans de gestion fonds sur des donnes scientifiques, lobjectif tant de rtablir les stocks de poissons le plus rapidement possible, au moins  des niveaux permettant dobtenir un rendement constant maximal compte tenu des caractristiques biologiques&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 14.4.1: Proportion de stocks de poissons dont le niveau estbiologiquement viable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2021-02-01&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicateurs connexes &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 14.7.1 : Proportion du PIB correspondant aux activits de pche viables dans les petits tats insulaires en dveloppement, les pays les moins avancs et tous les pays.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organisation des Nations Unies pour l&apos;alimentation et l&apos;agriculture (FAO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et dfinitions &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dfinition :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur Proportion de stocks de poissons marins se situant dans des niveaux biologiquement viables mesure la viabilit des pcheries de capture marines du monde par leur abondance. Un stock de poissons dont l&apos;abondance est gale ou suprieure au niveau qui peut produire le rendement maximal durable (RMD) est considr comme biologiquement durable. En revanche, lorsque l&apos;abondance tombe en dessous du niveau du RMD, le stock est considr comme biologiquement non durable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le RMD est dfini comme la plus grande quantit de prises qui peut tre rcolte de faon continue  partir d&apos;un stock dans des conditions environnementales constantes et actuelles (par exemple, l&apos;habitat, les conditions de l&apos;eau, la composition et les interactions des espces, et tout ce qui pourrait affecter les taux de naissance, de croissance ou de mortalit du stock) sans affecter la productivit  long terme du stock. L&apos;indicateur mesure la durabilit des ressources halieutiques sur la base d&apos;un bon quilibre entre l&apos;utilisation humaine et la conservation cologique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les points de rfrence bass sur le RMD sont le type de points de rfrence le plus communment utilis dans la gestion des pches aujourd&apos;hui. Cela s&apos;explique principalement par le fait que, pendant des dcennies, les points de rfrence des modles de production excdentaire ont le plus souvent t fixs sur la base du concept de RMD et qu&apos;ils constituent les repres de base pour la durabilit des pches fixs par la Convention des Nations unies sur le droit de la mer (UNCLOS, article 61(3)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Un stock de poissons&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;dsigne un groupe d&apos;individus d&apos;une seule espce ou parfois d&apos;espces combines vivant dans une zone dfinie et dont les captures sont effectues dans le cadre d&apos;une pche&lt;/p&gt;.
Une &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;liste de rfrence des stocks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; devrait tre tablie par chaque pays et consiste en une liste de stocks slectionns selon les directives de l&apos;Organisation pour l&apos;alimentation et l&apos;agriculture (FAO), par rapport auxquels l&apos;indicateur sera rapport (Annexe 1). La liste de rfrence devrait inclure les stocks nationaux et partags, mais pas les stocks chevauchants tels que dfinis ci-dessous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Les stocks nationaux &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; sont entirement situs dans une ZEE et/ou des eaux territoriales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Les stocks partags &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;sont rpartis dans la ZEE et/ou les eaux territoriales de deux pays adjacents ou plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Les stocks chevauchants&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; se dplacent  travers les frontires entre les eaux de la ZEE ou entre la ZEE et la haute mer (par exemple, les stocks de thon), et sont capturs par plusieurs pays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il est demand aux pays de faire rapport sur les stocks numrs dans sa liste de rfrence, y compris ceux qui sont surveills par des &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;valuations officielles des stocks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; par une agence faisant autorit, selon un processus scientifique et en utilisant les meilleures donnes scientifiques disponibles. Ces valuations pourraient tre bases sur des mthodes classiques ou limites aux donnes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;valuation des stocks utilise des informations biologiques, des donnes de pche telles que les statistiques de capture et l&apos;effort de pche, et des donnes d&apos;enqutes scientifiques pour estimer la dynamique de la population des stocks de poissons  des fins de gestion. Les mthodes d&apos;valuation des stocks comprennent les modles biologiques dynamiques, les modles structurs par ge, les mthodes bases sur la longueur et les modles de recrutement des stocks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Sources de donnes &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le point de rfrence bas sur le RMD est souvent tabli par un processus formel d&apos;valuation des stocks. Les donnes utilises pour l&apos;valuation des stocks peuvent provenir de nombreuses sources diffrentes, y compris des sources dpendantes et indpendantes de la pche. Les donnes dpendantes de la pche sont collectes  partir de la pche elle-mme, en utilisant des sources commerciales et rcratives par le biais de dclarations ou d&apos;enqutes par sondage en mer, sur les sites de dbarquement ou au sein des communauts de pcheurs. Les donnes provenant de ces sources sont gnralement compiles dans des statistiques sur la pche. Elles peuvent comprendre des informations sur les prlvements de poissons dans la mer, qui peuvent inclure les dbarquements et les rejets, et des informations sur la flotte telles que le nombre de bateaux, le nombre de remorques, le temps pass en mer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les donnes indpendantes de la pche sont obtenues de manire non lie  une quelconque activit de pche et sont gnralement recueillies par des scientifiques par le biais d&apos;enqutes (souvent des croisires scientifiques) conues pour chantillonner l&apos;abondance et la biomasse des espces sur de longues sries temporelles, et sur des saisons et des zones gographiques cohrentes. En gnral, les donnes indpendantes de la pche recueillent des informations biologiques sur l&apos;espce (ge, longueur, poids, maturit, etc.), ainsi que des informations sur l&apos;habitat et l&apos;environnement (temprature, salinit, profondeur, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trois catgories principales de donnes sont ncessaires pour l&apos;valuation des stocks, y compris les donnes sur les caractristiques du cycle de vie et les sries chronologiques des prises et de l&apos;effort de pche &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;l&apos;abondance du stock&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; est souvent inconnue et l&apos;abondance relative ou les indices sont souvent utiliss pour reflter les changements historiques de la taille de la population. Ces donnes peuvent provenir d&apos;enqutes indpendantes de la pche, par exemple d&apos;un chantillonnage acoustique ou au chalut, ou d&apos;estimations dpendantes de la pche utilisant les donnes de capture et d&apos;effort. Les paramtres du cycle biologique fournissent des informations sur la croissance individuelle et la productivit du stock, par exemple la taille du poisson, l&apos;ge, les taux de reproduction et la mortalit naturelle. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;La capture &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; est la quantit de poissons prlevs d&apos;un stock par tous les types de pche.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global/Rgional:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En raison des exigences leves en matire de donnes des mthodes classiques d&apos;valuation des stocks, seul un nombre limit de stocks de poissons a t valu. Ces espces reprsentent 17&amp;#x2013;25 pour cent des prises mondiales (Branch et al., 2011), et la plupart sont captures par les pcheries des pays dvelopps. Pour quilibrer la reprsentativit mondiale des rsultats de l&apos;valuation et l&apos;objectif d&apos;utiliser les meilleures informations disponibles, la FAO utilise un large ventail de donnes et de mthodes pour tendre son valuation aux stocks de poissons qui reprsentent la majorit (70-80 pour cent) des prises mondiales (FAO, 2005).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour la dclaration des pays, un questionnaire a t envoy  tous les tats membres de la FAO ayant des frontires maritimes en 2019, et sera renvoy en 2020, 2021, puis tous les deux ans. Pour la liste complte des questions utilises pour renseigner cet indicateur, veuillez vous rfrer  l&apos;annexe 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Collection process:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global/regional: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;Les stocks de poissons que l&apos;organisation pour l&apos;agriculture et l&apos;alimentation (FAO) surveille depuis 1974 reprsentent un large ventail de donnes disponibles, allant des stocks riches en donnes et formellement valus  ceux qui ne disposent que de trs peu d&apos;informations,  l&apos;exception des statistiques de capture par grande zone de pche de la FAO, et  ceux qui ne font l&apos;objet d&apos;aucune valuation de stock. Afin d&apos;utiliser les meilleures donnes et informations disponibles et de maintenir la cohrence entre les stocks et les valuateurs, une procdure a t dfinie pour identifier les informations sur l&apos;tat des stocks (FAO 2011). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;FAO collecte des donnes nationales par le biais d&apos;un questionnaire envoy au Point Focal Principal (PFP) de chaque pays. Le PFP organise un dispositif institutionnel qui identifie les autorits comptentes pour tablir une liste de rfrence des stocks et remplit le questionnaire. Les informations ou les donnes recueillies par le biais du questionnaire auprs d&apos;un pays ne serviront initialement qu&apos; informer les progrs de chaque pays. En fonction de l&apos;volution et de la poursuite de la normalisation des rapports nationaux au cours des 3  5 prochaines annes, les donnes nationales pourront tre utilises pour alimenter les estimations mondiales/rgionales.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendrier &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Collecte des donnes : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mondial/rgional : tous les 2 ans (c&apos;est--dire 2013, 2015, 2017, 2019, etc.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National : Rapports tous les 2 ans (c&apos;est--dire 2019, 2021, 2023, 2025, etc.) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fournisseurs de donnes &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;Organisation pour l&apos;agriculture et l&apos;alimentation (FAO) fournit des donnes mondiales et rgionales. Les donnes au niveau national sont gnralement communiques par l&apos;Office national des statistiques ou le ministre de la pche et/ou de l&apos;agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FAO&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justification :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Convention des Nations Unies sur le droit de la mer (UNCLOS), l&apos;Accord des Nations Unies sur les stocks de poissons (UNFSA [UN, 1995]) et le Code de conduite pour une pche responsable de l&apos;organisation pour l&apos;agriculture et l&apos;alimentation (FAO) (FAO, 1995a) exigent tous le maintien ou la restauration des stocks de poissons  des niveaux capables de produire leur rendement maximal durable (RMD). Pour atteindre les objectifs de ces traits internationaux, les autorits de gestion des pches doivent entreprendre une valuation de l&apos;tat des stocks de poissons et laborer des politiques et des stratgies de gestion efficaces. En tant qu&apos;agence des Nations Unies ayant un mandat pour la pche, la FAO s&apos;efforce de fournir  la communaut internationale les meilleures informations sur l&apos;tat des ressources halieutiques marines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depuis 1974, la FAO a priodiquement valu et rapport l&apos;tat des ressources halieutiques marines en utilisant un large ventail de mthodes allant des modles numriques aux approches pauvres en donnes. Les estimations mondiales et rgionales de la FAO ont galement t utilises comme indicateur des OMD pour l&apos;objectif 7 sur l&apos;environnement au cours de la priode 2000-2015. Cela a facilit son approbation en tant qu&apos;indicateur de niveau I des ODD par le 2e GIAE-GDD en octobre 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur a une nature particulire par rapport aux indicateurs ODD plus conventionnels. L&apos;indicateur estime la durabilit des stocks de poissons qui se dplacent souvent au-del des frontires nationales. Cela a conduit l&apos;indicateur  tre initialement rapport uniquement aux niveaux mondial et rgional, les rgions ne correspondant pas aux rgions continentales des OMD ou des ODD, mais aux rgions marines appeles &amp;#x201C;Zones de pche majeures de la FAO&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Cadre mondial d&apos;indicateurs des ODD est un mcanisme volontaire, mais les pays sont tenus de faire rapport si les donnes sont disponibles. En tant qu&apos;agence gardienne, la FAO s&apos;efforce de mettre en action l&apos;accent mis par l&apos;Agenda 2030&amp;#x2019;sur l&apos;appropriation par les pays et l&apos;incitation plus forte  prendre des mesures aux niveaux national, rgional et mondial. La FAO a dvelopp, depuis 2018, une approche par questionnaire pour permettre aux diffrents pays de rendre compte de la durabilit des stocks de poissons. Cette approche 1) fournit un cadre pour l&apos;tablissement de rapports significatifs au niveau des pays, qui complte mais ne modifie pas la mthodologie de base de l&apos;indicateur 14.4.1 des ODD aux niveaux mondial/rgional, et 2) fournit aux pays des mthodes simplifies pour raliser l&apos;valuation des stocks de poissons dans des contextes o les donnes sont limites, en surmontant dans une certaine mesure les obstacles techniques que prsentaient les mthodes traditionnelles. En effet, les rapports nationaux seront limits  l&apos;valuation des stocks qui se trouvent uniquement dans la ZEE d&apos;un pays, et ne comprendront donc pas les stocks chevauchants, les espces hautement migratoires ou les stocks dans les zones situes au-del de la juridiction nationale (ZJN). Par consquent, les donnes nationales seules ne peuvent pas tre agrges de manire significative aux niveaux mondial/rgional, mais elles peuvent tre utilises pour informer les progrs des pays sur la durabilit des stocks de poissons dans la ZEE. La FAO a dvelopp une plateforme en ligne pour faciliter l&apos;estimation et le rapport de l&apos;indicateur par un pays&amp;#x2019;. La plateforme fournit un cours d&apos;apprentissage en ligne qui aide les pays  comprendre l&apos;indicateur, la mthodologie d&apos;estimation et le processus de rapport, ainsi que certaines mthodes simples d&apos;valuation des stocks qui peuvent tre utilises pour estimer l&apos;tat des stocks lorsque seules des donnes limites sont disponibles, afin de contribuer  remdier  l&apos;insuffisance de capacit  laquelle sont confronts de nombreux pays en dveloppement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En 2019, la FAO a commenc  envoyer un questionnaire aux pays pour recueillir des donnes nationales dans le but d&apos;aider les pays dans le processus de dclaration. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires et limites :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur mesure la durabilit des ressources halieutiques et constitue une mesure du rsultat final de la cible 14.4. Son calcul ncessite les donnes et l&apos;expertise technique ncessaires  l&apos;valuation des stocks. L&apos;indicateur au niveau mondial est estim par la FAO sur la base de la mthodologie dveloppe dans les annes 1980. Bien que des mises  jour rgulires aient t effectues pour incorporer les progrs techniques et les changements dans les principales espces de poissons, certaines divergences entre les rgions peuvent se produire dans la reprsentativit de la liste de rfrence dans les pcheries pratiques. Toutefois, cela n&apos;aura pas un impact important sur la fiabilit des tendances temporelles de l&apos;indicateur&amp;#x2019;678.
&lt;p&gt;Au niveau national, la composition des stocks dans la liste de rfrence des stocks et les critres de slection utiliss pour dvelopper la liste varieront entre les pays, rendant l&apos;indicateur appropri pour vrifier les progrs des pays&amp;#x2019; eux-mmes au fil du temps. Cependant, cela rduit la comparabilit des niveaux de durabilit entre les pays.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Mthodologie &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mthode de calcul :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;La FAO rapporte actuellement les indicateurs mondiaux et rgionaux calculs  partir de l&apos;valuation par la FAO&amp;#x2019;d&apos;une liste slectionne de stocks de poissons dans le monde. La mthodologie est dcrite dans le document technique de la FAO (FAO 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La FAO dveloppe la nouvelle approche pour les rapports nationaux depuis 2017, et a consult les pays dans le cadre de trois ateliers de consultation d&apos;experts ddis : En novembre 2017, la FAO a organis un atelier pour changer des points de vue avec les praticiens nationaux sur les nouvelles mthodes analytiques proposes pour produire l&apos;indicateur 14.4.1 au niveau des pays&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-1&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. En fvrier 2019, la FAO a organis un atelier de consultation d&apos;experts&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; sur l&apos;laboration des mthodes d&apos;valuation mondiale de l&apos;tat des stocks de poissons, avec des participants des pays et des organisations rgionales de pche. En octobre 2019, la FAO a organis un atelier de renforcement des capacits sur l&apos;valuation de l&apos;tat des stocks et les mthodes d&apos;estimation de l&apos;indicateur 14.4.1 des ODD pour la rgion Asie-Pacifique, avec des participants de 17 pays&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Cependant, jusqu&apos; prsent, trs peu de pays ont commenc leur propre estimation et rapport de l&apos;indicateur 14.4.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global/Regional:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;Des estimations mondiales et rgionales de la durabilit des stocks ont t ralises pour 584 stocks de poissons dans le monde depuis 1974, reprsentant 70% des dbarquements mondiaux. Chaque stock est estim en utilisant la mthodologie dcrite dans le document technique de la FAO (FAO, 2011). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur est calcul comme le nombre de stocks ayant un statut durable divis par le nombre de stocks ayant un statut connu dans la liste de rfrence. Cette proportion est calcule sur la base du nombre de stocks, sans pondration ni par son volume de production ni par l&apos;abondance du stock, c&apos;est--dire que chaque stock de poissons est considr comme ayant la mme importance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;Il est demand aux pays de rendre compte de l&apos;tat d&apos;une liste de rfrence des stocks de poissons, qui devrait tre dtermine en fonction de l&apos;importance d&apos;un stock spcifique dans une socit, soit en termes de dbarquements, de contribution conomique  la socit, ou de valeurs culturelles et traditionnelles, plutt qu&apos;en fonction de l&apos;existence d&apos;une valuation du stock &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-1&quot;&gt;1 &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p&gt; Le rapport complet est accessible ici : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/documents/card/en/c/I8714EN/%20%20&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/documents/card/en/c/I8714EN/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt; &amp;#x2191; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;2 &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p&gt; Le rapport complet est accessible ici : http://www.fao.org/3/ca4355en/ca4355en.pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt; &amp;#x2191; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;.&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traitement des valeurs manquantes : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Au niveau national : &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur examine les stocks de poissons marins. Si un pays n&apos;a pas de pche de capture marine, l&apos;indicateur n&apos;est pas calcul pour ce pays. Dans ce cas, aucune imputation n&apos;est effectue pour obtenir des estimations. Pour les pays rapportant des donnes limites sur les stocks de poissons marins, des donnes supplmentaires sont compiles  partir de groupes de travail scientifiques et sont rvises par des pairs et analyses sur la base des connaissances des experts de la FAO. Cependant, l&apos;estimation de l&apos;indicateur aux niveaux rgional et mondial n&apos;a pas t ralise  partir de questionnaires nationaux, mais par la FAO grce  une valuation systmatique d&apos;une liste de rfrence slectionne au niveau mondial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Aux niveaux rgional et mondial : &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour assurer l&apos;exhaustivit des informations rgionales et mondiales sur les stocks, la FAO recueille des informations supplmentaires en plus de celles fournies par chaque pays, notamment en ce qui concerne les stocks de grands migrateurs et les stocks chevauchants. Pour les stocks partags, la FAO peut consulter les organismes rgionaux de pche (ORP), qui sont mandats pour valuer et grer les stocks avec leurs parties contractantes, afin de recevoir des informations et des donnes et de procder  une valuation des stocks si ncessaire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agrgats rgionaux : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comme expliqu dans la section &amp;#x201C;Justification&amp;#x201D;,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;les donnes nationales seules ne peuvent pas tre agrges de manire significative au niveau mondial/rgional car les rapports nationaux seront limits  l&apos;valuation des stocks qui se trouvent uniquement dans la ZEE d&apos;un pays&amp;#x2019;et n&apos;incluront donc pas les stocks chevauchants, les espces hautement migratoires ou les stocks dans les zones situes au-del de la juridiction nationale (ZJN). Par consquent, les &amp;#x201C;agrgats rgionaux&amp;#x201D; par zone de pche principale de la FAO et la valeur de l&apos;indicateur mondial sont calculs selon une approche spcifique, comme dcrit dans le document technique de la FAO (FAO 2011).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Mthodes et instructions  la disposition des pays pour la compilation des donnes au niveau national :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dans chaque pays, les donnes disponibles pour chaque stock et le niveau d&apos;expertise pour raliser les diffrents types d&apos;valuations seront diffrents. Certains pays peuvent avoir des valuations classiques dj ralises pour un grand nombre de leurs stocks, tandis que d&apos;autres peuvent avoir trs peu ou pas d&apos;valuations disponibles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour certains pays, peu d&apos;valuations de stocks ont t ralises. Pour aider ces pays et faciliter leur dclaration, la FAO a prpar du matriel et des outils en ligne, y compris une slection de mthodes qui peuvent tre utilises pour valuer l&apos;tat des stocks avec des mthodes  donnes limites telles que les mthodes bases sur la longueur et les mthodes de capture uniquement. Les forces et les limites de ces mthodes sont discutes dans un cours d&apos;apprentissage en ligne (leon 4), et des mises en garde ont galement t fournies pour viter les mauvaises utilisations et faire preuve de prudence dans la pratique. En outre, des ateliers de renforcement des capacits ont t organiss pour aider les pays  valuer les stocks et  tablir des rapports sur l&apos;ODD 14.4.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cours en ligne:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=502&quot;&gt;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=502&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Assurance de la qualit : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non disponible &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilit des donnes &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur dispose de donnes mondiales de 1974  2017. La ventilation rgionale se fait par grande zone de pche de la FAO. Les indicateurs rgionaux et mondiaux ont t calculs sur la base de la liste de rfrence des stocks de poissons tablie par la FAO en 1974.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mondial/rgional : l&apos;indicateur comporte des donnes mondiales et rgionales de 1974  2017. La ventilation rgionale se fait par grande zone de pche de la FAO. Les pays ne sont pas directement impliqus dans le calcul de l&apos;indicateur au niveau mondial/rgional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National : le questionnaire au niveau national a t envoy pour la premire fois en novembre 2019 ; la FAO identifie 165 pays ayant une frontire maritime, et trois pays ayant une frontire avec la mer Caspienne, comme tant ligibles, en principe,  la dclaration.  la suite du premier appel  questionnaire, quatre-vingt-dix-sept pays ont exprim leur intrt pour l&apos;indicateur (57 %), dont 81 ont rpondu par des questionnaires remplis, 11 pays ont dclar ne pas pouvoir faire de rapport par manque de donnes ou de temps, un a rpondu avec quelques donnes sur les captures, et trois pays ont dclar leur indicateur sparment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Srie chronologique : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De 1974  2017&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Niveau mondial/rgional : de 1974  2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Niveau national : Pas encore disponible (premier questionnaire expdi en novembre 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dsagrgation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Par grandes zones de pche marine de la FAO  des fins statistiques&lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-3&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt; [3] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D&apos;un point de vue taxonomique, la FAO publie l&apos;indicateur sparment pour les stocks chevauchants (principalement le thon et les thonids) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-3&quot;&gt;3 &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/cwp-on-fishery-statistics/handbook/general-concepts/fishing-areas-for-statistical-purposes/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/cwp-on-fishery-statistics/handbook/general-concepts/fishing-areas-for-statistical-purposes/en/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt; &amp;#x2191; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;.&lt;h2&gt;Sources de divergences :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur est estim par la FAO sur la base de la mthodologie dveloppe dans les annes 1980. Bien que des mises  jour rgulires aient t effectues pour intgrer les progrs techniques et les changements dans les principales espces de poissons, certaines divergences entre les rgions peuvent se produire dans la reprsentativit de la liste de rfrence dans les pcheries pratiques. Cependant, cela n&apos;aura pas un grand impact sur la fiabilit des tendances temporelles de l&apos;indicateur&amp;#x2019;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Rfrences &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ODD 14.4.1 : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/sustainable-development-goals/indicators/1441/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/sustainable-development-goals/indicators/1441/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cours eLearning : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=502&quot;&gt;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=502&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Branch, T.A., Jensen, O.P., Ricard, D., Ye, Y. &amp;amp; Hilborn, R. (2011) Contrasting global trends in marine fishery status obtained from catches and from stock assessments. &lt;em&gt;Conservation Biology &lt;/em&gt;, 25 : 777&amp;#x2013;783. doi : 10.1111/j.1523-1739.2011.01687.x. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO (1995) Code de conduite pour une pche responsable. 41 pp. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO (2005) Examen de l&apos;tat des ressources halieutiques marines mondiales. Document technique sur les pches de la FAO n 457. Rome. 235 pp &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO (2011) Examen de l&apos;tat des ressources halieutiques marines mondiales. Document technique de la FAO 569 : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/docrep/015/i2389e/i2389e00.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/docrep/015/i2389e/i2389e00.htm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONU (1995) Accord aux fins de l&apos;application des dispositions de la Convention des Nations unies sur le droit de la mer du 10 dcembre 1982 relatives  la conservation et  la gestion des stocks de poissons chevauchants et des stocks de poissons grands migrateurs. 40 pp. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Annexe 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directives pour l&apos;tablissement d&apos;une liste de rfrence des stocks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La liste de rfrence compile une liste de stocks de poissons base sur les donnes de la zone considre, c&apos;est--dire la ZEE et/ou les eaux territoriales d&apos;un pays&amp;#x2019;et/ou ventuellement la zone de comptence d&apos;une organisation rgionale de gestion des pches. Cette liste de stocks de poissons inclura idalement les units d&apos;valuation ou les units de gestion existantes, et aussi ventuellement d&apos;autres stocks de poissons non valus qui sont pchs dans un pays donn. La liste exclura les stocks chevauchant en haute mer, principalement les thons et les espces apparentes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cette liste devrait : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reprsenter au moins 60% (un pourcentage plus lev est prfrable si possible) du total national des captures dbarques et/ou dclares (total en tonnes,  l&apos;exclusion des dbarquements des stocks chevauchants). Des informations doivent tre fournies sur tous les stocks qui contribuent  ces 60% (ou plus) des dbarquements, que leur statut soit connu ou non. Les stocks doivent tre saisis de gauche  droite sur la feuille de calcul, dans l&apos;ordre du plus grand au plus petit dbarquement total pour chaque stock, en tonnes. Les espces ayant plusieurs stocks diffrents doivent tre saisies en tant que stocks distincts. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contient des stocks d&apos;importance majeure en termes de capture, de rle dans l&apos;cosystme, de valeur conomique et de considrations sociales et culturelles. Si possible, la liste doit reprsenter les stocks de chacune de ces catgories pour un pays donn. Par exemple, il faut veiller  inclure les stocks de poissons qui sont importants pour les pches  petite chelle ainsi que pour les pches industrielles  grande chelle. La prise en compte de ces diffrentes catgories variera selon les pays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rester inchang (c&apos;est--dire pendant au moins 5 ans) pour mieux reflter les changements dans l&apos;tat des stocks au niveau national et minimiser l&apos;effet de la modification de la liste de rfrence des stocks (c&apos;est--dire l&apos;ajout, la suppression, la fusion de stocks) dans l&apos;indicateur des ODD. Cela permettra d&apos;assurer la cohrence du calcul de l&apos;indicateur et de mieux reflter la durabilit des stocks de poissons au fil du temps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Annexe 2 &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liste complte des questions poses aux pays pour renseigner l&apos;indicateur. Les cellules roses sont obligatoires, les cellules blanches sont facultatives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. LISTE DE RFRENCE DES STOCKS DE POISSONS &amp;amp; STATUT &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;1.1 Nom du stock &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.2 Rpartition juridictionnelle de l&apos;action &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Veuillez taper &amp;quot;X&amp;quot; dans la case correspondante) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Partag entre les nations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.3 Pour les stocks partags uniquement, veuillez numrer les pays exploitants &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;1.4 Veuillez indiquer si le stock est valu (Oui) ou non valu (Non) &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.5 Mthode d&apos;valuation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Si &amp;quot;Oui&amp;quot; valu, veuillez indiquer quelle approche a t utilise : (1) Classique ; (2) Limite aux donnes ; (3) Non spcifie &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Si &amp;quot;Non&amp;quot; veuillez indiquer les meilleures connaissances disponibles utilises pour dfinir l&apos;tat du stock (par ex. tendances des taux de capture ou indice d&apos;abondance).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        1.6 tat actuel du stock&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;.
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indiquez si le stock est biologiquement viable (Oui ou Non)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anne d&apos;valuation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indiquer les rfrences de la source de l&apos;valuation officielle du stock ou d&apos;autres informations, y compris les liens vers les documents en ligne lorsqu&apos;ils sont disponibles.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.7 Dbarquements totaux pour l&apos;ensemble du stock&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Dbarquements (en tonnes) &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anne de rfrence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proportion du total des dbarquements par rapport au total des dbarquements nationaux ( l&apos;exclusion des dbarquements des stocks chevauchants) (en pourcentage)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;2.1 INFORMATIONS INDIVIDUELLES SUR LES STOCKS &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.1 Nom du stock &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Nom de l&apos;action individuelle.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.2 Nom scientifique&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Nom scientifique de l&apos;espce, de prfrence selon la liste ASFIS des espces  des fins de statistiques de pche.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.3 Nom commun&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Nom commun de l&apos;espce en anglais (si disponible) &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;Nom commun de l&apos;espce dans la langue locale (en citer plusieurs si ncessaire.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.4 Zone de pche principale de la FAO/ avec les sous-niveaux le cas chant.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indiquez le code de la principale zone de pche de la FAO.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;Indiquez le code des sous-niveaux de la zone, le cas chant.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.5 Le stock est considr comme ...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(possibilit de slectionner plusieurs rponses, mettre &amp;quot;X&amp;quot; dans la ou les cellules correspondantes).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;... Unit d&apos;valuation (pour les stocks dont l&apos;valuation officielle est disponible) &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &amp;#x2026; Unit de gestion (Unit utilise pour mettre en uvre des mesures de gestion bases ou non sur une valuation de stock) &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &amp;#x2026; Autre unit (c.--d., Espce x Zone) (si aucune des units ci-dessus) &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;2.1.8 Agence de gestion/organisme consultatif &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Agence de gestion ou organe consultatif responsable de l&apos;valuation (si unit d&apos;valuation) ou de la gestion (si unit de gestion).&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;2.2 INFORMATIONS D&apos;VALUATION &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.1 Statut de l&apos;valuation (Oui, Non) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Indiquez si le stock est valu (Oui) ou non valu (Non) &lt;/p&gt;.
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.2 Surexploit (Oui, Non, Inconnu)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        L&apos;valuation officielle du stock conclut  une &amp;quot;Surexploitation&amp;quot; par rapport aux points de rfrence d&apos;abondance (Oui, Non, Inconnu). Remarque : si le stock est surexploit, il n&apos;est pas biologiquement viable (veuillez rpondre NON  la question de la ligne 15, section 1). Dans la mesure du possible, tayez votre rponse avec les informations de la section 2.3 (par exemple, la biomasse actuelle est infrieure au point de rfrence de la biomasse cible).&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.3 Surpche (Oui, Non, Inconnu)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;L&apos;valuation officielle du stock conclut  la &amp;quot;Surpche&amp;quot; en ce qui concerne les points de rfrence de la mortalit par pche (Oui, Non, Inconnu). Note : voir le cours d&apos;apprentissage en ligne sur la faon de relier les points de rfrence de la mortalit par pche  la durabilit biologique.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;2.2.4 Mthode d&apos;valuation/logiciel&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        9528]S&apos;il existe une valuation officielle du stock, veuillez indiquer la mthode ou le logiciel utilis. Par exemple : synthse du stock ; ASPIC, MULTIFAN-CL ; VIT, tendances des CPUE, tendances des captures, tendances des tailles/longueurs, aucune, autres &lt;/p&gt;.
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;2.2.5 Disponibilit de l&apos;valuation (Oui, Non) &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        9905]L&apos;valuation est disponible publiquement (Oui ou Non)&lt;/p&gt;.
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.6 Rfrences des sources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Liste des rfrences des sources utilises pour collecter les informations, y compris les liens vers les documents en ligne lorsqu&apos;ils sont disponibles.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.7 Fiabilit (L/M/H) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;leve (H) &amp;#x2013; L&apos;valuation formelle des stocks aux niveaux rgional, national ou local constitue la base de la classification de l&apos;tat des stocks ; &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Moyen (M) &amp;#x2013; Les donnes/informations grises et l&apos;analyse des tendances des captures constituent la base de la classification de l&apos;tat du stock ;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Faible (L) &amp;#x2013; Les donnes/informations noires et l&apos;valuation qualitative (par exemple, le jugement d&apos;experts) ont t utilises pour la classification de l&apos;tat du stock ;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;2.3 DONNES D&apos;ENTRE&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disponibilit des donnes (Oui, Non)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Donnes d&apos;entre ncessaires pour l&apos;valuation du stock &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3.1 Abundance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Biomasse actuelle.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Biomasse ou abondance la plus rcente en tonnes (NA si non disponible).&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Biomasse du stock vierge/principal (B0)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Valeur du point de rfrence de la biomasse ou de l&apos;abondance cible en tonnes (c&apos;est--dire la biomasse du stock vierge) &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Type de point de rfrence cible&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Type de biomasse ou de point de rfrence d&apos;abondance utilis (par exemple 0,4B0 ; BMSY, etc.) &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Anne de rfrence&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Dernire anne des donnes d&apos;entre utilises dans l&apos;valuation (c&apos;est--dire l&apos;anne de la biomasse actuelle)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3.2 Mortalit par pche&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;F actuel &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Mortalit par pche (F) ou taux d&apos;exploitation (U) les plus rcents.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Point de rfrence F&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Valeur du point de rfrence de la mortalit par pche &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Type de point de rfrence &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Type de point de rfrence de la mortalit par pche utilis (par ex. FMSY, F01, etc.) &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Anne de rfrence &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Dernire anne des donnes d&apos;entre utilises dans l&apos;valuation (c&apos;est--dire l&apos;anne du F actuel) &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3.3 CPUE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;CPUE actuelles&lt;/p&gt;.
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;Valeur actuelle des captures par unit d&apos;effort&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Units de CPUE&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Unit (par exemple kg/pige), au cas o les PUE ne seraient pas normalises.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;Anne de la PUE actuelle.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Anne de la CPUE actuelle&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3.4 Catches&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Capture actuelle &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Valeur actuelle des captures (en tonnes) &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Anne de rfrence&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Anne de la capture actuelle&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Capture moyenne Max &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Valeur de la capture maximale dans la srie chronologique (en tonnes) (aprs un lissage sur 5 ans)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. SUPPORT DES SRIES TEMPORELLES &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
        Les sries chronologiques sont facultatives mais il est recommand de les dclarer par stock pour toutes les annes disponibles. &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;ID du stock de poisson&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dbarquements (en tonnes)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Captures (en tonnes) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abundance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CPUE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exploitation rate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fishing Effort&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obs_measure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obs_measure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obs_measure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obs_measure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;METADONNES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. La liste de rfrence des stocks reprsente au moins 60% du total actuel des statistiques nationales de captures dbarques et/ou dclares ? &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1a. Si vous avez rpondu &amp;quot;Non&amp;quot;, veuillez spcifier&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. La liste de rfrence des stocks contient tous les stocks d&apos;importance majeure en termes de capture, de rle dans l&apos;cosystme, de valeur conomique et de considrations sociales/culturelles &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Veuillez indiquer la frquence de l&apos;valuation du stock &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3a. Si vous avez rpondu &amp;quot;Autre&amp;quot;, veuillez prciser&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Si l&apos;indicateur 14.4.1 des ODD est rapport dans le portail national des ODD, la base de donnes ou autre, veuillez indiquer l&apos;adresse &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;.
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2a. Veuillez fournir des adresses supplmentaires si disponibles &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Toute information supplmentaire : &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt; 14:     ,      &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 14.4:  2020        , ,         ,        ,          ,        ,             &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 14.4.1:   ,     &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  : 13  2020  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;   &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  14.7.1:             ,         &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;   &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;  (): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;       () &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;    &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     ,             .  ,       ,  ,        (),    . ,      ,    . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      ,             (,  ,  ,    ,   ,      ,    ),      .                . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  ,   M,      ,     .     ,                 M,       ,       (UNCLOS,  61 (3). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;   &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;          ,    ,       . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;             ,       ,       ( 1).        ,    ,   . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;   &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;      (  )  /   . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;   &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;      /        . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;   &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;             (,  ),      . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    ,     ,     ,     &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;    &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;  ,             .            . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     ,   ,       ,              .       ,        ,            . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;   &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;            .           ,         . ,   ,        ,           ,       .         .         ,       ,     ,    ,  , ,   . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      ,    -  ,       (  ),           ,        .           (, , ,   . .),          (, ,   . .).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;         ,          ,    . &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;   &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;  ,             .          ,          ,   ,        .           ,   , ,     . &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; -  ,       . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;  / : &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; -    ,      ,       .     17-25%   (Branch et al., 2011),          .            ,       ,        ,     (70-80 )    (FAO, 2005). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; : &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    ,   2019   - ,   ,   ,      2020, 2021 ,     .   ,     , .   2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;  : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;  / : &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ,       1974 ,     ,             ,      ,         ,   ,       .                           (FAO 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; : &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;       ,      .     ,          ,   .   ,      ,        .             3-5         /  . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;  &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;  : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  /  :  2  (, 2013, 2015, 2017, 2019  . .) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  :   2  (. . 2019, 2021, 2023, 2025  . .) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;  : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  :     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  /  :     &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;   &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      .             /    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;   &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     ()    (UNCLOS),        (UNFSA [UN, 1995])       (FAO, 1995a) -           ,       (M).                     .    ,   ,             . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  1974            ,    ,         .              7      2000-2015 .          I         -     (-)   2015 . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;           .     ,     .    ,           ,         ,   ,      .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     -   ,     ,     .   ,    ,        2030                 ,    .  2018     ,        .  1)        ,  ,       14.4.1    /  ,  2)             ,      ,    .    ,         ,     , , ,     ,            ().               /  ,                .   -          .     ,      ,     ,       ,       ,     ,       ,     .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  2019                 . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;  :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;            14.4.       ,     .         ,   1980- .             ,              .           .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;           ,    ,      ,            .          . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;         ,            .       (FAO 2011). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;           2017              :   2017          -         14.4.1    &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-1&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.   2019       &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;                 .   2019        17             14.4.1   - . &lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;                 14.4.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;  / :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;         584       1974 ,   70%   .      ,      (FAO, 2011). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;  :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;       ,          .       ,        ;   ,       .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;        ,               ,         ,          .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt;    : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/documents/card/en/c/I8714EN/%20%20&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/documents/card/en/c/I8714EN/ &lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt;   &lt;a href=&quot;:%20http:/www.fao.org/3/ca4355en/ca4355en.pdf%20%20&quot;&gt;: http://www.fao.org/3/ca4355en/ca4355en.pdf &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;  :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;  :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      .      ,      .         .  ,       ,                 .                ,           ,    . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;    :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;        ,      ,    ,  ,       .            (),           ,           . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    &amp;#x201C;  &amp;#x201D;            /  ,         ,     , , ,    ,       ,      (ABNJ). ,  &amp;#x201C;  &amp;#x201D;              ,       (FAO 2011).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;          :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;   ,            ,  .           ,               . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;       .         ,   -  ,   ,             ,   ,         .            ( 4),     ,         .  ,                   14.4.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eLearning course:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=502&quot;&gt;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=502&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;  : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     1974  2017 .        .           ,    1974 .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; /  :        1974  2017 .        .           /  . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; :         2019 ;   165   ,      ,     ,        .             (57%),   81      , 11  ,       -    ,        ,       . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 1974  2017 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/ :  1974  2018 .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; :    (     2019 .)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;        &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-3&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;        (     ).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/cwp-on-fishery-statistics/handbook/general-concepts/fishing-areas-for-statistical-purposes/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/cwp-on-fishery-statistics/handbook/general-concepts/fishing-areas-for-statistical-purposes/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2&gt; :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     ,   1980- .             ,             .           .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 14.4.1:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/sustainable-development-goals/indicators/1441/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/sustainable-development-goals/indicators/1441/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;  : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=502&quot;&gt;https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=502&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Branch, T.A., Jensen, O.P., Ricard, D., Ye, Y. &amp;amp; Hilborn, R. (2011) Contrasting global trends in marine fishery status obtained from catches and from stock assessments. &lt;em&gt;Conservation Biology&lt;/em&gt;, 25: 777&amp;#x2013;783. doi: 10.1111/j.1523-1739.2011.01687.x.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO (1995) Code of conduct for responsible fisheries. 41 pp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO (2005) Review of the state of world marine fishery resources. FAO Fisheries Technical Paper No. 457. Rome. 235 pp&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO (2011) Review of the state of world marine fishery resources. FAO technical paper 569: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/docrep/015/i2389e/i2389e00.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/docrep/015/i2389e/i2389e00.htm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; (1995 .)             10  1982 ,              . 40 .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt; 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      ,       ,      /     / , ,     .              ,  , ,    ,     .           ,      .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;   60% (     )
    /    (  ,    ).       ,    60% ( )  ,   ,    .                    .            . &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; ,       ,  ,
    /  .  ,             . ,      ,     ,      .         .&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;   (      5 ),  
               (.. , ,  )   .               .&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt; 2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;       .    ,   - .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.     &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.1  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.2   &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(,  &quot;X&quot;   )&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.3      -&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.4 ,    ()    ()&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.5  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;  &quot;&quot;, ,   : (1) ;
(2)   ; (3)  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &quot;&quot;    ,  
   (,       )&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.6   &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;,      (  )&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;        
,  -  -,   &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.7     &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; ( )&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;         (
   ) ( )&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1    &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.1  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.2  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  ,      
     &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.3  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;      ( )&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;      (  
  )&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.4    /  ,  
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;     .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;     .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot; rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.5  ...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(   ,  &quot;X&quot;  
)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;...   (      )&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2026;   (,    
       )&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2026;  (,  x ) (   
 )&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1.8   /  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;    ,   
(   )   (   )&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2   &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.1   (, )&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;,     ()   ()&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.2  (, , )&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;       
   (, , ). :   ,      (     15,  1).         2.3 (,       )&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.3  (, , )&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;      &quot;&quot; 
    (, , ). : .     ,         .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.4  /   &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;    , ,    
 . :  ; ASPIC, MULTIFAN-CL; VIT,  CPUE,  ,   / , , &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.5   (, )&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  (  )&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.6   &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;   ,    , 
-  -,   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2.7  ( /  / )&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; ()     , 
       ;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; ()   /      
    ;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; ()   /     (,
 )     .&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;  (, )&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; ,    &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3.1 &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;        (,  
)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; /   (0)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;        
(..   )&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;       (,
0,4B0; BMSY  . .)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;   ,    (..  
)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3.2  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; F&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;    (F)   (U)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  F&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;      (,
FMSY, F01  . .)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;   ,    (..  
F)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3.3     &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;     &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;      &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;     &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; (,  / ),      
 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;      &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;      &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.3.4 &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;   ( )&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; /p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;      ( ) ( 5-
)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.   &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;  ,   
     &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; ( )&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td rowspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; ( )&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;    &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.       60% 
    /   ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1a.   &quot;&quot;, &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.      ,  
    ,  ,     /  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.    &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3a.   &quot;&quot;, &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
     &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.  14.4.1     
,      ,  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2a.   ,   &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.   :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
