<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 14-5-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 14: Conserve and sustainably use the oceans, seas and marine resources for sustainable development&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 14.5: By 2020, conserve at least 10 per cent of coastal and marine areas, consistent with national and international law and based on the best available scientific information&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 14.5.1: Coverage of protected areas in relation to marine areas&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These metadata apply to all series under this indicator. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;July 2021&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the coverage by protected areas of important sites for marine biodiversity as an indicator towards SDG 14.5, other disaggregations of particular relevance as indicators towards SDG targets (Brooks et al. 2016) include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SDG 15.1.2 Proportion of important sites for terrestrial and freshwater biodiversity that are covered by protected areas, by ecosystem type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SDG 15.4.1 Coverage by protected areas of important sites for mountain biodiversity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UN Environment World Conservation Monitoring Centre (UNEP-WCMC)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BirdLife International (BLI)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UN Environment World Conservation Monitoring Centre (UNEP-WCMC)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BirdLife International (BLI)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator Coverage of protected areas in relation to marine areas shows temporal trends in the mean percentage of each important site for marine biodiversity (i.e., those that contribute significantly to the global persistence of biodiversity) that is covered by designated protected areas and Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures (OECMs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protected areas, as defined by the International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN; Dudley 2008), are clearly defined geographical spaces, recognized, dedicated and managed, through legal or other effective means, to achieve the long-term conservation of nature with associated ecosystem services and cultural values. Importantly, a variety of specific management objectives are recognised within this definition, spanning conservation, restoration, and sustainable use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Category Ia: Strict nature reserve&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Category Ib: Wilderness area&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Category II: National park&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Category III: Natural monument or feature&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Category IV: Habitat/species management area&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Category V: Protected landscape/seascape&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Category VI: Protected area with sustainable use of natural resources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The status &amp;quot;designated&amp;quot; is attributed to a protected area when the corresponding authority, according to national legislation or common practice (e.g., by means of an executive decree or the like), officially endorses a document of designation. The designation must be made for the purpose of biodiversity conservation, not de facto protection arising because of some other activity (e.g., military).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data on protected areas are managed in the World Database on Protected Areas (www.protectedplanet.net) by the UN Environment World Conservation Monitoring Centre (UNEP-WCMC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures are defined by the Convention on Biological Diversity (CBD) as &amp;#x201C;A geographically defined area other than a Protected Area, which is governed and managed in ways that achieve positive and sustained long-term outcomes for the in situ conservation of biodiversity, with associated ecosystem functions and services and where applicable, cultural, spiritual, socio&amp;#x2013;economic, and other locally relevant values&amp;#x201D; (CBD, 2018). Data on OECMs are managed in the World Database on OECMs (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net/en/thematic-areas/oecms&quot;&gt;www.protectedplanet.net/en/thematic-areas/oecms&lt;/a&gt;) by the UN Environment World Conservation Monitoring Centre (UNEP-WCMC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sites contributing significantly to the global persistence of biodiversity are identified following globally criteria set out in A Global Standard for the Identification of Key Biodiversity Areas (KBAs) (IUCN 2016) applied at national levels. Key Biodiversity Areas encompass (a) Important Bird &amp;amp; Biodiversity Areas, that is, sites contributing significantly to the global persistence of biodiversity, identified using data on birds, of which more than13,000 sites in total have been identified from all of the world&amp;#x2019;s countries (BirdLife International 2014, Donald et al. 2018); (b) Alliance for Zero Extinction sites (Ricketts et al. 2005), that is, sites holding effectively the entire population of at least one species assessed as Critically Endangered or Endangered on the IUCN Red List of Threatened Species, of which 853 sites have been identified for 1,483 species of mammals, birds, amphibians, reptiles, freshwater crustaceans, reef-building corals, conifers, cycads and other taxa; (c) Key Biodiversity Areas identified under an earlier version of the Key Biodiversity Area criteria (Langhammer et al. 2007), including those identified in Ecosystem Hotspot Profiles developed with support of the Critical Ecosystem Partnership Fund. These three subsets are being reassessed using the Global Standard, which unifies these approaches along with other mechanisms for identification of important sites for other species and ecosystems (IUCN 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data on KBAs are managed in the World Database of Key Biodiversity Areas (www.keybiodiversityareas.org/kba-data) by BirdLife International on behalf of the Key Biodiversity Areas Partnership.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mean percentage of each marine Key Biodiversity Area covered by (i.e. overlapping with) protected areas and/or Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Protected Areas are defined as described above by the International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN; Dudley 2008) and documented in the World Database on Protected Areas (www.protectedplanet.net).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures are defined as described above by the Convention on Biological Diversity (CBD 2018) and documented in the World Database on Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net/en/thematic-areas/oecms&quot;&gt;www.protectedplanet.net/en/thematic-areas/oecms&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Biodiversity Areas are defined as described above by IUCN (2016) and documented in the World Database of Key Biodiversity Areas (www.keybiodiversityareas.org/kba-data).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Protected area data are compiled by ministries of environment and other ministries responsible for the designation and maintenance of protected areas. Protected Areas data for sites designated under the Ramsar Convention and the UNESCO World Heritage Convention are collected through the relevant convention international secretariats. Protected area data are aggregated globally into the World Database on Protected Areas by the UN Environment World Conservation Monitoring Centre, according to the mandate for production of the United Nations List of Protected Areas (Deguignet et al. 2014). They are disseminated through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net/&quot;&gt;Protected Planet&lt;/a&gt;, which is jointly managed by UNEP-WCMC and IUCN and its World Commission on Protected Areas (UNEP-WCMC 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OECMs are collated in the World Database of Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures (WDOECM). This database can be regarded as a sister database to the WDPA as it is also hosted on Protected Planet. Furthermore, the databases share many of the same fields and have an almost identical workflow; differing only in what they list. OECMs are a quickly evolving area of work, as such for the latest information on OECMs and the WDOECM please contact UNEP-WCMC. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KBAs are identified at national scales through multi-stakeholder processes, following standard criteria and thresholds. Key Biodiversity Areas data are aggregated into the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;World Database on &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;Key Biodiversity Areas&lt;/a&gt;, managed by BirdLife International. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;See information under other sections, and detailed information on the process by which Key Biodiversity Areas are identified at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/working-with-kbas/proposing-updating&quot;&gt;www.keybiodiversityareas.org/working-with-kbas/proposing-updating&lt;/a&gt;. Guidance on Proposing, Reviewing, Nominating and Confirming KBAs is available in KBA Secretariat (2019) at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/assets/35687f50ac0bcad155ab17447b48885a&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/assets/35687f50ac0bcad155ab17447b48885a&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The KBA identification process is highly inclusive and consultative. Anyone with appropriate data may propose a site. Consultation with stakeholders at the national level (both non-governmental and governmental organisations) is required during the proposal process. Any site proposal must undergo independent review. This is followed by the official site nomination with full documentation meeting the Documentation Standards for KBAs. Sites confirmed by the KBA Secretariat to qualify as KBAs are then published on the KBA Website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Submission of proposals for KBAs to the World Database of Key Biodiversity Areas follows a systematic review process to ensure that the KBA criteria have been applied correctly and that the sites can be recognised as important for the global persistence of biodiversity. Regional Focal Points have been appointed to help KBA proposers develop proposals and then ensure they are reviewed independently. Guidance on Proposing, Reviewing, Nominating and Confirming sites has been published to help guide proposers through the development of proposals and the review process, highlighting where they can obtain help in making a proposal. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UNEP-WCMC produces the UN List of Protected Areas every 5&amp;#x2013;10 years, based on information provided by national ministries/agencies. In the intervening period between compilations of UN Lists, UNEP-WCMC works closely with national ministries/agencies and NGOs responsible for the designation and maintenance of protected areas, continually updating the WDPA as new data become available. The World Database of Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures is also updated on an ongoing basis. The World Database of Key Biodiversity Areas is also updated on an ongoing basis with updates currently released twice a year, as new national data are submitted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The indicator of protected area coverage of important sites for biodiversity is updated each November-December using the latest versions of the datasets on protected areas, OECMs and Key Biodiversity Areas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Protected area data are compiled by ministries of environment and other ministries responsible for the designation and maintenance of protected areas. Key Biodiversity Areas are identified at national scales through multi-stakeholder processes, following established processes and standard criteria and thresholds (see above for details).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UNEP-WCMC, IUCN and BirdLife International&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protected area data are aggregated globally into the World Database on Protected Areas by the UN Environment World Conservation Monitoring Centre, according to the mandate for production of the United Nations List of Protected Areas (Deguignet et al. 2014). They are disseminated through Protected Planet, which is jointly managed by UNEP-WCMC and IUCN and its World Commission on Protected Areas (UNEP-WCMC 2016). Key Biodiversity Areas data are aggregated into the World Database of Key Biodiversity Areas, managed by BirdLife International (2019). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Protected area data and OECM data are aggregated globally into the World Database on Protected Areas by the UNEP-WCMC, according to the mandate for production of the United Nations List of Protected Areas (Deguignet et al. 2014). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BirdLife International is mandated by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/assets/dfbb558651f335617813f6c0c42f9e50&quot;&gt;Key Biodiversity Areas Partnership Agreement&lt;/a&gt; to manage data on KBAs in the World Database of Key Biodiversity Areas on behalf of the Key Biodiversity Areas Partnership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BirdLife International, IUCN and UN Environment World Conservation Monitoring Centre collaborate to produce the indicator of coverage of Key Biodiversity Areas by Protected Areas and Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The safeguard of important sites is vital for stemming the decline in biodiversity and ensuring long term and sustainable use of marine natural resources. The establishment of protected areas is an important mechanism for achieving this aim, and this indicator serves as a means of measuring progress toward the conservation, restoration and sustainable use of marine ecosystems and their services, in line with obligations under international agreements. Importantly, while it can be disaggregated to report on any given single ecosystem of interest, it is not restricted to any single ecosystem type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Levels of access to protected areas vary among the protected area management categories. Some areas, such as scientific reserves, are maintained in their natural state and closed to any other use. Others are used for recreation or tourism, or even open for the sustainable extraction of natural resources. In addition to protecting biodiversity, protected areas have high social and economic value: supporting local livelihoods; maintaining fisheries; harbouring an untold wealth of genetic resources; supporting thriving recreation and tourism industries; providing for science, research and education; and forming a basis for cultural and other non-material values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator adds meaningful information to, complements and builds from traditionally reported simple statistics of marine area covered by protected areas, computed by dividing the total protected area within a country by the total territorial area of the country and multiplying by 100 (e.g., Chape et al. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2005). Such percentage area coverage statistics do not recognise the extreme variation of biodiversity importance over space (Rodrigues et al. 2004), and so risk generating perverse outcomes through the protection of areas which are large at the expense of those which require protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator was used to track progress towards the 2011&amp;#x2013;2020 Strategic Plan for Biodiversity (CBD 2014, Tittensor et al. 2014, CBD 2020a), and was used as an indicator towards the Convention on Biological Diversity&amp;#x2019;s 2010 Target (Butchart et al. 2010). It has been proposed as an indicator for monitoring progress towards the post-2020 Global Biodiversity Framework (CBD 2020b).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quality control criteria are applied to ensure consistency and comparability of the data in the World Database on Protected Areas. New data are validated at UNEP-WCMC through a number of tools and translated into the standard data structure of the World Database on Protected Areas. Discrepancies between the data in the World Database on Protected Areas and new data are minimised by provision of a manual (UNEP-WCMC 2019) and resolved in communication with data providers. Similar processes apply for the incorporation of data into the World Database of Key Biodiversity Areas (BirdLife International 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator does not measure the effectiveness of protected areas in reducing biodiversity loss, which ultimately depends on a range of management and enforcement factors not covered by the indicator. A number of initiatives are underway to address this limitation. Most notably, numerous mechanisms have been developed for assessment of protected area management, which can be synthesised into an indicator (Leverington et al. 2010). This is used by the Biodiversity Indicators Partnership as a complementary indicator of progress towards Aichi Biodiversity Target 11 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(http://www.bipindicators.net/pamanagement). However, there may be little relationship between these measures and protected area outcomes (Nolte &amp;amp; Agrawal 2013). More recently, approaches to &amp;#x201C;green listing&amp;#x201D; have started to be developed, to incorporate both management effectiveness and the outcomes of protected areas, and these are likely to become progressively important as they are tested and applied more broadly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data and knowledge gaps can arise due to difficulties in determining whether a site conforms to the IUCN definition of a protected area or the CBD definition of an Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures. However, given that both are incorporated into the indicator, misclassifications (as one or the other) do not impact the calculated indicator value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding important sites, the biggest limitation is that site identification to date has focused mainly on specific subsets of biodiversity, for example birds (for Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas) and highly threatened species (for Alliance for Zero Extinction sites). While Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas have been documented to be good surrogates for biodiversity more generally (Brooks et al. 2001, Pain et al. 2005), the application of the unified standard for identification of Key Biodiversity Areas (IUCN 2016) sites across different levels of biodiversity (genes, species, ecosystems) and different taxonomic groups remains a high priority, building from efforts to date (Eken et al. 2004, Knight et al. 2007, Langhammer et al. 2007, Foster et al. 2012). Birds now comprise less than 50% of the species for which Key Biodiversity Areas have been identified, and as Key Biodiversity Area identification for other taxa and elements of biodiversity proceeds, such bias will become a less important consideration in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Biodiversity Area identification has been validated for a number of countries and regions where comprehensive biodiversity data allow formal calculation of the site importance (or &amp;#x201C;irreplaceability&amp;#x201D;) using systematic conservation planning techniques (Di Marco et al. 2016, Montesino Pouzols et al. 2014).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Future developments of the indicator will include: a) expansion of the taxonomic coverage of marine Key Biodiversity Areas through application of the Key Biodiversity Areas standard (IUCN 2016) to a wide variety of marine vertebrates, invertebrates, plants and ecosystem type; b) improvements in the data on protected areas by continuing to increase the proportion of sites with documented dates of designation and with digitised boundary polygons (rather than coordinates); and c) increased documentation of Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures in the World Database of OECMs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This indicator is calculated from data derived from a spatial overlap between digital polygons for protected areas from the World Database on Protected Areas (UNEP-WCMC &amp;amp; IUCN 2020), digital polygons for Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures from the World Database on OECMs and digital polygons for marine Key Biodiversity Areas (from the World Database of Key Biodiversity Areas, including Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas, Alliance for Zero Extinction sites, and other Key Biodiversity Areas). Sites were classified as marine Key Biodiversity Areas by undertaking a spatial overlap between the Key Biodiversity Area polygons and an ocean raster layer (produced from the &amp;#x2018;adm0&amp;#x2019; layer from the database of Global Administrative Areas (GADM 2019)), classifying any Key Biodiversity Area as a marine Key Biodiversity Area where it had &amp;#x2265;5% overlap with the ocean layer (hence some sites were classified as both marine and terrestrial). The value of the indicator at a given point in time, based on data on the year of protected area establishment recorded in the World Database on Protected Areas, is computed as the mean percentage of each Key Biodiversity Area currently recognised that is covered by protected areas and/or Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protected areas lacking digital boundaries in the World Database of Protected Areas, and those sites with a status of &amp;#x2018;proposed&amp;#x2019; or &amp;#x2018;not reported&amp;#x2019; are omitted. Degazetted sites are not kept in the WDPA and are also not included. Man and Biosphere Reserves are also excluded as these often contain potentially unprotected areas. Year of protected area establishment is unknown for ~12% of protected areas in the World Database on Protected Areas, generating uncertainty around changing protected area coverage over time. To reflect this uncertainty, a year was randomly assigned from another protected area within the same country, and then this procedure repeated 1,000 times, with the median plotted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to 2017, the indicator was presented as the percentage of Key Biodiversity Areas completely covered by protected areas. However, it is now presented as the mean % of each Key Biodiversity Area that is covered by protected areas in order to better reflect trends in protected area coverage for countries or regions with few or no Key Biodiversity Areas that are completely covered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Protected Areas and OECMs are validated through dialogue with the governing authority, who signs a data contributor agreement that these sites are, to the best of their knowledge, an accurate depiction of the sites in question. Over time the data for sites may improve or other aspects of the sites may change, as and when this occurs a further data sharing agreement is required by the site&amp;#x2019;s governing authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proposed Key Biodiversity Areas undergo detailed checking by Regional Focal Points, formal Review of KBA Proposals by independent Reviewers, and validation of Nominated Key Biodiversity Areas by the Key Biodiversity Areas Secretariat. For further information, see the Guidance on Proposing, Reviewing, Nominating and Confirming KBAs available in KBA Secretariat (2019) at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/assets/35687f50ac0bcad155ab17447b48885a&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/assets/35687f50ac0bcad155ab17447b48885a&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the indicators of protected area coverage of Key Biodiversity Areas are updated each year, the updated indicators (and underlying numbers of protected areas, Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures, and Key Biodiversity Areas) are made available for review by countries prior to submission to the SDG Indicators Database. This is achieved through updating the country profiles in the Integrated Biodiversity Assessment Tool (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ibat-alliance.org/country_profiles&quot;&gt;https://ibat-alliance.org/country_profiles&lt;/a&gt;) and circulating these for consultation and review to CBD National Focal Points, SDG National Statistical Office Focal Points, and IUCN State Members.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No adjustments are made to the index with respect to harmonization of breakdowns or for compliance with specific international or national definitions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are available for protected areas and Key Biodiversity Areas in all of the world&amp;#x2019;s countries, and so no imputation or estimation of national level data is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global indicators of protected area coverage of important sites for biodiversity are calculated as the mean percentage of each Key Biodiversity Area that is covered by protected areas and Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures. The data are generated from all countries, and so while there is uncertainty around the data, there are no missing values as such and so no need for imputation or estimation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regional indices are calculated as the mean percentage of each Key Biodiversity Area in the region covered by (i.e. overlapping with) protected areas and/or Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures: in other words, the percentage of each Key Biodiversity Area covered by these designations, averaged over all Key Biodiversity Areas in the particular region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Protected areas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data on protected areas are submitted by government agencies to the World Database on Protected Areas and disseminated through Protected Planet. The WDPA has its origins in a 1959 UN mandate when the United Nations Economic and Social Council called for a list of national parks and equivalent reserves Resolution 713 (XXVIII). More details are available here: https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas. The UN List of Protected Areas has been published in 1961/62, 1966/71, 1972 (addendum to the 1966/71 edition), 1973, 1974, 1975, 1980, 1982, 1985, 1990, 1993, 1997, 2003, 2014 and 2018 which have resulted in a global network of national data providers for the WDPA. For example, in 2014 all Convention on Biological Diversity (CBD) National Focal points and all National Focal points for the CBD Protected Areas Programme of Work (PoWPA) to request data for the 2014 Un List of Protected Areas (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas-2014&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas-2014&lt;/a&gt;). Protected areas data are therefore compiled directly from government agencies, regional hubs and other authoritative sources in the absence of a government source. All records have a unique metadata identifier (MetadataID) which links the spatial database to the Source table where all sources are described. The data is collated and standardised following the WDPA Data Standards and validated with the source. The process of collation, validation and publication of data as well as protocols and the WDPA data standards are regularly updated in the WDPA User Manual (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&lt;/a&gt;) made available through www.protectedplanet.net where all spatial data and the Source table are also published every month and can be downloaded. The WDPA User Manual (published in English, Spanish, and French) provides guidance to countries on how to submit protected areas data to the WDPA, the benefits of providing such data, and the data standards and quality checks that are performed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guiding principles, common characteristics and criteria for identification of OECMs are available in CBD (2018) at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/doc/decisions/cop-14/cop-14-dec-08-en.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/doc/decisions/cop-14/cop-14-dec-08-en.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guidance on recognising and reporting other effective area-based conservation measures is available in IUCN-WCPA Task Force on OECMs (2019) at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/48773&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/48773&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Key Biodiversity Areas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;#x201C;Global Standard for the Identification of Key Biodiversity Areas&amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&lt;/a&gt;) comprises the standard recommendations available to countries in the identification of Key Biodiversity Areas. Guidelines for using A global standard for the identification of Key Biodiversity Areas are available at https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/49131.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guidance on Proposing, Reviewing, Nominating and Confirming KBAs is available in KBA Secretariat (2019) at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/assets/35687f50ac0bcad155ab17447b48885a&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/assets/35687f50ac0bcad155ab17447b48885a&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A summary of the process by which Key Biodiversity Areas are identified is available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/working-with-kbas/proposing-updating&quot;&gt;www.keybiodiversityareas.org/working-with-kbas/proposing-updating&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The KBA identification process is highly inclusive, consultative and nationally driven. Anyone with appropriate data may propose a site as a KBA, although consultation with relevant stakeholders at the local and national level is required when identifying the site and needs to be documented in the proposal. In order to propose a site as a KBA, a proposer must apply the KBA criteria to data on biodiversity elements (species and ecosystems) at the site. Associated with the proposal process is the need to delineate the site accurately so that its boundaries are clear. Although anyone with appropriate scientific data may propose a site to qualify as a Key Biodiversity Area, wide consultation with stakeholders at the national level (both non-governmental and governmental organizations) is required during the proposal process. The formal proposal is then made using a proposal process that ensures there is an independent review of the proposal before a site is incorporated in the World Database of KBAs. This is important given that KBA status of a site may lead to changes in actions of governments, private sector companies and other institutions following consultation as appropriate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Biodiversity Area identification builds off the existing network of Key Biodiversity Areas, including those identified as (a) Important Bird &amp;amp; Biodiversity Areas through the BirdLife Partnership of 120 national organisations (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.birdlife.org/worldwide/partnership/birdlife-partners&quot;&gt;http://www.birdlife.org/worldwide/partnership/birdlife-partners&lt;/a&gt;), (b) Alliance for Zero Extinction sites by 93 national and international organisations in the Alliance (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zeroextinction.org/partners.html&quot;&gt;http://www.zeroextinction.org/partners.html&lt;/a&gt;), and (c) other Key Biodiversity Areas by civil society organisations supported by the Critical Ecosystem Partnership Fund in developing ecosystem profiles, named in each of the profiles listed here (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cepf.net/resources/publications/Pages/ecosystem_profiles.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.cepf.net/resources/publications/Pages/ecosystem_profiles.aspx&lt;/a&gt;), with new data strengthening and expanding expand the network of these sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main steps of the Key Biodiversity Area identification process are the following: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;submission of Expressions of Intent to identify a Key Biodiversity Area to Regional Focal Points; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proposal Development process, in which proposers compile relevant data and documentation and consult national experts, including organizations that have already identified Key Biodiversity Areas in the country, either through national Key Biodiversity Area Coordination Groups or independently;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;review of proposed Key Biodiversity Areas by Independent Expert Reviewers, verifying the accuracy of information within their area of expertise; and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a Site Nomination phase comprising the submission of all the relevant documentation for verification by the Key Biodiversity Areas Secretariat. Sites confirmed by the Key Biodiversity Areas Secretariat to qualify as Key Biodiversity Areas are then published on the Key Biodiversity Areas website (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a Key Biodiversity Area is identified, monitoring of its qualifying features and its conservation status is important. Proposers, reviewers and those undertaking monitoring can join the Key Biodiversity Areas Community to exchange their experiences, case studies and best practice examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The R code for calculating protected area coverage of Key Biodiversity Areas is documented in Simkins et al. (2020). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For protected areas and OECMs please see the section on validation. Ensuring the WDPA and WDOECM remain an accurate and true depiction of reality is a never-ending task; however, over time the quality of the data (e.g. the proportion of sites with defined boundaries) is increasing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Key Biodiversity Areas, see above and below, plus the guidance on Proposing, Reviewing, Nominating and Confirming KBAs which is available in KBA Secretariat (2019) at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/assets/35687f50ac0bcad155ab17447b48885a&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/assets/35687f50ac0bcad155ab17447b48885a&lt;/a&gt;. Data quality is ensured through wide stakeholder engagement in the KBA proposal process, data checking by Regional Focal Points, formal Review of KBA Proposals by independent Reviewers, and validation of Nominations by the Key Biodiversity Areas Secretariat. Furthermore, an independent KBA Standards and Appeals Committee ensures the correct application of the Global Standard for the identification of Key Biodiversity Areas, and oversees a formal Procedure for handling of appeals against the identification of Key Biodiversity Areas (see http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/assets/1b388c918e14c5f4c3d7a0237eb0d366).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Information on the process of how protected area data are collected, standardised and published is available in the WDPA User Manual at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&lt;/a&gt; which is available in English, French and Spanish. Specific guidance is provided at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&lt;/a&gt; on, for example, predefined fields or look up tables in the WDPA: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-lookup-tables&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-lookup-tables&lt;/a&gt;, how WDPA records are coded how international designations and regional designations data is collected, how regularly is the database updated, and how to perform protected areas coverage statistics. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data quality in the process of identifying Key Biodiversity Areas is ensured through processes established by the Key Biodiversity Areas Partnership (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/kba-partners&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/kba-partners&lt;/a&gt;) and Key Biodiversity Areas Secretariat. Data quality is ensured through wide stakeholder engagement in the KBA proposal process, data checking by Regional Focal Points, formal Review of KBA Proposals by independent Reviewers, and validation of Nominations by the Key Biodiversity Areas Secretariat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the Chairs of the IUCN Species Survival Commission and World Commission on Protected Areas (both of whom are elected by the IUCN Membership of governments and non-governmental organisations), appoint the Chair of an independent Key Biodiversity Areas Standards and Appeals Committee, which ensures the correct application of the Global Standard for the identification of Key Biodiversity Areas, and oversees a formal Procedure for handling of appeals against the identification of Key Biodiversity Areas (see http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/assets/1b388c918e14c5f4c3d7a0237eb0d366).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before submission to the UN SDG Indicators database the annually updated indicators of coverage of Key Biodiversity Areas by protected areas and Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures are incorporated into updated Country Profiles on the Integrated Biodiversity Assessment Tool (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ibat-alliance.org/country_profiles&quot;&gt;https://ibat-alliance.org/country_profiles&lt;/a&gt;) and then sent for consultation to National Focal Points of the Convention on Biological Diversity (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/information/nfp.shtml&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/information/nfp.shtml&lt;/a&gt;), National Statistics Offices SDG Representatives and UN Permanent Missions (Geneva) representatives. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;High.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator has been classified by the IAEG-SDGs as Tier 1. Current data are available for all countries in the world, and these are updated on an ongoing basis. Index values for each country are available in the UN SDG Indicators Database &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/sdgs/indicators/database/&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/sdgs/indicators/database/&lt;/a&gt;. Graphs of Protected area coverage of Key Biodiversity Areas are also available for each country in the BIP Indicators Dashboard (&lt;a href=&quot;https://bipdashboard.natureserve.org/bip/SelectCountry.html&quot;&gt;https://bipdashboard.natureserve.org/bip/SelectCountry.html&lt;/a&gt;), and the Integrated Biodiversity Assessment Tool Country Profiles (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ibat-alliance.org/country_profiles&quot;&gt;https://ibat-alliance.org/country_profiles&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Underlying data on protected areas and Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures are available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net&quot;&gt;www.protectedplanet.net&lt;/a&gt;. Data on Key Biodiversity Areas are available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org&quot;&gt;www.keybiodiversityareas.org&lt;/a&gt;. Data on subsets of KBAs are available for Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas at &lt;a href=&quot;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&quot;&gt;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&lt;/a&gt; and for Alliance for Zero Extinction sites at https://zeroextinction.org.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that data for the global indicator are compiled at national levels, it is straightforward to disaggregate to national and regional levels (e.g., Han et al. 2014), or conversely to aggregate to the global level. Key Biodiversity Areas span all ecosystem types through the marine environment (Edgar et al. 2008) and beyond. The indicator can therefore be reported in combination across marine systems along with terrestrial or freshwater systems, or disaggregated among them. However, individual Key Biodiversity Areas can encompass marine, terrestrial, and freshwater systems simultaneously, and so determining the results is not simply additive. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National processes provide the data that are incorporated into the World Database on Protected Areas, the World Database on Other Effective Area-based Conservation Measures, and the World Database of Key Biodiversity Areas, so there are very few discrepancies between national indicators and the global one. One minor source of difference is that the World Database on Protected Areas incorporates internationally-designated protected areas (e.g., UNESCO World Heritage sites, Ramsar sites, etc), a few of which are not considered by their sovereign nations to be protected areas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that because countries do not submit comprehensive data on degazetted protected areas to the WDPA, earlier values of the indictor may marginally underestimate coverage. Furthermore, there is also a lag between the point at which a protected area is designated on the ground and the point at which it is reported to the WDPA. As such, current or recent coverage may also be underestimated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.unep-wcmc.org/; http://www.birdlife.org/; http://www.iucn.org/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These metadata are based on http://mdgs.un.org/unsd/mi/wiki/7-6-Proportion-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;of-terrestrial-and-marine-areas-protected.ashx, supplemented by http://www.bipindicators.net/paoverlays and the references listed below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BIRDLIFE INTERNATIONAL (2014). Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas: a global network for conserving nature and benefiting people. Cambridge, UK: BirdLife International. Available at datazone.birdlife.org/sowb/sowbpubs#IBA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BIRDLIFE INTERNATIONAL (2019) World Database of Key Biodiversity Areas.Developed by the KBA Partnership: BirdLife International, International Union for the Conservation of Nature, Amphibian Survival Alliance, Conservation International, Critical Ecosystem Partnership Fund, Global Environment Facility, Global Wildlife Conservation, NatureServe, Rainforest Trust, Royal Society for the Protection of Birds, Wildlife Conservation Society and World Wildlife Fund. September 2019 version. Available at http://keybiodiversity areas.org/site/search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BROOKS, T. et al. (2001). Conservation priorities for birds and biodiversity: do East African Important Bird Areas represent species diversity in other terrestrial vertebrate groups? Ostrich suppl. 15: 3&amp;#x2013;12. Available &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from: http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.2989/00306520109485329#.VafbVJPVq75.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BROOKS, T.M. et al. (2016) Goal 15: Life on land. Sustainable manage forests, combat desertification, halt and reverse land degradation, halt biodiversity loss. Pp. 497&amp;#x2013;522 in Dur&amp;#xE1;n y Lalaguna, P., D&amp;#xED;az Barrado, C.M. &amp;amp; Fern&amp;#xE1;ndez Liesa, C.R. (eds.) International Society and Sustainable Development Goals. Editorial Aranzadi, Cizur Menor, Spain. Available from: https://www.thomsonreuters.es/es/tienda/pdp/duo.html?pid=10008456&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2010). Global biodiversity: indicators of recent declines. Science 328: 1164&amp;#x2013;1168. Available from http://www.sciencemag.org/content/328/5982/1164.short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2012). Protecting important sites for biodiversity contributes to meeting global conservation targets. PLoS One 7(3): e32529. Available from http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0032529.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2015). Shortfalls and solutions for meeting national and global conservation area targets. Conservation Letters 8: 329&amp;#x2013;337. Available from http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12158/full.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBD (2014). Global Biodiversity Outlook 4. Convention on Biological Diversity, Montr&amp;#xE9;al, Canada. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/gbo4/&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/gbo4/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBD (2018). Protected areas and other effective area-based conservation measures. Decision 14/8 adopted by the Conference of the Parties to the Convention on Biological Diversity. Available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/doc/decisions/cop-14/cop-14-dec-08-en.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/doc/decisions/cop-14/cop-14-dec-08-en.pdf&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBD (2020a). Global Biodiversity Outlook 5. Convention on Biological Diversity, Montr&amp;#xE9;al, Canada. Available from https://www.cbd.int/gbo5/. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBD (2020b). Post-2020 Global Biodiversity Framework: Scientific and technical information to support the review of the updated Goals and Targets, and related indicators and baselines. Document CBD/SBSTTA/24/3. Available at: https://www.cbd.int/doc/c/705d/6b4b/a1a463c1b19392bde6fa08f3/sbstta-24-03-en.pdf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CHAPE, S. et al. (2005). Measuring the extent and effectiveness of protected areas as an indicator for meeting global biodiversity targets. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B 360: 443&amp;#x2013;445. Available from http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/360/1454/443.short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DEGUIGNET, M., et al. (2014). 2014 United Nations List of Protected Areas. UNEP-WCMC, Cambridge, UK. Available from http://unep-wcmc.org/system/dataset_file_fields/files/000/000/263/original/2014_UN_List_of_Protected_Areas_EN_web.PDF?1415613322.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DI MARCO, M., et al. (2016). Quantifying the relative irreplaceability of Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas. Conservation Biology 30: 392&amp;#x2013;402. Available from http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/cobi.12609/abstract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DONALD, P. et al. (2018) Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas (IBAs): the development and characteristics of a global inventory of key sites for biodiversity. Bird Conserv. Internat. 29:177&amp;#x2013;198.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DUDLEY, N. (2008). Guidelines for Applying Protected Area Management Categories. International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN). Gland, Switzerland. Available from https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9243.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDGAR, G.J. et al. (2008). Key Biodiversity Areas as globally significant target sites for the conservation of marine biological diversity. Aquatic Conservation: Marine and Freshwater Ecosystems 18: 969&amp;#x2013;983. Available from http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/aqc.902/abstract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EKEN, G. et al. (2004). Key biodiversity areas as site conservation targets. BioScience 54: 1110&amp;#x2013;1118. Available from http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/54/12/1110.short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOSTER, M.N. et al. (2012) The identification of sites of biodiversity conservation significance: progress with the application of a global standard. Journal of Threatened Taxa 4: 2733&amp;#x2013;2744. Available from &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.threatenedtaxa.in/index.php/JoTT/article/view/779.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global Administrative Areas (2019). GADM database of Global Administrative Areas, version 2.8. Available from www.gadm.org.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HAN, X. et al. (2014). A Biodiversity indicators dashboard: addressing challenges to monitoring progress towards the Aichi Biodiversity Targets using disaggregated global data. PLoS ONE 9(11): e112046. Available from http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0112046.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOLLAND, R.A. et al. (2012). Conservation priorities for freshwater biodiversity: the key biodiversity area approach refined and tested for continental Africa. Biological Conservation 148: 167&amp;#x2013;179. Available from &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320712000298.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IUCN (2016). A Global Standard for the Identification of Key Biodiversity Areas. International Union for Conservation of Nature, Gland, Switzerland. Available from https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IUCN-WCPA Task Force on OECMs (2019). Recognising and reporting other effective area-based conservation measures. Gland, Switzerland: IUCN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JONAS, H.D. et al. (2014) New steps of change: looking beyond protected areas to consider other effective area-based conservation measures. Parks 20: 111&amp;#x2013;128. Available from http://parksjournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/PARKS-20.2-Jonas-et-al-10.2305IUCN.CH_.2014.PARKS-20-2.HDJ_.en_.pdf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KBA Secretariat (2019). Key Biodiversity Areas Proposal Process: Guidance on Proposing, Reviewing, Nominating and Confirming sites. Version 1.0. Prepared by the KBA Secretariat and KBA Committee of the KBA Partnership. Cambridge, UK. Available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/assets/35687f50ac0bcad155ab17447b48885a&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/assets/35687f50ac0bcad155ab17447b48885a&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KNIGHT, A. T. et al. (2007). Improving the Key Biodiversity Areas approach for effective conservation planning. BioScience 57: 256&amp;#x2013;261. Available from &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/57/3/256.short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LANGHAMMER, P. F. et al. (2007). Identification and Gap Analysis of Key Biodiversity Areas: Targets for Comprehensive Protected Area Systems. IUCN World Commission on Protected Areas Best Practice Protected Area Guidelines Series No. 15. IUCN, Gland, Switzerland. Available from https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9055.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LEVERINGTON, F. et al. (2010). A global analysis of protected area management effectiveness. Environmental Management 46: 685&amp;#x2013;698. Available from http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00267-010-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9564-5#page-1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MONTESINO POUZOLS, F., et al. (2014) Global protected area expansion is compromised by projected land-use and parochialism. Nature 516: 383&amp;#x2013;386. Available from http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v516/n7531/abs/nature14032.html.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOLTE, C. &amp;amp; AGRAWAL, A. (2013). Linking management effectiveness indicators to observed effects of protected areas on fire occurrence in the Amazon rainforest. Conservation Biology 27: 155&amp;#x2013;165. Available from http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2012.01930.x/abstract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PAIN, D.J. et al. (2005) Biodiversity representation in Uganda&amp;#x2019;s forest IBAs. Biological Conservation 125: 133&amp;#x2013;138. Available from http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320705001412.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RICKETTS, T. H. et al. (2005). Pinpointing and preventing imminent extinctions. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the U.S.A. 102: 18497&amp;#x2013;18501. Available from http://www.pnas.org/content/102/51/18497.short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RODRIGUES, A. S. L. et al. (2004). Effectiveness of the global protected area network in representing species diversity. Nature 428: 640&amp;#x2013;643. Available from http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v428/n6983/abs/nature02422.html.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RODR&amp;#xCD;GUEZ-RODR&amp;#xCD;GUEZ, D., et al. (2011). Progress towards international targets for protected area coverage in mountains: a multi-scale assessment. Biological Conservation 144: 2978&amp;#x2013;2983. Available from &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320711003454.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIMKINS, A.T., PEARMAIN, E.J., &amp;amp; DIAS, M.P. (2020). Code (and documentation) for calculating the protected area coverage of Key Biodiversity Areas. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BirdLifeInternational/kba-overlap&quot;&gt;https://github.com/BirdLifeInternational/kba-overlap&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TITTENSOR, D. et al. (2014). A mid-term analysis of progress towards international biodiversity targets. Science 346: 241&amp;#x2013;244. Available from http://www.sciencemag.org/content/346/6206/241.short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNEP-WCMC (2019). World Database on Protected Areas User Manual 1.6. UNEP-WCMC, Cambridge, UK. Available from http://wcmc.io/WDPA_Manual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNEP-WCMC &amp;amp; IUCN (2020). The World Database on Protected Areas (WDPA). UNEP-WCMC, Cambridge, UK. Available from http://www.protectedplanet.net.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 14: Conservar y utilizar sosteniblemente los ocanos, los mares y los recursos marinos para el desarrollo sostenible&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 14.5: De aqu a 2020, conservar al menos el 10% de las zonas costeras y marinas, de conformidad con las leyes nacionales y el derecho internacional y sobre la base de la mejor informacin cientfica disponible&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 14.5.1: Cobertura de las zonas protegidas en relacin con las zonas marinas&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;ltima actualizacin: 12 de febrero de 2020&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Informacin institucional&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organizaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Centro Mundial de Vigilancia de la Conservacin de las Naciones Unidas (PNUMA-WCMC)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BirdLife International (BLI)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unin Internacional para la Conservacin de la Naturaleza (UICN)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definicin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador Cobertura de las reas protegidas en relacin con las reas marinas muestra las tendencias temporales en el porcentaje medio de cada sitio importante para la biodiversidad marina (es decir, aquellos que contribuyen significativamente a la persistencia global de la biodiversidad) que est cubierto por reas protegidas designadas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las reas protegidas, segn la definicin de la Unin Internacional para la Conservacin de la Naturaleza (UICN; Dudley 2008), son espacios geogrficos claramente definidos, reconocidos, dedicados y gestionados, a travs de medios legales u otros medios eficaces, para lograr la conservacin a largo plazo de la naturaleza con los servicios ecosistmicos y los valores culturales asociados. Es importante destacar que en esta definicin se reconocen diversos objetivos de gestin especficos que abarcan la conservacin, la restauracin y el uso sostenible:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; - Categora Ia: Reserva natural estricta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Categora Ib: rea silvestre&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Categora II: Parque nacional&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Categora III: Monumento o elemento natural&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Categora IV: Zona de gestin de hbitats/especies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Categora V: Paisaje terrestre/marino protegido&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Categora VI: rea protegida con uso sostenible de los recursos naturales&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El estatus &amp;quot;designado&amp;quot; se atribuye a un rea protegida cuando la autoridad correspondiente, segn la legislacin nacional o la prctica comn (por ejemplo, mediante un decreto ejecutivo o similar), refrenda oficialmente un documento de designacin. La designacin debe realizarse con el fin de conservar la biodiversidad, y no como una proteccin de facto derivada de alguna otra actividad (por ejemplo, militar).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los sitios que contribuyen significativamente a la persistencia global de la biodiversidad se identifican siguiendo los criterios globales establecidos en &lt;em&gt;Un estndar global para la identificacin de reas clave para la biodiversidad &lt;/em&gt;(UICN 2016) aplicados a nivel nacional. Las reas Clave para la Biodiversidad abarcan (a) reas Importantes para las Aves y la Biodiversidad, es decir, sitios que contribuyen significativamente a la persistencia global de la biodiversidad, identificados utilizando datos sobre aves, de los cuales se han identificado &amp;gt;13.000 sitios en total de todos los pases del mundo (BirdLife International 2014, Donald &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; 2018); (b) sitios de la Alianza para la Cero Extincin (Ricketts et al. 2005), es decir, sitios que albergan efectivamente la totalidad de la poblacin de al menos una especie evaluada como En Peligro Crtico o En Peligro en la Lista Roja de Especies Amenazadas de la UICN, de los cuales se han identificado 853 sitios para 1.483 especies de mamferos, aves, anfibios, reptiles, crustceos de agua dulce, corales constructores de arrecifes, conferas, ccadas y otros taxones; (c) reas Clave para la Biodiversidad identificadas segn una versin anterior de los criterios de reas Clave para la Biodiversidad (Langhammer &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; 2007), incluidas las identificadas en los perfiles de puntos calientes de los ecosistemas desarrollados con el apoyo del Fondo de Asociacin de Ecosistemas Crticos. Estos tres subconjuntos estn siendo reevaluados utilizando el Estndar Global, que unifica estos enfoques junto con otros mecanismos para la identificacin de sitios importantes para otras especies y ecosistemas (UICN 2016).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripcin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos de las reas protegidas son compilados por los ministerios de medio ambiente y otros ministerios responsables de la designacin y el mantenimiento de las reas protegidas. Los datos sobre reas protegidas de los sitios designados en el marco de la Convencin de Ramsar y la Convencin del Patrimonio Mundial de la UNESCO se recopilan a travs de las secretaras internacionales de las convenciones correspondientes. Los datos de las reas protegidas son agregados globalmente en la Base de Datos Mundial sobre reas Protegidas por el Centro Mundial de Monitoreo de la Conservacin de ONU Medio Ambiente, de acuerdo con el mandato de produccin de la Lista de reas Protegidas de las Naciones Unidas (Deguignet et al. 2014). Se difunden a travs de &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net/&quot;&gt;Planeta Protegido&lt;/a&gt;, gestionado conjuntamente por el PNUMA-WCMC y la UICN y su Comisin Mundial de reas Protegidas (PNUMA-WCMC 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las reas Clave para la Biodiversidad se identifican a escala nacional a travs de procesos de mltiples partes interesadas, siguiendo criterios y umbrales estndar. Los datos de las reas Clave para la Biodiversidad se agregan a la &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;Base de Datos Mundial sobre &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;reas clave para la biodiversidad&lt;/a&gt;, gestionada por BirdLife International. En concreto, los datos sobre las reas Importantes para las Aves y la Biodiversidad estn disponibles en lnea en &lt;a href=&quot;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&quot;&gt;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&lt;/a&gt; y los datos sobre los lugares de la Alianza para la Cero Extincin estn disponibles en lnea en https://zeroextinction.org. Ambos conjuntos de datos, junto con las reas Clave para la Biodiversidad identificadas a travs de otros procesos, estn disponibles a travs de la &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;Base de Datos Mundial sobre reas Clave para la Biodiversidad&lt;/a&gt;, y junto con la Base de Datos Mundial sobre reas Protegidas, tambin se difunden a travs de la &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/login&quot;&gt;Herramienta Integrada de Evaluacin de la Biodiversidad para la Investigacin y la Planificacin de la Conservacin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Proceso de recoleccin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ver informacin en otros apartados.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendario&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recopilacin de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El PNUMA-WCMC elabora la Lista de reas Protegidas de la ONU cada 5&amp;#x2013;10 aos, basndose en la informacin proporcionada por los ministerios/agencias nacionales. En el periodo que transcurre entre las compilaciones de las Listas de la ONU, el PNUMA-WCMC trabaja en estrecha colaboracin con los ministerios/agencias nacionales y las ONG responsables de la designacin y el mantenimiento de las reas protegidas, actualizando continuamente la WDPA a medida que se dispone de nuevos datos. La Base de Datos Mundial de reas Clave para la Biodiversidad tambin se actualiza de forma continua, a medida que se presentan nuevos datos nacionales. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publicacin de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se prev que el indicador de cobertura de reas protegidas de lugares importantes para la biodiversidad se publique anualmente. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos de las reas protegidas son compilados por los ministerios de ambiente y otros ministerios responsables de la designacin y el mantenimiento de las reas protegidas. Las reas clave para la biodiversidad se identifican a escala nacional mediante procesos en los que participan mltiples partes interesadas, siguiendo criterios y umbrales estndar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nombre:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PNUMA-WCMC y UICN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripcin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos de las reas protegidas son agregados globalmente en la Base de Datos Mundial sobre reas Protegidas por el Centro Mundial de Monitoreo de la Conservacin de ONU Medio Ambiente, de acuerdo con el mandato de produccin de la Lista de reas Protegidas de las Naciones Unidas (Deguignet et al. 2014). Se difunden a travs de &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net/&quot;&gt;Planeta Protegido&lt;/a&gt;, gestionado conjuntamente por el PNUMA-WCMC y la UICN y su Comisin Mundial de reas Protegidas (PNUMA-WCMC 2016). Los datos de las reas Clave para la Biodiversidad se agregan en la &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;Base de Datos Mundial sobre reas Clave para la Biodiversidad&lt;/a&gt;, gestionada por BirdLife International (2019). En concreto, los datos sobre las reas Importantes para las Aves y la Biodiversidad estn disponibles en lnea en &lt;a href=&quot;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&quot;&gt;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&lt;/a&gt; y los datos sobre los sitios de la Alianza para la Cero Extincin estn disponibles en lnea en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zeroextinction.org/search.cfm&quot;&gt;http://www.zeroextinction.org/search.cfm&lt;/a&gt;. Ambos conjuntos de datos, junto con la Base de Datos Mundial sobre reas Protegidas, tambin se difunden a travs de la &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/login&quot;&gt;Herramienta de Evaluacin Integrada de la Biodiversidad para la Investigacin y la Planificacin de la Conservacin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justificacin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La salvaguarda de lugares importantes es vital para frenar el declive de la biodiversidad y asegurar el uso sostenible y a largo plazo de los recursos naturales marinos. El establecimiento de reas protegidas es un mecanismo importante para lograr este objetivo, y este indicador sirve como medio para medir el progreso hacia la conservacin, la restauracin y el uso sostenible de los ecosistemas marinos y sus servicios, en lnea con las obligaciones de los acuerdos internacionales. Es importante destacar que, aunque puede desglosarse para informar sobre cualquier ecosistema de inters, no se limita a ningn tipo de ecosistema.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los niveles de acceso a las reas protegidas varan segn las categoras de gestin de las mismas. Algunas reas, como las reservas cientficas, se mantienen en su estado natural y estn cerradas a cualquier otro uso. Otras se utilizan para el ocio o el turismo, o incluso estn abiertas para la extraccin sostenible de recursos naturales. Adems de proteger la biodiversidad, las reas protegidas tienen un alto valor social y econmico: apoyan los medios de vida locales; mantienen la pesca; albergan una riqueza incalculable de recursos genticos; apoyan industrias prsperas de ocio y turismo; proporcionan ciencia, investigacin y educacin; y forman una base para los valores culturales y otros valores no materiales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Este indicador aade informacin significativa, complementa y se basa en las estadsticas simples de la superficie marina cubierta por reas protegidas, calculadas dividiendo la superficie protegida total de un pas por la superficie territorial total del pas y multiplicando por 100 (por ejemplo, Chape et al. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2005). Estas estadsticas de porcentaje de cobertura de superficie no reconocen la extrema variacin de la importancia de la biodiversidad en el espacio (Rodrigues et al. 2004), por lo que se corre el riesgo de generar resultados perversos a travs de la proteccin de reas que son grandes a expensas de las que requieren proteccin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador se utiliza para seguir el progreso hacia el Plan Estratgico para la Diversidad Biolgica 2011&amp;#x2013;2020 (CDB 2014, Tittensor et al. 2014), y se utiliz como indicador hacia el Objetivo 2010 del Convenio sobre la Diversidad Biolgica (Butchart et al. 2010).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se aplican criterios de control de calidad para garantizar la coherencia y la comparabilidad de los datos de la Base de Datos Mundial sobre reas Protegidas. Los nuevos datos se validan en el PNUMA-WCMC mediante una serie de herramientas y se traducen a la estructura de datos estndar de la Base de Datos Mundial sobre reas Protegidas. Las discrepancias entre los datos de la Base de Datos Mundial sobre reas Protegidas y los nuevos datos se minimizan mediante un manual (PNUMA-WCMC 2019) y se resuelven en comunicacin con los proveedores de datos. Se aplican procesos similares para la incorporacin de datos en la &lt;em&gt;Base de datos mundial de reas clave para la biodiversidad &lt;/em&gt;(BirdLife International 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador no mide la eficacia de las reas protegidas en la reduccin de la prdida de biodiversidad, que en ltima instancia depende de una serie de factores de gestin y aplicacin que no estn cubiertos por el indicador. Se estn llevando a cabo varias iniciativas para abordar esta limitacin. En particular, se han desarrollado numerosos mecanismos para evaluar la gestin de las reas protegidas, que pueden sintetizarse en un indicador (Leverington et al. 2010). La Asociacin de Indicadores de Biodiversidad lo utiliza como indicador complementario del progreso hacia la Meta 11 de Aichi para la Biodiversidad &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bipindicators.net/pamanagement&quot;&gt;http://www.bipindicators.net/pamanagement&lt;/a&gt;). Sin embargo, puede haber poca relacin entre estas medidas y los resultados de las reas protegidas (Nolte y Agrawal 2013). Ms recientemente, se han empezado a desarrollar enfoques de &amp;#x201C;listas verdes&amp;#x201D; para incorporar tanto la eficacia de la gestin como los resultados de las reas protegidas, y es probable que adquieran una importancia progresiva a medida que se prueben y se apliquen ms ampliamente.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pueden surgir lagunas de datos y conocimientos debido a las dificultades para determinar si un lugar se ajusta a la definicin de rea protegida de la UICN, y a algunas reas protegidas no se les asignan categoras de gestin. Adems, &amp;#x201C;otras medidas efectivas de conservacin basadas en reas&amp;#x201D;, como se especifica en la Meta de Aichi para la Diversidad Biolgica &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11 del Plan Estratgico para la Diversidad Biolgica 2011&amp;#x2013;2020, reconocen que algunos lugares ms all de la red formal de reas protegidas, si bien no se gestionan principalmente para la conservacin de la naturaleza, pueden ser gestionados de manera coherente con la persistencia de la biodiversidad para la que son importantes (Jonas et al. 2014). Sin embargo, la definicin formalmente acordada de un OECM (&amp;#x201C;Un rea geogrficamente definida que no es un rea Protegida, que se gobierna y gestiona de manera que se logran resultados positivos y sostenidos a largo plazo para la conservacin in situ de la biodiversidad, con funciones y servicios de los ecosistemas asociados y, en su caso, valores culturales, espirituales, socioeconmicos y otros valores relevantes a nivel local&amp;#x201D;) no se acord hasta noviembre de 2018 y las medidas para que los pases presenten los datos del OECM al PNUMA-WCMC son recientes. Los OECM son ahora cotejados por el PNUMA-WCMC en una base de datos separada, el WD-OECM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En cuanto a los sitios importantes, la mayor limitacin es que la identificacin de sitios hasta la fecha se ha centrado principalmente en subconjuntos especficos de la biodiversidad, por ejemplo las aves (para las reas Importantes para las Aves y la Biodiversidad) y las especies altamente amenazadas (para los sitios de la Alianza para la Extincin Cero). Aunque se ha documentado que las reas Importantes para las Aves y la Biodiversidad son buenos sustitutos de la biodiversidad en general (Brooks et al. 2001, Pain et al. 2005), la aplicacin de la norma unificada para la identificacin de sitios de reas Clave para la Biodiversidad (UICN 2016) a travs de diferentes niveles de biodiversidad (genes, especies, ecosistemas) y diferentes grupos taxonmicos sigue siendo una alta prioridad, a partir de los esfuerzos realizados hasta la fecha (Eken et al. 2004, Knight et al. 2007, Langhammer et al. 2007, Foster et al. 2012). Las aves comprenden ahora el &amp;lt;50% de las especies para las que se han identificado reas Clave de Biodiversidad, y a medida que avance la identificacin de reas Clave de Biodiversidad para otros taxones y elementos de la biodiversidad, este sesgo ser una consideracin menos importante en el futuro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La identificacin de reas Clave para la Biodiversidad ha sido validada para una serie de pases y regiones en los que los datos exhaustivos sobre la biodiversidad permiten el clculo formal de la importancia del sitio (o &amp;#x201C;insustituibilidad&amp;#x201D;) utilizando tcnicas de planificacin sistemtica de la conservacin (Di Marco et al. 2016, Montesino Pouzols et al. 2014).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La evolucin futura del indicador incluir: a) la ampliacin de la cobertura taxonmica de las reas Clave de Biodiversidad marinas mediante la aplicacin de la norma de reas Clave de Biodiversidad (UICN 2016) a una amplia variedad de vertebrados marinos, invertebrados, plantas y tipo de ecosistema; b) la mejora de los datos sobre las reas protegidas mediante el aumento continuo de la proporcin de sitios con fechas documentadas de designacin y con polgonos de lmites digitalizados (en lugar de coordenadas).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Metodologa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mtodo de clculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Este indicador se calcula a partir de los datos derivados de una superposicin espacial entre los polgonos digitales de las reas protegidas de la Base de Datos Mundial sobre reas Protegidas (PNUMA-WCMC y UICN 2020) y los polgonos digitales de las reas Clave de Biodiversidad marinas (de la Base de Datos Mundial de reas Clave de Biodiversidad, que incluye las reas Importantes para las Aves y la Biodiversidad, los sitios de la Alianza para la Cero Extincin y otras reas Clave de Biodiversidad). Los sitios se clasificaron como reas Clave de Biodiversidad marinas realizando una superposicin espacial entre los polgonos de las reas Clave de Biodiversidad y una capa raster del ocano (producida a partir de la capa &amp;#x2018;adm0&amp;#x2019; de la base de datos de reas Administrativas Globales (GADM 2019)), clasificando cualquier rea Clave de Biodiversidad como rea Clave de Biodiversidad marina cuando tena una superposicin del &amp;#x2265;5% con la capa del ocano (por lo tanto, algunos sitios se clasificaron como marinos y terrestres). El valor del indicador en un momento dado, basado en los datos sobre el ao de establecimiento del rea protegida registrados en la Base de Datos Mundial sobre reas Protegidas, se calcula como el porcentaje medio de cada rea Clave de Biodiversidad actualmente reconocida que est cubierta por reas protegidas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se desconoce el ao de establecimiento del rea protegida para el ~12% de las reas protegidas en la Base de Datos Mundial sobre reas Protegidas, lo que genera incertidumbre en torno a la evolucin de la cobertura de reas protegidas a lo largo del tiempo. Para reflejar esta incertidumbre, se asign aleatoriamente un ao de otra rea protegida dentro del mismo pas, y luego se repiti este procedimiento 1.000 veces, con la mediana trazada. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antes de 2017, el indicador se presentaba como el porcentaje de reas Clave para la Biodiversidad completamente cubiertas por reas protegidas. Sin embargo, ahora se presenta como el porcentaje medio de cada rea Clave de Biodiversidad que est cubierta por reas protegidas para reflejar mejor las tendencias en la cobertura de reas protegidas para los pases o regiones con pocas o ninguna rea Clave de Biodiversidad que est completamente cubierta.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;A nivel de pas: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se dispone de datos para las reas protegidas y las reas clave para la biodiversidad en todos los pases del mundo, por lo que no es necesario imputar o estimar los datos a nivel nacional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A nivel regional y mundial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los indicadores globales de la cobertura de reas protegidas de lugares importantes para la biodiversidad se calculan como el porcentaje medio de cada rea clave para la biodiversidad que est cubierta por reas protegidas. Los datos se generan a partir de todos los pases, por lo que, aunque existe incertidumbre en torno a los datos, no hay valores perdidos como tales y, por tanto, no es necesario imputarlos o estimarlos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El PNUMA-WCMC es el organismo encargado de calcular y comunicar las cifras mundiales y regionales de este indicador, y colabora con BirdLife International y la UICN para combinar los datos de las reas protegidas con los de los lugares de importancia para la biodiversidad. El PNUMA-WCMC agrega las cifras mundiales y regionales sobre reas protegidas a partir de las cifras nacionales que se calculan a partir de la Base de Datos Mundial sobre reas Protegidas y se difunden a travs de Protected Planet. La Base de Datos Mundial sobre reas Protegidas y Protected Planet son gestionados conjuntamente por el PNUMA-WCMC y la UICN y su Comisin Mundial de reas Protegidas. La Base de Datos Mundial sobre reas Protegidas se mantiene dentro de un Sistema de Informacin Geogrfica que almacena informacin sobre las reas protegidas, como su nombre, tamao, tipo, fecha de establecimiento, ubicacin geogrfica (punto) y/o lmites (polgono). La cobertura de reas protegidas se calcula utilizando todas las reas protegidas registradas en la Base de Datos Mundial sobre reas Protegidas cuya ubicacin y extensin se conocen, aparte de las reas protegidas sin lmites digitales y los sitios que tienen un estado de &amp;#x2018;propuesto&amp;#x2019; o &amp;#x2018;no informado&amp;#x2019;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Mtodos y directrices a disposicin de los pases para la compilacin de los datos a nivel nacional:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La WDPA tiene su origen en un mandato de la ONU de 1959, cuando el Consejo Econmico y Social de las Naciones Unidas pidi una lista de parques nacionales y reservas equivalentes Resolucin 713 (XXVIII). Puede consultar ms detalles aqu: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&lt;/a&gt;. La Lista de reas Protegidas de las Naciones Unidas se ha publicado en 1961/62, 1966/71, 1972 (adicin a la edicin de 1966/71), 1973, 1974, 1975, 1980, 1982, 1985, 1990, 1993, 1997, 2003, 2014 y 2018, lo que ha dado lugar a una red mundial de proveedores de datos nacionales para la WDPA. Por ejemplo, en 2014 todos los puntos focales nacionales del Convenio sobre la Diversidad Biolgica (CDB) y todos los puntos focales nacionales del Programa de Trabajo de reas Protegidas del CDB (PoWPA) para solicitar datos para la Lista Un de reas Protegidas de 2014 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas-2014&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas-2014&lt;/a&gt;). Por lo tanto, los datos de las reas protegidas se recopilan directamente de los organismos gubernamentales, los centros regionales y otras fuentes autorizadas en ausencia de una fuente gubernamental. Todos los registros tienen un identificador de metadatos nico (MetadataID) que vincula la base de datos espacial con la tabla de fuentes donde se describen todas las fuentes. Los datos se cotejan y normalizan siguiendo las Normas de Datos de la APD y se validan con la fuente. El proceso de cotejo, validacin y publicacin de los datos, as como los protocolos y las normas de datos de la WDPA, se actualizan peridicamente en el Manual del Usuario de la WDPA (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&lt;/a&gt;) que se pone a disposicin a travs de &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net&quot;&gt;www.protectedplanet.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;donde tambin se publican cada mes todos los datos espaciales y la tabla de fuentes, que pueden descargarse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El proceso de recopilacin de datos sobre los lugares que contribuyen significativamente a la persistencia global de la biodiversidad (reas Clave de Biodiversidad) est documentado en lnea (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;). En concreto, (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/what-are-kbas&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/what-are-kbas&lt;/a&gt;), el proceso de identificacin de las reas Clave para la Biodiversidad es un ejercicio altamente inclusivo, consultivo y ascendente. Aunque cualquiera que disponga de los datos cientficos adecuados puede proponer un lugar para que sea calificado como rea Clave para la Biodiversidad, se requiere una amplia consulta con las partes interesadas a nivel nacional (tanto organizaciones no gubernamentales como gubernamentales) durante el proceso de propuesta. La identificacin de reas Clave para la Biodiversidad se basa en la red existente de reas Clave para la Biodiversidad, incluidas las identificadas como reas Importantes para las Aves y la Biodiversidad a travs de la Asociacin BirdLife de 120 organizaciones nacionales (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.birdlife.org/worldwide/partnership/birdlife-partners&quot;&gt;http://www.birdlife.org/worldwide/partnership/birdlife-partners&lt;/a&gt;), para la Alianza para la Cero Extincin por 93 organizaciones nacionales e internacionales (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zeroextinction.org/partners.html&quot;&gt;http://www.zeroextinction.org/partners.html&lt;/a&gt;), y como otras reas Clave para la Biodiversidad por organizaciones de la sociedad civil apoyadas por el Fondo de la Alianza para los Ecosistemas Crticos en el desarrollo de perfiles de ecosistemas, nombrados en cada uno de los perfiles aqu enumerados (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cepf.net/resources/publications/Pages/ecosystem_profiles.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.cepf.net/resources/publications/Pages/ecosystem_profiles.aspx&lt;/a&gt;), con nuevos datos que refuerzan y amplan la red de estos sitios. Cualquier propuesta de sitio se somete a una revisin cientfica independiente. A continuacin, se procede a la designacin oficial del lugar con una documentacin completa que cumple las Normas de Documentacin para reas Clave para la Biodiversidad. Los lugares confirmados por la Secretara de reas Clave para la Biodiversidad como reas Clave para la Biodiversidad aparecen entonces en el sitio web de reas Clave para la Biodiversidad (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El Manual del usuario de la WDPA (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&lt;/a&gt;) publicado en ingls, espaol y francs ofrece orientacin a los pases sobre cmo presentar los datos de las reas protegidas a la WDPA, cules son los beneficios de proporcionar dichos datos, cules son las normas de los datos y qu controles de calidad se realizan. Tambin ofrecemos un resumen de nuestros mtodos para calcular la cobertura de reas protegidas a todos los usuarios de la WDPA: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/calculating-protected-area-coverage&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/calculating-protected-area-coverage&lt;/a&gt;. El &amp;#x201C;Estndar global para la identificacin de reas clave para la biodiversidad&amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&lt;/a&gt;) comprende las recomendaciones estndar disponibles para los pases en la identificacin de reas clave para la biodiversidad, con ms directrices disponibles en el sitio web de reas clave para la biodiversidad (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;). Concretamente (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&lt;/a&gt;), los principales pasos del proceso de identificacin de reas Clave para la Biodiversidad son los siguientes &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;presentacin de Expresiones de Intencin para identificar un rea Clave de Biodiversidad a los Puntos Focales Regionales; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proceso de desarrollo de propuestas, en el que los proponentes recopilan los datos y la documentacin pertinentes y consultan a expertos nacionales, incluidas las organizaciones que ya han identificado reas Clave para la Biodiversidad en el pas, ya sea a travs de los Grupos de Coordinacin de reas Clave para la Biodiversidad nacionales o de forma independiente; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;revisin de las reas Clave para la Biodiversidad propuestas por parte de Revisores Expertos Independientes, verificando la exactitud de la informacin dentro de su rea de experiencia; y&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;una fase de nominacin de sitios que comprende la presentacin de toda la documentacin pertinente para su verificacin por parte de la Secretara de reas Clave para la Biodiversidad (vase la seccin 3.3 ms adelante). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Una vez identificada un rea Clave para la Biodiversidad, es importante el seguimiento de sus caractersticas cualificadas y su estado de conservacin. Los proponentes, los revisores y quienes realicen el seguimiento pueden unirse a la Comunidad de reas Clave para la Biodiversidad para intercambiar sus experiencias, estudios de caso y ejemplos de mejores prcticas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Garanta de calidad:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El proceso de recoleccin, normalizacin y publicacin de los datos est disponible en el Manual del usuario de la APD en &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&lt;/a&gt; que est disponible en ingls, francs y espaol. En &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&lt;/a&gt; se ofrecen directrices especficas sobre, por ejemplo, los campos predefinidos o las tablas de bsqueda en la WDPA: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-lookup-tables&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-lookup-tables&lt;/a&gt;, cmo se codifican los registros de la WDPA, cmo se recolectan los datos de las designaciones internacionales y las designaciones regionales, con qu regularidad se actualiza la base de datos y cmo se realizan las estadsticas de cobertura de reas protegidas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El proceso de identificacin de las reas Clave para la Biodiversidad cuenta con el apoyo de la Asociacin de reas Clave para la Biodiversidad (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/kba-partners&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/kba-partners&lt;/a&gt;). Entre las funciones de la asociacin se encuentra el establecimiento de la Secretara de reas Clave para la Biodiversidad, que comprueba la informacin presentada en la fase de nominacin del sitio para la correcta aplicacin de la Norma de reas Clave para la Biodiversidad (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&lt;/a&gt;), y la adecuacin de la documentacin del sitio y luego verifica el sitio, que se publica en el sitio web de reas Clave para la Biodiversidad (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&lt;/a&gt;). Adems, los presidentes de la Comisin de Supervivencia de Especies y de la Comisin Mundial de reas Protegidas de la UICN (ambos elegidos por los miembros de la UICN, que son gobiernos y organizaciones no gubernamentales), nombran al presidente de un Comit de Normas y Apelaciones de reas Clave para la Biodiversidad independiente, que garantiza la correcta aplicacin de la Norma Mundial para la identificacin de reas Clave para la Biodiversidad. El cdigo R para calcular la cobertura de reas protegidas de las reas Clave para la Biodiversidad est documentado como Dias, M. (2017) &amp;#x201C;Cdigo R para calcular la cobertura de reas protegidas de las KBAs&amp;#x201D;. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/userfiles/files/R_code_for_calculating_protected_area_coverage_of_KBAs_March_2017.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/userfiles/files/R_code_for_calculating_protected_area_coverage_of_KBAs_March_2017.pdf&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adems de la difusin a travs del sitio web de Planeta Protegido (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/&lt;/a&gt;), el proceso de la Lista de las Naciones Unidas descrito en el punto 3.1 el hecho de que los datos de las reas protegidas se recolectan de los organismos nacionales reconocidos en los metadatos de la WDPA, y el sitio web de reas Clave de Biodiversidad (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;), los datos de Planeta Protegido y reas Clave de Biodiversidad se difunden a travs de la Herramienta Integrada de Evaluacin de la Biodiversidad, disponible para la investigacin y la conservacin en lnea (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/&quot;&gt;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/&lt;/a&gt;). Esta herramienta incorpora los documentos de los Perfiles de Pas de todos los pases del mundo que incluyen la documentacin del indicador de cobertura de reas protegidas de las reas Clave para la Biodiversidad. Cada actualizacin anual de estos Perfiles de Pas se enva para su consulta a los Puntos Focales Nacionales del Convenio sobre la Diversidad Biolgica (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/information/nfp.shtml&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/information/nfp.shtml&lt;/a&gt;), a los Representantes de los ODS de las Oficinas Nacionales de Estadstica y a los representantes de las Misiones Permanentes de la ONU (Ginebra).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripcin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Este indicador ha sido clasificado por el IAEG-SDGs como Nivel 1. Los datos actuales estn disponibles para todos los pases del mundo y se actualizan de forma continua.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~150 aos &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregacin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dado que los datos del indicador global se compilan a nivel nacional, es sencillo desagregarlos a nivel nacional y regional (por ejemplo, Han et al. 2014) o, a la inversa, agregarlos a nivel global. Las reas Clave para la Biodiversidad abarcan todos los tipos de ecosistemas a travs del medio marino (Edgar et al. 2008) y ms all. Por lo tanto, el indicador puede ser reportado en combinacin a travs de sistemas marinos junto con sistemas terrestres o de agua dulce, o desagregado entre ellos. Sin embargo, las reas clave de biodiversidad individuales pueden abarcar sistemas marinos, terrestres y de agua dulce simultneamente, por lo que la determinacin de los resultados no es simplemente aditiva. Por ltimo, el indicador puede desagregarse segn las diferentes categoras de gestin de reas protegidas (categoras I&amp;#x2013;VI) para reflejar los diferentes objetivos de gestin especficos de las reas protegidas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adems de la agregacin de la cobertura de reas protegidas a travs de sitios importantes para la biodiversidad marina como indicador hacia el ODS 14.5, otras desagregaciones de la cobertura de reas protegidas de particular relevancia como indicadores hacia las metas de los ODS (Brooks et al. 2016) incluyen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ODS 15.1.2 Proporcin de sitios importantes para la biodiversidad terrestre y de agua dulce que estn cubiertos por reas protegidas, por tipo de ecosistema.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ODS 15.4.1 Cobertura de reas protegidas de sitios importantes para la biodiversidad de las montaas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos de cobertura de reas protegidas pueden combinarse con otras fuentes de datos para obtener otros indicadores complementarios. Por ejemplo, la superposicin de reas protegidas con mapas ecorregionales puede utilizarse para proporcionar informacin sobre la cobertura de reas protegidas de diferentes regiones biogeogrficas amplias. La cobertura de reas protegidas de las distribuciones de diferentes grupos de especies (por ejemplo, mamferos, aves) puede proporcionar igualmente indicadores de las tendencias de la cobertura de la biodiversidad a nivel de especie. La cobertura de reas protegidas puede combinarse con el ndice de la Lista Roja para generar indicadores de los impactos de las reas protegidas en la reduccin de la prdida de biodiversidad (Butchart et al. 2012). Por ltimo, los indicadores derivados de la superposicin de reas protegidas tambin pueden informar sobre el desarrollo urbano sostenible; por ejemplo, la superposicin de reas protegidas en mapas urbanos podra proporcionar un indicador del espacio pblico como proporcin del espacio total de la ciudad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Fuentes de discrepancia:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los procesos nacionales proporcionan la mayor parte de los datos que posteriormente se agregan a la Base de Datos Mundial sobre reas Protegidas y a la Base de Datos Mundial de reas Clave para la Biodiversidad, por lo que hay muy pocas diferencias entre los indicadores nacionales y el global. Una fuente menor de diferencia es que la Base de Datos Mundial sobre reas Protegidas incorpora reas protegidas designadas internacionalmente (por ejemplo, sitios del Patrimonio Mundial de la UNESCO, sitios Ramsar, etc.), algunas de las cuales no son consideradas por sus naciones soberanas como reas protegidas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obsrvese que, dado que los pases no presentan datos completos sobre las reas protegidas desclasificadas a la WDPA, los valores anteriores del indicador pueden subestimar marginalmente la cobertura. Adems, tambin hay un desfase entre el momento en que se designa un rea protegida sobre el terreno y el momento en que se informa a la WDPA. Por ello, la cobertura actual o reciente tambin puede estar subestimada.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unep-wcmc.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.unep-wcmc.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.birdlife.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.birdlife.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iucn.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.iucn.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Referencias:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estos metadatos se basan en&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mdgs.un.org/unsd/mi/wiki/7-6-Proportion-of-terrestrial-and-marine-areas-protected.ashx&quot;&gt;http://mdgs.un.org/unsd/mi/wiki/7-6-Proportion-&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mdgs.un.org/unsd/mi/wiki/7-6-Proportion-of-terrestrial-and-marine-areas-protected.ashx&quot;&gt;of-terrestrial-and-marine-areas-protected.ashx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;complementado por &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bipindicators.net/paoverlays&quot;&gt;http://www.bipindicators.net/paoverlays&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;y las referencias que se indican a continuacin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BIRDLIFE INTERNATIONAL (2014). reas importantes para las Aves y la Biodiversidad: Una red mundial para conservar la naturaleza y beneficiar a las personas. Cambridge, Reino Unido: BirdLife International. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://datazone.birdlife.org/sowb/sowbpubs#IBA.&quot;&gt;datazone.birdlife.org/sowb/sowbpubs#IBA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BIRDLIFE INTERNATIONAL (2019) &lt;em&gt;Base de datos mundial de reas clave para la biodiversidad.&lt;/em&gt;Desarrollada por la Asociacin KBA: BirdLife International, Unin Internacional para la Conservacin de la Naturaleza, Amphibian Survival Alliance, Conservation International, Critical Ecosystem Partnership Fund, Global Environment Facility, Global Wildlife Conservation, NatureServe, Rainforest Trust, Royal Society for the Protection of Birds, Wildlife Conservation Society y World Wildlife Fund. Versin de septiembre de 2019. Disponible en http://keybiodiversity areas.org/site/search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BROOKS, T. et al. (2001). Prioridades de conservacin para las aves y la biodiversidad: representan las reas Importantes para las Aves de frica Oriental la diversidad de especies de otros grupos de vertebrados terrestres? Ostrich suppl. 15: 3&amp;#x2013;12. Disponible &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;de: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.2989/00306520109485329%23.VafbVJPVq75&quot;&gt;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.2989/00306520109485329#.VafbVJPVq75&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BROOKS, T.M. et al. (2016) Objetivo 15: La vida en la tierra. Gestionar sosteniblemente los bosques, combatir la desertificacin, detener e invertir la degradacin de la tierra, detener la prdida de biodiversidad. Pp. 497&amp;#x2013;522 en Dur&amp;#xE1;n y Lalaguna, P., D&amp;#xED;az Barrado, C.M. y Fern&amp;#xE1;ndez Liesa, C.R. (eds.) Sociedad internacional y Objetivos de Desarrollo Sostenible. Editorial Aranzadi, Cizur Menor, Espaa. Disponible en: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thomsonreuters.es/es/tienda/pdp/duo.html?pid=10008456&quot;&gt;https://www.thomsonreuters.es/es/tienda/pdp/duo.html?pid=10008456&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2010). Biodiversidad mundial: indicadores de los recientes descensos. Science 328: 1164&amp;#x2013;1168. Disponible en&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/328/5982/1164.short&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/328/5982/1164.short&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2012). La proteccin de lugares importantes para la biodiversidad contribuye a alcanzar los objetivos de conservacin globales. PLoS One 7(3): e32529. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0032529&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0032529&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2015). Carencias y soluciones para cumplir con los objetivos nacionales y mundiales de reas de conservacin. Conservation Letters 8: 329&amp;#x2013;337. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12158/full&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12158/full&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBD (2014). Perspectiva mundial sobre la biodiversidad 4. Convenio sobre la Diversidad Biolgica, Montr&amp;#xE9;al, Canad. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/gbo4/&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/gbo4/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CHAPE, S. et al. (2005). Measuring the extent and effectiveness of protected areas as an indicator for meeting global biodiversity targets. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B 360: 443&amp;#x2013;445. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/360/1454/443.shor&quot;&gt;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/360/1454/443.shor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DEGUIGNET, M., et al. (2014). Lista de reas protegidas de las Naciones Unidas de 2014. UNEP-WCMC, Cambridge, Reino Unido. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://unep-wcmc.org/system/dataset_file_fields/files/000/000/263/original/2014_UN_List_of_Protected_Areas_EN_web.PDF?1415613322&quot;&gt;http://unep-wcmc.org/system/dataset_file_fields/files/000/000/263/original/2014_UN_List_of_Protected_Areas_EN_web.PDF?1415613322&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DI MARCO, M., et al. (2016). Cuantificacin de la insustituibilidad relativa de las reas importantes para las aves y la biodiversidad. Biologa de la conservacin 30: 392&amp;#x2013;402. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/cobi.12609/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/cobi.12609/abstract&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DONALD, P. et al. (2018) reas Importantes para las Aves y la Biodiversidad (IBAs): el desarrollo y las caractersticas de un inventario global de sitios clave para la biodiversidad. Bird Conserv. Internat. 29:177&amp;#x2013;198.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DUDLEY, N. (2008). Directrices para la aplicacin de las categoras de gestin de reas protegidas. Unin Internacional para la Conservacin de la Naturaleza (UICN). Gland, Suiza. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9243&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9243&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDGAR, G.J. et al. (2008). Key Biodiversity Areas as globally significant target sites for the conservation of marine biological diversity. Aquatic Conservation: Marine and Freshwater Ecosystems 18: 969&amp;#x2013;983. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/aqc.902/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/aqc.902/abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EKEN, G. et al. (2004). Key biodiversity areas as site conservation targets. BioScience 54: 1110&amp;#x2013;1118. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/54/12/1110.short&quot;&gt;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/54/12/1110.short&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOSTER, M.N. et al. (2012) La identificacin de sitios de importancia para la conservacin de la biodiversidad: avances en la aplicacin de una norma mundial. Journal of Threatened Taxa 4: 2733&amp;#x2013;2744. Disponible en &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.threatenedtaxa.in/index.php/JoTT/article/view/779&quot;&gt;http://www.threatenedtaxa.in/index.php/JoTT/article/view/779&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;reas administrativas globales (2019). Base de datos GADM de reas administrativas globales, versin 2.8. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gadm.org/home&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.gadm.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HAN, X. et al. (2014). A Biodiversity indicators dashboard: addressing challenges to monitoring progress towards the Aichi Biodiversity Targets using disaggregated global data. PLoS ONE 9(11): e112046. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0112046&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0112046&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOLLAND, R.A. et al. (2012). Prioridades de conservacin de la biodiversidad de agua dulce: el enfoque de reas clave de biodiversidad refinado y probado para el frica continental. Biological Conservation 148: 167&amp;#x2013;179. Disponible en &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320712000298&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320712000298&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IUCN (2016). Un estndar global para la identificacin de reas clave para la biodiversidad. Unin Internacional para la Conservacin de la Naturaleza, Gland, Suiza. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JONAS, H.D. et al. (2014) New steps of change: looking beyond protected areas to consider other effective area-based conservation measures. Parks 20: 111&amp;#x2013;128. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://parksjournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/PARKS-20.2-Jonas-et-al-10.2305IUCN.CH_.2014.PARKS-20-2.HDJ_.en_.pdf&quot;&gt;http://parksjournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/PARKS-20.2-Jonas-et-al-10.2305IUCN.CH_.2014.PARKS-20-2.HDJ_.en_.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KNIGHT, A. T. et al. (2007). Improving the Key Biodiversity Areas approach for effective conservation planning. BioScience 57: 256&amp;#x2013;261. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/57/3/256.short&quot;&gt;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/57/3/256.short&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LANGHAMMER, P. F. et al. (2007). Identification and Gap Analysis of Key Biodiversity Areas: Targets for Comprehensive Protected Area Systems. UICN World Commission on Protected Areas Best Practice Protected Area Guidelines Series No. 15. UICN, Gland, Suiza. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9055&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9055&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LEVERINGTON, F. et al. (2010). Un anlisis global de la eficacia de la gestin de las reas protegidas. Environmental Management 46: 685&amp;#x2013;698. Disponible en http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00267-010-9564-5#page-1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MONTESINO POUZOLS, F., et al. (2014) La expansin global de las reas protegidas se ve comprometida por el uso de la tierra y el parroquialismo proyectados. Nature 516: 383&amp;#x2013;386. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v516/n7531/abs/nature14032.html&quot;&gt;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v516/n7531/abs/nature14032.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOLTE, C. y AGRAWAL, A. (2013). Vinculacin de los indicadores de eficacia de la gestin con los efectos observados de las reas protegidas en la aparicin de incendios en la selva amaznica. Conservation Biology 27: 155&amp;#x2013;165. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2012.01930.x/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2012.01930.x/abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PAIN, D.J. et al. (2005) Biodiversity representation in Uganda forest IBAs. Biological Conservation 125: 133&amp;#x2013;138. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320705001412&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320705001412&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RICKETTS, T. H. et al. (2005). Localizacin y prevencin de extinciones inminentes. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the U.S.A. 102: 18497&amp;#x2013;18501. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/102/51/18497.short&quot;&gt;http://www.pnas.org/content/102/51/18497.short&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RODRIGUES, A. S. L. et al. (2004). Effectiveness of the global protected area network in representing species diversity. Nature 428: 640&amp;#x2013;643. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v428/n6983/abs/nature02422.html&quot;&gt;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v428/n6983/abs/nature02422.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RODR&amp;#xCD;GUEZ-RODR&amp;#xCD;GUEZ, D., et al. (2011). Progreso hacia los objetivos internacionales de cobertura de reas protegidas en las montaas: una evaluacin a mltiples escalas. Biological Conservation 144: 2978&amp;#x2013;2983. Disponible en &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320711003454&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320711003454&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TITTENSOR, D. et al. (2014). Un anlisis a medio plazo del progreso hacia los objetivos internacionales de biodiversidad. Science 346: 241&amp;#x2013;244. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/346/6206/241.short&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/346/6206/241.short&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PNUMA-WCMC (2019). Base de datos mundial sobre reas protegidas. Manual del usuario 1.6. PNUMA-WCMC, Cambridge, Reino Unido. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://wcmc.io/WDPA_Manual&quot;&gt;http://wcmc.io/WDPA_Manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PNUMA-WCMC y IUCN (2020). The World Database on Protected Areas (WDPA). PNUMA-WCMC, Cambridge, Reino Unido. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net&quot;&gt;http://www.protectedplanet.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 14: Conserver et exploiter de manire durable les ocans, les mers et les ressources marines aux fins dudveloppement durable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 14.5: Dici  2020, prserver au moins 10pourcent des zones marines et ctires, conformment au droit national etinternational et compte tenu des meilleures informations scientifiques disponibles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 14.5.1: Surface des aires marines protges, en proportion de la surface totale&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Juillet 2021&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Informations institutionnelles &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organization(s) :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Centre mondial de surveillance continue de la conservation de la nature de l&apos;ONU Environnement (PNUE-WCMC)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BirdLife International (BLI)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Union internationale pour la conservation de la nature (UICN)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et dfinitions &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dfinition : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur Couverture des aires protges par rapport aux aires marines montre les tendances temporelles du pourcentage moyen de chaque site important pour la biodiversit marine (c&apos;est--dire ceux qui contribuent de manire significative  la persistance de la biodiversit mondiale) qui est couvert par des aires protges dsignes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les aires protges, telles que dfinies par l&apos;Union internationale pour la conservation de la nature (UICN ; Dudley 2008), sont des espaces gographiques clairement dfinis, reconnus, ddis et grs, par des moyens lgaux ou d&apos;autres moyens efficaces, pour raliser la conservation  long terme de la nature avec les services cosystmiques et les valeurs culturelles associs. Il est important de noter qu&apos;une varit d&apos;objectifs de gestion spcifiques sont reconnus dans cette dfinition, couvrant la conservation, la restauration et l&apos;utilisation durable :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Catgorie Ia : Rserve naturelle stricte&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Catgorie Ib : Zone de nature sauvage &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Catgorie II : Parc national &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Catgorie III : Monument ou lment naturel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Catgorie IV : Zone de gestion de l&apos;habitat/des espces&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Catgorie V : Paysage terrestre ou marin protg &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Catgorie VI : Zone protge avec utilisation durable des ressources naturelles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le statut &amp;quot;dsign&amp;quot; est attribu  une aire protge lorsque l&apos;autorit correspondante, conformment  la lgislation nationale ou  la pratique courante (par exemple, au moyen d&apos;un dcret excutif ou autre), approuve officiellement un document de dsignation. La dsignation doit tre faite dans un but de conservation de la biodiversit, et non de protection de facto rsultant d&apos;une autre activit (par exemple, militaire).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les sites contribuant de manire significative  la persistance de la biodiversit  l&apos;chelle mondiale sont identifis en suivant les critres mondiaux dfinis dans &lt;em&gt;Une norme mondiale pour l&apos;identification des zones cls pour la biodiversit &lt;/em&gt;(UICN 2016) appliqus au niveau national. Les zones cls pour la biodiversit englobent (a) les zones importantes pour la biodiversit des oiseaux, c&apos;est--dire les sites contribuant de manire significative  la persistance de la biodiversit au niveau mondial, identifis  l&apos;aide de donnes sur les oiseaux, dont &amp;gt;13 000 sites au total ont t identifis dans tous les pays du monde (BirdLife International 2014, Donald &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; 2018) ; (b) les sites de l&apos;Alliance pour une extinction zro (Ricketts et al. 2005), c&apos;est--dire des sites dtenant effectivement la totalit de la population d&apos;au moins une espce value comme tant en danger critique d&apos;extinction ou en danger sur la liste rouge des espces menaces de l&apos;UICN, dont 853 sites ont t identifis pour 1 483 espces de mammifres, oiseaux, amphibiens, reptiles, crustacs d&apos;eau douce, coraux constructeurs de rcifs, conifres, cycadales et autres taxons ; (c) les zones cls pour la biodiversit identifies dans le cadre d&apos;une version antrieure des critres relatifs aux zones cls pour la biodiversit (Langhammer &lt;em&gt; et al.&lt;/em&gt; 2007), y compris celles identifies dans les profils de points chauds des cosystmes labors avec le soutien du Fonds de partenariat pour les cosystmes critiques. Ces trois sous-ensembles sont en cours de rvaluation  l&apos;aide de la Norme mondiale, qui unifie ces approches ainsi que d&apos;autres mcanismes d&apos;identification de sites importants pour d&apos;autres espces et cosystmes (UICN 2016).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Sources de donnes &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les donnes sur les aires protges sont compiles par les ministres de l&apos;environnement et autres ministres responsables de la dsignation et de l&apos;entretien des aires protges. Les donnes sur les aires protges pour les sites dsigns dans le cadre de la Convention de Ramsar et de la Convention du patrimoine mondial de l&apos;UNESCO sont recueillies par les secrtariats internationaux des conventions concernes. Les donnes sur les aires protges sont agrges au niveau mondial dans la base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges par le Centre mondial de surveillance de la conservation de l&apos;environnement de l&apos;ONU, conformment au mandat de production de la liste des aires protges de l&apos;ONU (Deguignet et al. 2014). Elles sont diffuses par le biais de &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net/&quot;&gt;Protected Planet&lt;/a&gt;, qui est gr conjointement par le PNUE-WCMC et l&apos;UICN et sa Commission mondiale des aires protges (PNUE-WCMC 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les zones cls pour la biodiversit sont identifies  l&apos;chelle nationale par des processus multipartites, selon des critres et des seuils standard. Les donnes sur les zones cls pour la biodiversit sont regroupes dans la &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;Base de donnes mondiale sur les &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;Zones cls pour la biodiversit&lt;/a&gt;, gre par BirdLife International. Plus prcisment, les donnes sur les zones importantes pour les oiseaux et la biodiversit sont disponibles en ligne sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&quot;&gt;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&lt;/a&gt; et les donnes sur les sites de l&apos;Alliance pour une extinction zro sont disponibles en ligne sur https://zeroextinction.org. Ces deux ensembles de donnes, ainsi que les zones cls pour la biodiversit identifies par d&apos;autres processus, sont disponibles par le biais de la &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;Base de donnes mondiale sur les zones cls pour la biodiversit&lt;/a&gt; et, avec la Base de donnes mondiale sur les zones protges, sont galement diffuss par le biais du &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/login&quot;&gt;Outil d&apos;valuation intgre de la biodiversit pour la recherche et la planification de la conservation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Processus de collecte : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voir les informations sous d&apos;autres sections. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendrier &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Collecte des donnes :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le PNUE-WCMC produit la Liste des aires protges des Nations Unies tous les 5 10 ans, sur la base des informations fournies par les ministres/agences nationales. Dans l&apos;intervalle entre les compilations des listes des Nations Unies, le PNUE-WCMC travaille en troite collaboration avec les ministres/agences nationales et les ONG responsables de la dsignation et de l&apos;entretien des zones protges, mettant continuellement  jour la WDPA au fur et  mesure que de nouvelles donnes sont disponibles. La base de donnes mondiale des zones cls pour la biodiversit est galement mise  jour de manire continue,  mesure que de nouvelles donnes nationales sont soumises. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publication des donnes : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il est prvu que l&apos;indicateur de la couverture en aires protges des sites importants pour la biodiversit soit publi annuellement. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fournisseurs de donnes &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les donnes sur les zones protges sont compiles par les ministres de l&apos;environnement et d&apos;autres ministres responsables de la dsignation et de l&apos;entretien des zones protges. Les zones cls pour la biodiversit sont identifies  l&apos;chelle nationale par le biais de processus multipartites, selon des critres et des seuils standard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compilateurs de donnes &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nom :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PNUE-WCMC et UICN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les donnes sur les aires protges sont agrges au niveau mondial dans la base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges par le Centre mondial de surveillance continue de la conservation de la nature de l&apos;ONU Environnement, conformment au mandat de production de la liste des aires protges des Nations unies (Deguignet et al. 2014). Elles sont diffuses par le biais de &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net/&quot;&gt;Protected Planet&lt;/a&gt;, qui est gr conjointement par le PNUE-WCMC et l&apos;UICN et sa Commission mondiale des aires protges (PNUE-WCMC 2016). Les donnes sur les zones cls pour la biodiversit sont regroupes dans la &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;Base de donnes mondiale sur les zones cls pour la biodiversit&lt;/a&gt;, gre par BirdLife International (2019). Plus prcisment, les donnes sur les zones importantes pour les oiseaux et la biodiversit sont disponibles en ligne sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&quot;&gt;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&lt;/a&gt; et les donnes sur les sites de l&apos;Alliance pour une extinction zro sont disponibles en ligne sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zeroextinction.org/search.cfm&quot;&gt;http://www.zeroextinction.org/search.cfm&lt;/a&gt;. Ces deux ensembles de donnes, ainsi que la base de donnes mondiale sur les zones protges, sont galement diffuss par le biais du &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/login&quot;&gt;Outil d&apos;valuation intgre de la biodiversit pour la recherche et la planification de la conservation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justification : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La sauvegarde des sites importants est essentielle pour enrayer le dclin de la biodiversit et garantir une utilisation durable et  long terme des ressources naturelles marines. La cration de zones protges est un mcanisme important pour atteindre cet objectif, et cet indicateur permet de mesurer les progrs raliss en matire de conservation, de restauration et d&apos;utilisation durable des cosystmes marins et de leurs services, conformment aux obligations dcoulant des accords internationaux. Il est important de noter que, bien qu&apos;il puisse tre dsagrg pour rendre compte de tout cosystme unique d&apos;intrt, il n&apos;est pas limit  un seul type d&apos;cosystme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les niveaux d&apos;accs aux zones protges varient selon les catgories de gestion des zones protges. Certaines zones, comme les rserves scientifiques, sont maintenues dans leur tat naturel et fermes  toute autre utilisation. D&apos;autres sont utilises pour les loisirs ou le tourisme, ou mme ouvertes  l&apos;extraction durable des ressources naturelles. Outre la protection de la biodiversit, les zones protges ont une grande valeur sociale et conomique : elles soutiennent les moyens de subsistance locaux, maintiennent les pcheries, abritent une richesse inestimable de ressources gntiques, soutiennent des industries florissantes de loisirs et de tourisme, permettent la science, la recherche et l&apos;ducation et constituent une base pour les valeurs culturelles et autres valeurs non matrielles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur ajoute des informations significatives aux statistiques simples traditionnellement rapportes sur les zones marines couvertes par des aires protges, les complte et les dveloppe, en divisant la zone protge totale d&apos;un pays par la zone territoriale totale du pays et en multipliant par 100 (par exemple, Chape et al. 2005). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De telles statistiques de couverture de zone en pourcentage ne reconnaissent pas l&apos;extrme variation de l&apos;importance de la biodiversit dans l&apos;espace (Rodrigues et al. 2004), et risquent donc de gnrer des rsultats pervers par la protection de zones qui sont grandes au dtriment de celles qui ncessitent une protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L&apos;indicateur est utilis pour suivre les progrs vers le Plan stratgique 2011  2020 pour la biodiversit (CBD 2014, Tittensor et al. 2014), et a t utilis comme indicateur pour l&apos;Objectif 2010 de la Convention sur la diversit biologique (Butchart et al. 2010). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Commentaires et limites:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Des critres de contrle de la qualit sont appliqus pour assurer luniformit et la comparabilit des donnes dans la base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges. De nouvelles donnes sont valides au PNUE-WCMC au moyen dun certain nombre doutils et traduites dans la structure de donnes standard de la Base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges. Les divergences entre les donnes de la Base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges et les nouvelles donnes sont minimises par la fourniture dun manuel (PNUE-WCMC 2019) et rsolues en communication avec les fournisseurs de donnes. Des processus similaires sappliquent  lincorporation de donnes dans la base de donnes mondiale &lt;em&gt;Des zones cls de biodiversit &lt;/em&gt;(BirdLife International 2019). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Lindicateur ne mesure pas lefficacit des aires protges dans la rduction de la perte de biodiversit, qui dpend en fin de compte dune srie de facteurs de gestion et dapplication qui ne sont pas couverts par lindicateur. Un certain nombre dinitiatives sont en cours pour remdier  cette limitation. Plus particulirement, de nombreux mcanismes ont t mis au point pour lvaluation de la gestion des aires protges, qui peuvent tre synthtiss en un indicateur (Leverington et al., 2010). Ceci est utilis par le Partenariat pour les indicateurs de biodiversit comme indicateur complmentaire des progrs raliss vers lobjectif 11 dAichi en matire de biodiversit &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bipindicators.net/pamanagement&quot;&gt;http://www.bipindicators.net/pamanagement&lt;/a&gt;). Toutefois, il peut y avoir peu de relations entre ces mesures et les rsultats des aires protges (Nolte &amp;amp; Agrawal 2013). Plus rcemment, des approches de &amp;#x201C;linscription verte&amp;#x201D;ont commenc  tre labores, afin dintgrer  la fois lefficacit de la gestion et les rsultats des aires protges, et celles-ci sont susceptibles de devenir progressivement importantes  mesure quelles sont testes et appliques de faon plus gnrale. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Des lacunes en matire de donnes et de connaissances peuvent survenir en raison de difficults  dterminer si un site est conforme  la dfinition daire protge donne par lUICN, et certaines aires protges ne sont pas affectes  des catgories de gestion. En outre, &amp;#x201C; dautres mesures efficaces de conservation axes sur les zones&amp;#x201D;, telles que spcifies par lObjectif biodiversit dAichi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11 du Plan stratgique pour la biodiversit 2011  2020, reconnaissent que certains sites au-del du rseau formel daires protges, bien quils ne soient pas grs principalement pour la conservation de la nature, peuvent nanmoins tre grs dune manire compatible avec la persistance de la biodiversit pour laquelle ils sont importants (Jonas et al., 2014). Toutefois, la dfinition formellement convenue dun OECM (&amp;#x201C;Une zone gographiquement dfinie autre quune aire protge, qui est gouverne et gre de manire  obtenir des rsultats positifs et soutenus  long terme pour la conservation in situ de la biodiversit, avec les fonctions et services cosystmiques associs et, le cas chant, culturelles, spirituelles, socioconomiques et autres valeurs pertinentes localement&amp;#x201D;) nont t convenues quen novembre 2018 et des mesures ne sont en place que rcemment pour que les pays soumettent des donnes de lOECM au PNUE-WCMC. Les OECM sont maintenant rassembls par le PNUE-WCMC dans une base de donnes distincte, le WD-OECM. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; En ce qui concerne les sites importants, la plus grande limitation est que lidentification des sites  ce jour sest concentre principalement sur des sous-ensembles spcifiques de biodiversit, par exemple des oiseaux (pour des zones importantes pour les oiseaux et la biodiversit) et des espces fortement menaces (pour les sites de lAlliance pour lextinction zro). Bien que dimportantes zones doiseaux et de biodiversit aient t documentes comme de bons substituts  la biodiversit en gnral (Brooks et coll., 2001, Pain et coll. 2005), lapplication de la norme unifie pour lidentification des zones cls de biodiversit (UICN 2016)  diffrents niveaux de biodiversit (gnes, espces, cosystmes) et de diffrents groupes taxonomiques demeure une priorit leve, sdussant des efforts dploys  ce jour (Eken et coll. 2004, Knight et coll. 2007, Langhammer et coll. 2007, Foster et coll. 2012). Les oiseaux reprsentent maintenant &amp;lt;50 % des espces pour lesquelles des zones cls de biodiversit ont t identifies, et comme lidentification de la zone cl de biodiversit pour dautres taxons et lments de la biodiversit procde, ce biais deviendra une considration moins importante  lavenir. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Lidentification cl de la zone de biodiversit a t valide pour un certain nombre de pays et de rgions o des donnes compltes sur la biodiversit permettent un calcul formel de limportance du site (ou &amp;#x201C;irremplaabilit&amp;#x201D;)  laide de techniques systmatiques de planification de la conservation (Di Marco et al., 2016, Montesino Pouzols et al., 2014). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les dveloppements futurs de lindicateur comprendront: a) lexpansion de la couverture taxonomique des zones marines cls de biodiversit grce  lapplication de la norme des zones cls de biodiversit (UICN 2016)  une grande varit de vertbrs marins, dinvertbrs, de plantes et de type cosystmique; b) lamlioration des donnes sur les aires protges en continuant daugmenter la proportion de sites dont les dates de dsignation sont documentes et avec les polygones limites numriss (plutt que les coordonnes). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mthodologie &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mthode de calcul : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur est calcul  partir de donnes drives d&apos;un chevauchement spatial entre les polygones numriques des zones protges de la base de donnes mondiale sur les zones protges (PNUE-WCMC &amp;amp; UICN 2020) et les polygones numriques des zones cls pour la biodiversit marine (de la base de donnes mondiale des zones cls pour la biodiversit, y compris les zones importantes pour les oiseaux et la biodiversit, les sites de l&apos;Alliance pour une extinction zro et d&apos;autres zones cls pour la biodiversit). Les sites ont t classs comme zones cls pour la biodiversit marines en effectuant un chevauchement spatial entre les polygones des zones cls pour la biodiversit et une couche matricielle ocanique (produite  partir de la couche &amp;#x2018;adm0&amp;#x2019; de la base de donnes des zones administratives mondiales (GADM 2019)), en classant toute zone cl pour la biodiversit comme zone cl pour la biodiversit marine lorsqu&apos;elle prsente un chevauchement de &amp;#x2265;5 % avec la couche ocanique (certains sites ont donc t classs  la fois comme marins et terrestres). La valeur de l&apos;indicateur  un moment donn, base sur les donnes relatives  l&apos;anne d&apos;tablissement de la zone protge enregistres dans la base de donnes mondiale sur les zones protges, est calcule comme le pourcentage moyen de chaque zone cl de biodiversit actuellement reconnue qui est couverte par des zones protges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;anne d&apos;tablissement des aires protges est inconnue pour ~12% des aires protges de la base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges, ce qui gnre une incertitude quant  l&apos;volution de la couverture des aires protges au fil du temps. Pour reflter cette incertitude, une anne a t assigne au hasard  partir d&apos;une autre aire protge dans le mme pays, puis cette procdure a t rpte 1 000 fois, avec la mdiane trace. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avant 2017, l&apos;indicateur tait prsent comme le pourcentage de zones cls pour la biodiversit entirement couvertes par des zones protges. Cependant, il est maintenant prsent comme le % moyen de chaque Zone cl pour la biodiversit qui est couverte par des zones protges afin de mieux reflter les tendances de la couverture des zones protges pour les pays ou les rgions avec peu ou pas de Zones cls pour la biodiversit qui sont compltement couvertes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Traitement des valeurs manquantes : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Au niveau national : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les donnes sont disponibles pour les zones protges et les zones cls pour la biodiversit dans tous les pays du monde et il n&apos;est donc pas ncessaire d&apos;imputer ou d&apos;estimer les donnes au niveau national.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aux niveaux rgional et mondial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les indicateurs mondiaux de la couverture en aires protges des sites importants pour la biodiversit sont calculs comme le pourcentage moyen de chaque zone cl pour la biodiversit qui est couverte par des aires protges. Les donnes sont gnres  partir de tous les pays, et donc, bien qu&apos;il y ait une incertitude autour des donnes, il n&apos;y a pas de valeurs manquantes en tant que telles et donc pas besoin d&apos;imputation ou d&apos;estimation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agrgats rgionaux :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le PNUE-WCMC est l&apos;agence charge de calculer et de communiquer les chiffres mondiaux et rgionaux pour cet indicateur, en collaboration avec BirdLife International et l&apos;UICN pour combiner les donnes sur les aires protges avec celles sur les sites importants pour la biodiversit. Le PNUE-WCMC regroupe les chiffres mondiaux et rgionaux sur les zones protges  partir des chiffres nationaux calculs  partir de la base de donnes mondiale sur les zones protges et diffuss par Protected Planet. La base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges et Protected Planet sont gres conjointement par le PNUE-WCMC, l&apos;UICN et sa Commission mondiale des aires protges. La base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges est conserve dans un systme d&apos;information gographique qui stocke des informations sur les aires protges telles que leur nom, leur taille, leur type, leur date de cration, leur emplacement gographique (point) et/ou leurs limites (polygone). La couverture des aires protges est calcule en utilisant toutes les aires protges enregistres dans la base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges dont l&apos;emplacement et l&apos;tendue sont connus,  l&apos;exception des aires protges sans limites numriques et des sites dont le statut est &amp;#x2018;propos&amp;#x2019; ou &amp;#x2018;non signal&amp;#x2019;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Mthodes et conseils  la disposition des pays pour la compilation des donnes au niveau national :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La WDPA trouve son origine dans un mandat des Nations Unies de 1959, lorsque le Conseil conomique et social des Nations Unies a demand une liste de parcs nationaux et de rserves quivalentes (Rsolution 713 (XXVIII)). Plus de dtails sont disponibles ici : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas &lt;/a&gt;. La liste des aires protges des Nations unies a t publie en 1961/62, 1966/71, 1972 (addendum  l&apos;dition 1966/71), 1973, 1974, 1975, 1980, 1982, 1985, 1990, 1993, 1997, 2003, 2014 et 2018, ce qui a donn lieu  un rseau mondial de fournisseurs de donnes nationales pour la WDPA. Par exemple, en 2014, tous les points focaux nationaux de la Convention sur la diversit biologique (CDB) et tous les points focaux nationaux du programme de travail sur les aires protges de la CDB (PoWPA) ont demand des donnes pour la Liste Un des aires protges 2014 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas-2014&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas-2014&lt;/a&gt;). Les donnes sur les aires protges sont donc compiles directement  partir d&apos;agences gouvernementales, de centres rgionaux et d&apos;autres sources faisant autorit en l&apos;absence de source gouvernementale. Tous les enregistrements ont un identifiant de mtadonnes unique (MetadataID) qui relie la base de donnes spatiale  la table Source o toutes les sources sont dcrites. Les donnes sont rassembles et standardises selon les normes de donnes de la WDPA et valides avec la source. Le processus de collecte, de validation et de publication des donnes ainsi que les protocoles et les normes de donnes de la WDPA sont rgulirement mis  jour dans le manuel de l&apos;utilisateur de la WDPA (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&lt;/a&gt;) disponible sur le site &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net&quot;&gt;www.protectedplanet.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;o toutes les donnes spatiales et le tableau des sources sont galement publis chaque mois et peuvent tre tlchargs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le processus de compilation des donnes sur les sites contribuant de manire significative  la persistance de la biodiversit mondiale (zones cls pour la biodiversit) est document en ligne (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;). Plus prcisment, (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/what-are-kbas&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/what-are-kbas&lt;/a&gt;), le processus d&apos;identification des zones cls pour la biodiversit est un exercice trs inclusif, consultatif et ascendant. Bien que toute personne disposant de donnes scientifiques appropries puisse proposer un site  qualifier de zone cl pour la biodiversit, une large consultation des parties prenantes au niveau national (organisations non gouvernementales et gouvernementales) est requise au cours du processus de proposition. L&apos;identification des zones cls pour la biodiversit s&apos;appuie sur le rseau existant de zones cls pour la biodiversit, y compris celles identifies comme zones importantes pour la biodiversit des oiseaux par le partenariat BirdLife de 120 organisations nationales (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.birdlife.org/worldwide/partnership/birdlife-partners&quot;&gt;http://www.birdlife.org/worldwide/partnership/birdlife-partners&lt;/a&gt;), pour l&apos;Alliance pour une extinction zro par 93 organisations nationales et internationales (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zeroextinction.org/partners.html&quot;&gt;http://www.zeroextinction.org/partners.html&lt;/a&gt;), et en tant qu&apos;autres zones cls pour la biodiversit par des organisations de la socit civile soutenues par le Fonds de partenariat pour les cosystmes critiques dans l&apos;laboration de profils d&apos;cosystmes, nomms dans chacun des profils numrs ici (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cepf.net/resources/publications/Pages/ecosystem_profiles.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.cepf.net/resources/publications/Pages/ecosystem_profiles.aspx&lt;/a&gt;), les nouvelles donnes renforant et largissant le rseau de ces sites. Toute proposition de site fait l&apos;objet d&apos;un examen scientifique indpendant. Il s&apos;ensuit la nomination officielle du site avec une documentation complte rpondant aux normes de documentation des zones cls pour la biodiversit. Les sites dont le Secrtariat des zones cls pour la biodiversit confirme qu&apos;ils remplissent les conditions requises pour devenir des zones cls pour la biodiversit apparaissent ensuite sur le site Web des zones cls pour la biodiversit (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le manuel de l&apos;utilisateur de la WDPA (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&lt;/a&gt;) publi en anglais, en espagnol et en franais fournit des conseils aux pays sur la manire de soumettre des donnes sur les zones protges  la WDPA, sur les avantages de fournir ces donnes, sur les normes de donnes et sur les contrles de qualit effectus. Nous fournissons galement un rsum de nos mthodes de calcul de la couverture des zones protges  tous les utilisateurs de la WDPA : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/calculating-protected-area-coverage&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/calculating-protected-area-coverage&lt;/a&gt;. La &amp;#x201C;Norme mondiale pour l&apos;identification des zones cls pour la biodiversit &amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&lt;/a&gt;) comprend les recommandations standard mises  la disposition des pays pour l&apos;identification des zones cls pour la biodiversit, d&apos;autres directives tant disponibles sur le site Web des zones cls pour la biodiversit (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;). Plus prcisment (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&lt;/a&gt;), les principales tapes du processus d&apos;identification des zones cls pour la biodiversit sont les suivantes : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;soumission des expressions d&apos;intention d&apos;identifier une Zone de Biodiversit Principale aux Points Focaux Rgionaux ; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Processus d&apos;laboration de la proposition, dans lequel les proposants compilent les donnes et la documentation pertinentes et consultent des experts nationaux, y compris des organisations qui ont dj identifi des Zones cls pour la biodiversit dans le pays, soit par l&apos;intermdiaire de groupes nationaux de coordination des Zones cls pour la biodiversit, soit de manire indpendante ; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;l&apos;examen des Zones cls pour la biodiversit proposes par des experts indpendants, qui vrifient l&apos;exactitude des informations dans leur domaine d&apos;expertise ; et &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;une phase de dsignation des sites comprenant la soumission de tous les documents pertinents pour vrification par le secrtariat des zones cls pour la biodiversit (voir section 3.3 ci-dessous). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Une fois qu&apos;une zone cl pour la biodiversit est identifie, il est important de surveiller ses caractristiques et son tat de conservation. Les auteurs de propositions, les valuateurs et les personnes charges de la surveillance peuvent rejoindre la communaut des zones cls pour la biodiversit afin d&apos;changer leurs expriences, leurs tudes de cas et leurs exemples de meilleures pratiques.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Assurance qualit : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le processus de collecte, de normalisation et de publication des donnes est disponible dans le manuel de l&apos;utilisateur de la WDPA  l&apos;adresse suivante : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&lt;/a&gt; qui est disponible en anglais, franais et espagnol. Des conseils spcifiques sont fournis  l&apos;adresse &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&lt;/a&gt; sur, par exemple, les champs prdfinis ou les tables de recherche dans la WDPA : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-lookup-tables&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-lookup-tables&lt;/a&gt;, comment les enregistrements de la WDPA sont cods, comment les donnes sur les dsignations internationales et rgionales sont collectes,  quelle frquence la base de donnes est mise  jour et comment raliser des statistiques sur la couverture des zones protges. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Le processus d&apos;identification des zones cls pour la biodiversit est soutenu par le partenariat des zones cls pour la biodiversit (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/kba-partners&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/kba-partners&lt;/a&gt;). Parmi les rles du partenariat figure la mise en place du secrtariat des zones cls pour la biodiversit, qui vrifie les informations soumises lors de la phase de dsignation des sites pour s&apos;assurer de l&apos;application correcte de la norme relative aux zones cls pour la biodiversit (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&lt;/a&gt;) et de l&apos;adquation de la documentation relative au site, puis vrifie le site, qui est ensuite publi sur le site Web des zones cls pour la biodiversit (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&lt;/a&gt;). En outre, les prsidents de la Commission de la sauvegarde des espces et de la Commission mondiale des aires protges de l&apos;UICN (tous deux lus par les membres de l&apos;UICN,  savoir les gouvernements et les organisations non gouvernementales), nomment le prsident d&apos;un comit indpendant, le Key Biodiversity Areas Standards and Appeals Committee, qui veille  l&apos;application correcte de la norme mondiale pour l&apos;identification des Key Biodiversity Areas. Le code R pour le calcul de la couverture des zones protges des zones cls pour la biodiversit est document comme Dias, M. (2017) &amp;#x201C;Code R pour le calcul de la couverture des zones protges des ZCB&amp;#x201D;. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/userfiles/files/R_code_for_calculating_protected_area_coverage_of_KBAs_March_2017.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/userfiles/files/R_code_for_calculating_protected_area_coverage_of_KBAs_March_2017.pdf&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outre la diffusion via le site web de Protected Planet (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/&lt;/a&gt;), le processus de la liste des Nations unies dcrit au point 3.1 le fait que les donnes sur les aires protges sont collectes auprs d&apos;agences nationales reconnues dans les mtadonnes de la WDPA, et le site web des zones cls pour la biodiversit (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;), les donnes de Protected Planet et des zones cls pour la biodiversit sont diffuses via l&apos;outil d&apos;valuation intgre de la biodiversit, disponible en ligne pour la recherche et la conservation (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/&quot;&gt;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/&lt;/a&gt;). Cet outil intgre les profils nationaux de tous les pays du monde, qui comprennent une documentation sur l&apos;indicateur de couverture des zones protges des zones cls pour la biodiversit. Chaque mise  jour annuelle de ces profils nationaux est envoye pour consultation aux points focaux nationaux de la Convention sur la diversit biologique (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/information/nfp.shtml&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/information/nfp.shtml&lt;/a&gt;), aux reprsentants des OMD des bureaux nationaux de statistiques et aux reprsentants des missions permanentes des Nations unies (Genve).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;leve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cet indicateur a t class par l&apos;IAEG-ODD comme tant de niveau 1. Des donnes actuelles sont disponibles pour tous les pays du monde, et elles sont mises  jour en permanence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sries chronologiques :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~150 ans &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Dsagrgation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tant donn que les donnes de l&apos;indicateur mondial sont compiles au niveau national, il est facile de les dsagrger aux niveaux national et rgional (par exemple, Han et al. 2014), ou inversement de les agrger au niveau mondial. Les zones cls pour la biodiversit couvrent tous les types d&apos;cosystmes jusqu&apos; l&apos;environnement marin (Edgar et al. 2008) et au-del. L&apos;indicateur peut donc tre rapport en combinaison dans les systmes marins ainsi que dans les systmes terrestres ou d&apos;eau douce, ou dsagrg entre eux. Cependant, les zones cls pour la biodiversit individuelles peuvent englober simultanment des systmes marins, terrestres et d&apos;eau douce, et la dtermination des rsultats n&apos;est donc pas simplement additive. Enfin, l&apos;indicateur peut tre dsagrg selon les diffrentes catgories de gestion des aires protges (catgories I  VI) pour reflter les diffrents objectifs de gestion spcifiques des aires protges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outre l&apos;agrgation de la couverture des aires protges dans les sites importants pour la biodiversit marine en tant qu&apos;indicateur de l&apos;ODD 14.5, d&apos;autres dsagrgations de la couverture des aires protges particulirement pertinentes en tant qu&apos;indicateurs des cibles des ODD (Brooks et al. 2016) comprennent :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ODD 15.1.2 Proportion de sites importants pour la biodiversit terrestre et d&apos;eau douce qui sont couverts par des aires protges, par type d&apos;cosystme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ODD 15.4.1 Couverture par des aires protges de sites importants pour la biodiversit des montagnes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les donnes sur la couverture des zones protges peuvent tre combines avec d&apos;autres sources de donnes pour produire d&apos;autres indicateurs complmentaires. Par exemple, la superposition des aires protges avec des cartes co-rgionales peut tre utilise pour fournir des informations sur la couverture par les aires protges de diffrentes grandes rgions biogographiques. La couverture par les aires protges des distributions de diffrents groupes d&apos;espces (par exemple, mammifres, oiseaux) peut galement fournir des indicateurs des tendances de la couverture de la biodiversit au niveau des espces. La couverture des aires protges peut tre combine avec l&apos;indice de la liste rouge pour gnrer des indicateurs de l&apos;impact des aires protges sur la rduction de la perte de biodiversit (Butchart et al. 2012). Enfin, les indicateurs drivs de la superposition des zones protges peuvent galement informer le dveloppement urbain durable ; par exemple, la superposition des zones protges sur les cartes urbaines pourrait fournir un indicateur de l&apos;espace public en tant que proportion de l&apos;espace global de la ville.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sources de divergences :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les processus nationaux fournissent la grande majorit des donnes qui sont ensuite agrges dans la Base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges et la Base de donnes mondiale sur les zones cls pour la biodiversit, et il y a donc trs peu de diffrences entre les indicateurs nationaux et l&apos;indicateur mondial. Il y a donc trs peu de diffrences entre les indicateurs nationaux et l&apos;indicateur mondial. Une source mineure de diffrence est que la Base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges incorpore les aires protges dsignes au niveau international (par exemple, les sites du patrimoine mondial de l&apos;UNESCO, les sites Ramsar, etc), dont quelques-unes ne sont pas considres par leurs nations souveraines comme des aires protges. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notez que parce que les pays ne soumettent pas de donnes compltes sur les aires protges dclasses  la WDPA, les valeurs antrieures de l&apos;indicateur peuvent marginalement sous-estimer la couverture. En outre, il y a galement un dcalage entre le moment o une zone protge est dsigne sur le terrain et le moment o elle est signale  la WDPA. De ce fait, la couverture actuelle ou rcente peut galement tre sous-estime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Rfrences &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unep-wcmc.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.unep-wcmc.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.birdlife.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.birdlife.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iucn.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.iucn.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rfrences:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ces mtadonnes sont bases sur &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mdgs.un.org/unsd/mi/wiki/7-6-Proportion-of-terrestrial-and-marine-areas-protected.ashx&quot;&gt;http://mdgs.un.org/unsd/mi/wiki/7-6-Proportion-&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mdgs.un.org/unsd/mi/wiki/7-6-Proportion-of-terrestrial-and-marine-areas-protected.ashx&quot;&gt;of-terrestrial-and-marine-areas-protected.ashx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;complte par &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bipindicators.net/paoverlays&quot;&gt;http://www.bipindicators.net/paoverlays&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;et les rfrences numres ci-dessous. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BIRDLIFE INTERNATIONAL (2014). Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas: a global network for conserving nature and benefiting people. Cambridge, UK: BirdLife International. Disponible  &lt;a href=&quot;http://datazone.birdlife.org/sowb/sowbpubs#IBA.&quot;&gt;datazone.birdlife.org/sowb/sowbpubs#IBA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BIRDLIFE INTERNATIONAL (2019) &lt;em&gt;World Database of Key Biodiversity Areas.&lt;/em&gt;Developed by the KBA Partnership: BirdLife International, International Union for the Conservation of Nature, Amphibian Survival Alliance, Conservation International, Critical Ecosystem Partnership Fund, Global Environment Facility, Global Wildlife Conservation, NatureServe, Rainforest Trust, Royal Society for the Protection of Birds, Wildlife Conservation Society and World Wildlife Fund. September 2019 version. Disponible  http://keybiodiversity areas.org/site/search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BROOKS, T. et al. (2001). Conservation priorities for birds and biodiversity: do East African Important Bird Areas represent species diversity in other terrestrial vertebrate groups? Ostrich suppl. 15: 3-12. Disponible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sur:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.2989/00306520109485329%23.VafbVJPVq75&quot;&gt;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.2989/00306520109485329#.VafbVJPVq75&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BROOKS, T.M. et al. (2016) Goal 15: Life on land. Sustainable manage forests, combat desertification, halt and reverse land degradation, halt biodiversity loss. Pp. 497-522 in Dur&amp;#xE1;n y Lalaguna, P., D&amp;#xED;az Barrado, C.M. &amp;amp;Fern&amp;#xE1;ndez Liesa, C.R. (eds.) International Society and Sustainable Development Goals. Editorial Aranzadi, Cizur Menor, Spain. Disponible sur: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thomsonreuters.es/es/tienda/pdp/duo.html?pid=10008456&quot;&gt;https://www.thomsonreuters.es/es/tienda/pdp/duo.html?pid=10008456&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2010). Global biodiversity: indicators of recent declines. Science 328: 1164  1168. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/328/5982/1164.short&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/328/5982/1164.short&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2012). Protecting important sites for biodiversity contributes to meeting global conservation targets. PLoS One 7(3): e32529. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0032529&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0032529&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2015). Shortfalls and solutions for meeting national and global conservation area targets. Conservation Letters 8: 329-337. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12158/full&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12158/full&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBD (2014). Global Biodiversity Outlook 4. Convention on Biological Diversity, Montral, Canada. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/gbo4/&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/gbo4/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CHAPE, S. et al. (2005). Measuring the extent and effectiveness of protected areas as an indicator for meeting global biodiversity targets. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B 360: 443-445. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/360/1454/443.shor&quot;&gt;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/360/1454/443.shor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DEGUIGNET, M., et al. (2014). 2014 United Nations List of Protected Areas. UNEP-WCMC, Cambridge, UK. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://unep-wcmc.org/system/dataset_file_fields/files/000/000/263/original/2014_UN_List_of_Protected_Areas_EN_web.PDF?1415613322&quot;&gt;http://unep-wcmc.org/system/dataset_file_fields/files/000/000/263/original/2014_UN_List_of_Protected_Areas_EN_web.PDF?1415613322&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DI MARCO, M., et al. (2016). Quantifying the relative irreplaceability of Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas. Conservation Biology 30: 392-402. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/cobi.12609/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/cobi.12609/abstract&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DONALD, P. et al. (2018) Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas (IBAs): the development and characteristics of a global inventory of key sites for biodiversity. Bird Conserv. Internat. 29:177-198.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DUDLEY, N. (2008). Guidelines for Applying Protected Area Management Categories. International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN). Gland, Switzerland. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9243&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9243&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDGAR, G.J. et al. (2008). Key Biodiversity Areas as globally significant target sites for the conservation of marine biological diversity. Aquatic Conservation: Marine and Freshwater Ecosystems 18: 969 - 983. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/aqc.902/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/aqc.902/abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EKEN, G. et al. (2004). Key biodiversity areas as site conservation targets. BioScience 54: 1110&amp;#x2013;1118. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/54/12/1110.short&quot;&gt;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/54/12/1110.short&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOSTER, M.N. et al. (2012) The identification of sites of biodiversity conservation significance: progress with the application of a global standard. Journal of Threatened Taxa 4: 2733&amp;#x2013;2744. Disponible sur &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.threatenedtaxa.in/index.php/JoTT/article/view/779&quot;&gt;http://www.threatenedtaxa.in/index.php/JoTT/article/view/779&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global Administrative Areas (2019). GADM database of Global Administrative Areas, version 2.8. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gadm.org/home&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.gadm.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HAN, X. et al. (2014). A Biodiversity indicators dashboard: addressing challenges to monitoring progress towards the Aichi Biodiversity Targets using disaggregated global data. PLoS ONE 9(11): e112046. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0112046&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0112046&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOLLAND, R.A. et al. (2012). Conservation priorities for freshwater biodiversity: the key biodiversity area approach refined and tested for continental Africa. Biological Conservation 148: 167-179. Disponible sur &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320712000298&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320712000298&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IUCN (2016). A Global Standard for the Identification of Key Biodiversity Areas. International Union for Conservation of Nature, Gland, Switzerland. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JONAS, H.D. et al. (2014) New steps of change: looking beyond protected areas to consider other effective area-based conservation measures. Parks 20: 111&amp;#x2013;128. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://parksjournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/PARKS-20.2-Jonas-et-al-10.2305IUCN.CH_.2014.PARKS-20-2.HDJ_.en_.pdf&quot;&gt;http://parksjournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/PARKS-20.2-Jonas-et-al-10.2305IUCN.CH_.2014.PARKS-20-2.HDJ_.en_.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KNIGHT, A. T. et al. (2007). Improving the Key Biodiversity Areas approach for effective conservation planning. BioScience 57: 256&amp;#x2013;261. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/57/3/256.short&quot;&gt;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/57/3/256.short&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LANGHAMMER, P. F. et al. (2007). Identification and Gap Analysis of Key Biodiversity Areas: Targets for Comprehensive Protected Area Systems. IUCN World Commission on Protected Areas Best Practice Protected Area Guidelines Series No. 15. IUCN, Gland, Switzerland. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9055&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9055&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LEVERINGTON, F. et al. (2010). A global analysis of protected area management effectiveness. Environmental Management 46: 685&amp;#x2013;698. Disponible sur http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00267-010-9564-5#page-1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MONTESINO POUZOLS, F., et al. (2014) Global protected area expansion is compromised by projected land-use and parochialism. Nature 516: 383&amp;#x2013;386. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v516/n7531/abs/nature14032.html&quot;&gt;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v516/n7531/abs/nature14032.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOLTE, C.&amp;amp;AGRAWAL, A. (2013). Linking management effectiveness indicators to observed effects of protected areas on fire occurrence in the Amazon rainforest. Conservation Biology 27: 155&amp;#x2013;165. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2012.01930.x/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2012.01930.x/abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PAIN, D.J. et al. (2005) Biodiversity representation in Uganda&amp;#x2019;s forest IBAs. Biological Conservation 125: 133&amp;#x2013;138. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320705001412&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320705001412&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RICKETTS, T. H. et al. (2005). Pinpointing and preventing imminent extinctions. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the U.S.A. 102: 18497&amp;#x2013;18501. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/102/51/18497.short&quot;&gt;http://www.pnas.org/content/102/51/18497.short&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RODRIGUES, A. S. L. et al. (2004). Effectiveness of the global protected area network in representing species diversity. Nature 428: 640&amp;#x2013;643. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v428/n6983/abs/nature02422.html&quot;&gt;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v428/n6983/abs/nature02422.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RODR&amp;#xCD;GUEZ-RODR&amp;#xCD;GUEZ, D., et al. (2011). Progress towards international targets for protected area coverage in mountains: a multi-scale assessment. Biological Conservation 144: 2978&amp;#x2013;2983. Available from &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320711003454&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320711003454&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TITTENSOR, D. et al. (2014). A mid-term analysis of progress towards international biodiversity targets. Science 346: 241&amp;#x2013;244. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/346/6206/241.short&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/346/6206/241.short&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNEP-WCMC (2019). World Database on Protected Areas User Manual 1.6. UNEP-WCMC, Cambridge, UK. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://wcmc.io/WDPA_Manual&quot;&gt;http://wcmc.io/WDPA_Manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNEP-WCMC&amp;amp;IUCN (2020). The World Database on Protected Areas (WDPA). UNEP-WCMC, Cambridge, UK. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net&quot;&gt;http://www.protectedplanet.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt; 14:     ,      &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 14.5:  2020       10                    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 14.5.1:         &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  : 12  2020  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;   &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;  (): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     -       (UNEP-WCMC) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     (BLI) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     () &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;    &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                   (.. ,        ),     . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  ,        (IUCN; Dudley 2008),      , ,                      .  ,          ,  ,    : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; -  Ia:   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; -  Ib:    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; -  II:   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; -  III:      &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; -  IV:          &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; -  V:   /   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; -  VI:        &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &quot;&quot;   ,          (,     ..)      .         ,    ,  -  -   (, ). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ,         ,      ,   &lt;em&gt;         &lt;/em&gt; (, 2016 .),    .       : (a)     ,   ,       ,      ,         13000      (BirdLife International 2014, Donald &lt; em&gt; et al. &lt;/em&gt; 2018); (b)       (Ricketts et al. 2005),   ,          -  ,            ,    ,   853     1483  , , , ,  ,  ,  ,    ; (c)    ,             (Langhammer &lt;em&gt; et al. &lt;/em&gt; 2007),  ,       ,        .        ,                  (IUCN 2016).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;   &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;           ,        .      ,           ,      .    ,    ,                            (Deguignet et al. 2014).    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net/&quot;&gt;   &lt;/a&gt;,         -       (UNEP-WCMC)      (),           (UNEP-WCMC 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                ,      .         &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;   ,    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;Key Biodiversity Areas&lt;/a&gt;,       .  ,               &lt;a href=&quot;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&quot;&gt; http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&lt;/a&gt;,               &lt;a href=&quot;https://zeroextinction.org/&quot;&gt;https://zeroextinction.org&lt;/a&gt;         ,     ,   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;World Database on Key Biodiversity Areas&lt;/a&gt;,             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/login&quot;&gt;Integrated Biodiversity Assessment Tool for Research and Conservation Planning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;  : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; .    . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;  :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     -       (UNEP-WCMC)        5-10    ,    / .           -       (UNEP-WCMC)      /   ,        ,             .                 . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;  : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ,     ,      ,   . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;   &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;           ,        .                ,      .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;   &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      -      (UNEP-WCMC)      () &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                     -       (UNEP-WCMC)            (Deguignet et al. 2014).     &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net/&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;,    UNEP-WCMC  ,           (UNEP-WCMC 2016 ).         &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&lt;/a/&gt;        &lt;/a&gt;,       (2019).  ,               &lt;a href=&quot;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&quot;&gt;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&lt;/a&gt;               &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zeroextinction.org/search.cfm&quot;&gt;http://www.zeroextinction.org/search.cfm&lt;/a&gt;.               &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/login&quot;&gt;            &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                  .          ,          ,                .  , ,   ,             ,    -   . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;            .  ,    ,          .               .   ,        :      ;  ;      ;      ;   ,   ;         . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     ,             ,   ,                   100 (, Chape et al. 2005 .).                   (Rodrigues et al. 2004), ,  ,           ,   ,  ,   ,   . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                  20112020 . (CBD 2014, Tittensor et al., 2014),          2010      (Butchart et al. 2010). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;   : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                 .           -        (UNEP-WCMC)                .                   (UNEP-WCMC 2019)       .        &lt;em&gt;         &lt;/em&gt; (BirdLife International 2019). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;               ,            ,   .          .  ,         ,      (Leverington et al. 2010).                11   ,         &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bipindicators.net/pamanagement&quot;&gt;http://www.bipindicators.net/pamanagement&lt;/a&gt;).                 (Nolte &amp; amp; Agrawal 2013).        ,    ,         ,  , ,             .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;       -    ,       ,        .  ,    ,    , ,      11                2011-2013 ., ,         ,         ,   ,    ,     ,      (Jonas et al. 2014).   ,    OECM -  &quot;     ,    &quot; (  ,    ,      ,            ,      ,  ,   , , , -        ;)      2018 ,         UNEP-WCMC   .    OECM       -        (UNEP-WCMC)    ,          ,     (WD-OECM). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    ,      ,             , ,  (      )  ,     (      ).                    (Brooks et al. 2001, Pain et al. 2005),         (IUCN 2016)     (, , )       ,        (Eken et al. 2004, Knight et al. 2007, Langhammer et al. 2007, Foster et al. 2012).      &amp;lt; 50% ,       ,    ,            ,     . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;            ,          ( )       (Di Marco et al., 2016, Montesino Pouzols et al.2014).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     : a)                ( 2016)     , ,    ; )                    ,    (  ).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;  &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;  : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      ,                   (     -        (UNEP-WCMC &amp;amp; IUCN 2020)          (        ,      ,            ).                       (    adm0       (GADM 2019)),            ,    5%     (,      ,   ).      ,   ,      ,        ,           ,    ,     . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;       ~ 12%         ,            .    ,             ,       1000    . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  2017          ,    .             ,   ,                          .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;   : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;  :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;             &amp;#x2019;  ,          . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;    :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      ,    ,           ,   .     , ,      ,     ,         .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;  : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      -       (UNEP-WCMC)  ,            ,         (BLI)      ()          ,    . UNEP-WCMC           ,                  .                 -       (UNEP-WCMC)      (),          .           ,       ,    , , ,  ,   ()  /   ().           ,        ,     ,          ,         .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;           : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;       (WDPA)       1959 ,         713 (XXVIII)        .     : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&quot;&gt; https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&lt;/a&gt;.        1961/62, 1966/71, 1972  (   1966/71), 1973, 1974, 1975, 1980, 1982, 1985, 1990, 1993, 1997, 2003, 2014   2018 .,                  (WDPA). ,  2014          (CBD)                (PoWPA)         2014  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas-2014&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas-2014&lt;/a&gt;).  ,         ,          .       (MetadataID),        ,     .             WDPA      .  ,    ,       WDPA      WDPA (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&lt;/a&gt;)    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net&quot;&gt; www.protectedplanet.net &lt;/a&gt;              . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     ,          (   ),    (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;).  , (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/what-are-kbas&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/what-are-kbas&lt;/a&gt;)       -   ,    -  .   ,    ,    ,       ,              ( ,    ).             ,    ,     120             (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.birdlife.org/worldwide/partnership/birdlife-partners&quot;&gt;http://www.birdlife.org/worldwide/partnership/birdlife -partners&lt;/a&gt;), 93          (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zeroextinction.org/partners.html&quot;&gt;http://www.zeroextinction.org /partners.html&lt;/a&gt;),                     ,        (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cepf.net/resources/publications/Pages/ecosystem_profiles.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.cepf.net/resources/publications/Pages/ecosystem_profiles.aspx&lt;/a&gt;),      ,    .        .          ,         . ,            ,    -     (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;         (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&lt;/a&gt;)   ,    ,       ,             ,       ,        .                    : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/calculating-protected-area-coverage&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/calculating-protected-area-coverage&lt;/a&gt;.        (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&lt;/a&gt;)   ,        ,    ,   -    (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;).   (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&lt;/a&gt;),        : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;       
    ; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;   ,      
       ,  ,         ,          ,  ; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;       
-        ;  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;   ,     
       (.  3.3 ). &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;               .  ,   ,   ,         ,    ,       . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;  : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  ,                : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual,&lt;/a&gt;    ,    .      &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on -protected-area,&lt;/a&gt; ,             :&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-lookup-tables&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-lookup-table, &lt;/a&gt;         ,        ,            .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;              (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/kba-partners&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/kba-partners.&lt;/a&gt;)    -       ,   ,     ,          (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&lt;/a&gt;),          ,       -    . (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&lt;/a&gt;).  ,                (      ,       ),            ,            .  R            Dias, M. (2017)  R         .(&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/userfiles/files/R_code_for_calculating_protected_area_coverage_of_KBAs_March_2017.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/userfiles/files/Files/R_code_for_calculating_procted_procted_archive_archive_archive_index)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    -   (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/&lt;/a&gt;),       . 3.1  ,         ,           ,   -     (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;),         ,        ,        (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/&quot;&gt;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/&lt;/a&gt;).         ,             .                (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/information/nfp.shtml&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/information/nfp.shtml&lt;/a&gt;),            ().&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;   &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;          -     1.       ,    . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;  : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ~ 150  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ,         ,         (, Han et al., 2014) , ,    .        ,    (Edgar et al. 2008)   .  ,         ,       ,    .          ,    ,       . ,           ( I &amp;#x2013; VI),        . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                    14.5,      ,           (Brooks et al., 2016), : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  15.1.2            ,   ,     . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  15.4.1         . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                  . ,                    .        (, , )            .                     (Butchart et al. 2012). , ,       ,        ; ,                . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;  : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      ,           ,           ,           .      ,          ,     (,    ,    . .),           . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; , ,                   ,        .  ,    ,        ,  ,           .  ,        . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;  &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unep-wcmc.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.unep-wcmc.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.birdlife.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.birdlife.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iucn.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.iucn.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    &lt;a href=&quot;http://mdgs.un.org/unsd/mi/wiki/7-6-Proportion-of-terrestrial-and-marine-areas-protected.ashx&quot;&gt;http://mdgs.un.org/unsd/mi/wiki/7-6-Proportion-of-terrestrial-and-marine-areas-protected.ashx&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bipindicators.net/paoverlays&quot;&gt;http://www.bipindicators.net/paoverlays&lt;/a&gt;   ,  .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BIRDLIFE INTERNATIONAL (2014). Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas: a global network for conserving nature and benefiting people. Cambridge, UK: BirdLife International.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://datazone.birdlife.org/sowb/sowbpubs#IBA.&quot;&gt;datazone.birdlife.org/sowb/sowbpubs#IBA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BIRDLIFE INTERNATIONAL (2019) &lt;em&gt;World Database of Key Biodiversity Areas.&lt;/em&gt;Developed by the KBA Partnership: BirdLife International, International Union for the Conservation of Nature, Amphibian Survival Alliance, Conservation International, Critical Ecosystem Partnership Fund, Global Environment Facility, Global Wildlife Conservation, NatureServe, Rainforest Trust, Royal Society for the Protection of Birds, Wildlife Conservation Society and World Wildlife Fund. September 2019 version.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://keybiodiversity areas.org/site/search&quot;&gt;http://keybiodiversity areas.org/site/search&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BROOKS, T. et al. (2001). Conservation priorities for birds and biodiversity: do East African Important Bird Areas represent species diversity in other terrestrial vertebrate groups? Ostrich suppl. 15: 3-12.  : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.2989/00306520109485329%23.VafbVJPVq75&quot;&gt;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.2989/00306520109485329#.VafbVJPVq75&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BROOKS, T.M. et al. (2016) Goal 15: Life on land. Sustainable manage forests, combat desertification, halt and reverse land degradation, halt biodiversity loss. Pp. 497-522 in Duran y Lalaguna, P., Diaz Barrado, C.M. &amp;Fernandez Liesa, C.R. (eds.) International Society and Sustainable Development Goals. Editorial Aranzadi, Cizur Menor, Spain.  : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thomsonreuters.es/es/tienda/pdp/duo.html?pid=10008456&quot;&gt;https://www.thomsonreuters.es/es/tienda/pdp/duo.html?pid=10008456&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2010). Global biodiversity: indicators of recent declines. Science 328: 1164&amp;#x2013;1168.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/328/5982/1164.short&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/328/5982/1164.short&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2012). Protecting important sites for biodiversity contributes to meeting global conservation targets. PLoS One 7(3): e32529.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0032529&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0032529&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2015). Shortfalls and solutions for meeting national and global conservation area targets. Conservation Letters 8: 329&amp;#x2013;337.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12158/full&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12158/full&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBD (2014). Global Biodiversity Outlook 4. Convention on Biological Diversity, Montr&amp;#xE9;al, Canada.   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/gbo4/&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/gbo4/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CHAPE, S. et al. (2005). Measuring the extent and effectiveness of protected areas as an indicator for meeting global biodiversity targets. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B 360: 443&amp;#x2013;445.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/360/1454/443.shor&quot;&gt;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/360/1454/443.shor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DEGUIGNET, M., et al. (2014). 2014 United Nations List of Protected Areas. UNEP-WCMC, Cambridge, UK.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://unep-wcmc.org/system/dataset_file_fields/files/000/000/263/original/2014_UN_List_of_Protected_Areas_EN_web.PDF?1415613322&quot;&gt;http://unep-wcmc.org/system/dataset_file_fields/files/000/000/263/original/2014_UN_List_of_Protected_Areas_EN_web.PDF?1415613322&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DI MARCO, M., et al. (2016). Quantifying the relative irreplaceability of Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas. Conservation Biology 30: 392&amp;#x2013;402.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/cobi.12609/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/cobi.12609/abstract&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DONALD, P. et al. (2018) Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas (IBAs): the development and characteristics of a global inventory of key sites for biodiversity. Bird Conserv. Internat. 29:177&amp;#x2013;198.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DUDLEY, N. (2008). Guidelines for Applying Protected Area Management Categories. International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN). Gland, Switzerland.   &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9243&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9243&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDGAR, G.J. et al. (2008). Key Biodiversity Areas as globally significant target sites for the conservation of marine biological diversity. Aquatic Conservation: Marine and Freshwater Ecosystems 18: 969&amp;#x2013;983.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/aqc.902/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/aqc.902/abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EKEN, G. et al. (2004). Key biodiversity areas as site conservation targets. BioScience 54: 1110&amp;#x2013;1118.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/54/12/1110.short&quot;&gt;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/54/12/1110.short&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOSTER, M.N. et al. (2012) The identification of sites of biodiversity conservation significance: progress with the application of a global standard. Journal of Threatened Taxa 4: 2733&amp;#x2013;2744.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.threatenedtaxa.in/index.php/JoTT/article/view/779&quot;&gt;http://www.threatenedtaxa.in/index.php/JoTT/article/view/779&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global Administrative Areas (2019). GADM database of Global Administrative Areas, version 2.8.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gadm.org/home&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.gadm.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HAN, X. et al. (2014). A Biodiversity indicators dashboard: addressing challenges to monitoring progress towards the Aichi Biodiversity Targets using disaggregated global data. PLoS ONE 9(11): e112046.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0112046&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0112046&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOLLAND, R.A. et al. (2012). Conservation priorities for freshwater biodiversity: the key biodiversity area approach refined and tested for continental Africa. Biological Conservation 148: 167&amp;#x2013;   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320712000298&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320712000298&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320712000298&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320712000298&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IUCN (2016). A Global Standard for the Identification of Key Biodiversity Areas. International Union for Conservation of Nature, Gland, Switzerland.   &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JONAS, H.D. et al. (2014) New steps of change: looking beyond protected areas to consider other effective area-based conservation measures. Parks 20: 111&amp;#x2013;128.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://parksjournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/PARKS-20.2-Jonas-et-al-10.2305IUCN.CH_.2014.PARKS-20-2.HDJ_.en_.pdf&quot;&gt;http://parksjournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/PARKS-20.2-Jonas-et-al-10.2305IUCN.CH_.2014.PARKS-20-2.HDJ_.en_.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KNIGHT, A. T. et al. (2007). Improving the Key Biodiversity Areas approach for effective conservation planning. BioScience 57: 256&amp;#x2013;261.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/57/3/256.short&quot;&gt;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/57/3/256.short&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LANGHAMMER, P. F. et al. (2007). Identification and Gap Analysis of Key Biodiversity Areas: Targets for Comprehensive Protected Area Systems. IUCN World Commission on Protected Areas Best Practice Protected Area Guidelines Series No. 15. IUCN, Gland, Switzerland.   &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9055&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9055&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LEVERINGTON, F. et al. (2010). A global analysis of protected area management effectiveness. Environmental Management 46: 685&amp;#x2013;698.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00267-010-9564-5#page-1&quot;&gt;http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00267-010-9564-5#page-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MONTESINO POUZOLS, F., et al. (2014) Global protected area expansion is compromised by projected land-use and parochialism. Nature 516: 383&amp;#x2013;386.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v516/n7531/abs/nature14032.html&quot;&gt;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v516/n7531/abs/nature14032.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOLTE, C. &amp;amp; AGRAWAL, A. (2013). Linking management effectiveness indicators to observed effects of protected areas on fire occurrence in the Amazon rainforest. Conservation Biology 27: 155&amp;#x2013;165.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2012.01930.x/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2012.01930.x/abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PAIN, D.J. et al. (2005) Biodiversity representation in Uganda&amp;#x2019;s forest IBAs. Biological Conservation 125: 133&amp;#x2013;138.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320705001412&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320705001412&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RICKETTS, T. H. et al. (2005). Pinpointing and preventing imminent extinctions. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the U.S.A. 102: 18497&amp;#x2013;18501.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/102/51/18497.short&quot;&gt;http://www.pnas.org/content/102/51/18497.short&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RODRIGUES, A. S. L. et al. (2004). Effectiveness of the global protected area network in representing species diversity. Nature 428: 640&amp;#x2013;643.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v428/n6983/abs/nature02422.html&quot;&gt;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v428/n6983/abs/nature02422.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RODR&amp;#xCD;GUEZ-RODR&amp;#xCD;GUEZ, D., et al. (2011). Progress towards international targets for protected area coverage in mountains: a multi-scale assessment. Biological Conservation 144: 2978&amp;#x2013;2983.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320711003454&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320711003454&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TITTENSOR, D. et al. (2014). A mid-term analysis of progress towards international biodiversity targets. Science 346: 241&amp;#x2013;244.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/346/6206/241.short&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/346/6206/241.short&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNEP-WCMC (2019). World Database on Protected Areas User Manual 1.6. UNEP-WCMC, Cambridge, UK. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://wcmc.io/WDPA_Manual&quot;&gt;http://wcmc.io/WDPA_Manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNEP-WCMC &amp;amp; IUCN (2020). The World Database on Protected Areas (WDPA). UNEP-WCMC, Cambridge, UK.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net&quot;&gt;http://www.protectedplanet.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
