<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 15-1-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 15: Protect, restore and promote sustainable use of terrestrial ecosystems, sustainably manage forests, combat desertification, and halt and reverse land degradation and halt biodiversity loss&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 15.1: By 2020, ensure the conservation, restoration and sustainable use of terrestrial and inland freshwater ecosystems and their services, in particular forests, wetlands, mountains and drylands, in line with obligations under international agreements&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 15.1.2: Proportion of important sites for terrestrial and freshwater biodiversity that are covered by protected areas, by ecosystem type&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last updated: 12 February 2020&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Institutional information &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization(s):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UN Environment World Conservation Monitoring Centre (UNEP-WCMC)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BirdLife International (BLI)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator Proportion of important sites for terrestrial and freshwater biodiversity that are covered by protected areas shows temporal trends in the mean percentage of each important site for terrestrial and freshwater biodiversity (i.e., those that contribute significantly to the global persistence of biodiversity) that is covered by designated protected areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protected areas, as defined by the International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN; Dudley 2008), are clearly defined geographical spaces, recognized, dedicated and managed, through legal or other effective means, to achieve the long-term conservation of nature with associated ecosystem services and cultural values. Importantly, a variety of specific management objectives are recognised within this definition, spanning conservation, restoration, and sustainable use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Category Ia: Strict nature reserve&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Category Ib: Wilderness area&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Category II: National park&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Category III: Natural monument or feature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Category IV: Habitat/species management area&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Category V: Protected landscape/seascape&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Category VI: Protected area with sustainable use of natural resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The status &amp;quot;designated&amp;quot; is attributed to a protected area when the corresponding authority, according to national legislation or common practice (e.g., by means of an executive decree or the like), officially endorses a document of designation. The designation must be made for the purpose of biodiversity conservation, not de facto protection arising because of some other activity (e.g., military).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sites contributing significantly to the global persistence of biodiversity are identified following globally criteria set out in &lt;em&gt;A Global Standard for the Identification of Key Biodiversity Areas &lt;/em&gt;(IUCN 2016) applied at national levels. Key Biodiversity Areas encompass (a) Important Bird &amp;amp; Biodiversity Areas, that is, sites contributing significantly to the global persistence of biodiversity, identified using data on birds, of which &amp;gt;13,000 sites in total have been identified from all of the world&amp;#x2019;s countries (BirdLife International 2014, Donald &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; 2018); (b) Alliance for Zero Extinction sites (Ricketts et al. 2005), that is, sites holding effectively the entire population of at least one species assessed as Critically Endangered or Endangered on The IUCN Red List of Threatened Species, of which 853 sites have been identified for 1,483 species of mammals, birds, amphibians, reptiles, freshwater crustaceans, reef-building corals, conifers, cycads and other taxa; (c) Key Biodiversity Areas identified under an earlier version of the Key Biodiversity Area criteria (Langhammer &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; 2007), including those identified in Ecosystem Hotspot Profiles developed with support of the Critical Ecosystem Partnership Fund. These three subsets are being reassessed using the Global Standard, which unifies these approaches along with other mechanisms for identification of important sites for other species and ecosystems (IUCN 2016).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protected area data are compiled by ministries of environment and other ministries responsible for the designation and maintenance of protected areas. Protected Areas data for sites designated under the Ramsar Convention and the UNESCO World Heritage Convention are collected through the relevant convention international secretariats. Protected area data are aggregated globally into the World Database on Protected Areas by the UN Environment World Conservation Monitoring Centre, according to the mandate for production of the United Nations List of Protected Areas (Deguignet et al. 2014). They are disseminated through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net/&quot;&gt;Protected Planet&lt;/a&gt;, which is jointly managed by UNEP-WCMC and IUCN and its World Commission on Protected Areas (Juffe-Bignoli et al. 2014).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Biodiversity Areas are identified at national scales through multi-stakeholder processes, following standard criteria and thresholds. Key Biodiversity Areas data are aggregated into the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;World Database on Key Biodiversity Areas&lt;/a&gt;, managed by BirdLife International. Specifically, data on Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas are available online at &lt;a href=&quot;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&quot;&gt;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&lt;/a&gt; and data on Alliance for Zero Extinction sites are available online at https://zeroextinction.org. Both datasets, along with Key Biodiversity Areas identified through other processes, are available through the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;World Database on Key Biodiversity Areas&lt;/a&gt;, and, along with the World Database on Protected Areas, are also disseminated through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/login&quot;&gt;Integrated Biodiversity Assessment Tool for Research and Conservation Planning&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collection process:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See information under other sections.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendar&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data collection:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNEP-WCMC produces the UN List of Protected Areas every 5&amp;#x2013;10 years, based on information provided by national ministries/agencies. In the intervening period between compilations of UN Lists, UNEP-WCMC works closely with national ministries/agencies and NGOs responsible for the designation and maintenance of protected areas, continually updating the WDPA as new data become available. The World Database of Key Biodiversity Areas is also updated on an ongoing basis, as new national data are submitted. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data release:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator of protected area coverage of important sites for biodiversity is anticipated to be released annually.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data providers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protected area data are compiled by ministries of environment and other ministries responsible for the designation and maintenance of protected areas. Key Biodiversity Areas are identified at national scales through multi-stakeholder processes, following standard criteria and thresholds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data compilers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNEP-WCMC and IUCN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protected area data are aggregated globally into the World Database on Protected Areas by the UN Environment World Conservation Monitoring Centre, according to the mandate for production of the United Nations List of Protected Areas (Deguignet et al. 2014). They are disseminated through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net/&quot;&gt;Protected Planet&lt;/a&gt;, which is jointly managed by UNEP-WCMC and IUCN and its World Commission on Protected Areas (UNEP-WCMC 2016). Key Biodiversity Areas data are aggregated into the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;World Database on Key Biodiversity Areas&lt;/a&gt;, managed by BirdLife International (2019). Specifically, data on Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas are available online at &lt;a href=&quot;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&quot;&gt;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&lt;/a&gt; and data on Alliance for Zero Extinction sites are available online at https://zeroextinction.org. Both datasets, along with the World Database on Protected Areas, are also disseminated through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/login&quot;&gt;Integrated Biodiversity Assessment Tool for Research and Conservation Planning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The safeguard of important sites is vital for stemming the decline in biodiversity and ensuring long term and sustainable use of terrestrial and freshwater natural resources. The establishment of protected areas is an important mechanism for achieving this aim, and this indicator serves as a means of measuring progress toward the conservation, restoration and sustainable use of terrestrial and freshwater ecosystems and their services, in particular forests, wetlands, mountains and drylands, in line with obligations under international agreements. Importantly, while it can be disaggregated to report on any given single ecosystem of interest (e.g., forests), it is not restricted to any single ecosystem type, and so faithfully reflects the intent of SDG target 15.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Levels of access to protected areas vary among the protected area management categories. Some areas, such as scientific reserves, are maintained in their natural state and closed to any other use. Others are used for recreation or tourism, or even open for the sustainable extraction of natural resources. In addition to protecting biodiversity, protected areas have high social and economic value: supporting local livelihoods; protecting watersheds from erosion; harbouring an untold wealth of genetic resources; supporting thriving recreation and tourism industries; providing for science, research and education; and forming a basis for cultural and other non-material values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator adds meaningful information to, complements and builds from traditionally reported simple statistics of terrestrial and freshwater area covered by protected areas, computed by dividing the total protected area within a country by the total territorial area of the country and multiplying by 100 (e.g., Chape et al. 2005). Such percentage area coverage statistics do not recognise the extreme variation of biodiversity importance over space (Rodrigues et al. 2004), and so risk generating perverse outcomes through the protection of areas which are large at the expense of those which require protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is used to track progress towards the 2011&amp;#x2013;2020 Strategic Plan for Biodiversity (CBD 2014, Tittensor et al. 2014), and was used as an indicator towards the Convention on Biological Diversity&amp;#x2019;s 2010 Target (Butchart et al. 2010).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments and limitations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quality control criteria are applied to ensure consistency and comparability of the data in the World Database on Protected Areas. New data are validated at UNEP-WCMC through a number of tools and translated into the standard data structure of the World Database on Protected Areas. Discrepancies between the data in the World Database on Protected Areas and new data are minimised by provision of a manual (UNEP-WCMC 2019) and resolved in communication with data providers. Similar processes apply for the incorporation of data into the &lt;em&gt;World Database of Key Biodiversity Areas&lt;/em&gt; (BirdLife International 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator does not measure the effectiveness of protected areas in reducing biodiversity loss, which ultimately depends on a range of management and enforcement factors not covered by the indicator. A number of initiatives are underway to address this limitation. Most notably, numerous mechanisms have been developed for assessment of protected area management, which can be synthesised into an indicator (Leverington et al. 2010). This is used by the Biodiversity Indicators Partnership as a complementary indicator of progress towards Aichi Biodiversity Target 11 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bipindicators.net/pamanagement&quot;&gt;http://www.bipindicators.net/pamanagement&lt;/a&gt;). However, there may be little relationship between these measures and protected area outcomes (Nolte &amp;amp; Agrawal 2013). More recently, approaches to &amp;#x201C;green listing&amp;#x201D; have started to be developed, to incorporate both management effectiveness and the outcomes of protected areas, and these are likely to become progressively important as they are tested and applied more broadly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data and knowledge gaps can arise due to difficulties in determining whether a site conforms to the IUCN definition of a protected area, and some protected areas are not assigned management categories. Moreover, &amp;#x201C;other effective area-based conservation measures&amp;#x201D;, as specified by Aichi Biodiversity Target &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11 of the Strategic Plan for Biodiversity 2011&amp;#x2013;2020, recognise that some sites beyond the formal protected area network, while not managed primarily for nature conservation, may nevertheless be managed in ways which are consistent with the persistence of the biodiversity for which they are important (Jonas et al. 2014). However, the formally agreed definition of an OECM (&amp;#x201C;A geographically defined area other than a Protected Area, which is governed and managed in ways that achieve positive and sustained long-term outcomes for the in situ conservation of biodiversity, with associated ecosystem functions and services and, where applicable, cultural, spiritual, socioeconomic, and other locally relevant values&amp;#x201D;) were only agreed in November 2018 and measures are only recently in place for countries to submit OECM data to UNEP-WCMC. OECMs are now collated by UNEP-WCMC in a separate database, the WD-OECM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding important sites, the biggest limitation is that site identification to date has focused mainly on specific subsets of biodiversity, for example birds (for Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas) and highly threatened species (for Alliance for Zero Extinction sites). While Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas have been documented to be good surrogates for biodiversity more generally (Brooks et al. 2001, Pain et al. 2005), the application of the unified standard for identification of Key Biodiversity Areas (IUCN 2016) sites across different levels of biodiversity (genes, species, ecosystems) and different taxonomic groups remains a high priority, building from efforts to date (Eken et al. 2004, Knight et al. 2007, Langhammer et al. 2007, Foster et al. 2012). Birds now comprise &amp;lt;50% of the species for which Key Biodiversity Areas have been identified, and as Key Biodiversity Area identification for other taxa and elements of biodiversity proceeds, such bias will become a less important consideration in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Biodiversity Area identification has been validated for a number of countries and regions where comprehensive biodiversity data allow formal calculation of the site importance (or &amp;#x201C;irreplaceability&amp;#x201D;) using systematic conservation planning techniques (Di Marco et al. 2016, Montesino Pouzols et al. 2014).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Future developments of the indicator will include: a) expansion of the taxonomic coverage of terrestrial and freshwater Key Biodiversity Areas through application of the Key Biodiversity Areas standard (IUCN 2016) to a wide variety of terrestrial and freshwater vertebrates, invertebrates, plants and ecosystem type; b) improvements in the data on protected areas by continuing to increase the proportion of sites with documented dates of designation and with digitised boundary polygons (rather than coordinates).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Computation method:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator is calculated from data derived from a spatial overlap between digital polygons for protected areas from the World Database on Protected Areas (UNEP-WCMC &amp;amp; IUCN 2020) and digital polygons for terrestrial and freshwater Key Biodiversity Areas (from the World Database of Key &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biodiversity Areas, including Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas, Alliance for Zero Extinction sites, and other Key Biodiversity Areas). Sites were classified as terrestrial Key Biodiversity Areas by undertaking a spatial overlap between the Key Biodiversity Area polygons and an ocean raster layer (produced from the &amp;#x2018;adm0&amp;#x2019; layer from the database of Global Administrative Areas (GADM 2019)), classifying any Key Biodiversity Area as a terrestrial Key Biodiversity Area where it had &amp;#x2264;95% overlap with the ocean layer (hence some sites were classified as both terrestrial and marine). Sites were classified as freshwater Key Biodiversity Areas if the resident species for which they were identified were documented in the IUCN Red List as dependent on &amp;#x2018;Inland Water&amp;#x2019; systems. For non-resident or migrant species, or species that shift habitats during the annual cycle, the site was tagged as freshwater if the species occurred at the site in the appropriate season of water-dependence (e.g. some species are only dependent on water during the breeding season). Sites were then screened (using the satellite imagery base layer within ArcGIS) as to whether they lay wholly in the Coastal Zone (defined here as within 10 km of the coast), and these sites were then untagged as Freshwater and instead tagged as Marine if the wetland habitats present at the site fell purely within the IUCN Habitat Classification Scheme class &amp;#x2018;Marine Supratidal&amp;#x2019; (i.e. estuaries, lagoons, etc.). If the site was within the Coastal Zone, but contained a mixture of Marine Supratidal and Inland Water classes, then it was tagged as both Freshwater and Marine. Each site was then manually cross-checked against other (less comprehensively available) site attributes, such as the habitat preferences of its trigger species, the site&amp;#x2019;s name (Delta, River, Humedal, etc.), its areal coverage by different habitat types, its overlap with Ramsar Sites, and its &amp;#x2018;shadow&amp;#x2019; Ramsar status, so as to confirm or remove the Freshwater tag appropriately. The value of the indicator at a given point in time, based on data on the year of protected area establishment recorded in the World Database on Protected Areas, is computed as the mean percentage of each Key Biodiversity Area currently recognised that it covered by protected areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Year of protected area establishment is unknown for ~12% of protected areas in the World Database on Protected Areas, generating uncertainty around changing protected area coverage over time. To reflect this uncertainty, a year was randomly assigned from another protected area within the same country, and then this procedure repeated 1,000 times, with the median plotted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to 2017, the indicator was presented as the percentage of Key Biodiversity Areas completely covered by protected areas. However, it is now presented as the mean % of each Key Biodiversity Area that is covered by protected areas in order to better reflect trends in protected area coverage for countries or regions with few or no Key Biodiversity Areas that are completely covered. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treatment of missing values:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At country level:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are available for protected areas and Key Biodiversity Areas in all of the world&amp;#x2019;s countries, and so no imputation or estimation of national level data is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At regional and global levels:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global indicators of protected area coverage of important sites for biodiversity are calculated as the mean percentage of each Key Biodiversity Area that is covered by protected areas. The data are generated from all countries, and so while there is uncertainty around the data, there are no missing values as such and so no need for imputation or estimation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regional aggregates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNEP-WCMC is the agency in charge of calculating and reporting global and regional figures for this indicator, working with BirdLife International and IUCN to combine data on protected areas with those for sites of importance for biodiversity. UNEP-WCMC aggregates the global and regional figures on protected areas from the national figures that are calculated from the World Database on Protected Areas and disseminated through Protected Planet. The World Database on Protected Areas and Protected Planet are jointly managed by UNEP-WCMC and IUCN and its World Commission on Protected Areas. The World Database on Protected Areas is held within a Geographic Information System that stores information about protected areas such as their name, size, type, date of establishment, geographic location (point) and/or boundary (polygon). Protected area coverage is calculated using all the protected areas recorded in World Database on Protected Areas whose location and extent is known apart from protected areas without digital boundaries and those sites who have a status of &amp;#x2018;proposed&amp;#x2019; or &amp;#x2018;not reported&amp;#x2019;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods and guidance available to countries for the compilation of the data at the national level:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WDPA has its origins in a 1959 UN mandate when the United Nations Economic and Social Council called for a list of national parks and equivalent reserves Resolution 713 (XXVIII). More details are available here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&lt;/a&gt;. The UN List of Protected Areas has been published in 1961/62, 1966/71, 1972 (addendum to the 1966/71 edition), 1973, 1974, 1975, 1980, 1982, 1985, 1990, 1993, 1997, 2003, 2014 and 2018 which have resulted in a global network of national data providers for the WDPA. For example, in 2014 all Convention on Biological Diversity (CBD) National Focal points and all National Focal points for the CBD Protected Areas Programme of Work (PoWPA) to request data for the 2014 Un List of Protected Areas (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas-2014&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas-2014&lt;/a&gt;). Protected areas data is therefore compiled directly from government agencies, regional hubs and other authoritative sources in the absence of a government source. All records have a unique metadata identifier (MetadataID) which links the spatial database to the Source table where all sources are described. The data is collated and standardised following the WDPA Data Standards and validated with the source. The process of collation, validation and publication of data as well as protocols and the WDPA data standards are regularly updated in the WDPA User Manual (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&lt;/a&gt;) made available through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net&quot;&gt;www.protectedplanet.net&lt;/a&gt; where all spatial data and the Source table are also published every month and can be downloaded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process for compilation of data on sites contributing significantly to the global persistence of biodiversity (Key Biodiversity Areas) is documented online (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;). Specifically, (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/what-are-kbas&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/what-are-kbas&lt;/a&gt;), the Key Biodiversity Area identification process is a highly inclusive, consultative and bottom-up exercise. Although anyone with appropriate scientific data may propose a site to qualify as a Key Biodiversity Area, wide consultation with stakeholders at the national level (both non-governmental and governmental organizations) is required during the proposal process. Key Biodiversity Area identification builds off the existing network of Key Biodiversity Areas, including those identified as Important Bird &amp;amp; Biodiversity Areas through the BirdLife Partnership of 120 national organisations (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.birdlife.org/worldwide/partnership/birdlife-partners&quot;&gt;http://www.birdlife.org/worldwide/partnership/birdlife-partners&lt;/a&gt;), for the Alliance for Zero Extinction by 93 national and international organisations (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zeroextinction.org/partners.html&quot;&gt;http://www.zeroextinction.org/partners.html&lt;/a&gt;), and as other Key Biodiversity Areas by civil society organisations supported by the Critical Ecosystem Partnership Fund in developing ecosystem profiles, named in each of the profiles listed here (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cepf.net/resources/publications/Pages/ecosystem_profiles.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.cepf.net/resources/publications/Pages/ecosystem_profiles.aspx&lt;/a&gt;), with new data strengthening and expanding expand the network of these sites. Any site proposal undergoes independent scientific review. This is followed by the official site nomination with full documentation meeting the Documentation Standards for Key Biodiversity Areas. Sites confirmed by the Key Biodiversity Areas Secretariat to qualify as Key Biodiversity Areas then appear on the Key Biodiversity Areas website (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WDPA User Manual (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&lt;/a&gt;) published in English, Spanish, and French provides guidance to countries on how to submit protected areas data to the WDPA, what are the benefits of providing such data, which are the data standards and which quality checks are performed. We also provide a summary of our methods to calculate protected areas coverage to all WDPA users: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/calculating-protected-area-coverage&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/calculating-protected-area-coverage&lt;/a&gt;. The &amp;#x201C;Global Standard for the Identification of Key Biodiversity Areas&amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&lt;/a&gt;) comprises the standard recommendations available to countries in the identification of Key Biodiversity Areas, with further guidelines available on the Key Biodiversity Areas website (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;). Specifically, (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&lt;/a&gt;), the main steps of the Key Biodiversity Area identification process are the following: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;submission of Expressions of Intent to identify a Key Biodiversity Area to Regional Focal Points; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;proposal Development process, in which proposers compile relevant data and documentation and consult national experts, including organizations that have already identified Key Biodiversity Areas in the country, either through national Key Biodiversity Area Coordination Groups or independently; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;review of proposed Key Biodiversity Areas by Independent Expert Reviewers, verifying the accuracy of information within their area of expertise; and &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a Site Nomination phase comprising the submission of all the relevant documentation for verification by the Key Biodiversity Areas Secretariat (see section 3.3 below). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a Key Biodiversity Area is identified, monitoring of its qualifying features and its conservation status is important. Proposers, reviewers and those undertaking monitoring can join the Key Biodiversity Areas Community to exchange their experiences, case studies and best practice examples.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quality assurance:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process on how the data is collected, standardised and published is available in the WDPA User Manual at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&lt;/a&gt; which is available in English, French and Spanish. Specific guidance is provided at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&lt;/a&gt; on, for example, predefined fields or look up tables in the WDPA: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-lookup-tables&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-lookup-tables&lt;/a&gt;, how WDPA records are coded how international designations and regional designations data is collected, how regularly is the database updated, and how to perform protected areas coverage statistics. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of identification of Key Biodiversity Areas is supported by the Key Biodiversity Areas Partnership (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/kba-partners&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/kba-partners&lt;/a&gt;). Among the roles of the partnership is establishment of the Key Biodiversity Areas Secretariat, which checks information submitted in the Site Nomination phase for the correct application of the Key Biodiversity Areas Standard ((&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&lt;/a&gt;), and the adequacy of site documentation and then verifies the site, which is then published on the Key Biodiversity Areas Website (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&lt;/a&gt;). In addition, the Chairs of the IUCN Species Survival Commission and World Commission on Protected Areas (both of whom are elected by the IUCN Membership of governments and non-governmental organisations), appoint the Chair of an independent Key Biodiversity Areas Standards and Appeals Committee, which ensures the correct application of the Global Standard for the identification of Key Biodiversity Areas. The R code for calculating protected area coverage of Key Biodiversity Areas is documented as Dias, M. (2017) &amp;#x201C;R code for calculating protected area coverage of KBAs&amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/userfiles/files/R_code_for_calculating_protected_area_coverage_of_KBAs_March_2017.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/userfiles/files/R_code_for_calculating_protected_area_coverage_of_KBAs_March_2017.pdf&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to dissemination via the Protected Planet website (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/&lt;/a&gt;), the UN List process described in 3.1 the fact that protected areas data is collected from national agencies acknowledged in the WDPA metadata, and Key Biodiversity Areas website (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;), Protected Planet and Key Biodiversity Areas data are disseminated through the Integrated Biodiversity Assessment Tool, available for research and conservation online (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/&quot;&gt;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/&lt;/a&gt;). This incorporates Country Profile documents for all of the world&amp;#x2019;s countries, which includes documentation of the indicator of protected area coverage of Key Biodiversity Areas. Each annual update to these Country Profiles are sent for consultation to National Focal Points of the Convention on Biological Diversity (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/information/nfp.shtml&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/information/nfp.shtml&lt;/a&gt;), National Statistics Offices SDG Representatives and UN Permanent Missions (Geneva) representatives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data availability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator has been classified by the IAEG-SDGs as Tier 1. Current data are available for all countries in the world, and these are updated on an ongoing basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~150 years&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that data for the global indicator are compiled at national levels, it is straightforward to disaggregate to national and regional levels (e.g., Han et al. 2014), or conversely to aggregate to the global level. Key Biodiversity Areas span all ecosystem types, including marine (Edgar et al. 2008), freshwater (Holland et al. 2012), and mountains (Rodr&amp;#xED;guez-Rodr&amp;#xED;guez et al. 2011). The indicator can therefore be reported in combination across terrestrial and freshwater (and indeed marine) systems, or disaggregated among them. However, individual Key Biodiversity Areas can encompass terrestrial, freshwater, and marine systems simultaneously, and so determining the results is not simply additive. Finally, the indicator can be disaggregated according to different protected area management categories (categories I&amp;#x2013;VI) to reflect differing specific management objectives of protected areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the aggregation of the coverage of protected areas across important sites for terrestrial and freshwater biodiversity as an indicator towards SDG 15.1, other disaggregations of coverage of protected areas of particular relevance as indicators towards SDG targets (Brooks et al. 2016) include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SDG 14.5.1 Coverage of protected areas in relation to marine areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SDG 15.4.1 Coverage by protected areas of important sites for mountain biodiversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protected area coverage data can be combined with other data sources to yield further, complementary, indicators. For example, protected area overlay with ecoregional maps can be used to provide information on protected area coverage of different broad biogeographical regions. Protected area coverage of the distributions of different groups of species (e.g., mammals, birds, amphibians) can similarly provide indicators of trends in coverage of biodiversity at the species level. Protected area coverage can be combined with the Red List Index to generate indicators of the impacts of protected areas in reducing biodiversity loss (Butchart et al. 2012). Finally, indicators derived from protected area overlay can also inform sustainable urban development; for example, the overlay of protected areas onto urban maps could provide an indicator of public space as a proportion of overall city space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National processes provide the great bulk of the data that are subsequently aggregated into both the World Database on Protected Areas and the World Database of Key Biodiversity Areas, and so there are very few differences between national indicators and the global one. One minor source of difference is that the World Database on Protected Areas incorporates internationally-designated protected areas (e.g., UNESCO World Heritage sites, Ramsar sites, etc), a few of which are not considered by their sovereign nations to be protected areas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that because countries do not submit comprehensive data on degazetted protected areas to the WDPA, earlier values of the indictor may marginally underestimate coverage. Furthermore, there is also a lag between the point at which a protected area is designated on the ground and the point at which it is reported to the WDPA. As such, current or recent coverage may also be underestimated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unep-wcmc.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.unep-wcmc.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.birdlife.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.birdlife.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iucn.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.iucn.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These metadata are based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://mdgs.un.org/unsd/mi/wiki/7-6-Proportion-of-terrestrial-and-marine-areas-protected.ashx&quot;&gt;http://mdgs.un.org/unsd/mi/wiki/7-6-Proportion-of-terrestrial-and-marine-areas-protected.ashx&lt;/a&gt;, supplemented by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bipindicators.net/paoverlays%20&quot;&gt;http://www.bipindicators.net/paoverlays&lt;/a&gt; and the references listed below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BIRDLIFE INTERNATIONAL (2014). Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas: a global network for conserving nature and benefiting people. Cambridge, UK: BirdLife International. Available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.datazone.birdlife.org/sowb/sowbpubs#IBA&quot;&gt;www.datazone.birdlife.org/sowb/sowbpubs#IBA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BIRDLIFE INTERNATIONAL (2019). &lt;em&gt;World Database of Key Biodiversity Areas.&lt;/em&gt;Developed by the KBA Partnership: BirdLife International, International Union for the Conservation of Nature, Amphibian Survival Alliance, Conservation International, Critical Ecosystem Partnership Fund, Global Environment Facility, Global Wildlife Conservation, NatureServe, Rainforest Trust, Royal Society for the Protection of Birds, Wildlife Conservation Society and World Wildlife Fund. September 2019 version. Available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://keybiodiversity.areas.org/site/search&quot;&gt;http://keybiodiversity.areas.org/site/search&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BROOKS, T. et al. (2001). Conservation priorities for birds and biodiversity: do East African Important Bird Areas represent species diversity in other terrestrial vertebrate groups? Ostrich suppl. 15: 3&amp;#x2013;12. Available from: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.2989/00306520109485329%23.VafbVJPVq75.&quot;&gt;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.2989/00306520109485329#.VafbVJPVq75.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BROOKS, T.M. et al. (2016) Goal 15: Life on land. Sustainable manage forests, combat desertification, halt and reverse land degradation, halt biodiversity loss. Pp. 497&amp;#x2013;522 in Dur&amp;#xE1;n y Lalaguna, P., D&amp;#xED;az Barrado, C.M. &amp;amp; Fern&amp;#xE1;ndez Liesa, C.R. (eds.) International Society and Sustainable Development Goals. Editorial Aranzadi, Cizur Menor, Spain. Available from: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thomsonreuters.es/es/tienda/pdp/duo.html?pid=10008456&quot;&gt;https://www.thomsonreuters.es/es/tienda/pdp/duo.html?pid=10008456&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2010). Global biodiversity: indicators of recent declines. Science 328: 1164&amp;#x2013;1168. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/328/5982/1164.short&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/328/5982/1164.short&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2012). Protecting important sites for biodiversity contributes to meeting global conservation targets. PLoS One 7(3): e32529. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0032529&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0032529&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2015). Shortfalls and solutions for meeting national and global conservation area targets. Conservation Letters 8: 329&amp;#x2013;337. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12158/full&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12158/full&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBD (2014). Global Biodiversity Outlook 4. Convention on Biological Diversity, Montr&amp;#xE9;al, Canada. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/gbo4/.&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/gbo4/.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CHAPE, S. et al. (2005). Measuring the extent and effectiveness of protected areas as an indicator for meeting global biodiversity targets. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B 360: 443&amp;#x2013;445. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/360/1454/443.short&quot;&gt;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/360/1454/443.short&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DEGUIGNET, M., et al. (2014). 2014 United Nations List of Protected Areas. UNEP-WCMC, Cambridge, UK. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://unep-wcmc.org/system/dataset_file_fields/files/000/000/263/original/2014_UN_List_of_Protected_Areas_EN_web.PDF?1415613322&quot;&gt;http://unep-wcmc.org/system/dataset_file_fields/files/000/000/263/original/2014_UN_List_of_Protected_Areas_EN_web.PDF?1415613322&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DI MARCO, M., et al. (2016). Quantifying the relative irreplaceability of Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas. Conservation Biology 30: 392&amp;#x2013;402. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/cobi.12609/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/cobi.12609/abstract&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DONALD, P. et al. (2018) Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas (IBAs): the development and characteristics of a global inventory of key sites for biodiversity. Bird Conserv. Internat. 29:177&amp;#x2013;198.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DUDLEY, N. (2008). Guidelines for Applying Protected Area Management Categories. International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN). Gland, Switzerland. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9243&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9243&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDGAR, G.J. et al. (2008). Key Biodiversity Areas as globally significant target sites for the conservation of marine biological diversity. Aquatic Conservation: Marine and Freshwater Ecosystems 18: 969&amp;#x2013;983. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/aqc.902/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/aqc.902/abstract&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EKEN, G. et al. (2004). Key biodiversity areas as site conservation targets. BioScience 54: 1110&amp;#x2013;1118. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/54/12/1110.short&quot;&gt;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/54/12/1110.short&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOSTER, M.N. et al. (2012) The identification of sites of biodiversity conservation significance: progress with the application of a global standard. Journal of Threatened Taxa 4: 2733&amp;#x2013;2744. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.threatenedtaxa.in/index.php/JoTT/article/view/779&quot;&gt;http://www.threatenedtaxa.in/index.php/JoTT/article/view/779&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global Administrative Areas (2019). GADM database of Global Administrative Areas, version 2.8. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gadm.org/home&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.gadm.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HAN, X. et al. (2014). A Biodiversity indicators dashboard: addressing challenges to monitoring progress towards the Aichi Biodiversity Targets using disaggregated global data. PLoS ONE 9(11): e112046. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0112046&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0112046&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOLLAND, R.A. et al. (2012). Conservation priorities for freshwater biodiversity: the key biodiversity area approach refined and tested for continental Africa. Biological Conservation 148: 167&amp;#x2013;179. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320712000298&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320712000298&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IUCN (2016). A Global Standard for the Identification of Key Biodiversity Areas. International Union for Conservation of Nature, Gland, Switzerland. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JONAS, H.D. et al. (2014) New steps of change: looking beyond protected areas to consider other effective area-based conservation measures. Parks 20: 111&amp;#x2013;128. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://parksjournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/PARKS-20.2-Jonas-et-al-10.2305IUCN.CH_.2014.PARKS-20-2.HDJ_.en_.pdf&quot;&gt;http://parksjournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/PARKS-20.2-Jonas-et-al-10.2305IUCN.CH_.2014.PARKS-20-2.HDJ_.en_.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KNIGHT, A. T. et al. (2007). Improving the Key Biodiversity Areas approach for effective conservation planning. BioScience 57: 256&amp;#x2013;261. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/57/3/256.short&quot;&gt;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/57/3/256.short&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LANGHAMMER, P. F. et al. (2007). Identification and Gap Analysis of Key Biodiversity Areas: Targets for Comprehensive Protected Area Systems. IUCN World Commission on Protected Areas Best Practice Protected Area Guidelines Series No. 15. IUCN, Gland, Switzerland. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9055&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9055&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LEVERINGTON, F. et al. (2010). A global analysis of protected area management effectiveness. Environmental Management 46: 685&amp;#x2013;698. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00267-010-9564-5#page-1&quot;&gt;http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00267-010-9564-5#page-1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MONTESINO POUZOLS, F., et al. (2014) Global protected area expansion is compromised by projected land-use and parochialism. Nature 516: 383&amp;#x2013;386. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v516/n7531/abs/nature14032.html&quot;&gt;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v516/n7531/abs/nature14032.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOLTE, C. &amp;amp; AGRAWAL, A. (2013). Linking management effectiveness indicators to observed effects of protected areas on fire occurrence in the Amazon rainforest. Conservation Biology 27: 155&amp;#x2013;165. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2012.01930.x/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2012.01930.x/abstract&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PAIN, D.J. et al. (2005) Biodiversity representation in Uganda&amp;#x2019;s forest IBAs. Biological Conservation 125: 133&amp;#x2013;138. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320705001412&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320705001412&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RICKETTS, T. H. et al. (2005). Pinpointing and preventing imminent extinctions. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the U.S.A. 102: 18497&amp;#x2013;18501. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/102/51/18497.short&quot;&gt;http://www.pnas.org/content/102/51/18497.short&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RODRIGUES, A. S. L. et al. (2004). Effectiveness of the global protected area network in representing species diversity. Nature 428: 640&amp;#x2013;643. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v428/n6983/abs/nature02422.html&quot;&gt;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v428/n6983/abs/nature02422.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RODR&amp;#xCD;GUEZ-RODR&amp;#xCD;GUEZ, D., et al. (2011). Progress towards international targets for protected area coverage in mountains: a multi-scale assessment. Biological Conservation 144: 2978&amp;#x2013;2983. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320711003454&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320711003454&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TITTENSOR, D. et al. (2014). A mid-term analysis of progress towards international biodiversity targets. Science 346: 241&amp;#x2013;244. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/346/6206/241.short&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/346/6206/241.short&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNEP-WCMC (2019). World Database on Protected Areas User Manual 1.6. UNEP-WCMC, Cambridge, UK. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://wcmc.io/WDPA_Manual&quot;&gt;http://wcmc.io/WDPA_Manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNEP-WCMC &amp;amp; IUCN (2020). The World Database on Protected Areas (WDPA). UNEP-WCMC, Cambridge, UK. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net&quot;&gt;http://www.protectedplanet.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 15: Proteger, restablecer y promover el uso sostenible de los ecosistemas terrestres, gestionar sosteniblemente los bosques, luchar contra la desertificacin, detener e invertir la degradacin de las tierras y detener la prdida de biodiversidad&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 15.1: De aqu a 2020, asegurar la conservacin, el restablecimiento y el uso sostenible de los ecosistemas terrestres y los ecosistemas interiores de agua dulce y sus servicios, en particular los bosques, los humedales, las montaas y las zonas ridas, en consonancia con las obligaciones contradas en virtud de acuerdos internacionales&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 15.1.2: Proporcin de lugares importantes para la biodiversidad terrestre y del agua dulce incluidos en zonas protegidas, desglosada por tipo de ecosistema&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 15 : Prserver et restaurer les cosystmes terrestres, en veillant  les exploiter de faon durable, grer durablement les forts, lutter contre la dsertification, enrayer et inverser le processus de dgradation des terres etmettre fin  lappauvrissement de la biodiversit&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 15.1: Dici  2020, garantir la prservation, la restauration et lexploitation durable des cosystmes terrestres et des cosystmes deau douce et des services connexes, en particulier des forts, des zones humides, des montagnes et des zones arides, conformment aux obligations dcoulant des accords internationaux&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 15.1.2 : Proportion des sites importants pour la biodiversit terrestre et la biodiversit des eaux douces quise trouvent dans des aires protges (par type dcosystme)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dernire mise  jour : 12 fvrier 2020&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Informations institutionnelles &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organisation(s) :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Centre mondial de surveillance continue de la conservation de la nature de l&apos;ONU Environnement (PNUE-WCMC)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BirdLife International (BLI)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Union internationale pour la conservation de la nature (UICN)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et dfinitions &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dfinition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur Proportion de sites importants pour la biodiversit terrestre et d&apos;eau douce qui sont couverts par des aires protges montre les tendances temporelles du pourcentage moyen de chaque site important pour la biodiversit terrestre et d&apos;eau douce (c&apos;est--dire ceux qui contribuent de manire significative  la persistance de la biodiversit mondiale) qui est couvert par des aires protges dsignes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les aires protges, telles que dfinies par l&apos;Union internationale pour la conservation de la nature (UICN ; Dudley 2008), sont des espaces gographiques clairement dfinis, reconnus, ddis et grs, par des moyens lgaux ou d&apos;autres moyens efficaces, afin de raliser la conservation  long terme de la nature avec les services cosystmiques et les valeurs culturelles associs. Il est important de noter qu&apos;une varit d&apos;objectifs de gestion spcifiques sont reconnus dans cette dfinition, couvrant la conservation, la restauration et l&apos;utilisation durable :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Catgorie Ia : Rserve naturelle stricte &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Catgorie Ib : Zone de nature sauvage &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Catgorie II : Parc National&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Catgorie III : Monument ou lment naturel&lt;/li&gt; 
  &lt;li&gt;Catgorie IV : Zone de gestion de l&apos;habitat/des espces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Catgorie V : Paysage terrestre ou marin protg &lt;/li&gt; 
  &lt;li&gt;Catgorie VI : Aire protge avec utilisation durable des ressources naturelles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le statut &amp;quot;dsign&amp;quot; est attribu  une zone protge lorsque l&apos;autorit correspondante, conformment  la lgislation nationale ou  la pratique courante (par exemple, au moyen d&apos;un dcret excutif ou autre), approuve officiellement un document de dsignation. La dsignation doit tre faite dans un but de conservation de la biodiversit, et non de protection de facto rsultant d&apos;une autre activit (par exemple, militaire).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les sites contribuant de manire significative  la persistance de la biodiversit  l&apos;chelle mondiale sont identifis selon des critres globaux dfinis dans &lt;em&gt;Une norme mondiale pour l&apos;identification des zones cls pour la biodiversit &lt;/em&gt;(UICN 2016) appliqus au niveau national. Les zones cls pour la biodiversit comprennent (a) les zones importantes pour la biodiversit des oiseaux &amp;amp;, c&apos;est--dire les sites contribuant de manire significative  la persistance mondiale de la biodiversit, identifis  l&apos;aide de donnes sur les oiseaux, dont &amp;gt;13 000 sites au total ont t identifis dans tous les pays du monde&amp;#x2019;(BirdLife International 2014, Donald &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; 2018) ; (b) les sites de l&apos;Alliance pour une extinction zro (Ricketts et al. 2005), c&apos;est--dire des sites dtenant effectivement la totalit de la population d&apos;au moins une espce value comme tant en danger critique d&apos;extinction ou en danger sur la Liste rouge des espces menaces de l&apos;UICN, dont 853 sites ont t identifis pour 1 483 espces de mammifres, d&apos;oiseaux, d&apos;amphibiens, de reptiles, de crustacs d&apos;eau douce, de coraux constructeurs de rcifs, de conifres, de cycadales et d&apos;autres taxons ; (c) les zones cls pour la biodiversit identifies selon une version antrieure des critres relatifs aux zones cls pour la biodiversit (Langhammer &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; 2007), y compris celles identifies dans les profils de points chauds des cosystmes labors avec le soutien du Fonds de partenariat pour les cosystmes critiques. Ces trois sous-ensembles sont en cours de rvaluation  l&apos;aide de la Norme mondiale, qui unifie ces approches ainsi que d&apos;autres mcanismes d&apos;identification de sites importants pour d&apos;autres espces et cosystmes (UICN 2016).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Sources de donnes &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les donnes sur les aires protges sont compiles par les ministres de l&apos;environnement et autres ministres responsables de la dsignation et de l&apos;entretien des aires protges. Les donnes sur les aires protges pour les sites dsigns dans le cadre de la Convention de Ramsar et de la Convention du patrimoine mondial de l&apos;UNESCO sont recueillies par les secrtariats internationaux des conventions concernes. Les donnes sur les aires protges sont agrges au niveau mondial dans la base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges par le Centre mondial de surveillance de la conservation de l&apos;environnement de l&apos;ONU, conformment au mandat de production de la liste des aires protges de l&apos;ONU (Deguignet et al. 2014). Elles sont diffuses par le biais de &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net/&quot;&gt;Protected Planet&lt;/a&gt;, qui est gr conjointement par le PNUE-WCMC et l&apos;UICN et sa Commission mondiale des aires protges (Juffe-Bignoli et al. 2014).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les zones cls pour la biodiversit sont identifies  l&apos;chelle nationale par des processus multipartites, selon des critres et des seuils standard. Les donnes sur les zones cls pour la biodiversit sont regroupes dans la &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;Base de donnes mondiale sur les zones cls pour la biodiversit&lt;/a&gt;, gre par BirdLife International. Plus prcisment, les donnes sur les zones importantes pour les oiseaux et la biodiversit sont disponibles en ligne sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&quot;&gt;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&lt;/a&gt; et les donnes sur les sites de l&apos;Alliance pour une extinction zro sont disponibles en ligne sur https://zeroextinction.org. Ces deux ensembles de donnes, ainsi que les zones cls pour la biodiversit identifies par d&apos;autres processus, sont disponibles par le biais de la &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;Base de donnes mondiale sur les zones cls pour la biodiversit&lt;/a&gt; et, avec la base de donnes mondiale sur les zones protges, sont galement diffuss par le biais de l&apos;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/login&quot;&gt;Outil d&apos;valuation intgre de la biodiversit pour la recherche et la planification de la conservation&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Processus de collecte :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voir les informations sous d&apos;autres sections.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendrier &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collecte des donnes :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le PNUE-WCMC produit la Liste des Nations Unies des aires protges tous les 5  10 ans, sur la base des informations fournies par les ministres/agences nationales. Dans l&apos;intervalle entre les compilations des listes des Nations Unies, le PNUE-WCMC travaille en troite collaboration avec les ministres/agences nationales et les ONG responsables de la dsignation et de l&apos;entretien des zones protges, mettant continuellement  jour la WDPA au fur et  mesure que de nouvelles donnes sont disponibles. La base de donnes mondiale des zones cls pour la biodiversit est galement mise  jour de manire continue, au fur et  mesure que de nouvelles donnes nationales sont soumises. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publication des donnes : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il est prvu que l&apos;indicateur de la couverture en aires protges des sites importants pour la biodiversit soit publi annuellement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fournisseurs de donnes &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les donnes sur les zones protges sont compiles par les ministres de l&apos;environnement et d&apos;autres ministres responsables de la dsignation et de l&apos;entretien des zones protges. Les zones cls pour la biodiversit sont identifies  l&apos;chelle nationale par le biais de processus multipartites, selon des critres et des seuils standard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compilateurs de donnes &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nom :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PNUE-WCMC et UICN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les donnes sur les aires protges sont agrges au niveau mondial dans la base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges par le Centre mondial de surveillance continue de la conservation de la nature de l&apos;ONU Environnement, conformment au mandat de production de la liste des aires protges de l&apos;ONU (Deguignet et al. 2014). Elles sont diffuses par le biais de &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net/&quot;&gt;Protected Planet&lt;/a&gt;, qui est gr conjointement par le PNUE-WCMC et l&apos;UICN et sa Commission mondiale des aires protges (PNUE-WCMC 2016). Les donnes sur les zones cls pour la biodiversit sont regroupes dans la &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;Base de donnes mondiale sur les zones cls pour la biodiversit&lt;/a&gt;, gre par BirdLife International (2019). Plus prcisment, les donnes sur les zones importantes pour les oiseaux et la biodiversit sont disponibles en ligne sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&quot;&gt;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&lt;/a&gt; et les donnes sur les sites de l&apos;Alliance pour une extinction zro sont disponibles en ligne sur https://zeroextinction.org. Ces deux ensembles de donnes, ainsi que la base de donnes mondiale sur les zones protges, sont galement diffuss par le biais de l&apos;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/login&quot;&gt;Outil d&apos;valuation intgre de la biodiversit pour la recherche et la planification de la conservation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Justification :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La sauvegarde des sites importants est essentielle pour enrayer le dclin de la biodiversit et assurer une utilisation durable et  long terme des ressources naturelles terrestres et d&apos;eau douce. La cration de zones protges est un mcanisme important pour atteindre cet objectif, et cet indicateur sert  mesurer les progrs raliss en matire de conservation, de restauration et d&apos;utilisation durable des cosystmes terrestres et d&apos;eau douce et de leurs services, en particulier les forts, les zones humides, les montagnes et les terres arides, conformment aux obligations dcoulant des accords internationaux. Il est important de noter que, bien qu&apos;il puisse tre dsagrg pour rendre compte d&apos;un seul cosystme d&apos;intrt (par exemple, les forts), il n&apos;est pas limit  un seul type d&apos;cosystme, et reflte donc fidlement l&apos;intention de la cible 15.1 des ODD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les niveaux d&apos;accs aux zones protges varient selon les catgories de gestion des zones protges. Certaines zones, comme les rserves scientifiques, sont maintenues dans leur tat naturel et fermes  toute autre utilisation. D&apos;autres sont utilises pour les loisirs ou le tourisme, ou mme ouvertes  l&apos;extraction durable des ressources naturelles. Outre la protection de la biodiversit, les zones protges ont une grande valeur sociale et conomique : elles soutiennent les moyens de subsistance locaux, protgent les bassins versants de l&apos;rosion, abritent une richesse inestimable de ressources gntiques, soutiennent des industries florissantes de loisirs et de tourisme, permettent la science, la recherche et l&apos;ducation, et constituent une base pour les valeurs culturelles et autres valeurs non matrielles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Cet indicateur ajoute des informations significatives aux statistiques simples traditionnellement rapportes sur la superficie terrestre et d&apos;eau douce couverte par les aires protges, en divisant la superficie totale protge dans un pays par la superficie territoriale totale du pays et en multipliant par 100 (par exemple, Chape et al. 2005). Ces statistiques de couverture de zone en pourcentage ne reconnaissent pas l&apos;extrme variation de l&apos;importance de la biodiversit dans l&apos;espace (Rodrigues et al. 2004), et risquent donc de gnrer des rsultats pervers par la protection des zones qui sont grandes au dtriment de celles qui ncessitent une protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur est utilis pour suivre les progrs vers le Plan stratgique 2011  2020 pour la biodiversit (CBD 2014, Tittensor et al. 2014), et a t utilis comme indicateur pour l&apos;Objectif 2010 de la Convention sur la diversit biologique (Butchart et al. 2010).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commentaires et limites : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des critres de contrle de qualit sont appliqus pour assurer la cohrence et la comparabilit des donnes de la Base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges. Les nouvelles donnes sont valides au PNUE-WCMC par le biais d&apos;un certain nombre d&apos;outils et traduites dans la structure de donnes standard de la Base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges. Les divergences entre les donnes de la base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges et les nouvelles donnes sont rduites au minimum grce  un manuel (UNEP-WCMC 2019) et rsolues en communiquant avec les fournisseurs de donnes. Des processus similaires s&apos;appliquent  l&apos;incorporation de donnes dans la &lt;em&gt;Base de donnes mondiale des zones cls pour la biodiversit&lt;/em&gt; (BirdLife International 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur ne mesure pas l&apos;efficacit des zones protges  rduire la perte de biodiversit, qui dpend en fin de compte d&apos;une srie de facteurs de gestion et d&apos;application non couverts par l&apos;indicateur. Un certain nombre d&apos;initiatives sont en cours pour remdier  cette limitation. Plus particulirement, de nombreux mcanismes ont t dvelopps pour valuer la gestion des aires protges, qui peuvent tre synthtiss dans un indicateur (Leverington et al. 2010). Ce dernier est utilis par le Partenariat pour les indicateurs de la biodiversit comme un indicateur complmentaire des progrs accomplis vers l&apos;Objectif 11 d&apos;Aichi pour la biodiversit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bipindicators.net/pamanagement&quot;&gt;http://www.bipindicators.net/pamanagement&lt;/a&gt;). Cependant, il peut y avoir peu de relation entre ces mesures et les rsultats des aires protges (Nolte &amp;amp; Agrawal 2013). Plus rcemment, des approches de la &amp;#x201C;liste verte&amp;#x201D; ont commenc  tre dveloppes, afin d&apos;incorporer  la fois l&apos;efficacit de la gestion et les rsultats des aires protges, et celles-ci sont susceptibles de devenir progressivement importantes au fur et  mesure qu&apos;elles sont testes et appliques plus largement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des lacunes dans les donnes et les connaissances peuvent survenir en raison des difficults  dterminer si un site est conforme  la dfinition de l&apos;UICN d&apos;une aire protge, et certaines aires protges ne se voient pas attribuer de catgories de gestion. En outre, &amp;#x201C;d&apos;autres mesures efficaces de conservation par zone&amp;#x201D;, telles que spcifies par l&apos;Objectif d&apos;Aichi pour la biodiversit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11 du Plan stratgique pour la biodiversit 2011  2020, reconnaissent que certains sites situs au-del du rseau officiel d&apos;aires protges, bien que n&apos;tant pas grs principalement pour la conservation de la nature, peuvent nanmoins tre grs de manire  assurer la persistance de la biodiversit pour laquelle ils sont importants (Jonas et al. 2014). Cependant, la dfinition officiellement convenue d&apos;une OECM (&amp;#x201C;Une zone gographiquement dfinie autre qu&apos;une aire protge, qui est gouverne et gre de manire  obtenir des rsultats positifs et durables  long terme pour la conservation in situ de la biodiversit, avec les fonctions et services cosystmiques associs et, le cas chant, les valeurs culturelles, spirituelles, socio-conomiques et autres valeurs pertinentes au niveau local&amp;#x201D;) n&apos;a t convenue qu&apos;en novembre 2018 et les mesures ne sont que rcemment en place pour que les pays soumettent les donnes des OECM au PNUE-WCMC. Les OECM sont dsormais rassembles par le PNUE-WCMC dans une base de donnes distincte, la WD-OECM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En ce qui concerne les sites importants, la plus grande limitation est que l&apos;identification des sites  ce jour s&apos;est principalement concentre sur des sous-ensembles spcifiques de la biodiversit, par exemple les oiseaux (pour les zones importantes pour les oiseaux et la biodiversit) et les espces hautement menaces (pour les sites de l&apos;Alliance pour une extinction zro). Bien qu&apos;il ait t dmontr que les zones importantes pour la conservation des oiseaux et de la biodiversit sont de bons substituts de la biodiversit en gnral (Brooks et al. 2001, Pain et al. 2005), l&apos;application de la norme unifie pour l&apos;identification des sites des zones cls pour la biodiversit (UICN 2016)  diffrents niveaux de biodiversit (gnes, espces, cosystmes) et  diffrents groupes taxonomiques reste une grande priorit, sur la base des efforts dploys  ce jour (Eken et al. 2004, Knight et al. 2007, Langhammer et al. 2007, Foster et al. 2012). Les oiseaux reprsentent dsormais &amp;lt;50 % des espces pour lesquelles des zones cls pour la biodiversit ont t identifies et,  mesure que l&apos;identification de zones cls pour la biodiversit pour d&apos;autres taxons et lments de la biodiversit progresse, ce biais deviendra une considration moins importante  l&apos;avenir.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;identification des zones cls pour la biodiversit a t valide pour un certain nombre de pays et de rgions o des donnes compltes sur la biodiversit permettent un calcul formel de l&apos;importance du site (ou de son &amp;#x201C;irremplaabilit&amp;#x201D;)  l&apos;aide de techniques systmatiques de planification de la conservation (Di Marco et al. 2016, Montesino Pouzols et al. 2014).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les dveloppements futurs de l&apos;indicateur comprendront : a) l&apos;expansion de la couverture taxonomique des zones cls pour la biodiversit terrestres et d&apos;eau douce par l&apos;application de la norme des zones cls pour la biodiversit (UICN 2016)  une grande varit de vertbrs, d&apos;invertbrs et de plantes terrestres et d&apos;eau douce, ainsi qu&apos; un type d&apos;cosystme ; b) l&apos;amlioration des donnes sur les zones protges en continuant  augmenter la proportion de sites dont les dates de dsignation sont documentes et dont les polygones de dlimitation sont numriss (plutt que des coordonnes).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Mthodologie &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mthode de calcul :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur est calcul  partir de donnes drives d&apos;un chevauchement spatial entre les polygones numriques des aires protges de la base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges (PNUE-WCMC &amp;amp; UICN 2020) et les polygones numriques des zones cls pour la biodiversit terrestres et d&apos;eau douce (de la Base de donnes mondiale des zones cls pour la biodiversit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zones cls pour la biodiversit, y compris les zones importantes pour les oiseaux et la biodiversit, les sites de l&apos;Alliance pour une extinction zro et d&apos;autres zones cls pour la biodiversit). Les sites ont t classs comme zones cls pour la biodiversit terrestres en effectuant un chevauchement spatial entre les polygones des zones cls pour la biodiversit et une couche matricielle ocanique (produite  partir de la couche &amp;#x2018;adm0&amp;#x2019; de la base de donnes des zones administratives mondiales (GADM 2019)), en classant toute zone cl pour la biodiversit comme zone cl pour la biodiversit terrestre lorsqu&apos;elle prsente un chevauchement de &amp;#x2264;95 % avec la couche ocanique (certains sites ont donc t classs comme tant  la fois terrestres et marins). Les sites ont t classs comme zones cls pour la biodiversit d&apos;eau douce si les espces rsidentes pour lesquelles ils ont t identifis taient documentes dans la liste rouge de l&apos;UICN comme dpendant des systmes d&apos;eaux intrieures. Pour les espces non rsidentes ou migrantes, ou les espces qui changent d&apos;habitat au cours du cycle annuel, le site a t tiquet comme tant d&apos;eau douce si l&apos;espce tait prsente sur le site pendant la saison approprie de dpendance  l&apos;eau (par exemple, certaines espces ne dpendent de l&apos;eau que pendant la saison de reproduction). Les sites ont ensuite t examins ( l&apos;aide de la couche de base de l&apos;imagerie satellite dans ArcGIS) pour dterminer s&apos;ils se trouvaient entirement dans la zone ctire (dfinie ici comme tant  moins de 10 km de la cte), et ces sites n&apos;ont pas t tiquets comme tant d&apos;eau douce, mais comme tant marins si les habitats de zones humides prsents sur le site relevaient uniquement de la classe &amp;#x2018;Marine Supratidal&amp;#x2019; du systme de classification des habitats de l&apos;UICN (c&apos;est--dire les estuaires, les lagunes, etc.). Si le site se trouvait dans la zone ctire, mais contenait un mlange de classes d&apos;eaux supratidales marines et d&apos;eaux intrieures, il a t tiquet  la fois comme eau douce et marine. Chaque site a ensuite fait l&apos;objet d&apos;une vrification croise manuelle par rapport  d&apos;autres attributs de site (disponibles de manire moins exhaustive), tels que les prfrences d&apos;habitat de ses espces dclencheuses, le nom du site (Delta, Rivire, Humedal, etc.), sa couverture en superficie par diffrents types d&apos;habitats, son chevauchement avec des sites Ramsar et son statut Ramsar fantme, de manire  confirmer ou  supprimer l&apos;tiquette Eau douce de manire approprie. La valeur de l&apos;indicateur  un moment donn, base sur les donnes relatives  l&apos;anne d&apos;tablissement de l&apos;aire protge enregistres dans la Base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges, est calcule comme le pourcentage moyen de chaque zone cl pour la biodiversit actuellement reconnue qu&apos;elle couvre par des aires protges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;anne d&apos;tablissement des aires protges est inconnue pour ~12% des aires protges de la base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges, ce qui gnre une incertitude quant  l&apos;volution de la couverture des aires protges au fil du temps. Pour reflter cette incertitude, une anne a t assigne au hasard  partir d&apos;une autre aire protge dans le mme pays, puis cette procdure a t rpte 1 000 fois, avec la mdiane trace. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avant 2017, l&apos;indicateur tait prsent comme le pourcentage de zones cls pour la biodiversit entirement couvertes par des zones protges. Cependant, il est maintenant prsent comme le % moyen de chaque zone cl pour la biodiversit qui est couverte par des zones protges afin de mieux reflter les tendances de la couverture des zones protges pour les pays ou les rgions avec peu ou pas de zones cls pour la biodiversit qui sont compltement couvertes. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traitement des valeurs manquantes : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Au niveau national : &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les donnes sont disponibles pour les zones protges et les zones cls pour la biodiversit dans tous les pays du monde et donc aucune imputation ou estimation des donnes au niveau national n&apos;est ncessaire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aux niveaux rgional et mondial :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les indicateurs mondiaux de la couverture par les aires protges des sites importants pour la biodiversit sont calculs comme le pourcentage moyen de chaque zone cl pour la biodiversit qui est couverte par des aires protges. Les donnes sont gnres  partir de tous les pays, et donc, bien qu&apos;il y ait une incertitude autour des donnes, il n&apos;y a pas de valeurs manquantes en tant que telles et il n&apos;y a donc pas besoin d&apos;imputation ou d&apos;estimation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agrgats rgionaux :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le PNUE-WCMC est l&apos;agence charge de calculer et de communiquer les chiffres mondiaux et rgionaux pour cet indicateur, en collaboration avec BirdLife International et l&apos;UICN pour combiner les donnes sur les aires protges avec celles des sites importants pour la biodiversit. Le PNUE-WCMC regroupe les chiffres mondiaux et rgionaux sur les zones protges  partir des chiffres nationaux calculs  partir de la base de donnes mondiale sur les zones protges et diffuss par Protected Planet. La base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges et Protected Planet sont gres conjointement par le PNUE-WCMC, l&apos;UICN et sa Commission mondiale des aires protges. La base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges est conserve dans un systme d&apos;information gographique qui stocke des informations sur les aires protges telles que leur nom, leur taille, leur type, leur date de cration, leur emplacement gographique (point) et/ou leurs limites (polygone). La couverture des aires protges est calcule en utilisant toutes les aires protges enregistres dans la base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges dont l&apos;emplacement et l&apos;tendue sont connus,  l&apos;exception des aires protges sans limites numriques et des sites dont le statut est &amp;#x2018;propos&amp;#x2019; ou &amp;#x2018;non signal&amp;#x2019;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mthodes et instructions  la disposition des pays pour la compilation des donnes au niveau national :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La WDPA trouve son origine dans un mandat des Nations Unies de 1959, lorsque le Conseil conomique et social des Nations Unies a demand une liste de parcs nationaux et de rserves quivalentes (Rsolution 713 (XXVIII)). Plus de dtails sont disponibles ici : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&lt;/a&gt;. La liste des aires protges des Nations Unies a t publie en 1961/62, 1966/71, 1972 (addendum  l&apos;dition 1966/71), 1973, 1974, 1975, 1980, 1982, 1985, 1990, 1993, 1997, 2003, 2014 et 2018, ce qui a donn lieu  un rseau mondial de fournisseurs de donnes nationales pour la WDPA. Par exemple, en 2014, tous les points focaux nationaux de la Convention sur la diversit biologique (CDB) et tous les points focaux nationaux du programme de travail sur les aires protges de la CDB (PoWPA) ont demand des donnes pour la liste de 2014 dess aires protges des Nations Unies (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas-2014&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas-2014&lt;/a&gt;). Les donnes sur les aires protges sont donc compiles directement  partir d&apos;agences gouvernementales, de centres rgionaux et d&apos;autres sources faisant autorit en l&apos;absence de source gouvernementale. Tous les enregistrements ont un identifiant de mtadonnes unique (MetadataID) qui relie la base de donnes spatiale  la table Source o toutes les sources sont dcrites. Les donnes sont rassembles et standardises selon les normes de donnes de la WDPA et valides avec la source. Le processus de collecte, de validation et de publication des donnes ainsi que les protocoles et les normes de donnes de la WDPA sont rgulirement mis  jour dans le manuel de l&apos;utilisateur de la WDPA (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&lt;/a&gt;) disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net&quot;&gt;www.protectedplanet.net&lt;/a&gt; o toutes les donnes spatiales et le tableau des sources sont galement publis chaque mois et peuvent tre tlchargs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le processus de compilation des donnes sur les sites contribuant de manire significative  la persistance de la biodiversit mondiale (zones cls pour la biodiversit) est document en ligne (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;). Plus prcisment, (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/what-are-kbas&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/what-are-kbas&lt;/a&gt;), le processus d&apos;identification des zones cls pour la biodiversit est un exercice trs inclusif, consultatif et ascendant. Bien que toute personne disposant de donnes scientifiques appropries puisse proposer un site  qualifier de zone cl pour la biodiversit, une large consultation des parties prenantes au niveau national (organisations non gouvernementales et gouvernementales) est requise au cours du processus de proposition. L&apos;identification des zones cls pour la biodiversit s&apos;appuie sur le rseau existant de zones cls pour la biodiversit, y compris celles identifies comme zones importantes pour la biodiversit des oiseaux par le partenariat BirdLife de 120 organisations nationales (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.birdlife.org/worldwide/partnership/birdlife-partners&quot;&gt;http://www.birdlife.org/worldwide/partnership/birdlife-partners&lt;/a&gt;), pour l&apos;Alliance pour une extinction zro par 93 organisations nationales et internationales (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zeroextinction.org/partners.html&quot;&gt;http://www.zeroextinction.org/partners.html&lt;/a&gt;), et en tant qu&apos;autres zones cls pour la biodiversit par des organisations de la socit civile soutenues par le Fonds de partenariat pour les cosystmes critiques dans l&apos;laboration de profils d&apos;cosystmes, nomms dans chacun des profils numrs ici (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cepf.net/resources/publications/Pages/ecosystem_profiles.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.cepf.net/resources/publications/Pages/ecosystem_profiles.aspx&lt;/a&gt;), les nouvelles donnes renforant et largissant le rseau de ces sites. Toute proposition de site fait l&apos;objet d&apos;un examen scientifique indpendant. Il s&apos;ensuit la nomination officielle du site avec une documentation complte rpondant aux normes de documentation des zones cls pour la biodiversit. Les sites dont le Secrtariat des zones cls pour la biodiversit confirme qu&apos;ils remplissent les conditions requises pour devenir des zones cls pour la biodiversit apparaissent ensuite sur le site Web des zones cls pour la biodiversit (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le manuel de l&apos;utilisateur de la WDPA (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&lt;/a&gt;) publi en anglais, en espagnol et en franais, fournit des conseils aux pays sur la manire de soumettre des donnes sur les zones protges  la WDPA, sur les avantages de fournir ces donnes, sur les normes de donnes et sur les contrles de qualit effectus. Nous fournissons galement un rsum de nos mthodes de calcul de la couverture des zones protges  tous les utilisateurs de la WDPA : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/calculating-protected-area-coverage&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/calculating-protected-area-coverage&lt;/a&gt;. La &amp;#x201C;Norme mondiale pour l&apos;identification des zones cls pour la biodiversit&amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&lt;/a&gt;) comprend les recommandations standard mises  la disposition des pays pour l&apos;identification des zones cls pour la biodiversit, d&apos;autres directives tant disponibles sur le site Web des zones cls pour la biodiversit (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;). Plus prcisment, (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&lt;/a&gt;), les principales tapes du processus d&apos;identification des zones cls pour la biodiversit sont les suivantes : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;soumission des expressions d&apos;intention d&apos;identifier une Zone de Biodiversit Cl aux Points Focaux Rgionaux ; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;processus d&apos;laboration de la proposition, au cours duquel les proposants compilent les donnes et la documentation pertinentes et consultent des experts nationaux, y compris des organisations qui ont dj identifi des zones cls pour la biodiversit dans le pays, soit par l&apos;intermdiaire de groupes nationaux de coordination des zones cls pour la biodiversit, soit de manire indpendante ; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;l&apos;examen des zones cls pour la biodiversit proposes par des experts indpendants, qui vrifient l&apos;exactitude des informations dans leur domaine d&apos;expertise ; et &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;une phase de dsignation des sites comprenant la soumission de tous les documents pertinents pour vrification par le secrtariat des zones cls pour la biodiversit (voir section 3.3 ci-dessous). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Une fois qu&apos;une zone cl pour la biodiversit est identifie, il est important de surveiller ses caractristiques et son tat de conservation. Les auteurs de propositions, les rviseurs et les personnes charges de la surveillance peuvent rejoindre la communaut des zones cls pour la biodiversit afin d&apos;changer leurs expriences, leurs tudes de cas et leurs exemples de meilleures pratiques. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assurance de la qualit :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le processus de collecte, de normalisation et de publication des donnes est disponible dans le manuel d&apos;utilisation de la WDPA  l&apos;adresse suivante : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&lt;/a&gt; qui est disponible en anglais, franais et espagnol. Des conseils spcifiques sont fournis  l&apos;adresse &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&lt;/a&gt; sur, par exemple, les champs prdfinis ou les tables de recherche dans la WDPA : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-lookup-tables&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-lookup-tables&lt;/a&gt;, comment les enregistrements de la WDPA sont cods, comment les donnes sur les dsignations internationales et rgionales sont collectes,  quelle frquence la base de donnes est mise  jour et comment raliser des statistiques sur la couverture des zones protges. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le processus d&apos;identification des zones cls pour la biodiversit est soutenu par le partenariat des zones cls pour la biodiversit (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/kba-partners&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/kba-partners&lt;/a&gt;). Parmi les rles du partenariat figure la mise en place du Secrtariat des zones cls pour la biodiversit, qui vrifie les informations soumises lors de la phase de dsignation des sites pour s&apos;assurer de l&apos;application correcte de la norme relative aux zones cls pour la biodiversit (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&lt;/a&gt;), et de l&apos;adquation de la documentation du site, puis vrifie le site, qui est ensuite publi sur le site Web des zones cls pour la biodiversit (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&lt;/a&gt;). En outre, les prsidents de la Commission de la sauvegarde des espces de lUICN et de la Commission mondiale des aires protges (qui sont tous deux lus par les membres de lUICN des gouvernements et des organisations non gouvernementales) nomment le prsident dun Comit indpendant des normes et dappels des zones cls de biodiversit, qui assure lapplication correcte de la Norme mondiale pour lidentification des zones cls de biodiversit. Le code R pour le calcul de la couverture des zones protges des zones cls pour la biodiversit est document comme Dias, M. (2017) &amp;#x201C;Code R pour le calcul de la couverture des zones protges des ZCB&amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/userfiles/files/R_code_for_calculating_protected_area_coverage_of_KBAs_March_2017.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/userfiles/files/R_code_for_calculating_protected_area_coverage_of_KBAs_March_2017.pdf&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outre la diffusion via le site Web de Protected Planet (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/&lt;/a&gt;), le processus de la liste des Nations Unies dcrit au point 3.1, le fait que les donnes sur les aires protges sont collectes auprs d&apos;organismes nationaux reconnus dans les mtadonnes de la WDPA, et le site Web des zones cls pour la biodiversit (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;), les donnes de Protected Planet et des zones cls pour la biodiversit sont diffuses via l&apos;outil d&apos;valuation intgre de la biodiversit, disponible en ligne pour la recherche et la conservation (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/&quot;&gt;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/&lt;/a&gt;). Cet outil intgre les profils nationaux de tous les pays du monde, qui comprennent une documentation sur l&apos;indicateur de couverture des zones protges des zones cls pour la biodiversit. Chaque mise  jour annuelle de ces profils nationaux est envoye pour consultation aux points focaux nationaux de la Convention sur la diversit biologique (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/information/nfp.shtml&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/information/nfp.shtml&lt;/a&gt;), aux reprsentants des OMD des bureaux nationaux de statistiques et aux reprsentants des missions permanentes des Nations Unies (Genve.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilit des donnes &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur a t class par lIAEG-ODD comme tant de niveau 1. Des donnes actuelles sont disponibles pour tous les pays du monde, et elles sont mises  jour en permanence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sries chronologiques :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~150 ans&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dsaggrgation :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tant donn que les donnes pour l&apos;indicateur mondial sont compiles au niveau national, il est facile de dsagrger aux niveaux national et rgional (par exemple, Han et al. 2014), ou inversement d&apos;agrger au niveau mondial. Les zones cls pour la biodiversit couvrent tous les types d&apos;cosystmes, y compris les milieux marins (Edgar et al. 2008), les eaux douces (Holland et al. 2012) et les montagnes (Rodr&amp;#xED;guez-Rodr&amp;#xED;guez et al. 2011). L&apos;indicateur peut donc tre rapport en combinaison dans les systmes terrestres et d&apos;eau douce (et mme marins), ou dsagrg entre eux. Cependant, les zones cls pour la biodiversit individuelles peuvent englober simultanment des systmes terrestres, d&apos;eau douce et marins, et la dtermination des rsultats n&apos;est donc pas simplement additive. Enfin, l&apos;indicateur peut tre dsagrg selon les diffrentes catgories de gestion des aires protges (catgories I  VI) pour reflter les diffrents objectifs de gestion spcifiques des aires protges.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;En plus de l&apos;agrgation de la couverture des aires protges  travers les sites importants pour la biodiversit terrestre et d&apos;eau douce en tant qu&apos;indicateur de l&apos;ODD 15.1, d&apos;autres dsagrgations de la couverture des aires protges particulirement pertinentes en tant qu&apos;indicateurs des cibles des ODD (Brooks et al. 2016) comprennent :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O DD14.5.1 Couverture des zones protges par rapport aux zones marines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ODD 15.4.1 Couverture par les aires protges des sites importants pour la biodiversit des montagnes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les donnes sur la couverture des zones protges peuvent tre combines avec d&apos;autres sources de donnes pour produire d&apos;autres indicateurs complmentaires. Par exemple, la superposition des aires protges avec des cartes corgionales peut tre utilise pour fournir des informations sur la couverture par les aires protges de diffrentes grandes rgions biogographiques. La couverture par les aires protges des distributions de diffrents groupes d&apos;espces (par exemple, les mammifres, les oiseaux, les amphibiens) peut galement fournir des indicateurs des tendances de la couverture de la biodiversit au niveau des espces. La couverture des zones protges peut tre combine avec l&apos;indice de la liste rouge pour gnrer des indicateurs de l&apos;impact des zones protges sur la rduction de la perte de biodiversit (Butchart et al. 2012). Enfin, les indicateurs drivs de la superposition des zones protges peuvent galement informer le dveloppement urbain durable ; par exemple, la superposition des zones protges sur les cartes urbaines pourrait fournir un indicateur de l&apos;espace public en tant que proportion de l&apos;espace global de la ville.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources des carts :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les processus nationaux fournissent la grande majorit des donnes qui sont ensuite agrges dans la Base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges et la Base de donnes mondiale sur les zones cls pour la biodiversit, et il y a donc trs peu de diffrences entre les indicateurs nationaux et l&apos;indicateur mondial. Une source mineure de diffrence est que la Base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges incorpore les aires protges dsignes au niveau international (par exemple, les sites du patrimoine mondial de l&apos;UNESCO, les sites Ramsar, etc), dont quelques-unes ne sont pas considres par leurs nations souveraines comme des aires protges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notez que parce que les pays ne soumettent pas de donnes compltes sur les aires protges dclasses  la WDPA, les valeurs antrieures de l&apos;indicateur peuvent marginalement sous-estimer la couverture. En outre, il y a galement un dcalage entre le moment o une zone protge est dsigne sur le terrain et le moment o elle est signale  la WDPA. Ainsi, la couverture actuelle ou rcente peut galement tre sous-estime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Rfrences &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unep-wcmc.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.unep-wcmc.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.birdlife.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.birdlife.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iucn.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.iucn.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rfrences:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ces mtadonnes sont bases sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://mdgs.un.org/unsd/mi/wiki/7-6-Proportion-of-terrestrial-and-marine-areas-protected.ashx&quot;&gt;http://mdgs.un.org/unsd/mi/wiki/7-6-Proportion-of-terrestrial-and-marine-areas-protected.ashx&lt;/a&gt;, compltes par &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bipindicators.net/paoverlays%20&quot;&gt;http://www.bipindicators.net/paoverlays&lt;/a&gt; et les rfrences numres ci-dessous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BIRDLIFE INTERNATIONAL (2014). Zones importantes pour les oiseaux et la biodiversit : un rseau mondial pour conserver la nature et en faire profiter les gens. Cambridge, UK : BirdLife International. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.datazone.birdlife.org/sowb/sowbpubs#IBA&quot;&gt;www.datazone.birdlife.org/sowb/sowbpubs#IBA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BIRDLIFE INTERNATIONAL (2019). &lt;em&gt;Base de donnes mondiale des zones cls pour la biodiversit.&lt;/em&gt;Dveloppe par le partenariat KBA : BirdLife International, Union internationale pour la conservation de la nature, Amphibian Survival Alliance, Conservation International, Critical Ecosystem Partnership Fund, Global Environment Facility, Global Wildlife Conservation, NatureServe, Rainforest Trust, Royal Society for the Protection of Birds, Wildlife Conservation Society et World Wildlife Fund. Version de septembre 2019. Disponible  l&apos;adresse &lt;a href=&quot;http://keybiodiversity.areas.org/site/search&quot;&gt;http://keybiodiversity.areas.org/site/search&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BROOKS, T. et al. (2001). Priorits de conservation des oiseaux et de la biodiversit : les zones importantes pour les oiseaux d&apos;Afrique de l&apos;Est reprsentent-elles la diversit des espces dans d&apos;autres groupes de vertbrs terrestres ? Ostrich suppl. 15 : 3  12. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.2989/00306520109485329%23.VafbVJPVq75.&quot;&gt;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.2989/00306520109485329#.VafbVJPVq75.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BROOKS, T.M. et al. (2016) Objectif 15 : La vie sur terre. Grer durablement les forts, lutter contre la dsertification, stopper et inverser la dgradation des terres, enrayer la perte de biodiversit. Pp. 497  522 in Dur&amp;#xE1;n y Lalaguna, P., D&amp;#xED;az Barrado, C.M.&amp;amp; Fern&amp;#xE1;ndez Liesa, C.R. (eds.) Socit internationale et objectifs de dveloppement durable. Editorial Aranzadi, Cizur Menor, Espagne. Disponible sur : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thomsonreuters.es/es/tienda/pdp/duo.html?pid=10008456&quot;&gt;https://www.thomsonreuters.es/es/tienda/pdp/duo.html?pid=10008456&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2010). Global biodiversity : indicators of recent declines. Science 328 : 1164  1168. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/328/5982/1164.short&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/328/5982/1164.short&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2012). La protection de sites importants pour la biodiversit contribue  atteindre les objectifs de conservation mondiaux. PLoS One 7(3) : e32529. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0032529&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0032529&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2015). Insuffisances et solutions pour atteindre les objectifs nationaux et mondiaux en matire de zones de conservation. Conservation Letters 8 : 329  337. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12158/full&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12158/full&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBD (2014). Perspectives mondiales de la biodiversit 4. Convention sur la diversit biologique, Montral, Canada. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/gbo4/.&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/gbo4/.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CHAPE, S. et al. (2005). Mesurer l&apos;tendue et l&apos;efficacit des zones protges comme indicateur pour atteindre les objectifs mondiaux en matire de biodiversit. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B 360 : 443  445. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/360/1454/443.short&quot;&gt;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/360/1454/443.short&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DEGUIGNET, M., et al. (2014). Liste 2014 des aires protges des Nations Unies. PNUE-WCMC, Cambridge, Royaume-Uni. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://unep-wcmc.org/system/dataset_file_fields/files/000/000/263/original/2014_UN_List_of_Protected_Areas_EN_web.PDF?1415613322&quot;&gt;http://unep-wcmc.org/system/dataset_file_fields/files/000/000/263/original/2014_UN_List_of_Protected_Areas_EN_web.PDF?1415613322&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DI MARCO, M., et al. (2016). Quantifier l&apos;irremplaabilit relative des zones importantes pour les oiseaux et la biodiversit. Conservation Biology 30 : 392  402. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/cobi.12609/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/cobi.12609/abstract&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DONALD, P. et al. (2018) Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas (IBAs) : the development and characteristics of a global inventory of key sites for biodiversity. Bird Conserv. Internat. 29:177  198.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DUDLEY, N. (2008). Lignes directrices pour l&apos;application des catgories de gestion des aires protges. Union internationale pour la conservation de la nature (UICN). Gland, Suisse. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9243&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9243&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDGAR, G.J. et al. (2008). Key Biodiversity Areas as globally significant target sites for the conservation of marine biological diversity. Aquatic Conservation : Ecosystmes marins et d&apos;eau douce 18 : 969  983. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/aqc.902/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/aqc.902/abstract&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EKEN, G. et al. (2004). Key biodiversity areas as site conservation targets. BioScience 54 : 1110  1118. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/54/12/1110.short&quot;&gt;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/54/12/1110.short&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOSTER, M.N. et al. (2012) The identification of sites of biodiversity conservation significance : progress with the application of a global standard. Journal of Threatened Taxa 4 : 2733  2744. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.threatenedtaxa.in/index.php/JoTT/article/view/779&quot;&gt;http://www.threatenedtaxa.in/index.php/JoTT/article/view/779&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zones administratives mondiales (2019). Base de donnes GADM des zones administratives mondiales, version 2.8. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gadm.org/home&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.gadm.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HAN, X. et al. (2014). Un tableau de bord des indicateurs de la biodiversit : relever les dfis du suivi des progrs vers les objectifs d&apos;Aichi en matire de biodiversit en utilisant des donnes mondiales dsagrges. PLoS ONE 9(11) : e112046. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0112046&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0112046&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOLLAND, R.A. et al. (2012). Priorits de conservation de la biodiversit d&apos;eau douce : l&apos;approche des zones cls pour la biodiversit affine et teste pour l&apos;Afrique continentale. Biological Conservation 148 : 167  179. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320712000298&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320712000298&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UICN (2016). Une norme mondiale pour l&apos;identification des zones cls pour la biodiversit. Union internationale pour la conservation de la nature, Gland, Suisse. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JONAS, H.D. et al. (2014) New steps of change : looking beyond protected areas to consider other effective area-based conservation measures. Parks 20 : 111  128. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://parksjournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/PARKS-20.2-Jonas-et-al-10.2305IUCN.CH_.2014.PARKS-20-2.HDJ_.en_.pdf&quot;&gt;http://parksjournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/PARKS-20.2-Jonas-et-al-10.2305IUCN.CH_.2014.PARKS-20-2.HDJ_.en_.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KNIGHT, A. T. et al. (2007). Improving the Key Biodiversity Areas approach for effective conservation planning. BioScience 57 : 256 261. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/57/3/256.short&quot;&gt;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/57/3/256.short&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LANGHAMMER, P. F. et al. (2007). Identification et analyse des lacunes des zones cls pour la biodiversit : Targets for Comprehensive Protected Area Systems. Commission mondiale des aires protges de l&apos;UICN, Best Practice Protected Area Guidelines Series No. 15. UICN, Gland, Suisse. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9055&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9055&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LEVERINGTON, F. et al. (2010). Une analyse globale de l&apos;efficacit de la gestion des aires protges. Environmental Management 46 : 685  698. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00267-010-9564-5#page-1&quot;&gt;http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00267-010-9564-5#page-1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MONTESINO POUZOLS, F., et al. (2014) Global protected area expansion is compromised by projected land-use and parochialism. Nature 516 : 383  386. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v516/n7531/abs/nature14032.html&quot;&gt;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v516/n7531/abs/nature14032.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOLTE, C. &amp;amp; AGRAWAL, A. (2013). Lier les indicateurs d&apos;efficacit de la gestion aux effets observs des zones protges sur l&apos;occurrence des incendies dans la fort tropicale amazonienne. Conservation Biology 27 : 155  165. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2012.01930.x/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2012.01930.x/abstract&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PAIN, D.J. et al. (2005) Biodiversity representation in Uganda&amp;#x2019;s forest IBAs. Biological Conservation 125 : 133  138. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320705001412&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320705001412&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RICKETTS, T. H. et al. (2005). Pinpointing and preventing imminent extinctions. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the U.S.A. 102 : 18497  18501. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/102/51/18497.short&quot;&gt;http://www.pnas.org/content/102/51/18497.short&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RODRIGUES, A. S. L. et al. (2004). Efficacit du rseau mondial de zones protges pour reprsenter la diversit des espces. Nature 428 : 640  643. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v428/n6983/abs/nature02422.html&quot;&gt;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v428/n6983/abs/nature02422.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RODR&amp;#xCD;GUEZ-RODR&amp;#xCD;GUEZ, D., et al. (2011). Progrs vers les objectifs internationaux de couverture des aires protges en montagne : une valuation multi-chelle. Biological Conservation 144 : 2978  2983. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320711003454&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320711003454&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TITTENSOR, D. et al. (2014). Une analyse  mi-parcours des progrs vers les objectifs internationaux en matire de biodiversit. Science 346 : 241  244. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/346/6206/241.short&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/346/6206/241.short&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNEP-WCMC (2019). Manuel d&apos;utilisation de la base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges 1.6. PNUE-WCMC, Cambridge, Royaume-Uni. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://wcmc.io/WDPA_Manual&quot;&gt;http://wcmc.io/WDPA_Manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNEP-WCMC &amp;amp; IUCN (2020). La base de donnes mondiale sur les aires protges (WDPA). PNUE-WCMC, Cambridge, Royaume-Uni. Disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net&quot;&gt;http://www.protectedplanet.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt; 15:          , ,   ,          &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 15.1:  2020  ,            ,    , - ,    ,    ,    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 15.1.2:            ,   ,     &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  : 12  2020  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;   &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;():&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     -      (UNEP-WCMC)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      (BLI) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     () &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;    &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;             ,   ,                    (. . ,        ),     .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  ,        (IUCN; Dudley 2008),      , ,                      .  ,          ,  ,    :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Ia:   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Ib:    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; II:   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; III:      &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; IV:          &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; V:   /   &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; VI:        &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &quot;&quot;   ,            (,     ..)      .         ,    ,  -  -   (, ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ,         ,      ,   &lt;em&gt;         &lt;/em&gt; (, 2016 .),    .       : (a)     ,   ,       ,      ,         13000      (BirdLife International 2014, Donald &lt;em&gt; et al. &lt;/em&gt; 2018); (b)       (  ., 2005),   ,             -  ,            ,    ,   853     1483  , , , ,  ,  ,  ,    ; (c)    ,             (Langhammer &lt;em&gt; et al. &lt;/em&gt; 2007),  ,       ,        .        ,                  ( 2016).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;   &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;           ,        .      ,           ,      .    ,    ,                           (Deguignet et al. 2014).    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net/&quot;&gt;     &lt;/a&gt;,         -       (UNEP-WCMC)      (),           (Juffe-Bignoli et al. 2014).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                ,      .               ,    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;,
 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;World Database on Key Biodiversity Areas&lt;/a&gt;,
        .  ,               &lt;a href=&quot;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&quot;&gt;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&lt;/a&gt;,               &lt;a 
 ref=&quot;https://zeroextinction.org&quot;&gt;https://zeroextinction.org&lt;/a&gt;         ,     ,   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;         &lt;/a&gt;,             &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/login&quot;&gt;            &lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; .    . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;  :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      -       (UNEP-WCMC)        5-10    ,    / .           -       (UNEP-WCMC)      /     (),        ,             .                 . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;  :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;,     ,      ,   .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;   &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;           ,        .                ,      .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;   &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      -      (UNEP-WCMC)      () &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                     -      (UNEP-WCMC)            (Deguignet et al. 2014).    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net/&quot;&gt;   &lt;/a&gt;,    UNEP-WCMC  ,           (UNEP-WCMC 2016 ).         &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/&quot;&gt;        &lt;/a&gt;,       (2019).  ,               &lt;a href=&quot;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&quot;&gt;http://datazone.birdlife.org/site/search&lt;/a&gt;,               &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zeroextinction.org/search.cfm&quot;&gt; http://www.zeroextinction.org/search.cfm &lt;/a&gt;.               &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/login&quot;&gt;           &lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                      .                   ,           ,   , - ,           .  , ,   ,              (, ),    -          15.1 . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;            .  ,    ,          .               .   ,        :      ;  ;      ;      ;   ,   ;         .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     ,               ,   ,                    100 (, Chape et al. 2005).                   (Rodrigues et al. 2004), ,  ,           ,   ,  ,   ,   .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                  20112020 . (CBD 2014, Tittensor et al., 2014),          2010      (Butchart et al. 2010). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;   :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                 .           -       (UNEP-WCMC)                .                   (UNEP-WCMC 2019)       .        &lt;em&gt;         &lt;/em&gt; (BirdLife International 2019). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;               ,           ,   .          .  ,         ,      (Leverington et al. 2010).                11   ,         (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bipindicators.net/pamanagement&quot;&gt;http://www.bipindicators.net/pamanagement&lt;/a&gt;).                 (Nolte &amp;amp; Agrawal 2013).       &amp;#x201C;   &amp;#x201D;,    ,         ,  , ,             .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;       -    ,       ,        .  , &amp;#x201C;    ,     &amp;#x201D;, ,      11                2011-2013 ., ,         ,         ,   ,    ,     ,      (Jonas et al. 2014).   ,    OECM -  &quot;     ,    &quot; (&amp;#x201C;   ,    ,      ,             ,      ,  ,   , , , -         &amp;#x201D;)      2018 ,         UNEP-WCMC   .    OECM       -       (UNEP-WCMC)    ,     &quot;     ,    &quot; (WD-OECM). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    ,      ,             , ,  (      )  ,     (      ).                    (Brooks et al. 2001, Pain et al. 2005),         (IUCN 2016)     (, , )       ,        (Eken et al. 2004, Knight et al. 2007, Langhammer et al. 2007, Foster et al. 2012).      &amp;lt; 50% ,       ,    ,            ,     . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;            ,          ( )       (Di Marco et al., 2016, Montesino Pouzols et al.2014).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     : a)                  ( 2016)       , ,    ; )                     ,    (  ).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;  &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;  : &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     ,                   (     -       (UNEP-WCMC),     (IUCN 2020))            (        ,      ,            ).                      (   &amp;#x2018; adm0 &amp;#x2019;       (GADM 2019),            ,    95%     (,        ).         ,     ,     ,           &amp;#x2018;   &amp;#x2019;.       ,        ,     ,           (,          ).     (        ArcGIS)   ,        (   ,    10   ),                ,   - ,    ,          (. . ,   . .).      ,         ,      ,   .         ( )  ,        ,   (, , -   . .),     ,            ,          .      ,        ,        ,    ,   ,     ,       .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      ~ 12%         ,            .    ,             ,       1000    .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  2017          ,    .             ,   ,                          . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;   : &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;   : &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;              ,          . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;     : &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      ,    ,           ,   .     , ,      ,     ,         .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;  : &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     -      UNEP-WCMC)  ,            ,         (BLI)      ()          ,    . UNEP-WCMC           ,                  .                 -      (UNEP-WCMC)      (),          .           ,        ,   , , ,  ,   ()  /   ().           ,        ,     ,          ,    &quot;&quot;  &quot;   &quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;           : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      (WDPA)       1959 ,         713 (XXVIII)        .     : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&quot;&gt; https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&lt;/a&gt;.        1961/62, 1966/71, 1972  (   1966/71), 1973, 1974, 1975, 1980, 1982, 1985, 1990, 1993, 1997, 2003, 2014  2018 ,                  (). ,  2014          ()                (PoWPA)         2014  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas-2014&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas/united-nations-list-of-protected-areas-2014&lt;/a&gt;).  ,         ,          .       (MetadataID),        ,     .                   .  ,    ,              (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&lt;/a&gt;)    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net&quot;&gt;www.protectedplanet.net&lt;/a&gt;,               .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     ,          (   ),    (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http: //www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;).  , (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/what-are-kbas&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/what-are-kbas&lt;/a&gt;)       -   ,    - .   ,    ,    ,       ,               ( ,    ).             ,    ,     120             (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.birdlife.org/worldwide/partnership/birdlife-partners&quot;&gt;http://www.birdlife.org/worldwide/partnership/birdlife -partners&lt;/a&gt;), 93          (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zeroextinction.org/partners.html&quot;&gt;http://www.zeroextinction.org /partners.html&lt;/a&gt;),                     ,        (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cepf.net/resources/publications/Pages/ecosystem_profiles.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.cepf.net/resources/publications/Pages/ecosystem_profiles.aspx&lt;/a&gt;),      ,    .        .          ,         . ,            ,    -     (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;        (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&lt;/a&gt;)   ,    ,       ,              ,       ,        .                    : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/calculating-protected-area-coverage&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/calculating-protected-area-coverage&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;#x201C;        &amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&lt;/a&gt;)   ,        ,    ,   -    (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;).   (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&lt;/a&gt;),        : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;           ; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;   ,              ,  ,         ,          ,  ; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;        -        ;  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;   ,             (.  3.3 ). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                .  ,   ,   ,         ,    ,       .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;  : &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ,                : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manual&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-manua &lt;/a&gt;,    ,    .      &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-areas&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/world-database-on-protected-area&lt;/a&gt;, ,             : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-lookup-tables&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net/c/wdpa-lookup-tables&lt;/a&gt;         ,        ,            .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;           (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/kba-partners&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/kba-partners&lt;/a&gt;).    -      ,   ,     ,         (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&lt;/a&gt;),      ,    ,       -    (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/get-involved&lt;/a&gt;).  ,             (   ,       ),             ,           .  R           Dias, M. (2017) &amp;#x201C;  R       &amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/userfiles/files/R_code_for_calculating_protected_area_coverage_of_KBAs_March_2017.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/userfiles/files/R_code_for_calculating_protected_area_coverage_of_KBAs_March_2017.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;   -   (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protectedplanet.net/&quot;&gt;https://www.protectedplanet.net &lt;/a&gt;),       . 3.1  ,         ,          ,   -     (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&quot;&gt;http://www.keybiodiversityareas.org/home&lt;/a&gt;),            ,        ,        (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/&quot;&gt;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/&lt;/a&gt;).         ,             .                (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/information/nfp.shtml&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/information/nfp.shtml&lt;/a&gt;),            ().&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;   &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; : &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                 (-)   1.           . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;  : &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ~ 150  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; : &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ,         ,         (, Han et al., 2014) , ,    .        ,   (Edgar et al. 2008),  (Holland et al. 2012)   (Rodr&amp;#xED;guez-Rodr&amp;#xED;guez et al. 2011).  ,           (  )      .          ,    ,       . ,           ( I &amp;#x2013; VI),        . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                      15.1,      ,           (Brooks et al., 2016), : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  14.5.1         . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  15.4.1        . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                  . ,                    .        (, , , )            .                     (Butchart et al. 2012). , ,       ,        ; ,                .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;  : &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      ,           ,           ,           .      ,          ,     (,    ,    . .),            . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; , ,                   ,         .  ,    ,        ,  ,           .  ,        . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;  &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unep-wcmc.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.unep-wcmc.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.birdlife.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.birdlife.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iucn.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.iucn.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    &lt;a href=&quot;http://mdgs.un.org/unsd/mi/wiki/7-6-Proportion-of-terrestrial-and-marine-areas-protected.ashx&quot;&gt;http://mdgs.un.org/unsd/mi/wiki/7-6-Proportion-of-terrestrial-and-marine-areas-protected.ashx&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bipindicators.net/paoverlays&quot;&gt;http://www.bipindicators.net/paoverlays&lt;/a&gt;   ,  .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BIRDLIFE INTERNATIONAL (2014). Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas: a global network for conserving nature and benefiting people. Cambridge, UK: BirdLife International.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://datazone.birdlife.org/sowb/sowbpubs#IBA&quot;&gt;http://datazone.birdlife.org/sowb/sowbpubs#IBA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BIRDLIFE INTERNATIONAL (2019) &lt;em&gt;World Database of Key Biodiversity Areas.&lt;/em&gt;Developed by the KBA Partnership: BirdLife International, International Union for the Conservation of Nature, Amphibian Survival Alliance, Conservation International, Critical Ecosystem Partnership Fund, Global Environment Facility, Global Wildlife Conservation, NatureServe, Rainforest Trust, Royal Society for the Protection of Birds, Wildlife Conservation Society and World Wildlife Fund. September 2019 version.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://keybiodiversity areas.org/site/search&quot;&gt;http://keybiodiversity areas.org/site/search&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BROOKS, T. et al. (2001). Conservation priorities for birds and biodiversity: do East African Important Bird Areas represent species diversity in other terrestrial vertebrate groups? Ostrich suppl. 15: 3&amp;#x2013;12.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.2989/00306520109485329%23.VafbVJPVq75&quot;&gt;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.2989/00306520109485329#.VafbVJPVq75&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BROOKS, T.M. et al. (2016) Goal 15: Life on land. Sustainable manage forests, combat desertification, halt and reverse land degradation, halt biodiversity loss. Pp. 497&amp;#x2013;522 in Dur&amp;#xE1;n y Lalaguna, P., D&amp;#xED;az Barrado, C.M. &amp;amp; Fern&amp;#xE1;ndez Liesa, C.R. (eds.) International Society and Sustainable Development Goals. Editorial Aranzadi, Cizur Menor, Spain.  : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thomsonreuters.es/es/tienda/pdp/duo.html?pid=10008456&quot;&gt;https://www.thomsonreuters.es/es/tienda/pdp/duo.html?pid=10008456&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2010). Global biodiversity: indicators of recent declines. Science 328: 1164&amp;#x2013;1168.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/328/5982/1164.short&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/328/5982/1164.short&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2012). Protecting important sites for biodiversity contributes to meeting global conservation targets. PLoS One 7(3): e32529.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0032529&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0032529&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2015). Shortfalls and solutions for meeting national and global conservation area targets. Conservation Letters 8: 329&amp;#x2013;337.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12158/full&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12158/full&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBD (2014). Global Biodiversity Outlook 4. Convention on Biological Diversity, Montr&amp;#xE9;al, Canada.   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/gbo4/&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/gbo4/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CHAPE, S. et al. (2005). Measuring the extent and effectiveness of protected areas as an indicator for meeting global biodiversity targets. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B 360: 443&amp;#x2013;445.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/360/1454/443.shor&quot;&gt;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/360/1454/443.shor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DEGUIGNET, M., et al. (2014). 2014 United Nations List of Protected Areas. UNEP-WCMC, Cambridge, UK.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://unep-wcmc.org/system/dataset_file_fields/files/000/000/263/original/2014_UN_List_of_Protected_Areas_EN_web.PDF?1415613322&quot;&gt;http://unep-wcmc.org/system/dataset_file_fields/files/000/000/263/original/2014_UN_List_of_Protected_Areas_EN_web.PDF?1415613322&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DI MARCO, M., et al. (2016). Quantifying the relative irreplaceability of Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas. Conservation Biology 30: 392&amp;#x2013;402.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/cobi.12609/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/cobi.12609/abstract&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DONALD, P. et al. (2018) Important Bird and Biodiversity Areas (IBAs): the development and characteristics of a global inventory of key sites for biodiversity. Bird Conserv. Internat. 29:177&amp;#x2013;198.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DUDLEY, N. (2008). Guidelines for Applying Protected Area Management Categories. International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN). Gland, Switzerland.   &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9243&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9243&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDGAR, G.J. et al. (2008). Key Biodiversity Areas as globally significant target sites for the conservation of marine biological diversity. Aquatic Conservation: Marine and Freshwater Ecosystems 18: 969&amp;#x2013;983.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/aqc.902/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/aqc.902/abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EKEN, G. et al. (2004). Key biodiversity areas as site conservation targets. BioScience 54: 1110&amp;#x2013;1118.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/54/12/1110.short&quot;&gt;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/54/12/1110.short&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOSTER, M.N. et al. (2012) The identification of sites of biodiversity conservation significance: progress with the application of a global standard. Journal of Threatened Taxa 4: 2733&amp;#x2013;2744.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.threatenedtaxa.in/index.php/JoTT/article/view/779&quot;&gt;http://www.threatenedtaxa.in/index.php/JoTT/article/view/779&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global Administrative Areas (2019). GADM database of Global Administrative Areas, version 2.8.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gadm.org/home&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.gadm.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HAN, X. et al. (2014). A Biodiversity indicators dashboard: addressing challenges to monitoring progress towards the Aichi Biodiversity Targets using disaggregated global data. PLoS ONE 9(11): e112046.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0112046&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0112046&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOLLAND, R.A. et al. (2012). Conservation priorities for freshwater biodiversity: the key biodiversity area approach refined and tested for continental Africa. Biological Conservation 148: 167&amp;#x2013;   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320712000298&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320712000298&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320712000298&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320712000298&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IUCN (2016). A Global Standard for the Identification of Key Biodiversity Areas. International Union for Conservation of Nature, Gland, Switzerland.   &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/46259&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JONAS, H.D. et al. (2014) New steps of change: looking beyond protected areas to consider other effective area-based conservation measures. Parks 20: 111&amp;#x2013;128.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://parksjournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/PARKS-20.2-Jonas-et-al-10.2305IUCN.CH_.2014.PARKS-20-2.HDJ_.en_.pdf&quot;&gt;http://parksjournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/PARKS-20.2-Jonas-et-al-10.2305IUCN.CH_.2014.PARKS-20-2.HDJ_.en_.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KNIGHT, A. T. et al. (2007). Improving the Key Biodiversity Areas approach for effective conservation planning. BioScience 57: 256&amp;#x2013;261.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/57/3/256.short&quot;&gt;http://bioscience.oxfordjournals.org/content/57/3/256.short&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LANGHAMMER, P. F. et al. (2007). Identification and Gap Analysis of Key Biodiversity Areas: Targets for Comprehensive Protected Area Systems. IUCN World Commission on Protected Areas Best Practice Protected Area Guidelines Series No. 15. IUCN, Gland, Switzerland.   &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9055&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9055&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LEVERINGTON, F. et al. (2010). A global analysis of protected area management effectiveness. Environmental Management 46: 685&amp;#x2013;698.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00267-010-9564-5#page-1&quot;&gt;http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00267-010-9564-5#page-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MONTESINO POUZOLS, F., et al. (2014) Global protected area expansion is compromised by projected land-use and parochialism. Nature 516: 383&amp;#x2013;386.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v516/n7531/abs/nature14032.html&quot;&gt;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v516/n7531/abs/nature14032.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOLTE, C. &amp;amp; AGRAWAL, A. (2013). Linking management effectiveness indicators to observed effects of protected areas on fire occurrence in the Amazon rainforest. Conservation Biology 27: 155&amp;#x2013;165.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2012.01930.x/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2012.01930.x/abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PAIN, D.J. et al. (2005) Biodiversity representation in Uganda&amp;#x2019;s forest IBAs. Biological Conservation 125: 133&amp;#x2013;138.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320705001412&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320705001412&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RICKETTS, T. H. et al. (2005). Pinpointing and preventing imminent extinctions. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the U.S.A. 102: 18497&amp;#x2013;18501.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pnas.org/content/102/51/18497.short&quot;&gt;http://www.pnas.org/content/102/51/18497.short&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RODRIGUES, A. S. L. et al. (2004). Effectiveness of the global protected area network in representing species diversity. Nature 428: 640&amp;#x2013;643.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v428/n6983/abs/nature02422.html&quot;&gt;http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v428/n6983/abs/nature02422.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RODR&amp;#xCD;GUEZ-RODR&amp;#xCD;GUEZ, D., et al. (2011). Progress towards international targets for protected area coverage in mountains: a multi-scale assessment. Biological Conservation 144: 2978&amp;#x2013;2983.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320711003454&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006320711003454&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TITTENSOR, D. et al. (2014). A mid-term analysis of progress towards international biodiversity targets. Science 346: 241&amp;#x2013;244.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/346/6206/241.short&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/346/6206/241.short&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNEP-WCMC (2019). World Database on Protected Areas User Manual 1.6. UNEP-WCMC, Cambridge, UK.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://wcmc.io/WDPA_Manual&quot;&gt;http://wcmc.io/WDPA_Manual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNEP-WCMC &amp;amp; IUCN (2020). The World Database on Protected Areas (WDPA). UNEP-WCMC, Cambridge, UK.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.protectedplanet.net&quot;&gt;http://www.protectedplanet.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
