<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 15-4-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 15: Protect, restore and promote sustainable use of terrestrial ecosystems, sustainably manage forests, combat desertification, and halt and reverse land degradation and halt biodiversity loss&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 15.4: By 2030, ensure the conservation of mountain ecosystems, including their biodiversity, in order to enhance their capacity to provide benefits that are essential for sustainable development&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 15.4.2: Mountain Green Cover Index&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;12 February 2021&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;6.6.1, 15.1.1, 15.2.1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mountain Green Cover Index (MGCI) is designed to measure the extent and the changes of green vegetation in mountain areas - i.e. forest, shrubs, trees, pasture land, cropland, etc. &amp;#x2013; in order to monitor progress towards the mountain target. MGCI is defined as the percentage of green cover over the total surface of the mountain region of a given country and for given reporting year. The aim of the index is to monitor the evolution of the green cover and thus assess the status of conservation of mountain ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mountain Green Cover index is based on two descriptor layers of information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;u&gt;A mountain descriptor layer&lt;/u&gt;: mountains can be defined with reference to a variety of parameters, such as climate, elevation, ecology (K&amp;#xF6;rner &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;, 2011) (Karagulle &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt;., 2017). This methodology adheres to the UNEP- WCMC mountain definition, relying in turn on the mountain description proposed by Kapos &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (2000).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This description classifies mountains according altitude, slope and elevation range into 6 categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Mountain Class &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Description &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Elevation &amp;gt; 4.500 meters&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Elevation 3.500&amp;#x2013;4.500 meters&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Elevation 2.500&amp;#x2013;3.500 meters&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Elevation 1.500&amp;#x2013;2.500 meters and slope &amp;gt; 2&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Elevation 1.000&amp;#x2013;1.500 meters and slope &amp;gt; 5 or local elevation range (LER 7 kilometer radius) &amp;gt; 300 meters&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Elevation 300&amp;#x2013;1.000 meters and local elevation range (7 kilometer radius) &amp;gt; 300 meters&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;u&gt;A vegetation descriptor layer&lt;/u&gt;: The vegetation descriptor layer categorizes land cover into green and non-green areas. Green vegetation includes both natural vegetation and vegetation resulting from anthropic activity (e.g. crops, afforestation, etc.). Non-green areas include very sparsely vegetated areas, bare land, water, permanent ice/snow and urban areas. The vegetation description layer can be derived in different ways, but remote sensing based land cover maps are the most convenient data source for this purpose, as they provide the required information on green and non-green areas in a spatially explicit manner and allow for comparison over time through land cover change analysis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, FAO uses land cover time series produced by the European Space Agency (ESA) under the Climate Change Initiative (CCI) as a general solution. The original CCI classes are re-classified into six IPCC classes and further into binary green/non-green cover classes as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;ESA CCI class&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;IPCC class&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Green / Non green&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;50, 60, 61, 62, 70, 71, 72, 80, 81, 82, 90, 100&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Forest&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Green&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;110, 120, 121, 122, 130, 140, &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Grassland&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Green&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;10,11, 12, 20, 30, 40&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Cropland&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Green&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;160, 170, 180&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Wetland&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Green&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;190&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Settlement&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Non Green&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;150, 151, 152, 153, 200, 201, 202, 210, 220&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Other land&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Non Green&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Please note, that here the term &amp;#x201C;Forest&amp;#x201D; refers to land cover, not necessarily land use &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Proportion (0 to 100)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Global estimates computed by FAO are derived using the following data sources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Vegetation descriptor layer: ESA CCI Land Cover data (ESA, 2017)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The European Space Agency Climate Change Initiative (ESA CCI) is a programme aiming at exploiting the full potential of the earth observation data collected by ESA to contribute to the Essential Climate Variables databases required by the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CCI Land Cover products have been produced using a combination of remote sensing data such as the 300 m MERIS, 1km SPOT &amp;#x2013;VEGETATION, 1km PROBA &amp;#x2013;V and 1km AVHRR. The CCI product consists of a series of annual Land Cover maps at 300 m resolution spanning the period 1992 to 2018. The period from 1992-2015 is available in raster format, whereas the 2016-2018 is available in netCDF format and a transformation to GTIFF is required to make these datasets available for processing in a GIS environment. The land cover data is updated every year by the European Space Agency. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ESA CCI adheres to the Cover Classification System of the United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization (UN FAO) (Santoro &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt;., 2015). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mountain descriptor layer:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The global mountain descriptor layer is based on the mountain classification proposed by Kapos &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (2000):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Class 1: elevation &amp;gt; 4500 meters &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Class 2: elevation 3500 - 4500 meters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Class 3: elevation 2500 &amp;#x2013; 3500 meters &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Class 4: elevation 1500 &amp;#x2013; 2500 meters and slope &amp;#x2265; 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Class 5: elevation 1,000&amp;#x2013;1,500 meters and slope &amp;#x2265; 5 or local elevation range (7 kilometers radius) &amp;#x2265; 300 meters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Class 6: elevation 300&amp;#x2013;1,000 meters and local elevation range (7 kilometres radius) &amp;#x2265; 300 meters outside 23&amp;#xB0;N&amp;#x2014;19&amp;#xB0;S &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Class 0: Defined to represent the non-mountainous areas. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mountain description layer used to derive the global estimates was created by the US Geological Survey from a 250 m DEM (Sayre &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; 2018)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These datasets may be replaced by nationally relevant data sources when available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The indicator is generated for all countries and regions having mountain areas by FAO using the geospatial data layers described in this document. FAO shares country figures with NSO SDG focal points for their validation before publication, in accordance to the IAEG-SDG guidelines of Global Data Flows and Reporting. On the same occasion, FAO requests countries to provide their own estimates for the indicator in case these are available. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;ESA CCI Land Cover is available from 1992 to 2018. A new global land cover map is delivered every year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All data are already available &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;European Space Agency (ESA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United States Geological Survey (USGS) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FAO&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Article 1 of FAO&amp;#x2019;s constitution specifies that, &amp;#x201C;The Organization shall collect, analyze, interpret, and disseminate information related to nutrition, food and agriculture.&amp;#x201D; In this regard, FAO collects national level data from member countries, which it then standardizes and disseminates through corporate statistical databases. FAO is the custodian UN agency for 21 SDG indicators, including 15.4.2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mountain ecosystems are important biodiversity centres that provide valuable ecosystem services to upstream and downstream areas. Yet, mountains are very fragile and impacted easily by both natural and anthropogenic factors. These can include climate change, natural hazards such as landslides and flooding, unplanned agricultural expansion, unplanned urbanization, timber extraction and recreational activities. The degradation of mountain ecosystems such as loss of the glacial cover, mountain biodiversity and green cover will affect the ability of the ecosystem to supply water downstream. The loss of forest and vegetative cover will reduce the ability of the ecosystem to retain soil and prevent landslides and flooding downstream. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, monitoring mountain vegetation changes provides information on the status of mountain ecosystems. Monitoring the MGCI over time can provide information on the extent of vegetation change and of the general health of the mountain ecosystem. Assessing the change of green cover differentiated by elevation is important in understanding the changes that are occurring in the mountain regions due to the influence of slope, aspect and altitude of the mountain terrain to the ecosystem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the MGCI values should be interpreted with care. It does not provide the details on species change, change in the tree line or rain shadow areas. Understanding the variation in the species composition and the tree line will be important in identifying the long-term impacts of climate change in mountain regions. Analysing the vegetative variations in each of the elevation zones over time will assist in determining the appropriate management and adaption measures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases, an increase in the indicator value in high elevation classes may also signify the encroachment of vegetation on areas previously covered by glaciers or other permanent or semi-permanent ice or snow layers, as a result of global warming due to climate change. Such a change can be tracked with the current methodology and flagged accordingly at the level of disaggregated data by land cover type and elevation class, to distinguish this case from the general desired trend of increasing mountain green cover.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The indicator can be calculated using freely available Earth Observation data and simple GIS operations that can be processed in free and open source software (FOSS) GIS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Potential limitations of the above describe methodology are related mainly to the quality of the land cover data. The ESA CCI land cover maps are currently available at 300 meter resolution which limits their applicability in the monitoring of small and highly heterogeneous landscapes. Therefore, if countries have national land cover maps of higher spatial resolution and comparable or better quality, FAO advises using them, following the same methodology presented here, for the generation of MGCI values. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the interpretation of the indicator, although in the great majority of cases the desired direction is an increase in green mountain cover which reflects restriction of damage to natural ecosystems and possibly even the expansion of forest, shrubland and grasslands through conservation efforts, in more limited cases, an increase in the indicator value in high elevation classes may also signify the encroachment of vegetation on areas previously covered by glaciers or other permanent or semi-permanent ice or snow layers, as a result of global warming due to climate change. Such a change can be tracked with the current methodology and flagged accordingly at the level of disaggregated data by land cover type and elevation class, to distinguish this case from the general desired trend of increasing mountain green cover.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Computation Method:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mountain Green Cover Index is defined as &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;M&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;G&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;C&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;I&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;M&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;G&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;C&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;v&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;A&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;T&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;M&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;A&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;&amp;#xD7;&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;100&lt;/mn&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where Mountain Green Cover area = Sum of areas covered by Cropland, Grassland, Forest and Wetland land cover classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vegetation descriptor is calculated from a land cover map using basic GIS functions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the country/region has no mountain area, it will be assigned value N/A.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Country figures generated by FAO are sent to official NSO SDG focal points for validation before publication. Indicator values provided by countries are considered validated. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At country level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not applicable, as the indicator has a universal coverage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At regional and global levels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not applicable, as the indicator has a universal coverage&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using spatially explicit data allows straightforward calculation of the indicator value for any delineated area. However, giving the spatial resolution of 300 meters of the CCI layer, calculation of the indicator values for smallest regions consisting of only few pixels may results in abrupt changes in the indicator values due to the relatively higher impact of classification errors. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The indicator value can be calculated as follows: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; The ESA CCI land cover classes are reclassified into six IPCC classes and Green/Non-Green cover map. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; The Kapos Elevation Ranges map is overlaid on top of the map resulting from step 1. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Zonal histogram is calculated for each country and regional grouping in such a way that the number of pixels belonging to green and non-green classes are counted within each elevation range. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; The ratio (%) between the sum of the green pixels and the total number of pixels (green plus non green) falling within each Kapos is calculated to obtain MGCI values per each Kapos class. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The same procedure is used to calculate the distribution of the land cover classes as defined by IPCC within each elevation range. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;FAO is responsible for the quality of the internal statistical processes used to compile the published datasets. The FAO Statistics Quality Assurance Framework (SQAF), available at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/docrep/019/i3664e/i3664e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/docrep/019/i3664e/i3664e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;, provides the necessary principles, guidelines and tools to carry out quality assessments. FAO is performing an internal bi-annual survey (FAO Quality Assessment and Planning Survey) designed to gather information on all of FAO&amp;#x2019;s statistical activities, notably to assess the extent to which quality standards are being implemented with a view to increasing compliance with the quality dimensions of SQAF, documenting best practices and prepare quality improvement plans, where necessary. Domain-specific quality assurance activities are carried out systematically (e.g. quality reviews, self-assessments, compliance monitoring).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data availability:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is generated by geospatial data and therefore has universal coverage. Countries with no values on the global SDG database are either A) countries with no mountains where the indicator is not applicable or B) countries that have not validated FAO&amp;#x2019;s estimates and yet have not provided figures of their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ESA CCI Land Cover Data is freely available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.esa-landcover-cci.org/?q=node/164&quot;&gt;https://www.esa-landcover-cci.org/?q=node/164&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kapos data is freely available at the below links:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The USGS Mountain Explorer Kapos classification can be found as GME_K1classes.zip in: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rmgsc.cr.usgs.gov/outgoing/ecosystems/Global/&quot;&gt;https://rmgsc.cr.usgs.gov/outgoing/ecosystems/Global/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Administrative boundaries are available from various global databases at the links below:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FAO Global Administrative Units Layer (GAUL) &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.europa.eu/euodp/data/dataset/jrc-10112-10004&quot;&gt;https://data.europa.eu/euodp/data/dataset/jrc-10112-10004&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Divas-GIS &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.diva-gis.org/gdata&quot;&gt;https://www.diva-gis.org/gdata&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UN Second Administrative Level Boundaries (SALB) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unsalb.org/&quot;&gt;https://www.unsalb.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time series:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Country, regional and global figures are available for the years 2000, 2010, 2015 and 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the global SDG database, the indicator is disaggregated by mountain elevation class (mountain descriptor). An additional disaggregation dimension, the IPCC land cover class, is available in FAO&amp;#x2019;s SDG indicators portal. The combination of six elevation classes and six main land cover types following the IPCC classification yields 36 different disaggregations per country per reporting year &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default methodology presented here is based on the use of the global ESA CCI Land Cover product, which has been reported to have an overall accuracy of 73.2%. However, the accuracy estimate was calculated using the original 22 land cover classes. As the methodology presented here is based on use of aggregate classes, the accuracy can be expected to be higher. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The accuracy of the global land cover products can vary regionally. For the same reason, the presented indicator values may differ from those derived using national land cover maps. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ESA (2017) Land Cover CCI Product User Guide Version 2. Tech. Rep. Available at:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.elie.ucl.ac.be/CCI/viewer/download/ESACCI-LC-Ph2-PUGv2_2.0.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;maps.elie.ucl.ac.be/CCI/viewer/download/ESACCI-LC-Ph2-PUGv2_2.0.pdf&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kapos, V., Rhind, J., Edwards, M., Prince, M., &amp;amp; Ravillous, C. (2000). Developing a map of the world&amp;#x2019;s mountain forests. In M. F. Price , &amp;amp; N. Butt (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Forests in Sustainable Mountain Development: A State-of-Knowledge Report for 2000&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 4-9). Wallingford: CAB International.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karagulle, D., Frye, C., Breyer, S., Aniello, P., Vaughan, R., &amp;amp; Wright, D. (2017). Modeling global Hammond landform regions from 250-m elevation data. &lt;em&gt;Transactions in GIS&lt;/em&gt;. doi:10.1111/tgis.12265&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;K&amp;#xF6;rner, C., Paulsen, J., &amp;amp; Spehn, E. (2011). A definition of mountains and their bioclimatic belts for global comparisons of biodiversity data. &lt;em&gt;Alpine Botany, 121&lt;/em&gt;, 73-78.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santoro, M., Kirches, G., Wevers, J., Boettcher, M., Brockmann, C., Lamarche, C., . . . Defourny, P. (2015). &lt;em&gt;Land Cover CCI PRODUCT USER GUIDE VERSION 2.0.&lt;/em&gt; European Spatial Agency. European Spatial Agency. Retrieved from http://maps.elie.ucl.ac.be/CCI/viewer/download/ESACCI-LC-Ph2-PUGv2_2.0.pdf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sayre, R., Frye, C. Karagulle, D., Krauer, J, Breyer, S., Aniello, P., Wright, D.J., Payne, D., Adler, C. Warner, H., VanSistine, D.P. &amp;amp; Cress, J. (2018). A New High-Resolution Map of World Mountains and an Online Tool for Visualizing and Comparing Characterizations of Global Mountain Distributions. &lt;em&gt;Mountain Research and Development&lt;/em&gt;, 38(3), 240-249. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 15: Proteger, restablecer y promover el uso sostenible de los ecosistemas terrestres, gestionar sosteniblemente los bosques, luchar contra la desertificación, detener e invertir la degradación de las tierras y detener la pérdida de biodiversidad&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 15.4: De aquí a 2030, asegurar la conservación de los ecosistemas montañosos, incluida su diversidad biológica, a fin de mejorar su capacidad de proporcionar beneficios esenciales para el desarrollo sostenible&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 15.4.2: Índice de cobertura verde de las montañas&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Última actualización: 14 de diciembre de 2020&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicadores relacionados&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.6.1, 15.1.1, 15.2.1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Información institucional&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organización(es):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organización de las Naciones Unidas para la Agricultura y la Alimentación (FAO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El Índice de Cobertura Verde (ICMG, por sus siglas en inglés) está diseñado para medir la extensión y los cambios de la vegetación verde en las zonas de montaña, es decir, bosques, arbustos, árboles, pastos, tierras de cultivo, etc. &amp;#x2013; con el fin de supervisar los avances en el objetivo de la montaña.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El ICMG se define como el porcentaje de cobertura verde sobre la superficie total de la región montañosa de un país determinado y para un año determinado. El objetivo del índice es supervisar la evolución de la cubierta verde y evaluar así el estado de conservación de los ecosistemas de montaña.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El índice de cobertura verde de las montañas se basa en dos capas de información descriptiva:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;1.Una capa descriptiva de la montaña&lt;/u&gt;: las montañas pueden definirse con referencia a una variedad de parámetros, como el clima, la elevación, la ecología (K&amp;#xF6;rner, Paulsen, &amp;amp; Spehn, 2011) (Karagulle, et al., 2017). Esta metodología se adhiere a la definición de montaña del PNUMA- WCMC, basándose a su vez en la descripción de la montaña propuesta por (Kapos, Rhind, Edwards, Prince, &amp;amp; Ravillous, 2000).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Esta descripción clasifica las montañas según la altitud, la pendiente y el rango de elevación en 6 categorías.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Clase de montaña&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Descripción &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Elevación &amp;gt; 4.500 metros&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Elevación 3.500&amp;#x2013;4.500 metros&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Elevación 2.500&amp;#x2013;3.500 metros&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Elevación 1.500&amp;#x2013;2.500 metros y pendiente &amp;gt; 2&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Elevación 1.000&amp;#x2013;1.500 metros y pendiente &amp;gt; 5 o rango de elevación local (LER 7 kilómetros de radio) &amp;gt; 300 metros&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Elevación 300&amp;#x2013;1.000 metros y rango de elevación local (7 kilómetros de radio) &amp;gt; 300 metros&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;2. Una capa descriptiva de la vegetación&lt;/u&gt;: La capa descriptiva de vegetación clasifica la cobertura del suelo en áreas verdes y no verdes. La vegetación verde incluye tanto la vegetación natural como la resultante de la actividad antrópica (por ejemplo, cultivos, forestación, etc.). Las zonas no verdes incluyen las zonas con muy&amp;#xA0;escasa&amp;#xA0;vegetación&amp;#xA0;, la tierra desnuda, el agua, el hielo/nieve permanente y las zonas urbanas. La capa de descripción de la vegetación puede obtenerse de diferentes maneras, pero los mapas de la cubierta terrestre basados en la teledetección son la fuente de datos más conveniente para este fin, ya que proporcionan la información necesaria sobre las zonas verdes y no verdes de forma espacialmente explícita y permiten la comparación a lo largo del tiempo mediante el análisis de los cambios en la cubierta terrestre. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actualmente, la FAO utiliza las series temporales de la cubierta terrestre producidas por la Agencia Espacial Europea (AEE) en el marco de la Iniciativa sobre el Cambio Climático (ICC) como solución general. Las clases originales de la ICC se reclasifican en seis clases del IPCC y, además, en clases binarias de cobertura verde/no verde como sigue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Clase ICC de la AEE&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Clase IPCC&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Verde / No verde&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;50, 60, 61, 62, 70, 71, 72, 80, 81, 82, 90, 100&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Bosque&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-1&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Verde&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;110, 120, 121, 122, 130, 140, &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Pasturas&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Verde&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;10,11, 12, 20, 30, 40&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tierras de cultivo&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Verde&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;160, 170, 180&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Humedal&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Verde&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;190&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Asentamiento&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;No verde&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;150, 151, 152, 153, 200, 201, 202, 210, 220&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Otros terrenos&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;No verde&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Tenga en cuenta que aquí el término &amp;#x201C;Bosque&amp;#x201D; se refiere a la cobertura del suelo, no necesariamente al uso del suelo &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1)Datos de la AEE ICC cubierta terrestre: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Iniciativa sobre el Cambio Climático de la Agencia Espacial Europea (ICC de la AEE) es un programa cuyo objetivo es aprovechar todo el potencial de los datos de observación de la Tierra recogidos por la AEE para contribuir a las bases de datos de las Variables Climáticas Esenciales exigidas por la Convención Marco de las Naciones Unidas sobre el Cambio Climático (CMNUCC). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los productos ICC cubierta terrestre han sido elaborados utilizando una combinación de datos de teledetección como el MERIS de 300 m, SPOT &amp;#x2013;VEGETACION de 1 km, PROBA &amp;#x2013;V de 1 km y AVHRR de 1 km. El producto ICC consiste en una serie de mapas anuales de la cubierta terrestre a 300 m de resolución que abarcan el período comprendido entre 1992 y 2018. El periodo 1992-2015 está disponible en formato raster, mientras que el 2016-2018 está disponible en formato netCDF y se requiere una transformación a GTIFF para que estos conjuntos de datos estén disponibles para su procesamiento en un entorno SIG. Los datos de la cubierta terrestre son actualizados cada año por la Agencia Espacial Europea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El ICC de la AEE se adhiere al Sistema de Clasificación de Cobertura de la Organización de las Naciones Unidas para la Agricultura y la Alimentación (FAO) (Santoro, et al., 2015). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) Capa de clase de montaña Kapos:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El conjunto de datos Kapos es un archivo ráster descriptor de montañas global. El archivo proporciona una clasificación de las cadenas montañosas de acuerdo con las definiciones propuestas por Kapos et al 2000:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clase 1: elevación &amp;gt; 4500 metros &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clase 2: elevación 3500 - 4500 metros&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clase 3: elevación 2500 &amp;#x2013; 3500 metros &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clase 4: elevación 1500 &amp;#x2013; 2500 metros y pendiente &amp;#x2265; 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clase 5: elevación 1.000&amp;#x2013;1.500 metros y pendiente &amp;#x2265; 5 o rango de elevación local (7 kilómetros de radio) &amp;#x2265; 300 metros&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clase 6: elevación 300&amp;#x2013;1.000 metros y rango de elevación local (7 kilómetros de radio) &amp;#x2265; 300 metros fuera de 23&amp;#xB0;N&amp;#x2014;19&amp;#xB0;S &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clase 0: Definida para representar las zonas no montañosas. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Proceso de recolección:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La FAO genera el indicador para todos los países y regiones que tienen zonas de montaña utilizando las capas de datos geoespaciales descritas en este documento. La FAO comparte las cifras de los países con los puntos focales de los ODS de los INE para su validación antes de la publicación, de acuerdo con las directrices del IAEG-SDG sobre flujos de datos globales y presentación de informes. En la misma ocasión, la FAO solicita a los países que proporcionen sus propias estimaciones para el indicador en caso de que estén disponibles. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendario&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recopilación de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La ICC cubierta terrestre de la AEE está disponible desde 1992 hasta 2018. Cada año se entrega un nuevo mapa global de la cubierta terrestre.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publicación de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todos los datos están ya disponibles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agencia Espacial Europea &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alianza para las Montañas, FAO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USGS &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAO&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los ecosistemas de montaña son importantes centros de biodiversidad que proporcionan valiosos servicios ecosistémicos a las zonas situadas aguas arriba y abajo. Sin embargo, las montañas son muy frágiles y se ven afectadas fácilmente por factores tanto naturales como antropogénicos. Entre ellos se encuentran el cambio climático, los riesgos naturales como los corrimientos de tierra y las inundaciones, la expansión agrícola no planificada, la urbanización no planificada, la extracción de madera y las actividades recreativas. La degradación de los ecosistemas de montaña, como la pérdida de la cubierta glaciar, la biodiversidad de la montaña y la cubierta vegetal, afectará a la capacidad del ecosistema para suministrar agua aguas abajo. La pérdida de la cubierta forestal y vegetal reducirá la capacidad del ecosistema para retener el suelo y evitar desprendimientos e inundaciones aguas abajo. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Por lo tanto, el seguimiento de los cambios en la vegetación de montaña proporciona información sobre el estado de los ecosistemas de montaña. El seguimiento del Índice de cobertura verde de las montañas (MGCI, por sus siglas en inglés) a lo largo del tiempo puede proporcionar información sobre el alcance del cambio vegetacional y de la salud general del ecosistema de montaña. La evaluación del cambio de la cubierta vegetal diferenciada por la elevación es importante para comprender los cambios que se producen en las regiones de montaña debido a la influencia de la pendiente, el aspecto y la altitud del terreno montañoso en el ecosistema. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sin embargo, los valores del MGCI deben interpretarse con cuidado. No proporciona los detalles sobre el cambio de las especies, el cambio en la línea de árboles o las zonas de sombra de la lluvia. Entender la variación en la composición de las especies y la línea de árboles será importante para identificar los impactos a largo plazo del cambio climático en las regiones de montaña. El análisis de las variaciones vegetativas en cada una de las zonas de elevación a lo largo del tiempo ayudará a determinar las medidas de gestión y adaptación adecuadas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En algunos casos, un aumento del valor del indicador en las clases de alta elevación también puede significar la invasión de la vegetación en zonas anteriormente cubiertas por glaciares u otras capas de hielo o nieve permanentes o semipermanentes, como resultado del calentamiento global debido al cambio climático. Este cambio puede rastrearse con la metodología actual y marcarse en consecuencia a nivel de datos desagregados por tipo de cubierta terrestre y clase de elevación, para distinguir este caso de la tendencia general deseada de aumento de la cubierta verde de las montañas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador puede calcularse utilizando datos de observación de la Tierra disponibles gratuitamente y operaciones sencillas de SIG que pueden procesarse en SIG de software libre y de código abierto (FOSS). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las posibles limitaciones de la metodología descrita anteriormente están relacionadas principalmente con la calidad de los datos sobre la cubierta terrestre. Los mapas de cobertura del suelo de la ICC AEE están actualmente disponibles a una resolución de 300 metros, lo que limita su aplicabilidad en el monitoreo de paisajes pequeños y altamente heterogéneos. Por lo tanto, si los países tienen mapas nacionales de cobertura territorial de mayor resolución espacial y comparable o de mejor calidad, la FAO aconseja utilizarlos, siguiendo la misma metodología presentada aquí, para la generación de valores MGCI. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En cuanto a la interpretación del indicador, aunque en la gran mayoría de los casos la dirección deseada es un aumento de la cubierta verde de montaña que refleja la restricción del daño a los ecosistemas naturales y posiblemente incluso la expansión de bosques, matorrales y pastizales a través de esfuerzos de conservación, en casos más limitados, un aumento en el valor del indicador en las clases de alta elevación también puede significar la invasión de vegetación en áreas previamente cubiertas por glaciares u otros permanentes o capas semipermanente de hielo o nieve, como resultado del calentamiento global debido al cambio climático. Ese cambio puede seguirse con la metodología actual y señalarse en consecuencia a nivel de datos desglosados por tipo de cubierta terrestre y clase de elevación, para distinguir este caso de la tendencia general deseada de aumentar la cubierta verde de las montañas. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El Índice de Cobertura Vegetal de Montaña se define como &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;MGCI = (Área de cobertura verde de la montaña/Área total de la montaña) X 100&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donde Área de Cobertura Verde de Montaña = Suma de las áreas cubiertas por las clases de cobertura terrestre de Tierras de Cultivo, Pastizales, Bosques y Humedales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El descriptor de vegetación se calcula a partir de un mapa de cobertura del suelo utilizando funciones básicas del SIG. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Si el país/región no tiene zona de montaña, se le asignará el valor N/A.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel de país:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No se aplica, ya que el indicador tiene una cobertura universal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel regional y mundial:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No procede, ya que el indicador tiene una cobertura universal&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La utilización de datos espacialmente explícitos permite calcular directamente el valor del indicador para cualquier zona delimitada. Sin embargo, teniendo en cuenta la resolución espacial de 300 metros de la capa ICC, el cálculo de los valores del indicador para las regiones más pequeñas que constan de pocos píxeles puede dar lugar a cambios bruscos en los valores del indicador debido al impacto relativamente mayor de los errores de clasificación. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Métodos y directrices a disposición de los países para la recopilación de los datos a nivel nacional:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El valor del indicador&amp;#xA0;puede calcularse como sigue:&amp;#xA0;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Las clases de cobertura del suelo de la AEE&amp;#xA0;ICC&amp;#xA0;están&amp;#xA0;reclasificadas en seis clases del IPCC&amp;#xA0;y mapa de cobertura verde/no verde&amp;#xA0;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;El mapa de rangos de elevación de Kapos&amp;#xA0;se superpone&amp;#xA0;al mapa&amp;#xA0;resultante del paso 1.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;El histograma zonal&amp;#xA0;se calcula&amp;#xA0;para cada país&amp;#xA0;y&amp;#xA0;agrupación regional&amp;#xA0;de tal manera que el número de píxeles que pertenecen a clases verdes y&amp;#xA0;no verdes&amp;#xA0;se contabilizan&amp;#xA0;dentro de cada rango de elevación.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Se calcula la relación (%) entre la suma de los píxeles verdes y el número total de píxeles (verdes más no verdes) que caen dentro de cada&amp;#xA0;Kapos&amp;#xA0;para obtener los valores de MGCI&amp;#xA0;por cada&amp;#xA0;clase de&amp;#xA0;Kapos.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;El mismo procedimiento&amp;#xA0;se utiliza&amp;#xA0;para calcular la distribución de las clases de cobertura del suelo&amp;#xA0;definidas por el IPCC dentro de cada rango de elevación.&amp;#xA0;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Garantía de calidad:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Las cifras de los países generadas por la FAO se envían a los puntos focales oficiales de los ODS para su validación antes de su publicación.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador se genera a partir de datos geoespaciales y, por tanto, tiene una cobertura universal. Los países que no tienen valores en la base de datos global de los ODS son A) países sin montañas en los que el indicador no es aplicable o B) países que no han validado las estimaciones de la FAO y que, sin embargo, no han proporcionado cifras propias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Los datos de la ICC de la AEE sobre la cubierta terrestre están disponibles de forma gratuita en &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.esa-landcover-cci.org/?q=node/164&quot;&gt;https://www.esa-landcover-cci.org/?q=node/164&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Los datos de Kapos están disponibles gratuitamente en los siguientes enlaces:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sitio web de la Alianza para las Montañas de la FAO, encontrar el archivo raster en el banner de la derecha. Acceso en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/mountain-partnership/our-work/focusareas/foodsecurity/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/mountain-partnership/our-work/focusareas/foodsecurity/en/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La clasificación Kapos del USGS Mountain Explorer se puede encontrar como GME_K1classes.zip en: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rmgsc.cr.usgs.gov/outgoing/ecosystems/Global/&quot;&gt;https://rmgsc.cr.usgs.gov/outgoing/ecosystems/Global&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Los límites administrativos están disponibles en varias bases de datos globales en los siguientes enlaces:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Capa de Unidades Administrativas Mundiales (GAUL, por sus siglas en inglés) de la FAO &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.europa.eu/euodp/data/dataset/jrc-10112-10004&quot;&gt;https://data.europa.eu/euodp/data/dataset/jrc-10112-10004&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Divas-GIS &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.diva-gis.org/gdata&quot;&gt;https://www.diva-gis.org/gdata&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Límites del segundo nivel administrativo de las Naciones Unidas (SALB) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unsalb.org/&quot;&gt;https://www.unsalb.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se dispone de cifras nacionales, regionales y mundiales para los años 2000, 2010, 2015 y 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En la base de datos global de los ODS, el indicador se desglosa por clase de elevación de la montaña (descriptor de montaña). En el portal de indicadores de los ODS de la FAO se encuentra disponible una dimensión de desagregación adicional, la clase de cubierta terrestre del IPCC. La combinación de seis clases de elevación y seis tipos principales de cobertura del suelo según la clasificación del IPCC da lugar a 36 desgloses diferentes por país y por año de referencia. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Fuentes de discrepancia:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La metodología por defecto que se presenta aquí se basa en el uso del producto global ICC cobertura terrestre de la AEE, del que se ha informado que tiene una precisión global del 73,2%. Sin embargo, la estimación de la precisión se calculó utilizando las 22 clases de cobertura del suelo originales. Como la metodología presentada aquí se basa en el uso de clases agregadas, cabe esperar que la precisión sea mayor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La precisión de los productos de cobertura terrestre global puede variar regionalmente. Por la misma razón, los valores de los indicadores presentados pueden diferir de los derivados de los mapas nacionales de la cubierta terrestre. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eurostat (2019). &lt;em&gt;Rejilla LUCAS&lt;/em&gt;. Recuperado de Eurostat Your Key to European statistcs: https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/web/lucas/data/lucas-grid &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kapos, V., Rhind, J., Edwards, M., Prince, M., &amp;amp; Ravillous, C. (2000). Developing a map of the world&amp;#x2019;s mountain forests. En M. F. Price , &amp;amp; N. Butt (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Forests in Sustainable Mountain Development: A State-of-Knowledge Report for 2000&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 4-9). Wallingford: CAB International.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karagulle, D., Frye, C., Breyer, S., Aniello, P., Vaughan, R., &amp;amp; Wright, D. (2017). Modelado de regiones globales de Hammond landform a partir de datos de elevación de 250 m. &lt;em&gt;Transacciones en SIG&lt;/em&gt;. doi:10.1111/tgis.12265&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;K&amp;#xF6;rner, C., Paulsen, J., &amp;amp; Spehn, E. (2011). Una definición de las montañas y sus cinturones bioclimáticos para las comparaciones globales de los datos de biodiversidad. &lt;em&gt;Alpine Botany, 121&lt;/em&gt;, 73-78.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santoro, M., Kirches, G., Wevers, J., Boettcher, M., Brockmann, C., Lamarche, C., . . . Defourny, P. (2015). &lt;em&gt;Land Cover CCI PRODUCT USER GUIDE VERSION 2.0.&lt;/em&gt; Agencia Espacial Europea. Agencia Espacial Europea. Recuperado de http://maps.elie.ucl.ac.be/CCI/viewer/download/ESACCI-LC-Ph2-PUGv2_2.0.pdf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mountainpartnership.org/our-work/focusareas/foodsecurity/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.mountainpartnership.org/our-work/focusareas/foodsecurity/en/&lt;/a&gt; (el ráster SIG de las montañas está disponible para su descarga en la barra de la derecha) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openforis.org/tools/collect-earth.html&quot;&gt;http://www.openforis.org/tools/collect-earth.html&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-i5175e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-i5175e.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 15 : Préserver et restaurer les écosystèmes terrestres, en veillant à les exploiter de façon durable, gérer durablement les forêts, lutter contre la désertification, enrayer et inverser le processus de dégradation des terres et mettre fin à l’appauvrissement de la biodiversité&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 15.4: D’ici à 2030, assurer la préservation des écosystèmes montagneux, notamment de leur biodiversité, afin de mieux tirer parti de leurs bienfaits essentiels pour le développement durable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 15.4.2: Indice de couvert végétal montagneux&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dernière mise à jour : 11 Juillet 2017&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Informations institutionnelles&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Organisation(s) :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Organisation des Nations Unies pour l’alimentation et l’agriculture (ONUAA)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Compilateurs de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; FAO&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 15: Защита и восстановление экосистем суши и содействие их рациональному использованию, рациональное лесопользование, борьба с опустыниванием, прекращение и обращение вспять процесса деградации земель и прекращение процесса утраты биологического разнообразия&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 15.4: К 2030 году обеспечить сохранение горных экосистем, в том числе их биоразнообразия, для того чтобы повысить их способность давать блага, необходимые для устойчивого развития&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 15.4.2: Индекс растительного покрова гор&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Последнее обновление: 14 декабря 2020 года &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Связанные показатели &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 6.6.1, 15.1.1, 15.2.1 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Институциональная информация &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Организация (и): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Продовольственная и сельскохозяйственная организация Объединенных Наций (ФАО) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Индекс растительного покрова предназначен для оценки размеров и изменений зеленой растительности в горных районах, т. е. лесов, кустарников, деревьев, пастбищ, сельскохозяйственных угодий и т. д. для того, чтобы отслеживать прогресс в горной задаче.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Индекс растительного покрова гор (ИРПГ) определяется как процентная доля растительного покрова от всей поверхности горного региона данной страны за данный отчетный год. Целью индекса является отслеживание эволюции растительного покрова и, таким образом, оценка состояния сохранности горных экосистем. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Индекс растительного покрова гор основан на информации, содержащейся в идентификаторах двух зон: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;u&gt;1. Идентификатор зоны гор&lt;/u&gt;: горы могут быть определены со ссылкой на множество параметров, таких как климат, высота над уровнем моря, экология (Korner, Paulsen, &amp; Spehn, 2011) (Karagulle , et al., 2017). Эта методология соответствует определению гор Программы ООН по окружающей среде - Всемирного центра мониторинга защиты природы (UNEP-WCMC), которое основано, в свою очередь, на описании гор, предложенном (Kapos, Rhind, Edwards, Prince, &amp; amp; Ravillous, 2000).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В этом описании горы классифицируются по высоте, уклону и перепаду высот по 6 категориям. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Класс Горы &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Описание &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 1 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Высота &amp;gt; 4,500 метров &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 2 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Высота 3,500 &amp;#x2013; 4,500 метров &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 3 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Высота 2,500 &amp;#x2013; 3,500 метров &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 4 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Высота 1.500 &amp;#x2013; 2.500 метров и уклон &amp;gt; 2 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 5 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Высота 1.000 &amp;#x2013; 1.500 метров и уклон &amp;gt; 5 или местный перепад
высот (местный перепад высот в радиусе 7 километров) &amp;gt; 300 метров &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 6 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td colspan=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Высота 300 &amp;#x2013; 1.000 метров и местный перепад высот (в радиусе
7 километров) &amp;gt; 300 метров &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;u&gt; 2. Идентификатор зоны растительности &lt;/u&gt;: Идентификатор зоны растительности подразделяет земной покров на зеленые и не зелёные области. Область зеленой растительности включает как естественную растительность, так и растительность, возникшую в результате антропогенной деятельности (например, посевы, лесонасаждение и т. д.). Не зеленые территории включают в себя районы с очень редкой растительностью, голые земли, водные поверхности, вечные льды / снега и городские районы. Описание зоны растительности может быть получено разными способами, но карты земного покрова на основе дистанционного зондирования являются наиболее удобным источником данных для этой цели, поскольку они предоставляют необходимую информацию о зеленых и не зелёных территориях в пространственно-выраженном виде и позволяют сравнивать данные с течением времени посредством анализа изменений земного покрова. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В настоящее время ФАО использует временные ряды данных земного покрова, подготовленные Европейским космическим агентством (ЕКА) в рамках Инициативы по изменению климата (ИИК), в качестве общего решения. Исходные классы CCI переклассифицированы в шесть классов Межправительственной группы экспертов по изменению климата (МГЭИК), а затем в бинарные классы зеленого / не зелёного покрытия следующим образом:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Класс ИИК ЕКА &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Класс МГЭИК&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Зеленый / не зеленый &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 50, 60, 61, 62, 70, 71, 72, 80, 81, 82, 90, 100 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Лес &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-1&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt; [1] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Зеленый &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 110, 120, 121, 122, 130, 140, &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Луга &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Зеленый &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 10,11, 12, 20, 30, 40 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Пахотные земли &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Зеленый &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 160, 170, 180 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Заболоченные земли &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Зеленый &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 190 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Поселение &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Не зеленый &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 150, 151, 152, 153, 200, 201, 202, 210, 220 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Прочие земли &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Не зеленый &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-1&quot;&gt; 1 &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p&gt; Обратите внимание, что здесь термин &amp;#x201C; Лес &amp;#x201D; относится к земному покрову, но не к землепользованию &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt; &amp;#x2191; [4951 ] &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; 1) Данные о растительном покрове ИИК-ЕКА: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Инициатива по изменению климата (ИИК) Европейского космического агентства (ЕКА) - это программа, направленная на использование всего потенциала данных наблюдения Земли, собранных ЕКА, для внесения вклада в базы данных основных климатических переменных, требуемых Рамочной конвенцией Организации Объединенных Наций об изменении климата (РКИК ООН). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Продукты ИИК-Растительный покров были произведены с использованием комбинации данных дистанционного зондирования, таких как MERIS - спектрометр с формированием изображения со средней разрешающей способностью 300 м, французская система СПОТ с разрешающей способностью 1 км; VEGETATION - прибор для наблюдения за растительным покровом, спутник PROBA - V для наблюдения Земли с разрешающей способностью 1 км и усовершенствованный радиометр очень высокого разрешения AVHRR с разрешающей способностью 1 км. Продукт ИИК состоит из серии годовых карт растительного покрова с разрешением 300 м, охватывающих период с 1992 по 2018 год. Период с 1992 по 2015 год доступен в растровом формате, тогда как карты за 2016-2018 годы доступны в формате netCDF и требуется их преобразование в формат GTIFF, чтобы эти наборы данных были доступны для обработки в среде ГИС. Данные о растительном покрове обновляются ежегодно Европейским космическим агентством. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ИИК ЕКА придерживается Системы классификации растительного покрова Продовольственной и сельскохозяйственной организации Объединенных Наций (ФАО ООН) (Santoro, et al., 2015). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; 2) Зона класса Горы Kapos: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Набор данных Kapos - это глобальный растровый файл идентификатора гор. В файле представлена классификация горных хребтов в соответствии с определениями, предложенными Kapos et al 2000: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Класс 1: высота &amp;gt; 4500 метров &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Класс 2: высота 3500–4500 метров &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Класс 3: высота 2500 &amp;#x2013; 3500 метров &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Класс 4: высота 1500 &amp;#x2013; 2500 метров и уклон &amp;#x2265; 2 &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Класс 5: высота 1000 &amp;#x2013; 1500 метров и уклон &amp;#x2265; 5 или местный
перепад высот (в радиусе 7 километров) &amp;#x2265; 300 метров &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Класс 6: высота 300 &amp;#x2013; 1000 метров и местный перепад высот (в радиусе
7 километров) &amp;#x2265; 300 метров вне пределов 23 &amp;#xB0; СШ &amp;#x2014; 19 &amp;#xB0; ЮШ &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Класс 0: Определен для представления не горных районов. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель создается ФАО для всех стран и регионов, имеющих горные районы, с использованием зон геопространственных данных, описанных в этом документе. ФАО рассылает страновые данные координаторам ЦУР в национальных статистических управлениях для проверки перед публикацией в соответствии с руководящими принципами Межучрежденческой координационной группы по окружающей среде-Целям в области устойчивого развития (МКГОС-ЦУР) по глобальным потокам данных и отчетности. В то же время ФАО просит страны предоставить свои собственные оценки показателя, если таковые имеются.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Календарь &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Сбор данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Информация по растительному покрову ИИК ЕКА доступна с 1992 по 2018 год. Ежегодно предоставляется новая глобальная карта растительного покрова. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Выпуск данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Все данные уже доступны &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Поставщики данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Европейское космическое агентство &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Горное партнерство, ФАО &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Геологическая служба США &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Составители данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ФАО &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Горные экосистемы являются важными центрами биоразнообразия, которые предоставляют ценные экосистемные услуги в районах, расположенных в верховьях и низовьях. Впрочем, горы являются очень хрупкими образованиями и легко подвергаются воздействию как природных, так и антропогенных факторов. Сюда могут входить изменение климата, стихийные бедствия, такие как оползни и наводнения, незапланированное расширение сельскохозяйственных угодий, незапланированная урбанизация, добыча древесины и рекреационная деятельность. Деградация горных экосистем, такая как потеря ледникового покрова, горного биоразнообразия и растительного покрова, повлияет на способность экосистемы снабжать водой районы, расположенные ниже по склону. Утрата лесного и растительного покрова снизит способность экосистемы удерживать почву и предотвращать оползни и наводнения в районах, расположенных ниже по склону. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Таким образом, мониторинг изменения растительного покрова гор дает информацию о состоянии горных экосистем. Мониторинг индекса растительного покрова гор с течением времени может предоставить информацию о степени изменения растительности и об общем состоянии горной экосистемы. Оценка изменения растительного покрова, дифференцированная по высоте, важна для понимания изменений, которые происходят в горных регионах из-за влияния на экосистему крутизны склона, ориентации склона по сторонам света и высоты горной местности.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Однако значения индекса растительного покрова гор следует интерпретировать с осторожностью. Индекс не дает подробных сведений об изменении видов, изменении линии распространения лесов или областей дождевых теней. Понимание различий в видовом составе и линии распространения лесов будет иметь важное значение для определения долгосрочных последствий изменения климата в горных регионах. Анализ вегетативных изменений с течением времени в каждой из высотных зон поможет определить соответствующие меры управления и адаптации. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;В некоторых случаях рост значения показателя в классах большой высоты может также означать распространение растительности на территории, ранее покрытые ледниками или другими многолетними или сезонными зонами льда или снега, в результате глобального потепления из-за изменения климата. Такое изменение можно отслеживать с помощью текущей методологии и соответствующим образом отмечать на уровне дезагрегированных данных по типу растительного покрова и классу высоты, чтобы отличить этот случай от общей желаемой тенденции увеличения растительного покрова гор. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель может быть рассчитан с использованием находящихся в свободном доступе данных наблюдения Земли и простых операций ГИС, которые можно обрабатывать в бесплатном программном обеспечении с открытым исходным кодом (FOSS) ГИС. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Потенциальные ограничения описанной выше методологии связаны в основном с качеством данных по растительному покрову. Карты растительного покрова ЕКА ИИК в настоящее время доступны с разрешением 300 метров, что ограничивает их применимость при мониторинге небольших и весьма неоднородных ландшафтов. Поэтому, если у стран есть национальные карты растительного покрова с более высоким пространственным разрешением и сопоставимым или лучшим качеством, ФАО рекомендует использовать их, следуя той же методологии, представленной здесь, для получения значений индекса растительного покрова гор. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Что касается интерпретации показателя, то в подавляющем большинстве случаев желаемым направлением является увеличение растительного покрова гор, что отражает снижение ущерба, наносимого естественным экосистемам и, возможно, даже расширение площади лесов, кустарников и пастбищ за счет усилий по сохранению экосистем, а в некоторых редких случаях рост значения показателя в классах больших высот может также означать распространение растительности на территории, ранее покрытые ледниками или другими многолетними или сезонными зонами льда или снега, в результате глобального потепления из-за изменения климата. Такое изменение можно отслеживать с помощью текущей методологии и соответствующим образом отмечать на уровне дезагрегированных данных по типу растительного покрова и классу высоты, чтобы отличить этот случай от общей желаемой тенденции увеличения растительного покрова гор.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Индекс растительного покрова гор (ИРПГ) определяется как &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt; ИРПГ = (Площадь растительного покрова гор / Общая площадь гор) X 100 &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Где площадь растительного покрова гор = сумма площадей, покрытых классами возделываемых земель, пастбищ, лесов и водно-болотных угодий. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Идентификатор растительности рассчитывается на основе карты растительного покрова с использованием основных функций ГИС. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Если в стране / регионе нет горной местности, ему будет присвоено значение &quot;Не применимо&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Не применимо, так как показатель имеет всеобщий охват &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Неприменимо, так как показатель имеет всеобщий охват &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Региональные агрегаты: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Использование пространственно-выраженных данных позволяет напрямую рассчитать значение показателя для любой очерченной области. Однако при пространственном разрешении 300 метров зоны ИИК расчет значений показателя для самых небольших областей, состоящих всего из нескольких пикселей, может привести к резким изменениям значений показателя из-за относительно более высокого влияния ошибок классификации.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Доступные странам методы и руководство для составления данных на национальном уровне: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Значение показателя &amp;#xA0; можно рассчитать следующим образом: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Классы растительного покрова ЕКА; ИИК переклассифицированы в шесть классов
МГЭИК и карту зеленого / не зеленого покрова &lt;/li&gt; 
  &lt;li&gt; Карта перепада высот Капоша наложена поверх карты полученной на стадии 1.
&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Зональная гистограмма рассчитывается для каждой группировки стран и регионов
таким образом, чтобы количество пикселей, принадлежащих зеленому и не зеленому классам подсчитывалось в пределах каждогодиапазона  перепадов. &amp;#xA0; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Отношение (%) между суммой зеленых пикселей и общим количеством пикселей
(зеленый плюс не зеленый), попадающих в каждый Капош вычисляется для получения значений ИРПГ на каждый класс Капоша &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Та же процедура используется для расчета распределения классов растительного
покрова, как определено МГЭИК, в пределах каждого перепада высот. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обеспечение качества: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Статистические данные по странам, полученные ФАО, перед публикацией направляются официальным координаторам НСУ по ЦУР для валидации. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель составляется на основе геопространственных данных и поэтому имеет всеобщий охват. Страны, не имеющие данных в глобальной базе данных ЦУР, - это либо A) страны, в которых нет гор и к ним показатель не применим, либо B) страны, которые не подтвердили оценки ФАО и еще не представили свои собственные данные. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Данные по растительному покрову ИИК ЕКА находятся в свободном доступе по
адресу:&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.esa-landcover-cci.org/?q=node/164&quot;&gt;https://www.esa-landcover-cci.org/?q=node/164&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Данные Kapos находятся в свободном доступе по следующим ссылкам: &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; На веб-сайте Горного партнерства ФАО находится растровый файл в правом баннере.
Доступ в&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/mountain-partnership/our-work/focusareas/foodsecurity/en/&quot;&gt; http://www.fao.org/mountain-partnership/our-work/focusareas/foodsecurity/en/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Классификацию Геологической службы США Mountain Explorer Kapos можно найти
как GME_K1classes.zip в: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rmgsc.cr.usgs.gov/outgoing/ecosystems/Global/&quot;&gt; https://rmgsc.cr.usgs.gov/outgoing/ecosystems/Global &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Административные границы доступны из различных глобальных баз данных по ссылкам
ниже: &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Зоны глобальных административных единиц ФАО (GAUL) &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.europa.eu/euodp/data/dataset/jrc-10112-10004&quot;&gt;
https://data.europa.eu/euodp/data/dataset/jrc-10112-10004 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Divas-GIS &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.diva-gis.org/gdata&quot;&gt; https://www.diva-gis.org/gdata
&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Границы второго административного уровня ООН (SALB) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unsalb.org/&quot;&gt;
https://www.unsalb.org/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные по странам, регионам и миру доступны за 2000, 2010, 2015 и 2018 годы. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В глобальной базе данных ЦУР показатель дезагрегирован по классу высоты гор (идентификатор гор). Дополнительный параметр дезагрегирования, класс растительного покрова МГЭИК доступен на портале показателей ЦУР ФАО. Комбинация шести классов высот и шести основных типов растительного покрова в соответствии с классификацией МГЭИК дает 36 различных дезагрегированных данных для каждой страны за отчетный год. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Представленная здесь методология по умолчанию основана на использовании глобального продукта ЕКА ИИК Land Cover, интегральная оценка точности которого, как сообщается, составляет 73,2%. Однако оценка точности была рассчитана с использованием исходных 22 классов растительного покрова. Поскольку представленная здесь методология основана на использовании агрегированных классов, можно ожидать, что точность будет выше. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Точность продуктов глобального растительного покрова может варьироваться в зависимости от региона. По той же причине представленные значения показателей могут отличаться от значений, полученных с использованием национальных карт растительного покрова. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eurostat (2019). &lt;em&gt;LUCAS Grid&lt;/em&gt;. Eurostat Your Key to European statistics: &lt;a ref=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/web/lucas/data/lucas-grid&quot;&gt;https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/web/lucas/data/lucas-grid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kapos, V., Rhind, J., Edwards, M., Prince, M., &amp;amp; Ravillous, C. (2000). Developing a map of the world&amp;#x2019;s mountain forests. In M. F. Price , &amp;amp; N. Butt (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Forests in Sustainable Mountain Development: A State-of-Knowledge Report for 2000&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 4-9). Wallingford: CAB International.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karagulle, D., Frye, C., Breyer, S., Aniello, P., Vaughan, R., &amp;amp; Wright, D. (2017). Modeling global Hammond landform regions from 250-m elevation data. &lt;em&gt;Transactions in GIS&lt;/em&gt;. doi:10.1111/tgis.12265&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;K&amp;#xF6;rner, C., Paulsen, J., &amp;amp; Spehn, E. (2011). A definition of mountains and their bioclimatic belts for global comparisons of biodiversity data. &lt;em&gt;Alpine Botany, 121&lt;/em&gt;, 73-78.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santoro, M., Kirches, G., Wevers, J., Boettcher, M., Brockmann, C., Lamarche, C., . . . Defourny, P. (2015). &lt;em&gt;Land Cover CCI PRODUCT USER GUIDE VERSION 2.0.&lt;/em&gt; European Spatial Agency. European Spatial Agency. Получено из &lt;a href&gt;&quot;http://maps.elie.ucl.ac.be/CCI/viewer/download/ESACCI-LC-Ph2-PUGv2_2.0.pdf&quot;&gt;http://maps.elie.ucl.ac.be/CCI/viewer/download/ESACCI-LC-Ph2-PUGv2_2.0.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mountainpartnership.org/our-work/focusareas/foodsecurity/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.mountainpartnership.org/our-work/focusareas/foodsecurity/en/&lt;/a&gt; (горный растер ГИС доступен для скачивания с правой панели) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openforis.org/tools/collect-earth.html&quot;&gt;http://www.openforis.org/tools/collect-earth.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-i5175e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-i5175e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
