<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 15-5-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 15: Protect, restore and promote sustainable use of terrestrial ecosystems, sustainably manage forests, combat desertification, and halt and reverse land degradation and halt biodiversity loss&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 15.5: Take urgent and significant action to reduce the degradation of natural habitats, halt the loss of biodiversity and, by 2020, protect and prevent the extinction of threatened species&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 15.5.1: Red List Index&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Red List Index (Value, UpperBound, LowerBound) &lt;/p&gt;2022-12-16&lt;p&gt;Disaggregations of the Red List Index are also of particular relevance as indicators towards the following SDG targets (Brooks et al. 2015): SDG 2.4 Red List Index (species used for food and medicine); SDG 2.5 Red List Index (wild relatives and local breeds); SDG 12.2 Red List Index (impacts of utilisation) (Butchart 2008); SDG 12.4 Red List Index (impacts of pollution); SDG 13.1 Red List Index (impacts of climate change); SDG 14.1 Red List Index (impacts of pollution on marine species); SDG 14.2 Red List Index (marine species); SDG 14.3 Red List Index (reef-building coral species) (Carpenter et al. 2008); SDG 14.4 Red List Index (impacts of utilisation on marine species); SDG 15.1 Red List Index (terrestrial &amp;amp; freshwater species); SDG 15.2 Red List Index (forest-specialist species); SDG 15.4 Red List Index (mountain species); SDG 15.7 Red List Index (impacts of utilisation) (Butchart 2008); and SDG 15.8 Red List Index (impacts of invasive alien species) (Butchart 2008, McGeoch et al. 2010).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BirdLife International (BLI)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Red List Index measures change in aggregate extinction risk across groups of species. It is based on genuine changes in the number of species in each category of extinction risk on The IUCN Red List of Threatened Species (www.iucnredlist.org) is expressed as changes in an index ranging from 0 to 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Threatened species are those listed on The IUCN Red List of Threatened Species in the categories Vulnerable, Endangered, or Critically Endangered (i.e., species that are facing a high, very high, or extremely high risk of extinction in the wild in the medium-term future). Changes over time in the proportion of species threatened with extinction are largely driven by improvements in knowledge and changing taxonomy. The indicator excludes such changes to yield a more informative indicator than the simple proportion of threatened species. It therefore measures change in aggregate extinction risk across groups of species over time, resulting from genuine improvements or deteriorations in the status of individual species. It can be calculated for any representative set of species that have been assessed for The IUCN Red List of Threatened Species at least twice (Butchart et al. 2004, 2005, 2007). To calculate the Red List Index for individual countries and regions, each species contributing to the index is weighted by the proportion of its global range within the particular country or region. The resulting index therefore shows the aggregate extinction risk for species within the country or region relative to its potential contribution to global species extinction risk (within the taxonomic groups included).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Red List Index for a particular country or region is an index of the aggregate extinction risk for species within the country or region relative to its potential contribution to global species extinction risk (within the taxonomic groups included).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is measured on a scale of 0 to 1, where 1 is the maximum contribution that the country or region can make to global species survival, equating to all species being classified as Least Concern on the IUCN Red List, and 0 is the minimum contribution that the country or region can make to global species survival, equating to all species in the country or region having gone extinct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Red List Index is based on categorisations of species on the IUCN Red List of Threatened Species (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iucnredlist.org&quot;&gt;www.iucnredlist.org&lt;/a&gt;), defined following IUCN (2012a).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Red List Index is based on data from The IUCN Red List of Threatened Species (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iucnredlist.org&quot;&gt;www.iucnredlist.org&lt;/a&gt;), in particular the numbers of species in each Red List category of extinction risk, and changes in these numbers over time resulting from genuine improvements or deteriorations in the status of species. Data on species&amp;#x2019; distribution, population size, trends and other parameters that underpin Red List assessments are gathered from published and unpublished sources, species experts, scientists, and conservationists through correspondence, workshops, and electronic fora. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A detailed description of the Red List Assessment process is provided at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iucnredlist.org/assessment/process&quot;&gt;https://www.iucnredlist.org/assessment/process&lt;/a&gt;. See also information under other categories.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The IUCN Red List of Threatened Species is updated at least three times per year. Red List Indices for sets of species that have been comprehensively reassessed are usually released alongside the relevant update of the IUCN Red List. Data are stored and managed in the Species Information Service database, and are made freely available for non-commercial use through the IUCN Red List website (www.iucnredlist.org). Re-assessments of extinction risk are required for every species assessed on The IUCN Red List of Threatened Species once every ten years, and ideally undertaken once every five years. A Red List Strategic Plan details a calendar of upcoming re-assessments for each taxonomic group. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Red List Index is updated annually in November-December using the latest data from reassessments on the IUCN Red List.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National agencies producing relevant data include government, non-governmental organisations (NGOs), and academic institutions working jointly and separately. Data are gathered from published and unpublished sources, species experts, scientists, and conservationists through correspondence, workshops, and electronic fora. Data are submitted by national agencies to IUCN, or are gathered through initiatives of the Red List Partnership. The members of the Red List Partnership are listed at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iucnredlist.org/about/partners&quot;&gt;https://www.iucnredlist.org/about/partners&lt;/a&gt;, and currently include: ABQ BioPark; Arizona State University Centre for Biodiversity Outcomes; BirdLife International; Botanic Gardens Conservation International; Conservation International; Global Wildlife Conservation; Missouri Botanical Garden; NatureServe; Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew; Sapienza University of Rome; Texas A&amp;amp;M University; and Zoological Society of London.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compilation and reporting of the Red List Index at the global level is conducted by the International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN) and BirdLife International, on behalf of the Red List Partnership. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Responsibility for overseeing Red List assessments, which underpin the Red List Index, is assigned to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Red List Authorities according to the IUCN Red List Rules of Procedure (https://nc.iucnredlist.org/redlist/content/attachment_files/Rules_of_Procedure_for_IUCN_Red_List_2017-2020.pdf). The role of Red List Authorities is to ensure that all species within their remit are correctly assessed against the IUCN Red List Categories and Criteria at least once every ten years and, if possible, every five years. Further details of the roles and responsibilities of Red List Authorities are provided at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iucnredlist.org/assessment/authorities&quot;&gt;https://www.iucnredlist.org/assessment/authorities&lt;/a&gt;, and the full list and contact details for all appointed Red List Authorities are available at https://www.iucn.org/commissions/ssc-groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The world&amp;#x2019;s species are impacted by a number of threatening processes, including habitat destruction and degradation, overexploitation, invasive alien species, human disturbance, pollution and climate change. This indicator can be used to assess overall changes in the extinction risk of groups of species as a result of these threats and the extent to which threats are being mitigated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Red List Index value ranges from 1 (all species are categorized as &amp;#x2018;Least Concern&amp;#x2019;) to 0 (all species are categorized as &amp;#x2018;Extinct&amp;#x2019;), and so indicates how far the set of species has moved overall towards extinction. Thus, the global Red List Index allows comparisons between sets of species in both their overall level of extinction risk (i.e., how threatened they are on average), and in the rate at which this risk changes over time. A downward trend in the global Red List Index over time means that the expected rate of future species extinctions is worsening (i.e., the rate of biodiversity loss is increasing). An upward trend means that the expected rate of species extinctions is abating (i.e., the rate of biodiversity loss is decreasing), and a horizontal line means that the expected rate of species extinctions is remaining the same, although in each of these cases it does not mean that biodiversity loss has stopped. An upward global Red List Index trend would indicate that the SDG Target 15.5 of reducing the degradation of natural habitats and protecting threatened species is on track. A global Red List Index value of 1 would indicate that biodiversity loss has been halted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name &amp;#x201C;Red List Index&amp;#x201D; should not be taken to imply that the indicator is produced as a composite indicator of a number of disparate metrics (in the same way that, e.g., the Multidimensional Poverty Index is compiled). The Red List Index provides an indicator of trends in species&amp;#x2019; extinction risk, as measured using the IUCN Red List Categories and Criteria (Mace et al. 2008, IUCN 2012a), and is compiled from data on changes over time in the Red List Category for each species, excluding any changes driven by improved knowledge or revised taxonomy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Red List Index was used as an indicator towards the 2011&amp;#x2013;2020 Strategic Plan for Biodiversity (CBD 2014, Tittensor et al. 2014, CBD 2020a), the Convention on Biological Diversity&amp;#x2019;s 2010 Target (Butchart et al. 2010) and Millennium Development Goal 7. It has been proposed as a Headline Indicator in the draft post-2020 Global Biodiversity Framework (CBD 2020b).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are four main sources of uncertainty associated with Red List Index values and trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inadequate, incomplete or inaccurate knowledge of a species&amp;#x2019; status. This uncertainty is minimized by assigning estimates of extinction risk to categories that are broad in magnitude and timing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delays in knowledge about a species becoming available for assessment. Such delays apply to a small (and diminishing) proportion of status changes, and can be overcome in the Red List Index through back-casting (Butchart et al. 2007).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inconsistency between species assessments. These can be minimized by the requirement to provide supporting documentation detailing the best available data, with justifications, sources, and estimates of uncertainty and data quality, which are checked and standardized by IUCN through Red List Authorities, a Red List Technical Working Group and an independent Standards and Petitions Sub-committee. Further, detailed Guidelines on the Application of the Categories and Criteria are maintained (IUCN SPSC 2019), as is an online training course (in English, Spanish and French).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Species that are too poorly known for the Red List Criteria to be applied are assigned to the Data Deficient category. For birds, only 0.8% of extant species are evaluated as Data Deficient, compared with 24% of amphibians. If Data Deficient species differ in the rate at which their extinction risk is changing, the Red List Index may give a biased picture of the changing extinction risk of the overall set of species. The degree of uncertainty this introduces is estimated through a bootstrapping procedure that randomly assigns each Data Deficient species a category based on the numbers of non-Data Deficient species in each Red List category for the set of species under consideration, and repeats this for 1,000 iterations, plotting the 2.5 and 97.5 percentiles as lower and upper confidence intervals for the median.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main limitation of the Red List Index is related to the fact that the Red List Categories are relatively broad measures of status, and thus the Red List Index for any individual taxonomic group can practically be updated at intervals of at least four years. However, as the overall index is aggregated across multiple taxonomic groups, with groups reassessed asynchronously, it can be updated annually. A further limitation is that the Red List Index does not reflect particularly well the deteriorating status of common species that remain abundant and widespread but are declining slowly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Red List Index is calculated at a point in time by first multiplying the number of species in each Red List Category by a weight (ranging from 1 for &amp;#x2018;Near Threatened&amp;#x2019; to 5 for &amp;#x2018;Extinct&amp;#x2019; and &amp;#x2018;Extinct in the Wild&amp;#x2019;) and summing these values. This is then divided by a maximum threat score, which is the total number of species multiplied by the weight assigned to the &amp;#x2018;Extinct&amp;#x2019; category. This final value is subtracted from 1 to give the Red List Index value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathematically this calculation is expressed as: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;L&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;msub&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;I&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/msub&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;1&lt;/mn&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;-&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;&amp;#x3A3;&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;W&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mfenced separators=&quot;|&quot;&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
                &lt;mo&gt;,&lt;/mo&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/mfenced&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;(&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;W&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;E&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;X&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;*&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;)&lt;/mo&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where Wc(t,s) is the weight for category (c) at time (t) for species (s) (the weight for &amp;#x2018;Critically Endangered&amp;#x2019; = 4, &amp;#x2018;Endangered&amp;#x2019; = 3, &amp;#x2018;Vulnerable&amp;#x2019; = 2, &amp;#x2018;Near Threatened&amp;#x2019; = 1, &amp;#x2018;Least Concern&amp;#x2019; = 0. &amp;#x2018;Critically Endangered&amp;#x2019; species tagged as &amp;#x2018;Possibly Extinct&amp;#x2019; or &amp;#x2018;Possibly Extinct in the Wild&amp;#x2019; are assigned a weight of 5); WEX = 5, the weight assigned to &amp;#x2018;Extinct&amp;#x2019; or &amp;#x2018;Extinct in the Wild&amp;#x2019; species; and N is the total number of assessed species, excluding those assessed as Data Deficient in the current time period, and those considered to be &amp;#x2018;Extinct&amp;#x2019; in the year the set of species was first assessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The formula requires that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exactly the same set of species is included in all time periods, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The only Red List Category changes are those resulting from genuine improvement or deterioration in status (i.e., excluding changes resulting from improved knowledge or taxonomic revisions), and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Deficient species are excluded (or treated according to the procedure described above).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many cases, species lists will change slightly from one assessment to the next (e.g., owing to taxonomic revisions). The conditions can therefore be met by retrospectively adjusting earlier Red List categorizations using current information and taxonomy. This is achieved by assuming that the current Red List Categories for the taxa have applied since the set of species was first assessed for the Red List, unless there is information to the contrary that genuine status changes have occurred. Such information is often contextual (e.g., relating to the known history of habitat loss within the range of the species). If there is insufficient information available for a newly added species, it is not incorporated into the Red List Index until it is assessed for a second time, at which point earlier assessments are retrospectively corrected by extrapolating recent trends in population, range, habitat and threats, supported by additional information. To avoid spurious results from biased selection of species, Red List Indices are typically calculated only for taxonomic groups in which all species worldwide have been assessed for the Red List, or for samples of species that have been systematically or randomly selected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The methods and scientific basis for the Red List Index were described by Butchart et al. (2004, 2005, 2007, 2010). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Butchart et al. (2010) also described the methods by which Red List Indices for different taxonomic groups are aggregated to produce a single multi-taxon Red List Index. Specifically, aggregated Red List Indices are calculated as the arithmetic mean of modelled Red List Indices. Red List Indices for each taxonomic group are interpolated linearly for years between data points and extrapolated linearly (with a slope equal to that between the two closest assessed points) to align them with years for which Red List Indices for other taxa are available. The Red List Indices for each taxonomic group for each year are modelled to take into account various sources of uncertainty: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Deficiency: Red List categories (from Least Concern to Extinct) are assigned to all Data Deficient species, with a probability proportional to the number of species in non-Data Deficient categories for that taxonomic group; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extrapolation uncertainty: although RLIs were extrapolated linearly based on the slope of the closest two assessed point, there is uncertainty about how accurate this slope may be. To incorporate this uncertainty, rather than extrapolating deterministically, the slope used for extrapolation is selected from a normal distribution with a probability equal to the slope of the closest two assessed points, and standard deviation equal to 60% of this slope (i.e., the CV is 60%); &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Temporal variability: the &amp;#x2018;true&amp;#x2019; Red List Index likely changes from year to year, but because assessments are repeated only at multi-year intervals, the precise value for any particular year is uncertain. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make this uncertainty explicit, the Red List Index value for a given taxonomic group in a given year is assigned from a moving window of five years, centred on the focal year (with the window set as 3-4 years for the first two and last two years in the series). Note that assessment uncertainty cannot yet be incorporated into the index. Practically, these uncertainties are incorporated into the aggregated Red List Indices as follows: Data Deficient species were allotted a category as described above, and a Red List Index for each taxonomic group was calculated interpolating and extrapolating as described above. A final Red List Index value was assigned to each taxonomic group for each year from a window of years as described above. Each such &amp;#x2018;run&amp;#x2019; produced a Red List Index for the complete time period for each taxonomic group, incorporating the various sources of uncertainty. Ten thousand such runs are generated for each taxonomic group, and the mean is calculated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods for generating national disaggregations of the Red List Index are described below in section 5 on Data availability and disaggregation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Red List Assessments are checked before submission to IUCN by Assessors and Red List Authority Coordinators, to ensure that all of the required supporting information is provided in the appropriate format, distribution maps follow the required mapping standards (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iucnredlist.org/resources/mappingstandards&quot;&gt;https://www.iucnredlist.org/resources/mappingstandards&lt;/a&gt;), and the IUCN Red List Criteria have been applied appropriately and consistently following IUCN Guidelines (IUCN SPSC 2019). For further details, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iucnredlist.org/assessment/process&quot;&gt;https://www.iucnredlist.org/assessment/process&lt;/a&gt;. All submitted assessments must be reviewed by at least one Reviewer designated by the Red List Authority. For more details on the review process, see the Rules of Procedure (&lt;a href=&quot;https://nc.iucnredlist.org/redlist/content/attachment_files/Rules_of_Procedure_for_IUCN_Red_List_2017-2020.pdf&quot;&gt;https://nc.iucnredlist.org/redlist/content/attachment_files/Rules_of_Procedure_for_IUCN_Red_List_2017-2020.pdf&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Red List Indices are updated each year, the updated index (and underlying numbers of species in each Red List Category) are made available for review by countries prior to submission to the SDG Indicators Database. This is achieved through updating the country profiles in the Integrated Biodiversity Assessment Tool (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ibat-alliance.org/country_profiles&quot;&gt;https://ibat-alliance.org/country_profiles&lt;/a&gt;) and circulating these for consultation and review to CBD National Focal Points, SDG National Statistical Office Focal Points, and IUCN State Members.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No adjustments are made to the index with respect to harmonization of breakdowns or for compliance with specific international or national definitions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Red List Indices for each taxonomic group are interpolated linearly for years between data points and extrapolated linearly (with a slope equal to that between the two closest assessed points, except for corals) back to the earliest time point and forwards to the present for years for which estimates are not available. The start year of the aggregated index is set as ten years before the first assessment year for the taxonomic group with the latest starting point. Corals are not extrapolated linearly because declines are known to have been much steeper subsequent to 1996 (owing to extreme bleaching events) than before. Therefore, the rate of decline prior to 1996 is set as the average of the rates for the other taxonomic groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Red List Index is calculated globally based on assessments of extinction risk of each species included, because many species have distributions that span many countries. Thus, while there is certainly uncertainty around the Red List Index, there are no missing values as such, and so no imputation is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Red List Categories and Criteria are applied for each species on The IUCN Red List of Threatened Species and are determined globally and provided principally by the Specialist Groups and stand-alone Red List Authorities of the IUCN Species Survival Commission, IUCN Secretariat-led initiatives, and Red List partner organizations. The staff of the IUCN Global Species Programme compile, validate, and curate these data, and are responsible for publishing and communicating the results. Each individual species assessment is supported by the application of metadata and documentation standards (IUCN 2013), including classifications of, for example, threats and conservation actions (Salafsky et al. 2008). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Red List assessments are undertaken either through open workshops or open-access web-based discussion fora. Assessments are reviewed by the appropriate Red List Authority (an individual or organization appointed by the IUCN Species Survival Commission to review assessments for specific species or groups of species) to ensure standardisation and consistency in the interpretation of information and application of the criteria. A Red List Technical Working Group and the IUCN Red List Unit work to ensure consistent categorization between species, groups and assessments. Finally, a Standards and Petitions Sub-committee monitors the process and resolves challenges and disputes over Red List assessments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, IUCN publishes guidelines on applying the IUCN Red List Categories and Criteria at regional or national scales (IUCN 2012b). Based on these, many countries have initiated programmes to assess the extinction risk of species occurring within their borders. These countries will be able to implement the Red List Index based on national extinction risk, once they have carried out at least two national Red Lists using the IUCN system in a consistent way (Bubb et al. 2009). An increasing number of countries have now completed national Red List Indices for a range of taxa (e.g., G&amp;#xE4;rdenfors 2010, Pihl &amp;amp; Flensted 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While global Red List Indices can be disaggregated to show trends for species at smaller spatial scales, the reverse is not true. National or regional Red List Indices cannot be aggregated to produce Red List Indices showing global trends. This is because a taxon&amp;#x2019;s global extinction risk has to be evaluated at the global scale and cannot be directly determined from multiple national scale assessments across its range (although the data from such assessments can be aggregated for inclusion in the global assessment).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods for generating regional disaggregations of the Red List Index are described below in section 5 on Data availability and disaggregation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods and guidance available to countries for the compilation of the data at the national level:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See above. In sum: the data underlying the Red List Index are compiled under the authority of the IUCN Red List Committee, through application of the IUCN Red List Categories &amp;amp; Criteria (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10315&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10315&lt;/a&gt;). This includes submissions of endemics from national red list processes, where these have been conducted following the &amp;#x201C;Guidelines for application of IUCN Red List Criteria at Regional and National Levels&amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10336&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10336&lt;/a&gt;) and following the &amp;#x201C;Required and Recommended Supporting Information for IUCN Red List Assessments&amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iucnredlist.org/resources/supporting-information-guidelines&quot;&gt;https://www.iucnredlist.org/resources/supporting-information-guidelines&lt;/a&gt;). Assessments may be submitted in all three IUCN languages (English, French and Spanish) and Portuguese. All assessments are peer reviewed through the relevant Red List Authority for the species or species group in question, as documented in the Red List Rules of Procedure (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iucnredlist.org/resources/rules-of-procedure&quot;&gt;https://www.iucnredlist.org/resources/rules-of-procedure&lt;/a&gt;); see in particular Annex 3, the &amp;#x201C;Details of the Steps Involved in the IUCN Red List Process&amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://nc.iucnredlist.org/redlist/content/attachment_files/Details_of_the_Steps_Involved_in_the_IUCN_Red_List_Process.pdf&quot;&gt;https://nc.iucnredlist.org/redlist/content/attachment_files/Details_of_the_Steps_Involved_in_the_IUCN_Red_List_Process.pdf&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key document providing international recommendations and guidelines to countries and all involved in application of the IUCN Red List Categories &amp;amp; Criteria (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10315&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10315&lt;/a&gt;) is the &amp;#x201C;Guidelines for Using the IUCN Red List Categories and Criteria&amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iucnredlist.org/resources/redlistguidelines&quot;&gt;https://www.iucnredlist.org/resources/redlistguidelines&lt;/a&gt;; available in English, French, Spanish, and Portuguese) accompanied by the &amp;#x201C;Required and Recommended Supporting Information for IUCN Red List Assessments&amp;#x201D;. For countries (and regions), this is supplemented by the &amp;#x201C;Guidelines for application of IUCN Red List Criteria at Regional and National Levels&amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10336&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10336&lt;/a&gt;). To support the calculation of Red List Indices for any given country (or region), &amp;#x201C;Code (and documentation) for calculating and plotting national RLIs weighted by the proportion of each species&amp;#x2019; distribution within a country or region&amp;#x201D; is posted online (Dias et al. 2020; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BirdLifeInternational/rli-codes&quot;&gt;https://github.com/BirdLifeInternational/rli-codes&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods for generating national disaggregations of the Red List Index are described below in section 5 on Data availability and disaggregation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;See above and below, and full documentation in the Red List Rules of Procedure (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iucnredlist.org/resources/rules-of-procedure&quot;&gt;https://www.iucnredlist.org/resources/rules-of-procedure&lt;/a&gt;) in particular Annex 3, the &amp;#x201C;Details of the Steps Involved in the IUCN Red List Process&amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/Details_of_the_Steps_Involved_in_the_IUCN_Red_List_Process.pdf&quot;&gt;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/Details_of_the_Steps_Involved_in_the_IUCN_Red_List_Process.pdf&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;See above, and full documentation in the Red List Rules of Procedure (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iucnredlist.org/resources/rules-of-procedure&quot;&gt;https://www.iucnredlist.org/resources/rules-of-procedure&lt;/a&gt;) in particular Annex 3, the &amp;#x201C;Details of the Steps Involved in the IUCN Red List Process&amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/Details_of_the_Steps_Involved_in_the_IUCN_Red_List_Process.pdf&quot;&gt;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/Details_of_the_Steps_Involved_in_the_IUCN_Red_List_Process.pdf&lt;/a&gt;). In sum: all Red List assessments are peer reviewed through the relevant Red List Authority for the species or species group in question; and all Red List assessments undergo consistency checks (to ensure consistency with assessments submitted for other taxonomic groups, regions, processes, etc.) by the Red List Unit before publication on the Red List website (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iucnredlist.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.iucnredlist.org/&lt;/a&gt;). Finally, the Chair of the IUCN Species Survival Commission (elected each four years by the government and non-governmental Members of IUCN) appoints a Chair for a Standards and Petitions Sub-Committee (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iucn.org/our-union/commissions/group/iucn-ssc-standards-and-petitions-committee&quot;&gt;https://www.iucn.org/our-union/commissions/group/iucn-ssc-standards-and-petitions-committee&lt;/a&gt;), which is responsible for ensuring the quality and standards of the IUCN Red List and for ruling on petitions against the listings of species on the IUCN Red List. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The IUCN Red List is governed by a Red List Committee (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iucn.org/our-union/commissions/group/iucn-ssc-red-list-committee&quot;&gt;https://www.iucn.org/our-union/commissions/group/iucn-ssc-red-list-committee&lt;/a&gt;), comprising representatives from the Red List Partnership, the IUCN Species Survival Commission, and the IUCN Secretariat. This committee establishes and maintains the Red List Strategic Plan, including ongoing evaluation of fitness for use i.e. the degree to which the IUCN Red List meets user&amp;#x2019;s requirements. This encompasses, inter alia, considerations of relevance, accuracy, timeliness, consistency, comprehensiveness, and accessibility. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Red List Index has been classified by the IAEG-SDGs as Tier 1. Current data are available for all countries in the world, and these are updated annually. Index values for each country are available in the UN SDG Indicators Database &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/sdgs/indicators/database/&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/sdgs/indicators/database/&lt;/a&gt;. Red List Index graphs and underlying index data are available for each country, SDG regions, IPBES region, CMS region and various thematic disaggregations at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iucnredlist.org/search&quot;&gt;https://www.iucnredlist.org/search&lt;/a&gt;. Red List Index graphs are also available for each country in the BIP Indicators Dashboard (&lt;a href=&quot;https://bipdashboard.natureserve.org/bip/SelectCountry.html&quot;&gt;https://bipdashboard.natureserve.org/bip/SelectCountry.html&lt;/a&gt;), the Integrated Biodiversity Assessment Tool Country Profiles (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ibat-alliance.org/country_profiles&quot;&gt;https://ibat-alliance.org/country_profiles&lt;/a&gt;), and (for birds) on the BirdLife International Data Zone (http://datazone.birdlife.org/species/dashboard).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Red List Index can be downscaled to show national and regional Red List Indices, weighted by the fraction of each species&amp;#x2019; distribution occurring within the country or region, building on the method published by Rodrigues et al. (2014) PLoS ONE 9(11): e113934. These show an index of how well species are conserved in a country or region to its potential contribution to global species conservation (for the taxonomic groups of species included). The index is calculated as: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;L&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;msub&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;I&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mfenced separators=&quot;|&quot;&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;,&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/mfenced&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/msub&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;1&lt;/mn&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;-&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;&amp;#x3A3;&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
        &lt;mfenced separators=&quot;|&quot;&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;msub&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;W&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mfenced separators=&quot;|&quot;&gt;
                  &lt;mrow&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
                    &lt;mo&gt;,&lt;/mo&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
                  &lt;/mrow&gt;
                &lt;/mfenced&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/msub&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;*&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mfenced separators=&quot;|&quot;&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mfrac&gt;
                  &lt;mrow&gt;
                    &lt;msub&gt;
                      &lt;mrow&gt;
                        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
                      &lt;/mrow&gt;
                      &lt;mrow&gt;
                        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
                        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
                      &lt;/mrow&gt;
                    &lt;/msub&gt;
                  &lt;/mrow&gt;
                  &lt;mrow&gt;
                    &lt;msub&gt;
                      &lt;mrow&gt;
                        &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
                      &lt;/mrow&gt;
                      &lt;mrow&gt;
                        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
                      &lt;/mrow&gt;
                    &lt;/msub&gt;
                  &lt;/mrow&gt;
                &lt;/mfrac&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/mfenced&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/mfenced&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;W&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;E&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;X&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;*&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;&amp;#x3A3;&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
        &lt;mfenced separators=&quot;|&quot;&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mfrac&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;msub&gt;
                  &lt;mrow&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
                  &lt;/mrow&gt;
                  &lt;mrow&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
                  &lt;/mrow&gt;
                &lt;/msub&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;msub&gt;
                  &lt;mrow&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
                  &lt;/mrow&gt;
                  &lt;mrow&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
                  &lt;/mrow&gt;
                &lt;/msub&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/mfrac&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/mfenced&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where t is the year of comprehensive reassessment, u is the spatial unit (i.e. country), W_((t,s)) is the weight of the global Red List category for species s at time t (Least Concern =0, Near Threatened =1, Vulnerable =2, Endangered =3, Critically Endangered =4, Critically Endangered (Possibly Extinct) =5, Critically Endangered (Possibly Extinct in the Wild) =5, Extinct in the Wild =5 and Extinct =5), WEX = 5 is the weight for Extinct species, r_su is the fraction of the total range of species s in unit u, and R_s is the total range size of species s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The index varies from 1 if the country has contributed the minimum it can to the global RLI (i.e., if the numerator is 0 because all species in the country are Least Concern) to 0 if the country has contributed the maximum it can to the global RLI (i.e., if the numerator equals the denominator because all species in the country are Extinct or Possibly Extinct). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The taxonomic groups included are those in which all species have been assessed for the IUCN Red List more than once. Red List categories for years in which comprehensive assessments (i.e. those in which all species in the taxonomic group have been assessed) were carried out are determined following the approach of Butchart et al. 2007; PLoS ONE 2(1): e140, i.e. they match the current categories except for those taxa that have undergone genuine improvement or deterioration in extinction risk of sufficient magnitude to qualify for a higher or lower Red List category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator can also be disaggregated by ecosystems, habitats, and other political and geographic divisions (e.g., Han et al. 2014), by taxonomic subsets (e.g., Hoffmann et al. 2011), by suites of species relevant to particular international treaties or legislation (e.g., Croxall et al. 2012), by suites of species exposed to particular threatening processes (e.g., Butchart 2008), and by suites of species that deliver particular ecosystem services, or have particular biological or life-history traits (e.g., Regan et al. 2015). In each case, information can be obtained from The IUCN Red List of Threatened Species to determine which species are relevant to particular subsets (e.g., which occur in particular ecosystems, habitats, and geographic areas of interest). These disaggregations are available on the IUCN Red List website at https://www.iucnredlist.org/search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disaggregations of the Red List Index are also of particular relevance as indicators towards the following SDG targets (Brooks et al. 2015): SDG 2.4 Red List Index (species used for food and medicine); SDG 2.5 Red List Index (wild relatives and local breeds); SDG 12.2 Red List Index (impacts of utilisation) (Butchart 2008); SDG 12.4 Red List Index (impacts of pollution); SDG 13.1 Red List Index (impacts of climate change); SDG 14.1 Red List Index (impacts of pollution on marine species); SDG 14.2 Red List Index (marine species); SDG 14.3 Red List Index (reef-building coral species) (Carpenter et al. 2008); SDG 14.4 Red List Index (impacts of utilisation on marine species); SDG 15.1 Red List Index (terrestrial &amp;amp; freshwater species); SDG 15.2 Red List Index (forest-specialist species); SDG 15.4 Red List Index (mountain species); SDG 15.7 Red List Index (impacts of utilisation) (Butchart 2008); and SDG 15.8 Red List Index (impacts of invasive alien species) (Butchart 2008, McGeoch et al. 2010).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some countries have assessed the national extinction risk of species occurring in the country, and have repeated such assessments, allowing a national Red List Index to be produced. This may differ from the indicator described here because (a) it considers national rather than global extinction risk, and (b) because it takes no account of the national responsibility for the conservation of each species, treating as equal both those species that occur nowhere outside the country (i.e. national endemics) and those with large ranges that occur in many other countries. Any such differences will be smaller for countries within which a high proportion of species are endemic (i.e., only found in that country), as in many island nations and mountainous countries, especially in the tropics. The differences will be larger for countries within which a high proportion of species have widespread distributions across many nations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iucn.org/assessment/red-list-index&quot;&gt;https://www.iucn.org/assessment/red-list-index&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These metadata are based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bipindicators.net/indicators/red-list-index&quot;&gt;https://www.bipindicators.net/indicators/red-list-index&lt;/a&gt; and the references listed below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BAILLIE, J. E. M. et al. (2004). 2004 IUCN Red List of Threatened Species: a Global Species Assessment. IUCN, Gland, Switzerland and Cambridge, United Kingdom. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9830&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9830&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BROOKS, T. M. et al. (2015). Harnessing biodiversity and conservation knowledge products to track the Aichi Targets and Sustainable Development Goals. Biodiversity 16: 157&amp;#x2013;174. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/pdf/10.1080/14888386.2015.1075903&quot;&gt;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/pdf/10.1080/14888386.2015.1075903&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUBB, P.J. et al. (2009). IUCN Red List Index - Guidance for National and Regional Use. IUCN, Gland, Switzerland. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9321&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9321&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2010). Global biodiversity: indicators of recent declines. Science 328: 1164&amp;#x2013;1168. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.1187512&quot;&gt;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.1187512&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. (2008). Red List Indices to measure the sustainability of species use and impacts of invasive alien species. Bird Conservation International 18 (suppl.): 245&amp;#x2013;262. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayJournal?jid=BCI&quot;&gt;http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayJournal?jid=BCI&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2007). Improvements to the Red List Index. PLoS ONE 2(1): e140. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0000140&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0000140&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2006). Biodiversity indicators based on trends in conservation status: strengths of the IUCN Red List Index. Conservation Biology 20: 579&amp;#x2013;581. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2006.00410.x/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2006.00410.x/abstract&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2005). Using Red List Indices to measure progress towards the 2010 target and beyond. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London B 360: 255&amp;#x2013;268. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/360/1454/255.full&quot;&gt;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/360/1454/255.full&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2004). Measuring global trends in the status of biodiversity: Red List Indices for birds. PLoS Biology 2(12): e383. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.plosbiology.org/article/info:doi/10.1371/journal.pbio.0020383&quot;&gt;http://www.plosbiology.org/article/info:doi/10.1371/journal.pbio.0020383&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CARPENTER, K. E. et al. (2008). One-third of reef-building corals face elevated extinction risk from climate change and local impacts. Science 321: 560&amp;#x2013;563. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.1159196&quot;&gt;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.1159196&lt;/a&gt; . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBD (2014). Global Biodiversity Outlook 4. Convention on Biological Diversity, Montr&amp;#xE9;al, Canada. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/gbo4/&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/gbo4/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBD (2020a). Global Biodiversity Outlook 5. Convention on Biological Diversity, Montr&amp;#xE9;al, Canada. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/gbo5/&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/gbo5/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBD (2020b). Post-2020 Global Biodiversity Framework: Scientific and technical information to support the review of the updated Goals and Targets, and related indicators and baselines. Document CBD/SBSTTA/24/3. Available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/doc/c/705d/6b4b/a1a463c1b19392bde6fa08f3/sbstta-24-03-en.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/doc/c/705d/6b4b/a1a463c1b19392bde6fa08f3/sbstta-24-03-en.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DIAS, M.P, SIMKINS, A.T., &amp;amp; PEARMAIN, E.J. (2020). Code (and documentation) for calculating and plotting national RLIs weighted by the proportion of each species&amp;#x2019; distribution within a country or region. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BirdLifeInternational/rli-codes&quot;&gt;https://github.com/BirdLifeInternational/rli-codes&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CROXALL, J. P. et al. (2012). Seabird conservation status, threats and priority actions: a global assessment. Bird Conservation International 22: 1&amp;#x2013;34. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;G&amp;#xC4;RDENFORS, U. (ed.) (2010). R&amp;#xF6;dlistade arter i Sverige 2010 &amp;#x2013; The 2010 Red List of Swedish Species. ArtDatabanken, SLU, Uppsala.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HAN, X. et al. (2014). A Biodiversity indicators dashboard: addressing challenges to monitoring progress towards the Aichi Biodiversity Targets using disaggregated global data. PLoS ONE 9(11): e112046. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0112046&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0112046&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOFFMANN, M. et al. (2010). The impact of conservation on the status of the world&amp;#x2019;s vertebrates. Science 330: 1503&amp;#x2013;1509. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.1194442&quot;&gt;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.1194442&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOFFMANN, M. et al. (2011). The changing fates of the world&amp;#x2019;s mammals. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London B 366: 2598&amp;#x2013;2610. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/366/1578/2598.abstract&quot;&gt;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/366/1578/2598.abstract&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IUCN SPSC (2019) Guidelines for Using the IUCN Red List Categories and Criteria. Version 14. International Union for Conservation of Nature &amp;#x2013; Standards and Petitions Subcommittee, Gland, Switzerland. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iucnredlist.org/resources/redlistguidelines&quot;&gt;https://www.iucnredlist.org/resources/redlistguidelines&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IUCN (2012a). IUCN Red List Categories and Criteria: Version 3.1. Second edition. International Union for Conservation of Nature, Gland, Switzerland. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10315&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10315&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IUCN (2012b). Guidelines for Application of IUCN Red List Criteria at Regional and National&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Levels: Version 4.0. International Union for Conservation of Nature, Gland, Switzerland. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10336&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10336&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IUCN (2013). Documentation Standards and Consistency Checks for IUCN Red List assessments and species accounts. International Union for Conservation of Nature, Gland, Switzerland. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iucnredlist.org/resources/supporting-information-guidelines&quot;&gt;https://www.iucnredlist.org/resources/supporting-information-guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IUCN (2015). IUCN Red List of Threatened Species. Version 2015.1. International Union for Conservation of Nature, Gland, Switzerland. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iucnredlist.org&quot;&gt;http://www.iucnredlist.org&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MACE, G. M. et al. (2008) Quantification of extinction risk: IUCN&amp;#x2019;s system for classifying threatened species. Conservation Biology 22: 1424&amp;#x2013;1442. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2008.01044.x/full&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2008.01044.x/full&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MCGEOCH, M. A. et al. (2010) Global indicators of biological invasion: species numbers, biodiversity impact and policy responses. Diversity and Distributions 16: 95&amp;#x2013;108. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1472-4642.2009.00633.x/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1472-4642.2009.00633.x/abstract&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PIHL, S. &amp;amp; FLENSTED, K. N. (2011). A Red List Index for breeding birds in Denmark in the period 1991-2009. Dansk Ornitologisk Forenings Tidsskrift 105: 211-218.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;REGAN, E. et al. (2015). Global trends in the status of bird and mammal pollinators. Conservation Letters. doi: 10.1111/conl.12162. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12162/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12162/abstract&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RODRIGUES, A. S. L. et al. (2014). Spatially explicit trends in the global conservation status of vertebrates. PLoS ONE 9(11): e113934. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0113934&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0113934&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SALAFSKY, N., et al. (2008) A standard lexicon for biodiversity conservation: unified classifications of threats and actions. Conservation Biology 22: 897&amp;#x2013;911. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2008.00937.x/full&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2008.00937.x/full&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TITTENSOR, D. et al. (2014). A mid-term analysis of progress towards international biodiversity targets. Science 346: 241&amp;#x2013;244. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.1257484&quot;&gt;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.1257484&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VISCONTI, P. et al. (2015) Projecting global biodiversity indicators under future development scenarios. Conservation Letters. doi: 10.1111/conl.12159. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12159/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12159/abstract&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 15: Proteger, restablecer y promover el uso sostenible de los ecosistemas terrestres, gestionar sosteniblemente los bosques, luchar contra la desertificacin, detener e invertir la degradacin de las tierras y detener la prdida de biodiversidad&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 15.5: Adoptar medidas urgentes y significativas para reducir la degradacin de los hbitats naturales, detener la prdida de biodiversidad y, de aqu a 2020, proteger las especies amenazadas y evitar su extincin&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 15.5.1: ndice de la Lista Roja&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;ltima actualizacin: 11 de julio de 2017&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Informacin institucional&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organizaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unin Internacional para la Conservacin de la Naturaleza (UICN)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BirdLife International (BLI)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definicin: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El ndice de la Lista Roja mide el cambio en el riesgo de extincin agregado entre grupos de especies. Se basa en cambios genuinos en el nmero de especies en cada categora de riesgo de extincin en La Lista Roja de Especies Amenazadas de la UICN (UICN 2015) se expresa como cambios en un ndice que vara de 0 a 1. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las especies amenazadas son aquellas que figuran en la Lista Roja de Especies Amenazadas de la UICN en las categoras Vulnerables, En Peligro o Crticamente Amenazadas (es decir, especies que enfrentan un alto, muy alto o extremadamente alto riesgo de extincin en la naturaleza en el futuro a medio plazo). Los cambios a lo largo del tiempo en la proporcin de especies en peligro de extincin estn impulsados en gran medida por mejoras en el conocimiento y cambios en la taxonoma. El indicador excluye tales cambios para producir un indicador ms informativo que la simple proporcin de especies amenazadas. Por lo tanto, mide el cambio en el riesgo de extincin agregado entre grupos de especies a lo largo del tiempo, como resultado de mejoras o deterioros genuinos en el estado de las especies individuales. Puede calcularse para cualquier conjunto representativo de especies que hayan sido evaluadas para la Lista Roja de Especies Amenazadas de la UICN al menos dos veces (Butchart et al. 2004, 2005, 2007). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripcin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entre los organismos nacionales que producen datos pertinentes figuran el Gobierno, las organizaciones no gubernamentales (ONG) y las instituciones acadmicas que trabajan conjuntamente y por separado. Los datos se recopilan de fuentes publicadas e inditas, expertos en especies, cientficos y conservacionistas a travs de correspondencia, talleres y programas electrnicos. Los datos son presentados por los organismos nacionales a la UICN, o se recopilan a travs de iniciativas de la Asociacin de la Lista Roja. Desde 2013&amp;#x2013;6, la Asociacin de la Lista Roja abarc: BirdLife International; Botanic Gardens Conservation International; Conservacin Internacional; Microsoft; NatureServe; Real Jardn Botnico, Kew; Universidad Sapienza de Roma; Universidad de Texas A&amp;amp;M; Pantalla salvaje; y Zoological Society of London. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Proceso de recoleccin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ver informacin en otras categoras. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendario &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recopilacin de datos: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Lista Roja de Especies Amenazadas de la UICN se actualiza anualmente. Los ndices de la Lista Roja para cualquier conjunto de especies que se hayan reevaluado exhaustivamente en ese ao generalmente se publican junto con la actualizacin de la Lista Roja de la UICN. Los datos se almacenan y gestionan en la base de datos del Servicio de Informacin de Especies y estn disponibles gratuitamente para uso no comercial a travs del sitio web de la Lista Roja de la UICN. Se requieren reevaluaciones del riesgo de extincin para cada especie evaluada en la Lista Roja de Especies Amenazadas de la UICN una vez cada diez aos, e idealmente una vez cada cuatro aos. Un Plan Estratgico de la Lista Roja detalla un calendario de prximas reevaluaciones para cada grupo taxonmico. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Lanzamiento de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Por lo general, cada ao se dispone de nuevos datos para el ndice de la Lista Roja. Por ejemplo, el primer ndice de la Lista Roja para las ccadas se public en 2015, las actualizaciones de los ndices de la Lista Roja para aves y mamferos se publicarn en 2016, y las actualizaciones para las conferas y los tiburones se anticipan en 2017. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entre los organismos nacionales que producen datos pertinentes figuran el gobierno, las organizaciones no gubernamentales (ONG) y las instituciones acadmicas que trabajan conjuntamente y por separado. Los datos se recopilan de fuentes publicadas e inditas, expertos en especies, cientficos y conservacionistas a travs de correspondencia, talleres y programas electrnicos. Los datos son presentados por los organismos nacionales a la UICN, o se recopilan a travs de iniciativas de la Asociacin de la Lista Roja. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nombre:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UICN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripcin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La compilacin y presentacin de informes del ndice de la Lista Roja a nivel mundial est a cargo de la Unin Internacional para la Conservacin de la Naturaleza (UICN) y BirdLife International, en nombre de la Asociacin de la Lista Roja. Por ejemplo, Baillie et al. (2004) y Hoffmann et al. (2010) han publicado sntesis exhaustivas de la Lista Roja de Especies Amenazadas de la UICN. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justificacin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las especies del mundo se ven afectadas por una serie de procesos amenazantes, incluyendo la destruccin y degradacin del hbitat, la sobreexplotacin, las especies exticas invasoras, la perturbacin humana, la contaminacin y el cambio climtico. Este indicador puede utilizarse para evaluar los cambios generales en el riesgo de extincin de grupos de especies como resultado de estas amenazas y la medida en que se estn mitigando las amenazas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El valor del ndice de la Lista Roja vara de 1 (todas las especies se clasifican como &amp;#x2018;Preocupacin menor&amp;#x2019;) a 0 (todas las especies se clasifican como &amp;#x2018;Extintas&amp;#x2019;), y por lo tanto indica hasta qu punto el conjunto de especies se ha movido en general hacia la extincin. Por lo tanto, el ndice de la Lista Roja permite comparaciones entre conjuntos de especies tanto en su nivel general de riesgo de extincin (es decir, qu tan amenazadas estn en promedio), como en la tasa a la que este riesgo cambia con el tiempo. Una tendencia a la baja en el ndice de la Lista Roja a lo largo del tiempo significa que la tasa esperada de extinciones futuras de especies est empeorando (es decir, la tasa de prdida de biodiversidad est aumentando). Una tendencia al alza significa que la tasa esperada de extinciones de especies est disminuyendo (es decir, la tasa de prdida de biodiversidad est disminuyendo), y una lnea horizontal significa que la tasa esperada de extinciones de especies sigue siendo la misma, aunque en cada uno de estos casos no significa que la prdida de biodiversidad se haya detenido. Una tendencia al alza del ndice de la Lista Roja indicara que la Meta 15.5 de los ODS de reducir la degradacin de los hbitats naturales y proteger las especies amenazadas va por buen camino. Un valor de ndice de la Lista Roja de 1 indicara que se ha detenido la prdida de biodiversidad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El nombre &amp;#x201C;ndice de la Lista Roja&amp;#x201D; no debe entenderse como un indicador compuesto de una serie de mtricas dispares (de la misma manera que, por ejemplo, se compila el ndice de Pobreza Multidimensional). El ndice de la Lista Roja proporciona un indicador de las tendencias en el riesgo de extincin de especies, medido utilizando las Categoras y Criterios de la Lista Roja de la UICN (Mace et al. 2008, IUCN 2012a), y se compila a partir de datos sobre los cambios a lo largo del tiempo en la Categora de la Lista Roja para cada especie, excluyendo cualquier cambio impulsado por un mejor conocimiento o una taxonoma revisada. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El ndice de la Lista Roja se utiliza como indicador hacia el Plan Estratgico para la Diversidad Biolgica 2011&amp;#x2013;2020 (CDB 2014, Tittensor et al. 2014), y se utiliz como indicador hacia la Meta 2010 del Convenio sobre la Diversidad Biolgica (Butchart et al. 2010) y el Objetivo de Desarrollo del Milenio 7. Tambin se puede proyectar para evaluar escenarios de desarrollo futuros (Visconti et al. 2015). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hay cuatro fuentes principales de incertidumbre asociadas con los valores y las tendencias del ndice de la Lista Roja. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conocimiento inadecuado, incompleto o inexacto del estado de una especie. Esta incertidumbre se minimiza asignando estimaciones del riesgo de extincin a categoras que son amplias en magnitud y momento. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Retrasos en el conocimiento de una especie que est disponible para su evaluacin. Tales retrasos se aplican a una pequea (y decreciente) proporcin de cambios de estatus, y pueden ser superados en el ndice de la Lista Roja a travs del clculo retrospectivo. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inconsistencia entre las evaluaciones de especies. Estos pueden reducirse al mnimo mediante el requisito de proporcionar documentacin de apoyo que detalle los mejores datos disponibles, con justificaciones, fuentes y estimaciones de incertidumbre y calidad de los datos, que son verificadas y estandarizadas por la UICN a travs de las Autoridades de la Lista Roja, un Grupo de Trabajo Tcnico de la Lista Roja y un Subcomit independiente de Normas y Peticiones. Adems, se mantienen directrices detalladas sobre la aplicacin de las categoras y criterios (IUCN SPSC 2016), as como un curso de formacin en lnea (en ingls, espaol y francs). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Las especies que son demasiado poco conocidas para que se apliquen los Criterios de la Lista Roja se asignan a la categora de Datos Deficientes y se excluyen del clculo del ndice de la Lista Roja. De las aves, solo el 0,8% de las especies existentes se evalan como Deficientes en Datos, en comparacin con el 24% de los anfibios. Si las especies con datos deficientes difieren en la tasa a la que su riesgo de extincin est cambiando, el ndice de la Lista Roja puede dar una imagen sesgada del riesgo de extincin cambiante del conjunto general de especies. El grado de incertidumbre que esto introduce se estima a travs de un procedimiento autodecimante que asigna aleatoriamente a cada especie con datos deficientes una categora basada en el nmero de especies no deficientes en datos en cada categora de la Lista Roja para el conjunto de especies bajo consideracin, y repite esto para 1,000 iteraciones, trazando los percentiles 2.5 y 97.5 como intervalos de confianza inferior y superior para la mediana. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La principal limitacin del ndice de la Lista Roja est relacionada con el hecho de que las Categoras de la Lista Roja son medidas relativamente amplias de estatus, y por lo tanto el ndice de la Lista Roja para cualquier grupo taxonmico individual puede actualizarse prcticamente a intervalos de al menos cuatro aos. Como el ndice general se agrega a travs de mltiples grupos taxonmicos, se puede actualizar tpicamente anualmente. Adems, el ndice de la Lista Roja no refleja particularmente bien el estado de deterioro de las especies comunes que siguen siendo abundantes y generalizadas, pero que estn disminuyendo lentamente. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Metodologa&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mtodo de clculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El ndice de la Lista Roja se calcula en un momento dado multiplicando primero el nmero de especies en cada categora de la Lista Roja por una ponderacin (que va de 1 para &amp;#x2018;Casi Amenazado&amp;#x2019; a 5 para &amp;#x2018;Extinto&amp;#x2019; y &amp;#x2018;Extinto en estado salvaje&amp;#x2019;) y sumando estos valores. A continuacin se divide por una puntuacin de amenaza mxima que es el nmero total de especies multiplicado por la ponderacin asignada a la categora &amp;#x2018;Extinta&amp;#x2019;. Este valor final se resta de 1 para obtener el valor del ndice de la Lista Roja.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matemticamente este clculo se expresa como: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ILRt = 1 &amp;#x2013; [(Ss Wc(t,s) / (WEX * N)]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donde Wc(t,s) es la ponderacin de la categora (c) en el momento (t) para la especie (s) (la ponderacin para &amp;#x2018;En peligro crtico&amp;#x2019; = 4, &amp;#x2018;En peligro&amp;#x2019; = 3, &amp;#x2018;Vulnerable&amp;#x2019; = 2, &amp;#x2018;Casi amenazada&amp;#x2019; = 1, &amp;#x2018;Preocupacin menor&amp;#x2019; = 0. A las especies &amp;#x2018;En peligro crtico&amp;#x2019; etiquetadas como &amp;#x2018;Posiblemente extinta&amp;#x2019; o &amp;#x2018;Posiblemente extinta en estado salvaje&amp;#x2019; se les asigna una ponderacin de 5); WEX = 5, la ponderacin asignada a las especies &amp;#x2018;Extinto&amp;#x2019; o &amp;#x2018;Extinta en estado salvaje&amp;#x2019;; y N es el nmero total de especies evaluadas, excluyendo las evaluadas como Datos Insuficientes en el perodo actual, y las consideradas como &amp;#x2018;Extintas&amp;#x2019; en el ao en que el conjunto de especies fue evaluado por primera vez.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La frmula requiere que:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Se incluya exactamente el mismo conjunto de especies en todos los periodos de tiempo, y&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;los nicos cambios en la categora de la Lista Roja sean los que resultan de una autntica mejora o deterioro del estado (es decir, se excluyen los cambios resultantes de la mejora de los conocimientos o de las revisiones taxonmicas), y&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;se excluyan las especies con datos insuficientes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En muchos casos, las listas de especies cambiarn ligeramente de una evaluacin a la siguiente (por ejemplo, debido a revisiones taxonmicas). Por lo tanto, las condiciones pueden cumplirse ajustando retrospectivamente las categorizaciones anteriores de la Lista Roja utilizando la informacin y la taxonoma actuales. Esto se consigue asumiendo que las categoras actuales de la Lista Roja para los taxones se han aplicado desde que el conjunto de especies fue evaluado por primera vez para la Lista Roja, a menos que haya informacin que indique lo contrario y que se hayan producido verdaderos cambios de estado. Dicha informacin suele ser contextual (por ejemplo, relacionada con la historia conocida de prdida de hbitat dentro del rea de distribucin de la especie). Si no se dispone de suficiente informacin sobre una especie recin aadida, no se incorpora al ndice de la Lista Roja hasta que se evala por segunda vez, momento en el que las evaluaciones anteriores se corrigen retrospectivamente extrapolando las tendencias recientes de la poblacin, el rea de distribucin, el hbitat y las amenazas, con el apoyo de informacin adicional. Para evitar resultados espurios derivados de una seleccin sesgada de especies, los ndices de la Lista Roja suelen calcularse slo para grupos taxonmicos en los que todas las especies del mundo han sido evaluadas para la Lista Roja, o para muestras de especies que han sido seleccionadas sistemtica o aleatoriamente.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los mtodos y la base cientfica del ndice de la Lista Roja fueron descritos por Butchart et al. (2004, 2005, 2007, 2010). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Butchart et al. (2010) tambin describieron los mtodos por los cuales los ndices de la Lista Roja para diferentes grupos taxonmicos se agregan para producir un nico ndice de la Lista Roja multi-taxn. En concreto, los ndices de la Lista Roja agregados se calculan como la media aritmtica de los ndices de la Lista Roja modelados. Los ndices de la Lista Roja para cada grupo taxonmico se interpolan linealmente para los aos entre los puntos de datos y se extrapolan linealmente (con una pendiente igual a la de los dos puntos evaluados ms cercanos) para alinearlos con los aos para los que se dispone de ndices de la Lista Roja para otros taxones. Los ndices de la Lista Roja para cada grupo taxonmico para cada ao se modelan para tener en cuenta varias fuentes de incertidumbre: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deficiencia de datos: las categoras de la Lista Roja (desde Preocupacin Menor hasta Extinto) se asignan a todas las especies con Datos Insuficientes, con una probabilidad proporcional al nmero de especies en categoras no insuficientes para ese grupo taxonmico; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Incertidumbre en la extrapolacin: aunque los ILR se extrapolaron linealmente basndose en la pendiente del punto ms cercano de dos evaluaciones, existe incertidumbre sobre la precisin de esta pendiente. Para incorporar esta incertidumbre, en lugar de extrapolar de forma determinista, la pendiente utilizada para la extrapolacin se selecciona a partir de una distribucin normal con una probabilidad igual a la pendiente de los dos puntos evaluados ms cercanos, y una desviacin estndar igual al 60% de esta pendiente (es decir, el CV es del 60%); &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Variabilidad temporal: el &amp;#x2018;verdadero&amp;#x2019; ndice de la Lista Roja probablemente cambie de un ao a otro, pero como las evaluaciones se repiten solo a intervalos de varios aos, el valor preciso para cualquier ao en particular es incierto. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para hacer explcita esta incertidumbre, el valor del ndice de la Lista Roja para un grupo taxonmico dado en un ao determinado se asigna a partir de una ventana mvil de cinco aos, centrada en el ao focal (con la ventana fijada en 3-4 aos para los dos primeros y los dos ltimos aos de la serie). Obsrvese que la incertidumbre de la evaluacin no puede incorporarse an al ndice. En la prctica, estas incertidumbres se incorporan a los ndices agregados de la Lista Roja de la siguiente manera: a las especies con datos insuficientes se les asign una categora como se ha descrito anteriormente, y se calcul un ndice de la Lista Roja para cada grupo taxonmico interpolando y extrapolando como se ha descrito anteriormente. Se asign un valor final del ndice de la Lista Roja a cada grupo taxonmico para cada ao de una ventana de aos como se ha descrito anteriormente. Cada una de estas &amp;#x2018;ejecuciones&amp;#x2019; produjo un ndice de la Lista Roja para el perodo completo de cada grupo taxonmico, incorporando las diversas fuentes de incertidumbre. Se generan diez mil ejecuciones de este tipo para cada grupo taxonmico y se calcula la media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A continuacin se describen los mtodos para generar desagregaciones nacionales del ndice de la Lista Roja.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel de pas:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los ndices de la Lista Roja para cada grupo taxonmico se interpolan linealmente para los aos entre los puntos de datos y se extrapolan linealmente (con una pendiente igual a la de los dos puntos evaluados ms cercanos, excepto para los corales) hasta el punto de tiempo ms antiguo y hacia el presente para los aos para los que no se dispone de estimaciones. El ao de inicio del ndice agregado se establece como diez aos antes del primer ao de evaluacin para el grupo taxonmico con el punto de inicio ms tardo. Los corales no se extrapolan linealmente porque se sabe que los descensos han sido mucho ms pronunciados despus de 1996 (debido a los eventos de blanqueo extremo) que antes. Por lo tanto, la tasa de disminucin anterior a 1996 se establece como la media de las tasas de los otros grupos taxonmicos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel regional y global:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El ndice de la Lista Roja se calcula a nivel mundial basndose en las evaluaciones del riesgo de extincin de cada especie incluida, ya que muchas especies tienen distribuciones que abarcan muchos pases. Por lo tanto, aunque ciertamente hay incertidumbre en torno al ndice de la Lista Roja, no hay valores faltantes como tales, por lo que no es necesaria la imputacin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las categoras y los criterios de la Lista Roja se aplican a cada una de las especies de la Lista Roja de Especies Amenazadas de la UICN y se determinan a nivel mundial y las proporcionan principalmente los Grupos Especialistas y las Autoridades independientes de la Lista Roja de la Comisin de Supervivencia de Especies de la UICN, las iniciativas dirigidas por la Secretara de la UICN, la asociacin BirdLife International y las dems organizaciones asociadas a la Lista Roja de la UICN. El personal del Programa Mundial de Especies de la UICN recopila, valida y conserva estos datos, y es responsable de publicar y comunicar los resultados. Cada evaluacin individual de las especies se apoya en la aplicacin de metadatos y normas de documentacin (UICN 2013), incluyendo clasificaciones de, por ejemplo, amenazas y acciones de conservacin (Salafsky et al. 2008). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las evaluaciones de la Lista Roja se realizan a travs de talleres abiertos o de foros de debate de libre acceso en la web. Las evaluaciones son revisadas por la Autoridad de la Lista Roja correspondiente (una persona u organizacin designada por la Comisin de Supervivencia de Especies de la UICN para revisar las evaluaciones de especies o grupos de especies especficos) para garantizar la normalizacin y la coherencia en la interpretacin de la informacin y la aplicacin de los criterios. Un Grupo de Trabajo Tcnico de la Lista Roja y la Unidad de la Lista Roja de la UICN trabajan para garantizar una categorizacin coherente entre especies, grupos y evaluaciones. Por ltimo, un Subcomit de Normas y Peticiones supervisa el proceso y resuelve las impugnaciones y disputas sobre las evaluaciones de la Lista Roja.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adems, la UICN publica directrices sobre la aplicacin de las categoras y criterios de la Lista Roja de la UICN a escala regional o nacional (UICN 2012b). Basndose en ellas, muchos pases han iniciado programas para evaluar el riesgo de extincin de las especies que se encuentran dentro de sus fronteras. Estos pases podrn aplicar el ndice de la Lista Roja basado en el riesgo de extincin nacional, una vez que hayan realizado al menos dos Listas Rojas nacionales utilizando el sistema de la UICN de forma coherente (Bubb et al. 2009). Un nmero cada vez mayor de pases ha completado los ndices de la Lista Roja nacional para una serie de taxones (por ejemplo, G&amp;#xE4;rdenfors 2010, Pihl &amp;amp; Flensted 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mientras que los ndices de la Lista Roja globales pueden desglosarse para mostrar las tendencias de las especies a escalas espaciales ms pequeas, lo contrario no es cierto. Los ndices de la Lista Roja nacionales o regionales no pueden agregarse para producir ndices de la Lista Roja que muestren las tendencias globales. Esto se debe a que el riesgo de extincin global de un taxn debe evaluarse a escala global y no puede determinarse directamente a partir de mltiples evaluaciones a escala nacional en su rea de distribucin (aunque los datos de dichas evaluaciones pueden agregarse para incluirlos en la evaluacin global).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Mtodos y directrices a disposicin de los pases para la compilacin de los datos a nivel nacional:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ver los metadatos existentes para el indicador 15.5.1 del ndice de la Lista Roja, especialmente la seccin sobre &amp;#x201C;Metodologa&amp;#x201D;. En resumen: los datos en los que se basa el ndice de la Lista Roja se compilan bajo la autoridad del Comit de la Lista Roja de la UICN, mediante la aplicacin de los Criterios y Categoras de la Lista Roja de la UICN(&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10315&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10315&lt;/a&gt;). Esto incluye la presentacin de endemismos a partir de los procesos nacionales de elaboracin de listas rojas, cuando estos se hayan llevado a cabo siguiendo las &amp;#x201C;Directrices para la aplicacin de los criterios de la Lista Roja de la UICN a nivel regional y nacional&amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10336&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10336&lt;/a&gt;) y siguiendo la &amp;#x201C;Informacin de apoyo necesaria y recomendada para las evaluaciones de la Lista Roja de la UICN&amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/O52euG&quot;&gt;http://goo.gl/O52euG&lt;/a&gt;). Las evaluaciones pueden presentarse en los tres idiomas de la UICN (ingls, francs y espaol) y en portugus. Todas las evaluaciones son revisadas por pares a travs de la Autoridad de la Lista Roja pertinente para la especie o grupo de especies en cuestin, como se documenta en el Reglamento de la Lista Roja (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/Rules_of_Procedure_for_IUCN_Red_List_Assessments_2017-2020.pdf&quot;&gt;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/Rules_of_Procedure_for_IUCN_Red_List_Assessments_2017-2020.pdf&lt;/a&gt;); vase en particular el Anexo 3, los &amp;#x201C;Detalles de los pasos implicados en el proceso de la Lista Roja de la UICN&amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/Details_of_the_Steps_Involved_in_the_IUCN_Red_List_Process.pdf&quot;&gt;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/Details_of_the_Steps_Involved_in_the_IUCN_Red_List_Process.pdf&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ver los metadatos existentes para el indicador 15.5.1 del ndice de la Lista Roja, especialmente la seccin sobre &amp;#x201C;Metodologa&amp;#x201D;. En resumen: el documento clave que ofrece recomendaciones y directrices internacionales a los pases y a todos los implicados en la aplicacin de los Criterios y Categoras de la Lista Roja de la UICN (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10315&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10315&lt;/a&gt;) es la &amp;#x201C;Directrices para el uso de las categoras y criterios de la Lista Roja de la UICN&amp;#x201D; (en ingls - &lt;a href=&quot;http://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/RedListGuidelines.pdf&quot;&gt;http://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/RedListGuidelines.pdf&lt;/a&gt; y en francs - &lt;a href=&quot;http://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/RedListGuidelines_FR.pdf&quot;&gt;http://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/RedListGuidelines_FR.pdf&lt;/a&gt;) acompaada de la &amp;#x201C;Informacin de apoyo necesaria y recomendada para las evaluaciones de la Lista Roja de la UICN&amp;#x201D;. En el caso de los pases (y regiones), esto se complementa con las &amp;#x201C;Directrices para la aplicacin de los criterios de la Lista Roja de la UICN a nivel regional y nacional&amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10336&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10336&lt;/a&gt;). Para apoyar el clculo de los ndices de la Lista Roja para cualquier pas (o regin), &amp;#x201C;El cdigo R para calcular y trazar los RLI nacionales ponderados por la proporcin de la distribucin de cada especie dentro de un pas o regin&amp;#x201D; est publicado en lnea (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/R_code_for_calculating_RLIs_weighted_by_proportion_of_each_species&amp;apos;_range_within_a_country_or_region.pdf&quot;&gt;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/R_code_for_calculating_RLIs_weighted_by_proportion_of_each_species&amp;apos;_rango_dentro_de_un_pas_o_regin.pdf&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Garanta de calidad:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vanse los metadatos existentes para el indicador 15.5.1 del ndice de la Lista Roja, especialmente la seccin sobre &amp;#x201C;Metodologa&amp;#x201D;, con la documentacin completa en las Normas de Procedimiento de la Lista Roja (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/Rules_of_Procedure_for_IUCN_Red_List_Assessments_2017-2020.pdf&quot;&gt;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/Rules_of_Procedure_for_IUCN_Red_List_Assessments_2017-2020.pdf&lt;/a&gt;) en particular el Anexo 3, los &amp;#x201C;Detalles de los pasos involucrados en el proceso de la Lista Roja de la UICN&amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/Details_of_the_Steps_Involved_in_the_IUCN_Red_List_Process.pdf&quot;&gt;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/Details_of_the_Steps_Involved_in_the_IUCN_Red_List_Process.pdf&lt;/a&gt;). En resumen: todas las evaluaciones de la Lista Roja son revisadas por pares a travs de la Autoridad de la Lista Roja pertinente para la especie o grupo de especies en cuestin; y todas las evaluaciones de la Lista Roja se someten a controles de coherencia (para garantizar la coherencia con las evaluaciones presentadas para otros grupos taxonmicos, regiones, procesos, etc.) por la Unidad de la Lista Roja antes de su publicacin en el sitio web de la Lista Roja (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iucnredlist.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.iucnredlist.org/&lt;/a&gt;). Por ltimo, el Presidente de la Comisin de Supervivencia de Especies de la UICN (elegido cada cuatro aos por los miembros gubernamentales y no gubernamentales de la UICN) nombra a un Presidente para un Subcomit de Normas y Peticiones (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iucn.org/theme/species/about/species-survival-commission/ssc-leadership-and-steering-committee/sub-committees/standards-and-petitions-subcommittee&quot;&gt;https://www.iucn.org/theme/species/about/species-survival-commission/ssc-leadership-and-steering-committee/sub-committees/standards-and-petitions-subcommittee&lt;/a&gt;), que se encarga de garantizar la calidad y las normas de la Lista Roja de la UICN y de resolver las peticiones contra la inclusin de especies en la Lista Roja de la UICN. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adems de la difusin a travs del sitio web de la Lista Roja (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iucnredlist.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.iucnredlist.org/&lt;/a&gt;), los datos de la Lista Roja se difunden a travs de la Herramienta Integrada de Evaluacin de la Biodiversidad, disponible para la investigacin y la conservacin en lnea (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/&quot;&gt;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/&lt;/a&gt;). En ella se incorporan los documentos de los perfiles de pas de todos los pases del mundo que incluyen la documentacin del indicador del ndice de la Lista Roja del ao en curso, a partir de 2016. La primera edicin de cada uno de estos Perfiles de Pas se envi para consulta a los Puntos Focales Nacionales del Convenio sobre la Diversidad Biolgica (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/information/nfp.shtml&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/information/nfp.shtml&lt;/a&gt;), en la 13 reunin de la Conferencia de las Partes del Convenio sobre la Diversidad Biolgica; y este proceso se repetir anualmente.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripcin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El ndice de la Lista Roja ha sido clasificado por el IAEG-SDG como Nivel 1. Se dispone de datos actuales para todos los pases del mundo, que se actualizan peridicamente (aproximadamente una vez cada cuatro aos).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desde 1980 (aproximadamente 35 aos). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregacin:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El ndice de la Lista Roja puede reducirse para mostrar los ndices de la Lista Roja nacionales y regionales, ponderados por la fraccin de la distribucin de cada especie que se da en el pas o regin, basndose en el mtodo publicado por Rodrigues et al. (2014) PLoS ONE 9(11): e113934. Estos muestran un ndice de probabilidad de supervivencia agregada (el inverso del riesgo de extincin) para todas las aves, mamferos, anfibios, corales y ccadas que se dan en el pas o regin. El ndice muestra el grado de conservacin de las especies en un pas o regin en relacin con su contribucin potencial a la conservacin global de las especies. El ndice se calcula como: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RLI(t,u) = 1 &amp;#x2013; [(Ss(W(t,s) * (rsu/Rs)) / (WEX * Ss (rsu/Rs))&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;donde t es el ao de la reevaluacin global, u es la unidad espacial (es decir pas), W_((t,s)) es la ponderacin de la categora global de la Lista Roja para la especie s en el momento t (Preocupacin mnima =0, Casi amenazada =1, Vulnerable =2, En peligro =3, En peligro crtico =4, En peligro crtico (posiblemente extinto) =5, En Peligro Crtico (Posiblemente Extinto en Estado Silvestre) =5, Extinto en Estado Silvestre =5 y Extinto =5), WEX = 5 es la ponderacin de las especies Extintas, r_su es la fraccin del rea de distribucin total de la especie s en la unidad u, y R_s es el tamao total del rea de distribucin de la especie s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El ndice vara de 1 si el pas ha contribuido lo mnimo que puede al ILR global (es decir, si el numerador es 0 porque todas las especies en el pas son LC) a 0 si el pas ha contribuido lo mximo que puede al ILR global (es decir, si el numerador es igual al denominador porque todas las especies en el pas estn Extintas o Posiblemente Extintas). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los grupos taxonmicos incluidos son aquellos en los que todas las especies han sido evaluadas para la Lista Roja de la UICN ms de una vez. Las categoras de la Lista Roja correspondientes a los aos en los que se han realizado evaluaciones completas (es decir, aquellas en las que se han evaluado todas las especies del grupo taxonmico) se determinan siguiendo el enfoque de Butchart et al. 2007; PLoS ONE 2(1): e140, es decir, coinciden con las categoras actuales, excepto en el caso de aquellos taxones que han experimentado una autntica mejora o deterioro del riesgo de extincin de magnitud suficiente como para optar a una categora de la Lista Roja superior o inferior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador tambin se puede desglosar por ecosistemas, hbitats y otras divisiones polticas y geogrficas (p. ej., Han et al. 2014), por subconjuntos taxonmicos (p. ej., Hoffmann et al. 2011), por conjuntos de especies relevantes para determinados tratados internacionales o legislacin (p. ej, Croxall et al. 2012), por conjuntos de especies expuestas a determinados procesos de amenaza (p. ej., Butchart 2008) y por conjuntos de especies que prestan determinados servicios ecosistmicos o tienen determinados rasgos biolgicos o vitales (p. ej., Regan et al. 2015). En cada caso, se puede obtener informacin de la Lista Roja de Especies Amenazadas de la UICN para determinar qu especies son relevantes para determinados subconjuntos (por ejemplo, las que se dan en determinados ecosistemas, hbitats y reas geogrficas de inters).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los desgloses del ndice de la Lista Roja tambin son de especial relevancia como indicadores para las siguientes metas de los ODS (Brooks et al. 2015): ODS 2.4 ndice de la Lista Roja (especies utilizadas para la alimentacin y la medicina); ODS 2.5 ndice de la Lista Roja (parientes silvestres y razas locales); ODS 12.2 ndice de la Lista Roja (impactos de la utilizacin) (Butchart 2008); ODS 12.4 ndice de la Lista Roja (impactos de la contaminacin); ODS 13.1 ndice de la Lista Roja (impactos del cambio climtico); ODS 14.1 ndice de la Lista Roja (impactos de la contaminacin en las especies marinas); ODS 14.2 ndice de la Lista Roja (especies marinas); ODS 14.3 ndice de la Lista Roja (especies de coral constructoras de arrecifes) (Carpenter et al. 2008); ODS 14.4 ndice de la Lista Roja (impactos de la utilizacin sobre las especies marinas) &amp;#x2013; un Grupo de Expertos Tcnicos ad hoc FAO-UICN est trabajando actualmente para desarrollar recomendaciones acordadas sobre el uso y la interpretacin de este indicador; ODS 15.1 ndice de la Lista Roja (especies terrestres y de agua dulce); ODS 15.2 ndice de la Lista Roja (especies forestales); ODS 15.4 ndice de la Lista Roja (especies de montaa); ODS 15.7 ndice de la Lista Roja (impactos de la utilizacin) (Butchart 2008); y ODS 15.8 ndice de la Lista Roja (impactos de las especies exticas invasoras) (Butchart 2008, McGeoch et al. 2010).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Fuentes de discrepancia:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Algunos pases han evaluado el riesgo de extincin nacional de las especies presentes en el pas y han repetido dichas evaluaciones, lo que permite elaborar un ndice nacional de la Lista Roja. Esto puede diferir del indicador descrito aqu porque (a) considera el riesgo de extincin nacional en lugar del global, y (b) porque no tiene en cuenta la responsabilidad nacional de la conservacin de cada especie, tratando como iguales tanto a las especies que no se dan en ninguna parte fuera del pas (es decir, las endmicas nacionales) como a las que tienen una gran rea de distribucin y se dan en muchos otros pases. Las diferencias sern menores en el caso de los pases en los que una alta proporcin de especies son endmicas (es decir, que solo se encuentran en ese pas), como en muchas naciones insulares y pases montaosos, especialmente en los trpicos. Las diferencias sern mayores en los pases en los que una alta proporcin de especies se distribuyen ampliamente en muchas naciones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iucn.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.iucn.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.birdlife.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.birdlife.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Referencias:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estos metadatos se basan en &lt;a href=&quot;http://mdgs.un.org/unsd/mi/wiki/7-7-Proportion-of-species-threatened-with-extinction.ashx,%20supplemented%20by%20http:/www.bipindicators.net/rli/2010%20&quot;&gt;http://mdgs.un.org/unsd/mi/wiki/7-7-Proportion-of-species-threatened-with-extinction.ashx, complementados por http://www.bipindicators.net/rli/2010&lt;/a&gt; y las referencias que se indican a continuacin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BAILLIE, J. E. M. et al. (2004). 2004 IUCN Red List of Threatened Species: a Global Species Assessment. UICN, Gland, Suiza y Cambridge, Reino Unido. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9830.%20&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9830.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BROOKS, T. M. et al. (2015). Aprovechamiento de los productos de conocimiento sobre biodiversidad y conservacin para el seguimiento de las Metas de Aichi y los Objetivos de Desarrollo Sostenible. Biodiversidad 16: 157&amp;#x2013;174. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/pdf/10.1080/14888386.2015.1075903&quot;&gt;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/pdf/10.1080/14888386.2015.1075903&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUBB, P.J. et al. (2009). IUCN Red List Index - Guidance for National and Regional Use. UICN, Gland, Suiza. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9321.&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9321.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2010). Global biodiversity: indicators of recent declines. Science 328: 1164&amp;#x2013;1168. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/328/5982/1164.short&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/328/5982/1164.short&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. (2008). ndices de la Lista Roja para medir la sostenibilidad del uso de las especies y los impactos de las especies exticas invasoras. Bird Conservation International 18 (suppl.): 245&amp;#x2013;262. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayJournal?jid=BCI&quot;&gt;http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayJournal?jid=BCI&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2007). Improvements to the Red List Index. PLoS ONE 2(1): e140. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0000140&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0000140&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2006). Biodiversity indicators based on trends in conservation status: strengths of the IUCN Red List Index. Conservation Biology 20: 579&amp;#x2013;581. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2006.00410.x/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2006.00410.x/abstract&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2005). Using Red List Indices to measure progress towards the 2010 target and beyond. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London B 360: 255&amp;#x2013;268. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/360/1454/255.full.&quot;&gt;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/360/1454/255.full.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2004). Measuring global trends in the status of biodiversity: Red List Indices for birds. PLoS Biology 2(12): e383. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.plosbiology.org/article/info:doi/10.1371/journal.pbio.0020383&quot;&gt;http://www.plosbiology.org/article/info:doi/10.1371/journal.pbio.0020383&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CARPENTER, K. E. et al. (2008). Un tercio de los corales constructores de arrecifes se enfrenta a un elevado riesgo de extincin por el cambio climtico y los impactos locales. Science 321: 560&amp;#x2013;563. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/321/5888/560.short&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/321/5888/560.short&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBD (2014). Perspectiva mundial sobre la biodiversidad 4. Convenio sobre la Diversidad Biolgica, Montr&amp;#xE9;al, Canad. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/gbo4/&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/gbo4/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CROXALL, J. P. et al. (2012). Estado de conservacin de las aves marinas, amenazas y acciones prioritarias: una evaluacin global. Bird Conservation International 22: 1&amp;#x2013;34. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;G&amp;#xC4;RDENFORS, U. (ed.) (2010). R&amp;#xF6;dlistade arter i Sverige 2010 &amp;#x2013; The 2010 Red List of Swedish Species. ArtDatabanken, SLU, Uppsala.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HAN, X. et al. (2014). A Biodiversity indicators dashboard: addressing challenges to monitoring progress towards the Aichi Biodiversity Targets using disaggregated global data. PLoS ONE 9(11): e112046. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0112046&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0112046&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOFFMANN, M. et al. (2010). The impact of conservation on the status of the world&amp;#x2019;s vertebrates. Science 330: 1503&amp;#x2013;1509. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/330/6010/1503.short&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/330/6010/1503.short&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOFFMANN, M. et al. (2011). The changing fates of the world&amp;#x2019;s mammals. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London B 366: 2598&amp;#x2013;2610. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/366/1578/2598.abstract%20&quot;&gt;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/366/1578/2598.abstract&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UICN SPSC (2016) Directrices para el uso de las categoras y criterios de la Lista Roja de la UICN. Versin 12. Unin Internacional para la Conservacin de la Naturaleza &amp;#x2013; Subcomit de Normas y Peticiones, Gland, Suiza. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iucnredlist.org/documents/RedListGuidelines.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.iucnredlist.org/documents/RedListGuidelines.pdf&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UICN (2012a). Categoras y criterios de la Lista Roja de la UICN: Versin 3.1. Segunda edicin. Unin Internacional para la Conservacin de la Naturaleza, Gland, Suiza. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10315&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10315&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UICN (2012b). Directrices para la aplicacin de los criterios de la Lista Roja de la UICN a nivel regional y nacional&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Niveles regionales y nacionales: Versin 4.0. Unin Internacional para la Conservacin de la Naturaleza, Gland, Suiza. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10336&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10336&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IUCN (2013). Normas de documentacin y controles de coherencia para las evaluaciones de la Lista Roja de la UICN y las cuentas de las especies. Unin Internacional para la Conservacin de la Naturaleza, Gland, Suiza. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/RL_Standards_Consistency.pdf&quot;&gt;http://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/RL_Standards_Consistency.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IUCN (2015). Lista roja de especies amenazadas de la UICN. Versin 2015.1. Unin Internacional para la Conservacin de la Naturaleza, Gland, Suiza. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iucnredlist.org&quot;&gt;http://www.iucnredlist.org&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MACE, G. M. et al. (2008) Quantification of extinction risk: El sistema de la UICN para clasificar las especies amenazadas. Conservation Biology 22: 1424&amp;#x2013;1442. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2008.01044.x/full&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2008.01044.x/full&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MCGEOCH, M. A. et al. (2010) Global indicators of biological invasion: species numbers, biodiversity impact and policy responses. Diversity and Distributions 16: 95&amp;#x2013;108. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1472-4642.2009.00633.x/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1472-4642.2009.00633.x/abstract&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PIHL, S. y FLENSTED, K. N. (2011). Un ndice de la Lista Roja para las aves reproductoras en Dinamarca en el perodo 1991-2009. Dansk Ornitologisk Forenings Tidsskrift 105: 211-218.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;REGAN, E. et al. (2015). Tendencias globales en el estado de los polinizadores de aves y mamferos. Conservation Letters. doi: 10.1111/conl.12162. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12162/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12162/abstract&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RODRIGUES, A. S. L. et al. (2014). Tendencias espacialmente explcitas en el estado de conservacin global de los vertebrados. PLoS ONE 9(11): e113934. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0113934&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0113934&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SALAFSKY, N., et al. (2008) Un lxico estndar para la conservacin de la biodiversidad: clasificaciones unificadas de amenazas y acciones. Conservation Biology 22: 897&amp;#x2013;911. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2008.00937.x/full&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2008.00937.x/full&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TITTENSOR, D. et al. (2014). Un anlisis a medio plazo del progreso hacia los objetivos internacionales de biodiversidad. Science 346: 241&amp;#x2013;244. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/346/6206/241.short&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/346/6206/241.short&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VISCONTI, P. et al. (2015) Proyeccin de los indicadores de biodiversidad global bajo futuros escenarios de desarrollo. Conservation Letters. doi: 10.1111/conl.12159. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12159/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12159/abstract&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 15 : Prserver et restaurer les cosystmes terrestres, en veillant  les exploiter de faon durable, grer durablement les forts, lutter contre la dsertification, enrayer et inverser le processus de dgradation des terres etmettre fin  lappauvrissement de la biodiversit&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 15.5: Prendre durgence des mesures nergiques pour rduire la dgradation du milieu naturel, mettre un terme  lappauvrissement de la biodiversit et, dici  2020, protger les espces menaces et prvenir leur extinction&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 15.5.1: Indice de la Liste rouge&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dernire mise  jour : 11 Juillet 2017&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;leve.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt; 15:          , ,   ,          &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 15.5:          ,       2020      ,    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 15.5.1:   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; : 11  2017 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;   &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;  (): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     () &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      (BLI) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;    &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;           .                 ,     ( 2015),         0  1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     -  ,             &quot;, &quot; &quot;  &quot;  &quot; (. . ,    ,   ,          ).       ,   ,         .    ,     ,     ,     .  ,                    .        ,                 (Butchart et al. 2004, 2005, 2007).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;   &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  ,   ,  ,   ()   ,       .       ,  , ,   ,     ,    .              .  2013  2016     :      (BLI);      ;  ,     Conservation International;  &quot;&quot;;   NatureServe;   , ;    ;  - ;   Wildscreen;    .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;  : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; .    . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;  &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;  : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;   ,    ,  .       ,        ,        .           ,         -   .         ,       ,     ,    -     .              . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;  : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;          . ,          2015 ,           2016 ,          2017 .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;   &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ,   ,  ,   ()   ,       .       ,  ,      ,    .              .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;   &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                ()       (BLI)     .         , , Baillie  . (2004.)  Hoffmann  . (2010.).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;        ,      ,  ,   ,  ,    .                    ,      .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;       1 (     &quot;   &quot;)  0 (     &quot; &quot;) ,  , ,       .  ,               ( ,       ),    ,         .          ,         (..    ).    ,       (. .    ),    ,       ,          ,    .          ,   15.5                 .    ,  1,  ,     .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      ,  ,           (  , , ,    ).          ,           (Mace et al., 2008, IUCN 2012a)                ,   ,      .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;               2011-2020 . (CBD 2014, Tittensor et al, 2014)            2010 (Butchart et al., 2010)   7   ,    .           (Visconti et al., 2015). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;   : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     ,        . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; ,       .  
         ,       . &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;     ,    .  
   (  )              .&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;    .       
           ,       ,            ,            .  ,          (IUCN SPSC 2016),     - ( ,    ). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;,          
,    &quot; &quot;       .   ,  0,8%        &quot; &quot;    24% .  ,    &quot; &quot;,       ,              .  ,   ,     /,         ,    ,      ,         ,     1000 ,  2,5  97,5          .&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;        ,          , ,  ,                 .        ,     .  ,           ,        ,     .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;  &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;  : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                    (   1        5      &quot;   &quot;)     .        ,      ,   ,   &quot; &quot;.      1,      . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; RLIt = 1 &amp;#x2013; [(Ss Wc (t, s) / (WEX * N)] &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  Wc (t, s) -     (c)    (t)   (   &quot;  &quot; = 4, &quot; &quot; = 3, &quot;  &quot;= 2, &quot;   &quot; = 1, &quot;   &quot; = 0.  &quot;  &quot;,   &quot;  &quot;  &quot;    &quot;,   5); WEX = 5, ,   &quot; &quot;  &quot;   &quot;  N -    ,   ,     &quot; &quot;    ,  ,   &quot; &quot;  ,       .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  , : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;           ,  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;        , 
       (. .  ,       ), &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;   &quot; &quot;   &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;              (, -  ).  ,                   .     ,           ,         ,     ,     .      (,           ).       ,          ,        ,             , ,    ,   .     -   ,         ,              ,    ,       .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;        Butchart et al. (2004, 2005, 2007, 2010). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;   . (2010)   ,               -   .  ,             .                  ( ,       ),     ,         .                : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;  :     (   
  )      ,  ,             ; &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;  :      
         ,     ,       .    ,    , ,   ,      ,        ,   ,  60%   (. .    60%); &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;  :    , , 
   ,        ,        . &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     ,                        (    3-4          ).  ,          .            :        ,   ,              ,   .                ,   .                 ,    .             .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;         . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;   : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;   : &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                  ( ,        ,   )               ,    .                    .    ,  ,  ,  1996  (-  )    ,  .  ,    1996          . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;     : &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                  ,      ,   .  , , ,       ,     ,    . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;  : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;              ,    ,     ,                   ,      ,       (BLI)       .       ,     ,         .            (IUCN 2013),  , ,     (Salafsky et al. 2008). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;        ,       .       (  ,               )           .                  ,   . ,            ,      .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  ,                 ( 2012b).   ,         ,    .       ,        ,                 (Bubb et al. 2009).                (, G&amp;#xE4;rdenfors 2010, Pihl &amp;amp; Flensted 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;       ,         ,       .               ,   .    ,                           (           ).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;           : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; .     15.5.1   ,   &amp;#x201C; &amp;#x201D;.  : ,      ,               (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10315&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10315&lt;/a&gt;).         ,        &amp;#x201C;             &amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10336&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10336&lt;/a&gt;)   &amp;#x201C;           &amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/O52euG&quot;&gt;http://goo.gl/O52euG&lt;/a&gt;).          (,   )  .                ,        (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/Rules_of_Procedure_for_IUCN_Red_List_Assessments_2017-2020.pdf&quot;&gt;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/Rules_of_Procedure_for_IUCN_Red_List_Assessments_2017-2020 .pdf&lt;/a&gt;); .,  ,  3, &amp;#x201C;   ,       &amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/Details_of_the_Steps_Involved_in_the_IUCN_Red_List_Process.pdf&quot;&gt;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/Details_of_the_Steps_Involved_in_the_IUCN_Red_List_Process.pdf&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; .     15.5.1    ,    &amp;#x201C;&amp;#x201D;.  :  ,          ,          (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10315&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10315&lt;/a&gt;) -  &amp;#x201C;          &amp;#x201D; (   - &lt;a href=&quot;http://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/RedListGuidelines.pdf&quot;&gt;http://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/RedListGuidelines.pdf&lt;/a&gt;     -&lt;a href=&quot;http://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/RedListGuidelines_FR.pdf&quot;&gt;http://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/RedListGuidelines_FR.pdf&lt;/a&gt;)   &amp;#x201C;         &amp;#x201D;.   ( )   &amp;#x201C;           &amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10336&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10336&lt;/a&gt;).           ( )    &amp;#x201C; R        ,          . (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/R_code_for_calculating_RLIs_weighted_by_proportion_of_each_species&amp;apos;_range_within_a_country_or_region.pdf&quot;&gt;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/R_code_for_calculating_RLIs_weighted_by_proportion_of_each_species&amp;apos; _range_within_a_country_or_region.pdf&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;  : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; .     15.5.1    ,   &amp;#x201C;&amp;#x201D;,         (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/Rules_of_Procedure_for_IUCN_Red_List_Assessments_2017-2020.pdf&quot;&gt;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/Rules_of_Procedure_for_IUCN_Red_List_Assessments_2017-2020.pdf&lt;/a&gt;),    3, &amp;#x201C;   ,       &amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/Details_of_the_Steps_Involved_in_the_IUCN_Red_List_Process.pdf&quot;&gt;https://cmsdocs.s3 .amazonaws.com/keydocuments/Details_of_the_Steps_Involved_in_the_IUCN_Red_List_Process.pdf&lt;/a&gt;).  :                    ;         (    ,     , ,   . .)       -   (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iucnredlist.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.iucnredlist .org/&lt;/a&gt;). ,       (        )        (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iucn.org/theme/species/about/species-survival-commission/ssc-leadership-and-steering-committee/sub-committees/standards-and-petitions-subcommittee&quot;&gt;https://www.iucn.org/theme/species/about/species-survival-commission/ssc-leadership-and-steering-committee/sub-committees/standards-and-petitions-subcommittee&lt;/a&gt;,                     . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      -   (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iucnredlist.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.iucnredlist.org/&lt;/a&gt;)         ,        (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/&quot;&gt;https://www.ibat-alliance.org/ibat-conservation/&lt;/a&gt;).         ,          ,   2016 .                  (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/information/nfp.shtml&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/information/nfp.shtml&lt;/a&gt;)  13-       ;      .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;   &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;                  (-)   1.             (    ). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;  : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  1980  ( 35 ). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;               ,      ,      ,   ,  Rodrigues et al. (2014) PLoS ONE 9 (11): e113934.       (  )   , , ,   ,     .  ,                 .   : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; RLI (t, u) = 1 &amp;#x2013; [(Ss (W (t, s) * (rsu / Rs)) / (WEX * Ss (rsu / RS)) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  t -   , u -   (.. ), W _ ((t, s)) -        s    t (&quot;   &quot; = 0 , &quot;   &quot; = 1, &quot;  &quot; = 2,&quot;  &quot; = 3, &quot;  &quot; = 4, &quot;   ( )&quot; = 5, &quot;   (    )&quot; = 5, &quot;   &quot; = 5  &quot; &quot; = 5 ), WEX = 5 -    , r_su -       s   u,  R_s -     s. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    1,           (. .    0,          )  0,            ( ,    ,           ). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     ,           .     ,      (. . ,         ),      Butchart et al. 2007; PLoS ONE 2 (1): e140, ..    ,    ,         ,   ,          .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;      ,         (, Han et al. 2014),    (, Hoffmann et al. 2011),   ,        (, Croxall et al.2012),  ,     (, Butchart 2008),   ,             (, Regan et al.2015).            ,  ,       (,     ,    ,  ). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;               (Brooks et al. 2015):     2.4 (,       );     2.5 (    );     12.2 ( ) (Butchart 2008);     12.4 ( );     13.1 (  );     14.1 (    );     14.2 ( );     14.3 ( ) (  ., 2008);     14.4 (    );      -              ;     15.1 (   );     15.2 ( -);     15.4 ( );     15.7 ( ) (Butchart 2008);      15.8 (   ) (Butchart 2008, McGeoch et al. 2010). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;  : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;       ,   ,    ,       .     ,  ,  ()   ,     ,  ()            ,      ,         (   ),   ,    ,      .       ,        ( ,     ),        ,   .     ,           . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; URL-:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iucn.org/&quot;&gt; http://www.iucn.org/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.birdlife.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.birdlife.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     &lt;a href=&quot;http://mdgs.un.org/unsd/mi/wiki/7-7-Proportion-of-species-threatened-with-extinction.ashx,%20supplemented%20by%20http:/www.bipindicators.net/rli/2010%20&quot;&gt;http://mdgs.un.org/unsd/mi/wiki/7-7-Proportion-of-species-threatened-with-extinction.ashx, supplemented by http://www.bipindicators.net/rli/2010&lt;/a&gt;  ,  .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BAILLIE, J. E. M. et al. (2004). 2004 IUCN Red List of Threatened Species: a Global Species Assessment. IUCN, Gland, Switzerland and Cambridge, United Kingdom.   &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9830.%20&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9830.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BROOKS, T. M. et al. (2015). Harnessing biodiversity and conservation knowledge products to track the Aichi Targets and Sustainable Development Goals. Biodiversity 16: 157&amp;#x2013;174.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/pdf/10.1080/14888386.2015.1075903&quot;&gt;http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/pdf/10.1080/14888386.2015.1075903&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUBB, P.J. et al. (2009). IUCN Red List Index - Guidance for National and Regional Use. IUCN, Gland, Switzerland.   &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9321.&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/9321.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2010). Global biodiversity: indicators of recent declines. Science 328: 1164&amp;#x2013;1168.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/328/5982/1164.short&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/328/5982/1164.short&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. (2008). Red List Indices to measure the sustainability of species use and impacts of invasive alien species. Bird Conservation International 18 (suppl.): 245&amp;#x2013;262.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayJournal?jid=BCI&quot;&gt;http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayJournal?jid=BCI&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2007). Improvements to the Red List Index. PLoS ONE 2(1): e140.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0000140&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0000140&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2006). Biodiversity indicators based on trends in conservation status: strengths of the IUCN Red List Index. Conservation Biology 20: 579&amp;#x2013;581.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2006.00410.x/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2006.00410.x/abstract&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2005). Using Red List Indices to measure progress towards the 2010 target and beyond. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London B 360: 255&amp;#x2013;268.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/360/1454/255.full.&quot;&gt;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/360/1454/255.full.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUTCHART, S. H. M. et al. (2004). Measuring global trends in the status of biodiversity: Red List Indices for birds. PLoS Biology 2(12): e383.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.plosbiology.org/article/info:doi/10.1371/journal.pbio.0020383&quot;&gt;http://www.plosbiology.org/article/info:doi/10.1371/journal.pbio.0020383&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CARPENTER, K. E. et al. (2008). One-third of reef-building corals face elevated extinction risk from climate change and local impacts. Science 321: 560&amp;#x2013;563.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/321/5888/560.short&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/321/5888/560.short&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CBD (2014). Global Biodiversity Outlook 4. Convention on Biological Diversity, Montr&amp;#xE9;al, Canada.   &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbd.int/gbo4/&quot;&gt;https://www.cbd.int/gbo4/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CROXALL, J. P. et al. (2012). Seabird conservation status, threats and priority actions: a global assessment. Bird Conservation International 22: 1&amp;#x2013;34. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;G&amp;#xC4;RDENFORS, U. (ed.) (2010). R&amp;#xF6;dlistade arter i Sverige 2010 &amp;#x2013; The 2010 Red List of Swedish Species. ArtDatabanken, SLU, Uppsala.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HAN, X. et al. (2014). A Biodiversity indicators dashboard: addressing challenges to monitoring progress towards the Aichi Biodiversity Targets using disaggregated global data. PLoS ONE 9(11): e112046.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0112046&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0112046&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOFFMANN, M. et al. (2010). The impact of conservation on the status of the world&amp;#x2019;s vertebrates. Science 330: 1503&amp;#x2013;1509.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/330/6010/1503.short&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/330/6010/1503.short&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOFFMANN, M. et al. (2011). The changing fates of the world&amp;#x2019;s mammals. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London B 366: 2598&amp;#x2013;2610.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/366/1578/2598.abstract%20&quot;&gt;http://rstb.royalsocietypublishing.org/content/366/1578/2598.abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IUCN SPSC (2016) Guidelines for Using the IUCN Red List Categories and Criteria. Version 12. International Union for Conservation of Nature &amp;#x2013; Standards and Petitions Subcommittee, Gland, Switzerland.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iucnredlist.org/documents/RedListGuidelines.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.iucnredlist.org/documents/RedListGuidelines.pdf&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IUCN (2012a). IUCN Red List Categories and Criteria: Version 3.1. Second edition. International Union for Conservation of Nature, Gland, Switzerland.   &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10315&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10315&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IUCN (2012b). Guidelines for Application of IUCN Red List Criteria at Regional and National Levels: Version 4.0. International Union for Conservation of Nature, Gland, Switzerland.   &lt;a href=&quot;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10336&quot;&gt;https://portals.iucn.org/library/node/10336&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IUCN (2013). Documentation Standards and Consistency Checks for IUCN Red List assessments and species accounts. International Union for Conservation of Nature, Gland, Switzerland.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/RL_Standards_Consistency.pdf&quot;&gt;http://cmsdocs.s3.amazonaws.com/keydocuments/RL_Standards_Consistency.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IUCN (2015). IUCN Red List of Threatened Species. Version 2015.1. International Union for Conservation of Nature, Gland, Switzerland.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iucnredlist.org&quot;&gt;http://www.iucnredlist.org&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MACE, G. M. et al. (2008) Quantification of extinction risk: IUCN&amp;#x2019;s system for classifying threatened species. Conservation Biology 22: 1424&amp;#x2013;1442.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2008.01044.x/full&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2008.01044.x/full&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MCGEOCH, M. A. et al. (2010) Global indicators of biological invasion: species numbers, biodiversity impact and policy responses. Diversity and Distributions 16: 95&amp;#x2013;108.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1472-4642.2009.00633.x/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1472-4642.2009.00633.x/abstract&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PIHL, S. &amp;amp; FLENSTED, K. N. (2011). A Red List Index for breeding birds in Denmark in the period 1991-2009. Dansk Ornitologisk Forenings Tidsskrift 105: 211-218.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;REGAN, E. et al. (2015). Global trends in the status of bird and mammal pollinators. Conservation Letters. doi: 10.1111/conl.12162.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12162/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12162/abstract&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RODRIGUES, A. S. L. et al. (2014). Spatially explicit trends in the global conservation status of vertebrates. PLoS ONE 9(11): e113934.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0113934&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0113934&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SALAFSKY, N., et al. (2008) A standard lexicon for biodiversity conservation: unified classifications of threats and actions. Conservation Biology 22: 897&amp;#x2013;911.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2008.00937.x/full&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1523-1739.2008.00937.x/full&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TITTENSOR, D. et al. (2014). A mid-term analysis of progress towards international biodiversity targets. Science 346: 241&amp;#x2013;244.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/346/6206/241.short&quot;&gt;http://www.sciencemag.org/content/346/6206/241.short&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VISCONTI, P. et al. (2015) Projecting global biodiversity indicators under future development scenarios. Conservation Letters. doi: 10.1111/conl.12159.   &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12159/abstract&quot;&gt;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/conl.12159/abstract&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
