<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 17-9-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Meta 17: Fortalecer los medios de implementación y revitalizar la Alianza Mundial para el Desarrollo Sostenible&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 17.9: Aumentar el apoyo internacional para realizar actividades de creación de capacidad eficaces y específicas en los países en desarrollo a fin de respaldar los planes nacionales de implementación de todos los Objetivos de Desarrollo Sostenible, incluso mediante la cooperación Norte-Sur, Sur-Sur y triangular&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 17.9.1: Valor en dólares de la asistencia financiera y técnica (incluso mediante la cooperación Norte-Sur, Sur‑Sur y triangular) prometida a los países en desarrollo&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 17: Renforcer les moyens de mettre en œuvre le Partenariat mondial pour le développement durable et le revitaliser&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 17.9: Apporter, à l’échelon international, un soutien accru pour assurer le renforcement efficace et ciblé des capacités des pays en développement et appuyer ainsi les plans nationaux visant à atteindre tous les objectifs de développement durable, notamment dans le cadre de la coopération Nord-Sud et Sud-Sud et de la coopération triangulaire&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 17.9.1: Valeur en dollars de l’aide financière et technique promise aux pays en développement (notamment dans le cadre de la coopération Nord-Sud et Sud-Sud et de la coopération triangulaire)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dernière mise à jour : 09 juillet 2017&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Information institutionnelle&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Organisation(s):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Organisation de coopération et de développement économiques (OCDE)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Sources de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le CAD de l&apos;OCDE collecte des données sur les flux de ressources officielles et privées depuis 1960 au niveau agrégé et depuis 1973 au niveau des activités par le biais du système de notification des créanciers (les données du SNPC sont considérées comme complètes depuis 1995 pour les engagements au niveau des activités et depuis 2002 pour les décaissements). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont communiquées par les donateurs selon les mêmes normes et méthodologies (voir ici : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont déclarées sur la base d&apos;une année civile annuelle par les déclarants statistiques des administrations nationales (agences d&apos;aide, ministères des affaires étrangères ou des finances, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Processus de collecte : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Un déclarant statistique est responsable de la collecte des statistiques du CAD dans chaque pays/organisme fournisseur. Ce déclarant se trouve généralement dans l&apos;organisme d&apos;aide national, le ministère des affaires étrangères ou des finances, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Calendrier &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Collecte de données:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les données sont publiées sur une base annuelle en décembre pour les flux de l&apos;année précédente. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les flux détaillés de 2015 ont été publiés en décembre 2016. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fournisseurs de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont déclarées sur la base d&apos;une année civile annuelle par les déclarants statistiques des administrations nationales (agences d&apos;aide, ministères des affaires étrangères ou des finances, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compilateurs de données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OCDE&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires et limitations : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données du système de notification des pays créanciers sont disponibles à partir de 1973. Toutefois, la couverture des données est considérée comme complète depuis 1995 pour les engagements au niveau des activités et 2002 pour les décaissements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sources d’écarts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les statistiques du CAD sont normalisées sur une base d’année civile pour tous les donateurs et peuvent différer des données de l’exercice disponible dans les documents budgétaires de certains pays. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Références&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats&quot;&gt;www.oecd.org/dac/stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Références:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voir tous les liens ici : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 17: Укрепление средств осуществления и активизация работы в рамках Глобального партнерства в интересах устойчивого развития&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 17.9: Усилить международную поддержку эффективного и целенаправленного наращивания потенциала развивающихся стран для содействия реализации национальных планов достижения всех целей в области устойчивого развития, в том числе благодаря сотрудничеству по линии Север — Юг и Юг — Юг и трехстороннему сотрудничеству&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 17.9.1: Объем финансовой и технической помощи (в том числе по линии Север — Юг, Юг — Юг и в рамках трехстороннего сотрудничества), предоставляемой развивающимся странам (в долларах США)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Институциональная информация &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Организация (и): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Организация экономического сотрудничества и развития (ОЭСР) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Процесс сбора:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Лицо, направляющее отчеты, отвечает за сбор статистики КСР в каждой отчитывающейся стране / агентстве. Это лицо, направляющее отчеты, обычно находится в национальном агентстве помощи, министерстве иностранных дел или финансов и т. д.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Поставщики данных&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Данные предоставляются ежегодно за календарный год лицами, ответственными за направление статистических отчетов в национальных администрациях (агентства по оказанию помощи, министерства иностранных дел или финансов и т. д.).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Составители данных&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ОЭСР&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Обработка отсутствующих значений:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;На страновом уровне:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Не производится&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;На региональном и глобальном уровнях:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Не производится&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Источники расхождений:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Статистика КСР стандартизирована на основе календарного года для всех доноров и может отличаться от данных, составленных на основе финансового года, применяющихся в бюджетных документах некоторых стран.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 17: Strengthen the means of implementation and revitalize the Global Partnership for Sustainable Development&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 17.9 : Enhance international support for implementing effective and targeted capacity-building in developing countries to support national plans to implement all the Sustainable Development Goals, including through North-South, South-South and triangular cooperation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 17.9.1: Dollar value of financial and technical assistance (including through North-South, South-South and triangular cooperation) committed to developing countries&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last updated: 09 July 2017&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Institutional information&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organization(s):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gross disbursements of total ODA and other official flows from all donors for capacity building and national planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ODA&lt;/strong&gt;: The DAC defines ODA as &amp;#x201C;those flows to countries and territories on the DAC List of ODA Recipients and to multilateral institutions which are &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;provided by official agencies, including state and local governments, or by their executive agencies; and &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;each transaction is administered with the promotion of the economic development and welfare of developing countries as its main objective; and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;is concessional in character and conveys a grant element of at least 25 per cent (calculated at a rate of discount of 10 per cent). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(See &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other official flows (OOF)&lt;/strong&gt;: Other official flows (excluding officially supported export credits) are defined as transactions by the official sector which do not meet the conditions for eligibility as ODA, either because they are not primarily aimed at development, or because they are not sufficiently concessional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(See &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/documentupload/DCDDAC(2016)3FINAL.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/documentupload/DCDDAC(2016)3FINAL.pdf&lt;/a&gt;, Para 24).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OECD/DAC has been collecting data on official and private resource flows from 1960 at an aggregate level and 1973 at an activity level through the Creditor Reporting System (CRS data are considered complete from 1995 for commitments at an activity level and 2002 for disbursements). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data are reported by donors according to the same standards and methodologies (see here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are reported on an annual calendar year basis by statistical reporters in national administrations (aid agencies, Ministries of Foreign Affairs or Finance, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Collection process:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A statistical reporter is responsible for the collection of DAC statistics in each providing country/agency. This reporter is usually located in the national aid agency, Ministry of Foreign Affairs or Finance etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendar&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Data collection:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are published on an annual basis in December for flows in the previous year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detailed 2015 flows was published in December 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data providers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are reported on an annual calendar year basis by statistical reporters in national administrations (aid agencies, Ministries of Foreign Affairs or Finance, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data compilers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OECD&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Rationale:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total ODA and OOF flows to developing countries quantify the public effort (excluding export credits) that donors provide to developing countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comments and limitations:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data in the Creditor Reporting System are available from 1973. However, the data coverage is considered complete since 1995 for commitments at an activity level and 2002 for disbursements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computation method:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sum of ODA and OOF flows from all donors to developing countries for capacity building and national planning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Treatment of missing values:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At country level:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At regional and global levels:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Regional aggregates:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global and regional figures are based on the sum of ODA and OOF flows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data availability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a recipient basis for all developing countries eligible for ODA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator can be disaggregated by type of flow (ODA or OOF), by donor, recipient country, type of finance, type of aid, sector, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DAC statistics are standardized on a calendar year basis for all donors and may differ from fiscal year data available in budget documents for some countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats&quot;&gt;www.oecd.org/dac/stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See all links here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/methodology.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
