<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 2-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 2: End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 2.4: By 2030, ensure sustainable food production systems and implement resilient agricultural practices that increase productivity and production, that help maintain ecosystems, that strengthen capacity for adaptation to climate change, extreme weather, drought, flooding and other disasters and that progressively improve land and soil quality&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 2.4.1: Proportion of agricultural area under productive and sustainable agriculture&lt;/p&gt;2022-03-31&lt;p&gt;Direct links to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.1.2 Prevalence of moderate or severe food insecurity in the population, based on the Food Insecurity Experience Scale (FIES)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.a.1 (a) Percentage of people with ownership or secure rights over agricultural land (out of total agricultural population), by sex; and (b) share of women among owners or rights-bearers of agricultural land, by type of tenure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indirect link to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator 2.3.2: Average income of small-scale food producers, by sex and indigenous status&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scope of indicator 2.4.1 is the agricultural farm holding, and more precisely the agricultural land area of the farm holding, i.e. land used primarily to grow crops and raise livestock. This choice of scope is fully consistent with the intended use of a country&amp;#x2019;s agricultural land area as the denominator of the aggregate indicator. Specifically, the following are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Included within scope:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Intensive and extensive crops and livestock production systems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Subsistence agriculture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;State and common land when used exclusively and managed by the farm holding.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Food and non-food crops and livestock products (e.g. tobacco, cotton, and sheep wool). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Crops grown for fodder or for energy purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agro-forestry (trees on the agriculture areas of the farm).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aquaculture, to the extent that it takes place within the agricultural land area. For example, rice-fish farming and similar systems. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excluded from scope:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;State and common land not used exclusively by the farm holding.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nomadic pastoralism.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Production from gardens and backyards. Production from hobby farms&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Holdings focusing exclusively on aquaculture. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Holdings focusing exclusively on forestry.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Food harvested from the wild.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The literature review (Hayati, 2017) identified a large number of potential sustainability themes across the three dimensions of sustainability and, for each theme, usually a large number of possible sub-indicators. The key considerations in the selection of themes are relevance and measurability. In terms of relevance, the relationship between the associated sub-indicator and sustainable agriculture outcomes at farm level should be strong. Following this approach, only sub-indicators that are responsive to farm level policies aimed at improving sustainable agriculture are considered. In terms of measurability, only a &amp;#x201C;core&amp;#x201D; set of themes and sub-indicators for which measurement and reporting is expected in the majority of countries are selected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key aspect of all approaches to measuring sustainable agriculture is the recognition that sustainability is a multi-dimensional concept, and that these multiple dimensions need to be reflected in the construction of the indicator. This implies that SDG indicator 2.4.1 must be based on a set of sub-indicators that cover these three dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through a consultative process that has lasted over two years, 11 themes and sub-indicators have been identified, which make up SDG 2.4.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;No.&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;Sub-indicators&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Land productivity&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Farm output value per hectare&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Profitability&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Net farm income &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Resilience&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Risk mitigation mechanisms &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Soil health&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Prevalence of soil degradation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Water use&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Variation in water availability&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Fertilizer pollution risk&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Management of fertilizers&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;7&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Pesticide risk&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Management of pesticides &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;8&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Biodiversity&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Use of agro-biodiversity-supportive practices &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;9&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Decent employment&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Wage rate in agriculture&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;10&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Food security&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Food Insecurity Experience Scale (FIES)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;11&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Land tenure&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Secure tenure rights to land&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please see the annex for a detailed description of the sub-indicators.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; The countries will define hobby farms as per their national criteria and remove these farms from the population of interest for 2.4.1 until an international definition is available. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Percentage (%):The member countries are required to report the proportion (percentage) of agriculture land area for all 11 sub-indicators separately by sustainability status. Aggregation at the national level is performed for each sub-indicator independently, by adding up the agricultural land area of each agriculture holding (selected through a nationally representative sample) and finally reporting the resulting national total as a percentage of the total nationally representative agriculture land area for the 11 sub-indicators in a dashboard. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The land area classification is that implemented in the FAO Land Use, Irrigation and Agricultural Practices Questionnaire (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/faostat/en/#data/RL/metadata&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/faostat/en/#data/RL/metadata&lt;/a&gt;), which is consistent with the classification of Census of Agriculture and the System of Environmental and Economic Accounts (SEEA). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Different data are collected through different instruments. Often, environmental data are collected through environmental monitoring systems, including remote sensing. Yet many countries do not have the capacity or resources to do so, and therefore these data are sparse or non-existent. In order to propose a manageable and cost-effective solution, a requirement stressed by several countries during the consultations, the methodology offers a single data collection instrument for all sub-indicators: the farm survey.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several countries have suggested using existing data sources or alternative data sources on the grounds that these instruments can be more cost-effective and sometimes provide more reliable results than farm surveys. These instruments include remote sensing, GIS, models, agricultural surveys, household surveys, administrative data or environmental monitoring systems. The methodology considers the possibility to use such instruments, subject to a series of criteria to ensure data quality and international comparability. Other data sources may also be used to complement and/or validate farm survey results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The methodology note also recommends that countries complement the farm survey with a monitoring systems that can measure the impact of agriculture on the environment (soil, water, fertilizer and pesticide pollution, biodiversity, etc.) and on health (pesticides residues in food and human bodies). This will provide additional information and help crosscheck the robustness of SDG indicator 2.4.1 with regard to the environmental dimension of sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A questionnaire is sent to all countries annually since 2020 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/sustainable-development-goals/indicators/241/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/sustainable-development-goals/indicators/241/en/&lt;/a&gt;). Furthermore, in order to facilitate data collection by countries, a data module has been designed, which contains the core set of questions necessary to obtain the data for SDG 2.4.1. If farm surveys already exist within a country, these questions can be integrated into existing instruments in order to minimize the burden to National Statistical Offices (NSOs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All data collection activities will be done through the NSO or the office designated to collect data for this indicator. FAO, together with the Global Strategy to improve Agriculture and Rural Statistics (GSARS), have developed the capacity development material necessary for this indicator, including a methodological guide, an enumerator manual, calculation document, sampling guidance and an e-learning course to train country NSO and other relevant staff on the indictor. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data collection will depend on currently existing data collection cycles for farm surveys within countries. FAO has integrated the questionnaire module associated with this indicator in in AGRISurvey Programme and 50x2030 initiative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although new data may not be available annually for each country, all new information is expected to be released annually through FAOSTAT.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National Statistical Offices or designated offices within countries will be responsible for collecting data for this indicator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National Statistical Offices or designated offices within countries will be responsible for collecting and compiling data for this indicator. They will in turn report to FAO who will provide capacity development, conduct quality control and disseminate the information through FAOSTAT. FAO will in turn report to the international statistical community and UNSD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Article I of the FAO constitution requires that the Organization collect, analyses, interpret and disseminate information relating to nutrition, food and agriculture &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/K8024E/K8024E.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/K8024E/K8024E.pdf&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The approaches to framing and defining sustainable agriculture vary in terms of their coverage of the three primary dimensions of sustainability, i.e. economic, environmental and social, and in terms of the scale that is used to assess sustainability, i.e. from field and farm scales, to national and global scales. Some approaches consider different features of sustainability, for example whether current practices are economically feasible, environmentally friendly and socially desirable. Other approaches focus on particular practices such as organic, regenerative or low-input agriculture and can equate these with sustainable agriculture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conclusion from a literature review associated with the methodological development of this indicator is that the multi-dimensional approach developed by FAO in 1988 is a meaningful framing of the concept. Thus, sustainable agriculture can be considered as &amp;#x201C;the management and conservation of the natural resource base, and the orientation of technological and institutional change in such a manner as to ensure the attainment and continued satisfaction of human needs for present and future generation. Such development (in agriculture, forestry and fishing etc.) conserves land, water, plant and animal genetic resources, environmentally non-degrading, technically appropriate, economically viable and socially acceptable.&amp;#x201D; (FAO, 1988)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the consultations undertaken, several countries highlighted the difficulties in combining data from different sources and requested that this be avoided to the extent possible. Other, relatively data rich, countries, instead, insisted on the need to allow for the use of existing data sources. The updated methodology addresses both concerns: it offers the farm survey as a single data collection instrument for all sub-indicators, but it also offers the possibility of using a combination of different data sources as an alternative option as long as certain criteria are satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision to use the farm survey as a data collection instrument for this indicator is in line with countries&amp;#x2019; efforts, supported by FAO, to develop farm surveys as the most appropriate tool for generating agricultural statistics. It also benefits from the FAO work in developing the Agricultural Integrated Survey (AGRIS) programme, which is implemented as part of a new initiative called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.data4sdgs.org/50by2030&quot;&gt;50 X 2030&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision to focus on farm survey has implications on the type of information that it is possible to capture in order to cover the different dimensions of sustainability. While farm surveys are well suited to measure the economic dimension of sustainability, they may not be the ideal tool for measuring environmental and social sustainability in terms of impact/outcomes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically, environmental impacts of agriculture are measured through monitoring systems like remote sensing, soil and water sampling, or other tools associated with a specific area, rather than with a single agricultural holding. For several environmental themes, it is unlikely that farmers would be able to assess the environmental impact of their farming practices on issues like fertilizer pollution or pesticide impact. Using a farm survey instrument, instead of environmental monitoring systems, therefore implies moving from measuring outcome/impact to assessing farmers&amp;#x2019; practices. Whenever possible, however, the revised methodology continues to focus on measuring outcomes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the sub-themes under the social dimension are usually best captured through household surveys. While in the majority of cases agricultural holdings are closely associated with a given household, this is not always the case, and therefore capturing the social dimension of sustainability through a farm survey, especially if it is not designed to cover social aspects could pose certain challenges.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The indicator is defined by the formula:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;S&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;D&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;G&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;2&lt;/mn&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;.&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;4&lt;/mn&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;.&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;1&lt;/mn&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;A&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;v&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;b&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;g&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;A&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;g&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This implies the need to measure both the extent of land under productive and sustainable agriculture (the numerator), as well as the extent of agriculture land area (the denominator).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;numerator&lt;/em&gt; captures the three dimensions of sustainable production: environmental, economic and social. It corresponds to agricultural land area of the farms that satisfy the sustainability criteria of the 11 sub-indicators selected across all three dimensions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;denominator&lt;/em&gt; in turn the sum of agricultural land area (as defined by FAO) utilized by agricultural holdings that are owned (excluding rented-out), rented-in, leased, sharecropped or borrowed. State or communal land used by farm holdings is not included. Please see the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/ca7154en/ca7154en.pdf&quot;&gt;methodological document&lt;/a&gt; prepared by FAO for a more detailed explanation. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steps to calculate SDG 2.4.1 include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Determining the &lt;strong&gt;scope &lt;/strong&gt;of the indicator: The scope of Indicator 2.4.1 is the agricultural farm holding, and more precisely the agricultural land area of the farm holding, i.e., land used primarily to grow crops and raise livestock. Forestry, fisheries and aquaculture activities may be included to the extent that they are secondary activities conducted on the agricultural area of the farm holding, for example rice-fish farming and similar systems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Determining the &lt;strong&gt;dimensions &lt;/strong&gt;to be covered: Indicator 2.4.1 includes environmental, economic and social dimensions in the sustainability assessment. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choosing the &lt;strong&gt;scale &lt;/strong&gt;for the sustainability assessment: Indicator 2.4.1 is farm level with aggregation to higher levels.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Selecting the data collection &lt;strong&gt;instrument(s)&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;It is recommended that indicator 2.4.1 be collected through a farm survey.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Selecting the &lt;strong&gt;themes &lt;/strong&gt;within each dimension, and choosing a &lt;strong&gt;sub-indicator&lt;/strong&gt; for each theme: The sub-indicators should satisfy a number of criteria (described in annex 1 for each sub-indicator, respectively). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assessing &lt;strong&gt;sustainability performance at farm level for each sub-indicator&lt;/strong&gt;: Specific sustainability &lt;strong&gt;criteria&lt;/strong&gt; are applied in order to assess the sustainability level of the farm for each theme according to the respective sub-indicators. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deciding the &lt;strong&gt;periodicity of monitoring the indicator&lt;/strong&gt;: It is recommended to be collected at least every three years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modality of reporting the indicator&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;The set of sub-indicators are presented in the form of a &lt;strong&gt;dashboard&lt;/strong&gt;. The dashboard approach offers a response in terms of measuring sustainability at farm level and aggregating it at national level. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2.4.1 methodology proposes reporting of indicator 2.4.1 through a national-level dashboard, presenting the different sub-indicators together but independently. The dashboard approach offers several advantages, including the possibility of combining data from different sources and identification of critical sustainability issues, facilitating the search for a balance between the three sustainability dimensions. As a result, countries can easily visualize their performance in terms of the different sustainability dimensions and themes, and understand where policy efforts can be focused for future improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computation of results and construction of the dashboard are performed for each sub-indicator separately using the &amp;#x2018;traffic light&amp;#x2019; approach already defined for each sub-indicator: aggregation at national level is performed for each sub-indicator independently, by summing the agricultural land area of each agricultural holdings by sustainability category (red, yellow or green), and reporting the resulting national total as percentage of the total national agricultural land area of all agricultural farm holdings in the country. In practice, the reported value of Indicator 2.4.1 is determined by the results of most-limiting sub-indicator in terms of sustainability performance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The data undergo comprehensive validation work that cover: detection of outliers, transmission errors and data consistency checks. Countries asked to examine the disseminated results for their country and either to confirm that they are correct or to provide remarks and/or revise data if they identify errors. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adjustments to total national agricultural area may be made to correct for common areas that are out of scope with regards to the indicator methodology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partial non-response at individual level (farm holding) will be imputed using appropriate statistical techniques, such as nearest-neighbour algorithms. The decision on whether to impute or not and the choice of the method is a function of the nature of the variable to impute and the amount and type of data available for the imputation, such as the availability of auxiliary data coming from different sources (e.g. surveys, administrative information). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to clearly distinguish missing data from non-applicable events. As specified above and in the sub-indicator methodology sheets, some sub-indicators can be recorded as &amp;#x2018;not applicable&amp;#x2019; for a given farm. In this case, the farm will be considered sustainable from the perspective of the given sub-indicators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the country level, if and when data are provided using alternative sources for some of the sub-indicators, relevant notes to be provided by the country explaining the type, nature, source and time period of the data reported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No treatment of missing values will be carried out at the regional and global level. The regional and global estimates will be constructed using data of countries that have reported all 11 sub-indicators and/or those that have reported a sub-set of the 11 only if some of the sub-indicators are not applicable or irrelevant in the context of those country. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These data will be disseminated through FAOSTAT, the largest database of food and agricultural statistics. Therefore, the method of calculation will follow the international standard established by the database. In the case of this indicator, regional and global aggregates will be computed by weighting the national indicators according to the country&amp;#x2019;s agricultural area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The methodology note provides a detailed description for the computation of the indicator on the basis of the farm survey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The values for reporting indicator 2.4.1 can be calculated as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;msub&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;S&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;D&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;G&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mn&gt;241&lt;/mn&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/msub&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;munder&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;min&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;:&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;mn&gt;1&lt;/mn&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;-&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;mn&gt;11&lt;/mn&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/munder&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mo&gt;&amp;#x2061;&lt;/mo&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;(&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;S&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;I&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;)&lt;/mo&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mrow&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SDG241&lt;sub&gt;d&lt;/sub&gt;is proportion of agricultural land area that have achieved the &amp;#x2018;desirable&amp;#x2019; level&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SI&lt;sub&gt;d n &lt;/sub&gt;is proportion of sub-indicator n that is classified as &amp;#x2018;desirable&amp;#x2019; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;min refers to the minimum level of SI&lt;sub&gt;d n&lt;/sub&gt; at national level across all 11 sub-indicators&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SDG241&lt;sub&gt;d &lt;/sub&gt;is proportion of agricultural area for which all sub-indicators are green.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;msub&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;S&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;D&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;G&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mn&gt;241&lt;/mn&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/msub&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;munder&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;min&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;:&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;mn&gt;1&lt;/mn&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;-&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;mn&gt;11&lt;/mn&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/munder&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mo&gt;&amp;#x2061;&lt;/mo&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;msub&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mo&gt;(&lt;/mo&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;S&lt;/mi&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;I&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/msub&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;msub&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;S&lt;/mi&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;I&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/msub&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;)&lt;/mo&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mrow&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SDG241&lt;sub&gt;a+d&lt;/sub&gt;is proportion of agricultural land area that have achieved at least the &amp;#x2018;acceptable&amp;#x2019; level (estimated by excess, see note below)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SI&lt;sub&gt;d n &lt;/sub&gt;is proportion of sub-indicator n that is classified as &amp;#x2018;desirable&amp;#x2019; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SI&lt;sub&gt;a n &lt;/sub&gt;is proportion of sub-indicator n that is classified as &amp;#x2018;acceptable&amp;#x2019; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;min refers to the minimum level of (SI&lt;sub&gt;d n &lt;/sub&gt;+ SI&lt;sub&gt;a n&lt;/sub&gt;) at national level across all 11 sub-indicators&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SDG241&lt;sub&gt;a+d &lt;/sub&gt;is proportion of agricultural area for which all indicators are either green or yellow, an acceptable situation, but that could be improved. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;msub&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;S&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;D&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;G&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mn&gt;241&lt;/mn&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/msub&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;1&lt;/mn&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;-&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;S&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;msub&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;D&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;G&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mn&gt;241&lt;/mn&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/msub&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;munder&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;max&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;:&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;mn&gt;1&lt;/mn&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;-&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;mn&gt;11&lt;/mn&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/munder&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mo&gt;&amp;#x2061;&lt;/mo&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;(&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;S&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;I&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;)&lt;/mo&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mrow&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SDG241&lt;sub&gt;u &lt;/sub&gt;is proportion estimated by default of agricultural area that is &amp;#x2018;unsustainable&amp;#x2019; (see note below)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SI&lt;sub&gt;u n &lt;/sub&gt;is proportion of sub-indicator n that is classified as &amp;#x2018;unsustainable&amp;#x2019;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;max refers to the highest value of SI&lt;sub&gt;u n&lt;/sub&gt; across all 11 sub-indicators at national level&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SDG241&lt;sub&gt;u &lt;/sub&gt;is proportion of agricultural area for which at least one sub-indicator is unsustainable, and is therefore classified as unsustainable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The performances of countries over time can be measured by the change in the value of SDG241&lt;sub&gt;d &lt;/sub&gt;and SDG241&lt;sub&gt;a+d&lt;/sub&gt;. An increase over time indicates improvement, while decrease indicates degradation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Standard quality management of the entire data reporting process and the data itself will be carried out in close coordination with countries to ensure the data reported conforms with the methodology and relevant international standards. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FAO will work closely with countries for quality assurance. Not only will data collection for SDG 2.4.1 respect international standards, it will also adhere to FAO&amp;#x2019;s data quality assurance &amp;#x201C;Statistics Quality Assurance Framework&amp;#x201D; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/statistics/standards/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/statistics/standards/en/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A qualitative assessment of the overall quality of the statistical outputs is provided in regular reports by summarizing the main strengths and possible quality deficiencies in country data, by sub-indicator. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is currently in the Tier II category because few countries are able to report it. Data are expected to be collected either as part of existing farm surveys or through other data sources such as environmental monitoring systems, administrative data or household surveys. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comprehensive capacity development efforts (using a mix of in person, mass online trainings and bilateral assistance) are underway to build countries capacities. The data will be reported by end of 2022, once the third and final round of the 3 years data collection and reporting cycle is completed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Time series:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SDG Indicator 2.4.1 measures progress towards more sustainable and productive agriculture over a three-year periodicity because for many sub-indicators, it is likely that changes will be relatively limited from a year to another. Furthermore, the 3-year periodicity will enable countries to have three data points on the indicator before 2030.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator 2.4.1 is expected to be collected through farm surveys and the result expressed as a national value. However, the methodology is scale independent and can be adopted at any geographical level. In addition, the indicator can be disaggregated according to type of farming system (crop, livestock or mixed) and other characteristics of the farm e.g. household/non-household sector, irrigated/non-irrigated or gender of the farm holder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that this is a Tier II indicator, no data currently exists for this indicator. Therefore, there are no discrepancies between national and sub-national data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FAO. 1988. Report of the FAO Council, 94th Session, 1988. FAO, Rome, Italy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FAO. 2014. Building a common vision for sustainable food and agriculture: Principles and approaches, FAO, Rome, Italy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FAO. 2017. Report from the Expert Group Meeting on SDG indicator 2.4.1. April, 2017. FAO, Rome, Italy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FAO. 2018. Land Use Classification. In: SEEA Agriculture, Forestry and Fisheries, Annex I, pg. 120, 130-135. FAO and UNSD, Rome, Italy..&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FAO. 2018. Report of the 26&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Committee on Agriculture, 1-5 October 2018. FAO, Rome, Italy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Global Strategy for Improving Agricultural and Rural Statistics. 2017. Handbook on the Agricultural Integrated Survey. FAO, Rome, Italy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FAO. 2020. SDG 2.4,1, methodological note. July, 2020. FAO, Rome, Italy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hayati, D. 2017. Literature Review: A Literature Review on Frameworks and Methods for Measuring and Monitoring Sustainable Agriculture. Technical Report n.22. Global Strategy Technical Report. FAO, Rome, Italy..&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annex: description of the sub-indicators&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Farm output value per hectare&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension: &lt;/strong&gt;Economic&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theme: &lt;/strong&gt;Land Productivity &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Land productivity is a measure of agricultural value of outputs obtained on a given area of land. Maintaining or improving the output over time relative to the area of land used is an important aspect in sustainability for a range of reasons. At farm level, the land productivity reflects technology and production processes for given agro-ecological conditions. In a broader sense, an increase in the level of land productivity enables higher production while reducing pressure on increasingly scarce land resources, commonly linked to deforestation and associated losses of ecosystem services and biodiversity.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coverage&lt;/strong&gt;: All farm types &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sub-indicator is described as farm output value per hectare (holdings that produce crops and livestock or its mix). Information on farm outputs and agricultural area should be standard information available from farm surveys thus providing a good basis for assessment at farm level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Farm output value: The volume of agricultural output at farm level generally takes into account production of multiple outputs, e.g. crop types and crop and livestock combinations, etc. Since the volume of agricultural outputs is not measured in commensurate units (e.g. not all outputs are measured in tonnes, and tonnes of different output represent different products), it is necessary to establish an appropriate means of aggregation, in this case using a monetary unit. A simple way to enable aggregation is to reflect the multiple outputs produced by a single farm in terms of values (i.e. quantity multiplied by prices).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Farm agricultural land area: defined as the area of land used for agriculture within the farm&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-3&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability criteria: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distance from the 90&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; percentile of the national distribution&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-4&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-4&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Green (desirable): Sub-indicator value is &amp;#x2265; 2/3 of the corresponding 90&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; percentile &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yellow (acceptable): Sub-indicator value is &amp;#x2265; 1/3 and &amp;lt; 2/3 of the corresponding 90&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; percentile &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red (unsustainable): Sub-indicator value is &amp;lt; 1/3 of the corresponding 90&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; percentile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data items:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference period: last calendar year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Quantities and farm gate prices (or value of production) of the 5 main crops and/or livestock products and by-products produced by the farm&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Quantities and farm gate prices (or value of production) of other agricultural products (agro-forestry or aquaculture products etc.) produced by the farm &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Agricultural land area of the holding&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Net Farm Income:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension:&lt;/strong&gt; Economic&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theme:&lt;/strong&gt; Profitability&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important part of sustainability in agriculture is the economic viability of the farm, driven to a large extent by its profitability. Profitability is measured using the net income that the farmer is able to gain from farming operations. Availability and use of information on farm economic performance, measured using profitability, will support better decision making both at micro and macro-economic level. Since performance measures drive behaviour, better information on performance can alter behaviour and decision-making by government and producers both in large-scale commercial farming and medium and small-scale subsistence agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coverage:&lt;/strong&gt; All farms types &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sub-indicator measures if the farm is consistently profitable over a 3-year period. The focus of this sub-indicator is on income from farming operations as distinct from the total income of the farming household, which may include other sources of income such as, for example, employment in local businesses by other family members, tourism activity, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Formula&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-5&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-5&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;F&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;I&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;C&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;msub&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;Y&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;k&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/msub&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;-&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;O&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;E&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;-&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;D&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;V&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;I&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;C&lt;/mi&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NFI = Total Net Farm Income&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CR = Total farm cash receipts including direct program payments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Y&lt;sub&gt;k&lt;/sub&gt; = Income in kind&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;OE = Total operating expenses after rebates (including costs of labour)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dep = Depreciation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;VIC = Value of inventory change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Net farm income refers to the return (both monetary and non-monetary) to farm operators for their labor, management and capital, after all production expenses have been paid (that is, gross farm income minus production expenses). It includes net income from farm production, the value of commodities consumed on the farm, depreciation, and inventory changes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gross farm income refers to the monetary and non-monetary income received by farm. Its main components include cash receipts from the sale of farm products, direct program payments to producers, other farm income (such as income from custom work), value of food and fuel produced and consumed on the same farm, and change in value of year-end inventories of crops and livestock&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-6&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-6&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Farm cash receipts include revenues from the sale of agricultural commodities in local currency units that include sales of crops, livestock and its by-products.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Direct program payments to producers included in farm cash receipts represent the amounts paid under various government and private programs to individuals involved in agricultural production. The payments related to current agricultural production include subsidies to encourage production or to compensate producers for low market returns, payments to stabilize incomes and payments to compensate producers for crop or livestock losses caused by extreme climatic conditions, disease or other reasons and insurance payments.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Income-in-kind measures the value of the agricultural goods produced on farms and consumed by farm operator families. It is included to measure total farm production. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Operating expenses represent business costs incurred by farm businesses for goods and services used in the production process. Expenses include both purchase and self-produced items that are: property taxes, custom work, seeds, rent, fertiliser and lime, chemicals, machinery and building repairs, irrigation, fuel for heating and machines, wages, interest and business share of insurance premiums. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Depreciation charges account for the economic depreciation or for the loss in fair market value of the capital assets of the farm business. Calculated on farm buildings, farm machinery, and the farm business share of autos, trucks and the farm home, depreciation is generally considered to be the result of aging, wear and tear, and obsolescence. It represents a decrease in the potential economic benefits that can be generated by the capital asset. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Value of inventory change (VIC) measures the currency value of the physical change in producer-owned inventories. This concept is used to value total agricultural economic production. To calculate VIC, the change in producer-owned inventories (between the end and the beginning of a calendar year) is first derived and then multiplied by the average annual crop prices or value per animal. This calculation is different from the financial or accounting book value approach, which values the beginning and ending stocks, and then derives the change.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The VIC over all the major commodities can vary widely (depending on the size of the change of inventories and prices). The VIC can be either positive (when inventories are larger at the end of the year compared to the beginning levels) or negative (when year- end inventories are smaller than the levels at the beginning of the year). If the inventory levels are the same at the beginning and end of the year, VIC will be zero despite price changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimating profitability at a farm level will generally require compilation of basic farm financial records, i.e. daily, weekly, monthly or seasonal transactions in an organized way. In general, large commercial farms maintain detailed financial records however, in case of medium farms and small subsistence agriculture, record keeping is seldom practiced and in most of the countries it doesn&amp;#x2019;t exist at all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case when detailed data are not available at farm level, then estimates will be calculated based on farmer declaration of both outputs and inputs quantities and prices. In these cases, depreciation, variation of stocks and taxes may be neglected. This is described below as simplified option (1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simplified option (2) is also offered, based on farmer&amp;#x2019;s declaration of the agricultural holding&amp;#x2019;s profitability over the last three calendar years. It is recommended to use this simplified option only when other two options are not feasible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability criteria: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a farm to be profitable the net farm income should be above zero. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Green (desirable): above zero for past 3 consecutive years&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yellow (acceptable): above zero for at least 1 of the past 3 consecutive years&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red (unsustainable): below zero for all of the past 3 consecutive years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data items:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference period: last three calendar years&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Recommended option:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data from farm financial records, i.e. daily, weekly, monthly or seasonal transactions are collected in an organized way (in general, large commercial farms maintain detailed financial records on the basis of which the NFI can be calculated as per above equation). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Simplified option (1):&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be used when the detailed data are not available at farm level (better adapted to smallholders and household sector). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Quantity produced (i.e. crops and livestock and its products and by-products produced both for market or self-consumption) &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Farm gate prices of the above quantities produces&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Operating expenses including inputs quantities and its market prices&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Quantity/output of other on-farm activities carried out and/or commodities produced on the holding e.g. aquaculture, agroforestry and others&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Farm gate prices of the other on-farm activities/commodities&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Input quantities and prices that are used to produce other on-farm outputs&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Simplified option (2):&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Respondent&amp;#x2019;s declaration on agricultural holding&amp;#x2019;s profitability over the last 3 calendar years&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Risk mitigation mechanisms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension: &lt;/strong&gt;Economic&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theme: &lt;/strong&gt;Resilience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resilience encompass absorptive, anticipatory and adaptive capacities and refers to the properties of a system that allows farms to deal with shocks and stresses, to persist and to continue to be well-functioning (in the sense of providing stability, predictable rules, security and other benefits to its members). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coverage: &lt;/strong&gt;All farms types&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sub-indicator measures the incidence of the following mitigation mechanisms: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Access to or availed credit&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-7&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-7&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Access to or availed insurance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On farm diversification (share of a single agricultural commodity not greater than 66% in the total value of production of the holding)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Access to credit and/or insurance is defined here as when a given service is available and the holder has enough means to obtain the service (required documents, collateral, positive credit history, etc.). Broadly, access to one or more the above 3 factors will allow the farm to prevent, resist, adapt and recover from external shocks such as, floods, droughts, market failure (e.g. price shock), climate shock and pest/animal diseases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability criteria: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A farm holding is considered resilient if it has availed or has the means to access the risk mitigation mechanisms as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Green (desirable): Access to or availed at least two of the above-listed mitigation mechanisms.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yellow (acceptable): Access to or availed at least one of the above-listed mitigation mechanisms.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red (unsustainable): No access to the listed mitigation mechanisms. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data items:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference period: last calendar year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.1. Agricultural holding access to or availed of credit, insurance or other financial instruments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Credit (both formal and informal) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Insurance &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.2 List of other on-farm activities apart from crops and livestock&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.3 Value of output for the listed on-farm activities/commodities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Prevalence of soil degradation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension: &lt;/strong&gt;Environmental&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theme: &lt;/strong&gt;Soil health &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the processes affecting soil health are driven by agricultural practices. FAO and the Intergovernmental Technical Panel on Soils (ITPS) have identified 10 main threats to soil functions: soil erosion; soil organic carbon losses; nutrient imbalance; acidification; contamination; waterlogging; compaction; soil sealing; salinization and loss of soil biodiversity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coverage: &lt;/strong&gt;All farms types&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sub-indicator measures the extent to which agriculture activities affects soil health and therefore represents a sustainability issue. A review of the 10 threats to soil shows that all except one (soil sealing, which is the loss of natural soil to construction/urbanisation) are potentially and primarily affected by inappropriate agricultural practices. Ideally, therefore, all soils under agricultural land area in a country should be the subject of periodic monitoring in order to assess the impact of agriculture on soils. This requires detailed surveys and sampling campaigns, associated with laboratory testing. In order to propose a manageable solution while capturing the main trends in the country in terms of soil health, the farm survey focuses on the four threats that combine the characteristics more widespread (for national monitoring, countries may choose to add any of the other areas indicated above, depending on relevance), and easier to assess through farm surveys:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soil erosion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reduction in soil fertility&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salinization of irrigated land&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Waterlogging&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Other - Specify&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The farm survey captures farmer&amp;#x2019;s knowledge about the situation of the agricultural holding in terms of soil degradation. Experience has shown that farmers are very much aware of the state of their soils, health and degradation level. Farmers may also be offered the opportunity to mention other threats than the above four. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other data sources on soil health may either complement the information collected through the farm survey and offer opportunities for cross-checking farmers&amp;#x2019; responses; or be used as alternative sources of data. Prior to the farm survey, a desk study could collect all available information on soil health, including using national official statistics or statistics available from international agencies such as FAO. This typically includes maps, models, results from soil sampling, laboratory analysis and field surveys, and all existing report on soil and land degradation at national level. On the basis of this information, maps or tables (by administrative boundaries or other divisions of the country) can be established, showing the threats to soils according to the above 4 categories of threats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability criteria: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportion of agricultural area of the farm affected by soil degradation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Green (desirable): The combined area affected by any of the four selected threats to soil health is negligible (less than 10% of the total agriculture area of the farm).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yellow (acceptable): The combined area affected by any of the four selected threats to soil health is between 10% and 50% of the total agriculture area of the farm.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red (unsustainable): The combined area affected by any of the four selected threats to soil health is above 50% of the total agriculture area of the farm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data items:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference period: last three calendar years&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.1 List of soil degradation threats experienced on the holding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Soil erosion (loss of topsoil through wind or water erosion)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Reduction in soil fertility&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-8&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-8&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Salinization of irrigated land&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Waterlogging&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Other &amp;#x2013; Specify&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;None of the above&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.2 Total area of the holding affected by threats related to soil degradation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Variation in water availability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension:&lt;/strong&gt; Environmental &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theme:&lt;/strong&gt; Water use&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agriculture, more specifically irrigated agriculture, is by far the main economic sector using freshwater resources. In many places, water withdrawal from rivers and groundwater aquifers is beyond what can be considered environmentally sustainable. This affects both rivers and underground aquifers. Sustainable agriculture therefore requires that that level of use of freshwater for irrigation remains within acceptable boundaries. While there are no internationally agreed standards of water use sustainability, signals associated with unsustainable use of water typically include progressive reduction in the level of groundwater, drying out of springs and rivers, increased conflicts among water users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coverage: &lt;/strong&gt;All farm types&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sub-indicator captures the extent to which agriculture contributes to unsustainable patterns of water use. Ideally, the level of sustainability in water use is measured at the scale of the river basin or groundwater aquifer, as it is the combined effect of all users sharing the same resource that impact water sustainability. The farm survey captures farmers&amp;#x2019; awareness and behaviour in relation with water scarcity, and associates them with three levels of sustainability. These awareness and behaviour are expressed in terms of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;whether the farmer uses water to irrigate crops on at least 10% of the agriculture area of the farm and why, if the answer is negative (does not need, cannot afford);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;whether the farmer is aware about issues of water availability in the area of the farm and notices a reduction in water availability over time;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;whether there are organizations (water users organisations, others) in charge of allocating water among users and the extent to which these organisations are working effectively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other data sources may either complement the farm survey on water use and offer opportunities for cross-checking farmers&amp;#x2019; responses; or be used as alternative sources of data. Prior to the farm survey, a desk study should collect all available information on water balance, including national official statistics or statistics available from international agencies such as FAO. Information on water resources and use is usually collected by the entities in charge of water management or monitoring and are organised by hydrological entity (river basin or groundwater aquifer). They typically include hydrological records (river flow, groundwater levels), models and maps showing the extent of water use by hydrological entity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability criteria: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farm sustainability in relation with water use will be assessed as follows: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Green (desirable): Water availability remains stable over the years, for farms irrigating crops on more than 10% of the agriculture area of the farm. Default result for farms irrigating less than 10% of their agricultural area &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yellow (acceptable): uses water to irrigate crops on at least 10% of the agriculture area of the farm, does not know whether water availability remains stable over the years, or experiences reduction on water availability over the years, but there is an organisation that effectively allocates water among users. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red (unsustainable): in all other cases. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data items:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference period: last three calendar years&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.1 Irrigated agricultural area of the holding &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.2 Reduction in water availability experienced on the holding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.3 Existence of organizations dealing with water allocation &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Management of fertilizers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension: &lt;/strong&gt;Environmental&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theme: &lt;/strong&gt;Fertilizer pollution risk &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agriculture can affect the quality of the environment through excessive use or inadequate management of fertilizers. Sustainable agriculture implies that the level of chemicals in soil and water bodies remains within acceptable thresholds. Integrated plant nutrient management considers all sources of nutrients (mineral and organic) and their management in order to obtain best nutrient balance. Measuring soil and water quality captures the extent and causes of pollution, but establishing monitoring systems of soil and water is costly and not always feasible in countries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: the management of plant nutrients addresses two sustainability issues: avoiding pollution, and maintaining a good level of soil fertility. This sub-indicator addresses the first issue, while the second one is addressed under sub-indicator 4 &amp;#x2018;Soil health&amp;#x2019;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coverage: &lt;/strong&gt;All farm types&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposed approach is based on questions to farmers about their use of fertilizer, in particular mineral or synthetic fertilizers and animal manure, their awareness about the environmental risks associated with fertilizer and manure applications, and their behaviour in terms of plant nutrient management&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-9&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-9&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Management measures considered to help reducing risk is as follows: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Follow protocols as per extension service or retail outlet directions or local regulations, not exceeding recommended doses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use organic source of nutrients (including manure or composting residues) alone, or in combination with synthetic or mineral fertilizers &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use legumes as a cover crop, or component of a multi/crop or pasture system to reduce fertilizer inputs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Distribute synthetic or mineral fertilizer application over the growing period&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consider soil type and climate&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-10&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-10&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in deciding fertilizer application doses and frequencies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use soil sampling at least every 5 years to perform nutrient budget calculations &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perform site-specific nutrient management or precision farming&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-11&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-11&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use buffer strips along water courses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability criteria: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farm sustainability in relation with fertilizer pollution risk will be assessed as follows: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Green (desirable): The farm takes specific measures to mitigate environmental risks (at least four from the list above). Default result for farms not using fertilizers&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-12&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-12&quot;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yellow (acceptable): The farm uses fertilizers and takes at least two measures from the above list to mitigate environmental risks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red (unsustainable): The farm uses fertilizer and does not take any of the above specific measures to mitigate environmental risks associated with their use. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data items:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference period: last calendar year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.1 Use of synthetic or mineral fertilizer or animal manure/slurry by the agricultural holding (Y/N)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.2 Specific measures taken to mitigate the environmental risks associated with the excessive use or misuse use of fertilizers as per list below: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x20DD; 1 Follow protocols as per extension service or retail outlet directions or local regulations, not exceeding recommended doses &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x20DD; 2 Use organic source of nutrients (including manure or composting residues) alone, or in combination with synthetic or mineral fertilizers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x20DD; 3 Use legumes as a cover crop, or component of a multi/crop or pasture system to reduce fertilizer inputs &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x20DD; 4 Distribute synthetic or mineral fertilizer application over the growing period&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x20DD; 5 Consider soil type and climate in deciding fertilizer application doses and frequencies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x20DD; 6 Use soil sampling at least every 5 years to perform nutrient budget calculations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x20DD; 7 Perform site-specific nutrient management or precision farming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x20DD; 8 Use buffer strips along water courses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Management of pesticides&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension: &lt;/strong&gt;Environmental&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theme: &lt;/strong&gt;Pesticide risk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pesticides are important inputs in modern agriculture (crop and livestock), but if not well managed they can cause harm to people&amp;#x2019;s health or to the environment. Practices associated with integrated pest management (IPM&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-13&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-13&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) exist that contribute to minimise risks associated with the use of pesticides and limit their impact on human health and on the environment. The International Code of Conduct on Pesticide Management defines best practice in pesticide management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coverage: &lt;/strong&gt;All farm types&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposed sub-indicator is based on information on the use of pesticides on the farms, the type of pesticide used and the type of measure(s) taken to mitigate the associated risks&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-14&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-14&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. It considers the possibility that the holding uses pesticides in the framework of an Integrated Pest Management (IPM) program, or adopts specific measures to help reducing risks associated with pesticide use. List of possible measures:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Health:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adherence to label directions for pesticide use (including use of protection equipment while applying pesticides)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maintenance and cleansing of protection equipment after use&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Safe disposal of waste (cartons, bottles and bags)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adherence to label directions for pesticide application&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adopt any of these good practices: adjust planting time, apply crop spacing, crop rotation, mixed cropping or inter-cropping &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perform biological pest control or use biopesticides&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adopt pasture rotation to suppress livestock pest population &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Systematic removal of plant parts attacked by pests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maintenance and cleansing of spray equipment after use&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use one pesticide no more than two times or in mixture in a season to avoid pesticide resistance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability criteria: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farm sustainability in relation with pesticides will be assessed as follows: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Green (desirable): The farm uses only moderately or slightly hazardous&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-15&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-15&quot;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; pesticides (WHO Class II or III). In this case, it adheres to all three health-related measures and at least four of the environment-related measures. Default result for farms not using pesticides.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yellow (acceptable): The farm uses only moderately or slightly hazardous pesticides (WHO Class II or III) and takes some measures to mitigate environmental and health risks (at least two from each of the lists above)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red (unsustainable): The farm uses highly or extremely hazardous pesticides (WHO Class Ia or Ib), illegal pesticides&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-16&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-16&quot;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, or uses moderately or slightly hazardous pesticides without taking specific measures to mitigate environmental or health risks associated with their use (fewer than two from each of the lists above). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data items:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference period: last calendar year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7.1 Use of pesticides for crop or livestock by the agricultural holding (Y/N) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7.2 Use of highly or extremely hazardous pesticides by the agricultural holding (Y/N) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7.3 Measures taken to protect people from health-related risks associated with pesticides: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adherence to label directions for pesticide use, including use of personal protection equipment (Y/N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maintenance and cleansing of protection equipment after use (Y/N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Safe disposal of waste (cartons, bottles and bags) (Y/N)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7.4 Measures taken to avoid environment-related risks associated with pesticides:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adherence to label directions for pesticide application (Y/N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adjustment of planting time (Y/N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application of crop spacing (Y/N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application of crop rotation (Y/N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application of mixed cropping (Y/N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application of inter-cropping (Y/N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perform biological pest control (Y/N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use of biopesticides (Y/N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adopting pasture rotation to suppress livestock pest population (Y/N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Systematic removal of plant parts attacked by pests (Y/N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maintenance and cleansing of spray equipment after use (Y/N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use one pesticide no more than two times or in mixture in a season to avoid pesticide resistance (Y/N)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Use of agro-biodiversity-supportive practices&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension: &lt;/strong&gt;Environmental&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theme: &lt;/strong&gt;Biodiversity &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Convention on Biological Diversity (CBD) stresses the close relationship between agriculture activities and biodiversity, considering three levels of biodiversity: genetic level diversity; agrobiodiversity at production system level; and ecosystem level (wild) biodiversity. The way agriculture is practiced influences all three levels. Attempts to develop indicators of biodiversity for agriculture systematically consider a large number of sub-indicators, with no universally agreed sustainability criteria. Considering these constraints, and the importance of addressing biodiversity in the construction of Indicator 2.4.1, it is proposed to develop a sub-indicator that captures the efforts towards more sustainable agriculture that better contributes to biodiversity, by identifying a limited list of practices that are conducive to biodiversity conservation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coverage: &lt;/strong&gt;All farm types&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sub-indicator measures the level of adoption of more sustainable agricultural practices that better contribute to biodiversity by the farm at ecosystem, species and genetic levels. This indicator addresses both crops and livestock. Specifically, in case of this sub-indicator the scope is the entire area of the farm holding as opposed to the agricultural area that is used for rest of the 10 sub-indicators. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, two separate scoring systems depending on the applicability of the organic farming criterion have been proposed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on whether organic certification system exists, countries will select one of the below two proposed set of criteria and thus will be evaluated/scored differently in terms of their sustainability status. According to this formulation, to secure green status, farms in countries with organic certification in place, will have to check 3 out of 6 criteria. On the contrary, farms operating in countries with no organic certification in place, will have to check 2 out of 5 criteria for obtaining the green status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The detailed formulation of the criteria for the 2 scoring systems is described below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Criteria for group of countries with organic certification systems/schemes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leaves at least 10% of the holding area for natural or diverse vegetation. This can include natural pasture/grassland, maintaining wildflower strips, stone and wood heaps, trees or hedgerows, natural ponds or wetlands. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Farm produces agricultural products that are organically certified, or its products are undergoing the certification process. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Farm does not use medically important antimicrobials as growth promoters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At least two of the following contribute to farm production: 1) temporary crops, 2) pasture, 3) permanent crops, 4) trees on farm, 5) livestock or animal products, and 6) aquaculture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practices crop or crop/pasture rotation involving at least 2 crops or crops and pastures on at least 80% of the farm agriculture area (excluding permanent crops and permanent pastures) over a period of 3 years. In case of a 2-crop rotation, the 2 crops have to be from different plant genus, e.g. a grass plus a legume, or a grass plus a tuber etc.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Livestock includes locally adapted breeds&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-17&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-17&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability status:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Green (desirable): The agricultural holding meets at least three of the above criteria &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Yellow (acceptable): The agricultural holding meets one or two of the above criteria&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Red (unsustainable): The agricultural holding meets none of the above criteria&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Criteria for group of countries with no organic certification systems/schemes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leaves at least 10% of the holding area for natural or diverse vegetation. This can include natural pasture/grassland, maintaining wildflower strips, stone and wood heaps, trees or hedgerows, natural ponds or wetlands. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Farm does not use medically important antimicrobials as growth promoters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At least two of the following contribute to farm production: 1) temporary crops, 2) pasture, 3) permanent crops, 4) trees on farm, 5) livestock or animal products, and 6) aquaculture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practices crop or crop/pasture rotation involving at least 2 crops or crops and pastures on at least 80% of the farm cultivated area (excluding permanent crops and permanent pastures) over a period of 3 years. In case of a 2-crop rotation, the 2 crops have to be from different plant genus, e.g. a grass plus a legume, or a grass plus a tuber etc. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Livestock includes locally adapted breeds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability status:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Green (desirable): The agricultural holding meets at least two of the above criteria &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Yellow (acceptable): The agricultural holding meets one of the above criteria&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Red (unsustainable): The agricultural holding meets none of the above criteria&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data items:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference period: last calendar year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.1 Percentage of the holding area covered by natural or diverse vegetation (not cultivated), including natural pasture or grasslands; wildflower strips; stone or wood heaps; trees or hedgerows; natural ponds or wetlands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.2 Farm produced products (crops and/or livestock) that are organically certified (Y/N)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.3 Farm produced products (crops and/or livestock) that are undergoing organic certification (Y/N)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.4 Report the holding organic certification number&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.5 Report the name of organic certifying body&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.6 Area on which certified organic [CROP/LIVESTOCK] was produced&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.7 Use of medically important antimicrobials as growth promoter for livestock (Y/N)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.8 Value of production of the holding (covered by sub-indicator 1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x20DD; 1 Temporary crops&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x20DD; 2 Pastures&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x20DD; 3 Permanent crops&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x20DD; 4 Trees on farm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x20DD; 5 Livestock and animal products&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x20DD; 6 Aquaculture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.9 Percentage of the cultivated area on which crop rotation or crop/pasture rotation involving at least two crops (excluding permanent crops and permanent pastures) from different plant genus is practiced over a 3 year period&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.10 Area of the agricultural holding covered by the (up to 5) main crops listed for sub-indicator 1 (excluding pasture)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.11 List of different breeds and cross-breed and percentage of animals they represent for each animal species&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Wage rate in agriculture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension: &lt;/strong&gt;Social &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theme: &lt;/strong&gt;Decent employment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme provides information on the remuneration of employees working for the farm and belonging to the elementary occupation group, as defined by the International Standard Classification of Occupation (ISCO-08 - code 92). It informs about economic risks faced by unskilled workers (those performing simple and routine tasks) in terms of remuneration received, the later benchmarked against the minimum wage set at national level in the agricultural sector. This sub-indicator allows distinguishing between holdings that pay a fair remuneration to its employees under the elementary occupation group, and agricultural holdings paying a remuneration to their employees belonging to the elementary occupation group that is below the minimum wage standard. In the latter case, agricultural holdings are deemed to be non-sustainable since the remuneration paid is not sufficient to ensure a decent living standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coverage: &lt;/strong&gt;Not applicable to farms that employ only family labour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sub-indicator measures the farm unskilled labour daily wage rate in Local Currency Units (LCU).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;D&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;y&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;w&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;g&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;k&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;b&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;T&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;m&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;T&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;w&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;k&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;*&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;8&lt;/mn&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where compensation is both monetary and in kind payments expressed in Local Currency Units (LCU)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability criteria: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unskilled labour wage rate in relation to national or agriculture sector minimum wage rate. In case there is no national or agriculture sector minimum wage rate, the national poverty line is used instead:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Green (desirable): If the wage rate paid to unskilled labour is above the minimum national wage rate or minimum agricultural sector wage rate (if available). Default result for farms not hiring labour.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yellow (acceptable): if the wage rate paid to unskilled labour is equals to the minimum national wage rate or minimum agricultural sector wage rate (if available). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red (unsustainable): if the wage rate paid to unskilled labour is below the minimum national wage rate or minimum agricultural sector wage rate (if available). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data items:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference period: last calendar year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9.1 Unskilled workers hired on the agricultural holding (Y/N)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9.2 Average pay in-cash and/or in-kind paid to the hired unskilled worker per day (of 8 hours)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9.3 Minimum agricultural sector wage rate (if available) or minimum national wage rate &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Food Insecurity Experience Scale (FIES)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension: &lt;/strong&gt;Social &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theme: &lt;/strong&gt;Food security &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FIES is a metric of severity of food insecurity at the household level that relies on people&amp;#x2019;s direct yes/no responses to eight simple questions regarding their access to adequate food. It is a statistical measurement scale similar to other widely-accepted statistical scales designed to measure unobservable traits such as aptitude/intelligence, personality, and a broad range of social, psychological and health-related conditions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coverage: &lt;/strong&gt;Only household farms &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Food Insecurity Experience Scale (FIES) produces a measure of the severity of food insecurity experienced by individuals or households, based on direct interviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FIES questions refer to the experiences of the individual respondent or of the respondent&amp;#x2019;s household as a whole. The questions focus on self-reported food-related behaviors and experiences associated with increasing difficulties in accessing food due to resource constraints. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FIES is derived from two widely-used experience-based food security scales: the U.S. Household Food Security Survey Module and the Latin American and Caribbean Food Security Scale (Spanish acronym ELCSA). It consists of a set of eight short yes/no questions asked directly to people. The questions focus on self-reported, food-related behaviours and experiences associated with increasing difficulties in accessing food due to resource constraints. The FIES is based on a well-grounded construct of the experience of food insecurity composed of three domains: uncertainty/anxiety, changes in food quality, and changes in food quantity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sub-indicator is SDG indicator 2.1.2, contextualised for a farm survey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability criteria: &lt;/strong&gt;Level on FIES scale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Green (desirable): Mild food insecurity&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-18&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-18&quot;&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yellow (acceptable)&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-19&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-19&quot;&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;: Moderate food insecurity &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red (unsustainable): Severe food insecurity &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data items:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference period: last 12 months&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10.1 The respondent&amp;#x2019;s recollection that he/she (or any other adult in the household) would be worried about not having enough food to eat due to lack of money or other resources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10.2 The respondent&amp;#x2019;s recollection that he/she (or any adult in the household) was unable to eat healthy and nutritious food because of lack of money or other resources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10.3 The respondent&amp;#x2019;s recollection that he/she (or any adult in the household) only ate a few kinds of food due to lack of money or other resources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10.4 The respondent&amp;#x2019;s recollection that he/she (or any adult in the household) had to skip a meal because there was no enough money or other resources for food&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10.5 The respondent&amp;#x2019;s recollection that he/she (or any adult in the household) ate less than he/she thought he should due to lack of money or other resources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10.6 The respondent&amp;#x2019;s recollection that his/her household ran out of food because of a lack of money or other resources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10.7 The respondent&amp;#x2019;s recollection that he/she (or any adult in the household) was hungry but not eating due to lack of money or other resources for food&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10.8 The respondent&amp;#x2019;s recollection that he/she (or any adult in the household) did not eat for a whole day because of a lack of money or other resources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11. Secure tenure rights to land&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension: &lt;/strong&gt;Social &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theme: &lt;/strong&gt;Land tenure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sub-indicator allows assessing sustainability in terms of rights over use of agricultural land areas. Since agricultural land is a key input for agricultural production, having secure rights over land ensures that the agricultural holding controls such a key asset and does not risk losing the land used by the holding for farming. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evidence shows that farmers tend to be less productive if they have limited access to and control of economic resources and services, particularly land. Long-lasting inequalities of economic and financial resources have positioned certain farmers at a disadvantage relative to others in their ability to participate in, contribute to and benefit from broader processes of development. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, adequate distribution of economic resources, particularly land, help ensure equitable economic growth, contributes to economic efficiency and has a positive impact on key development outcomes, including poverty reduction, food security and the welfare of households.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sub-indicator is SDG indicator 5.a.1, customised for SDG indicator 2.4.1. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coverage: &lt;/strong&gt;All farms types&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sub-indicator measures the ownership or secure rights over use of agricultural land areas using the following criteria:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Formal document issued by the Land Registry/Cadastral Agency &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Name of the holder listed as owner/use right holder on legally recognized documents&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rights to sell any of the parcel of the holding&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rights to bequeath any of the parcel of the holding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability criteria: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Level of security of access to land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Green (desirable): has a formal document with the name of the holder/holding on it, or has the right to sell any of the parcel of the holding, or has the right to bequeath any of the parcel of the holding&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yellow (acceptable): has a formal document even if the name of the holder/holding is not on it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red (unsustainable): no positive responses to any of the 4 questions above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data items:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference period: last calendar year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11.1 Type of formal document for any of the agricultural land of the holder/holding that it holds (alternatively &amp;#x2018;possess, use, occupy) issued by the Land Registry/Cadastral Agency&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x20DD; 1 Title deed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x20DD; 2 Certificate of customary tenure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x20DD; 3 Certificate of occupancy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x20DD; 4 Registered will or registered certificate of hereditary acquisitions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x20DD; 5 Registered certificate of perpetual / long term lease&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x20DD; 6 Registered rental contract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x20DD; 7 Other&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11.2 Name of any member of the holding listed as an owner or use right holder on any of the legally recognized documents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11.3 The right of the holder/holding to sell any of the parcel of the holding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11.4 The right of the holder/holding to bequeath any of the parcel of the holding&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-3&quot;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; According to the SEEA-AFF classification and the classification of the World Agricultural Census 2020 &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-4&quot;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; The 90&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; percentile and respective 1/3 and 2/3 thresholds for productivity are calculated by major production system (crops, livestock, or a mix of crops and livestock or if possible by major agricultural areas of the country). Thereafter the individual farm productivity is estimated and compared with thresholds derived from the productivities of similar farms. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-4&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-5&quot;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; See Statistics Canada at: http://www.statcan.gc.ca/pub/21-010-x/21-010-x2014001-eng.pdf &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-5&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-6&quot;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Rental value of farm dwellings is not considered as part of farm income. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-6&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-7&quot;&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Include cash loans and in-kind loans (e.g., seeds provided by another farmer and repaid with a share of the harvest, seeds, etc.) only for agriculture related investments. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-7&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-8&quot;&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Reduction in soil fertility will be experienced by farmers as progressive reduction in yield and will be the result of a negative nutrient balance by which the amount of nutrient application (including through mineral and organic fertilizers, legumes, or green manure) is lower than the amount that is lost and exported by crops. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-8&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-9&quot;&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; In order to keep the questionnaire manageable, the module does not consider different type of crop or practice. The method therefore assumes that if a farmer reports best practices, these practices are applied over the entire farm. It may therefore over-estimate the area under good practices. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-9&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-10&quot;&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Soil type, combined with climate, and in particular the frequency and intensity of rainfall events, are important elements to consider in deciding fertilizer application doses and frequencies. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-10&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-11&quot;&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Precision farming is a farming management concept based on observing, measuring and responding to inter and intra-field variability in crops. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-11&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-12&quot;&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Fertilizers to be considered include mineral and synthetic fertilizers as well as animal manure. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-12&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-13&quot;&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Integrated Pest Management (IPM) is an ecosystem approach to crop production and protection that combines different management strategies and practices to grow healthy crops and minimize the use of pesticides (FAO). &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-13&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-14&quot;&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; In order to keep the questionnaire manageable, the module does not consider different types of crop or livestock. The method therefore assumes that if a farmer reports best practices, these practices are applied over the entire farm. It may therefore over-estimate the area under good practices. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-14&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-15&quot;&gt;14&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; WHO Class II or III pesticides as defined by WHO classification (https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240005662or equivalent national classification. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-15&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-16&quot;&gt;15&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; In principle, illegal pesticides refer to any products which do not comply with national regulations on pesticide management, such as un-registered, mislabeled, illegally imported etc. It does not cover &amp;quot;off-label uses,&amp;quot; which could be considered as an illegal use action. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-16&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-17&quot;&gt;16&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Breeds which have been in the country for a sufficient time to be genetically adapted to one or more of traditional production systems or environments in the country. The phrase &amp;#x201C;sufficient time&amp;#x201D; refers to time present in one or more of the country&amp;#x2019;s traditional production systems or environments. Taking cultural, social and genetic aspects into account, a period of 40 years and six generations of the respective species might be considered as a guiding value for &amp;#x201C;sufficient time&amp;#x201D;, subject to specific national circumstances (definition of locally adapted breeds adopted by the Fourteenth Regular Session (April 2013) of the FAO Commission on Genetic Resources for Food and Agriculture). &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-17&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-18&quot;&gt;17&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Computation of food insecurity level is described in detail in e-learning course on SDG 2.1.2: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/elearning/#/elc/en/course/SDG212&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/elearning/#/elc/en/course/SDG212&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-18&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-19&quot;&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;u&gt;The terminology &amp;#x201C;Acceptable&amp;#x201D; must be read within the context of SDG 2.4.1; it should be interpreted as a situation that nevertheless merits attention and actions aimed at improvement.&lt;/u&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-19&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 2: liminer la faim, assurer la scurit alimentaire, amliorer la nutrition et promouvoir l&apos;agriculture durable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 2.4: D&apos;ici 2030, garantir des systmes de production alimentaire durables et mettre en uvre des pratiques agricoles rsilientes qui augmentent la productivit et la production, qui aident  maintenir les cosystmes, qui renforcent la capacit d&apos;adaptation au changement climatique, aux conditions mtorologiques extrmes,  la scheresse, aux inondations et  d&apos;autres catastrophes et qui amliorent progressivement la qualit des terres et des sols&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 2.4.1: Proportion de la superficie agricole consacre  une agriculture productive et durable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2022-03-31&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Liens directs avec:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.1.2 Prvalence de linscurit alimentaire modre ou grave dans la population, selon lchelle de scurit alimentaire fonde sur l&apos;exprience (FIES)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.a.1 a) Pourcentage de personnes ayant la proprit ou des droits srs sur les terres agricoles (sur lensemble de la population agricole), par sexe; et b) la part des femmes parmi les propritaires ou les dtenteurs de droits de terres agricoles, par type de tenure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lien indirect avec:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 2.3.2: Revenu moyen des petits producteurs alimentaires, selon le sexe et le statut autochtone&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organisation des Nations Unies pour l&apos;alimentation et l&apos;agriculture (FAO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organisation des Nations Unies pour l&apos;alimentation et l&apos;agriculture (FAO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dfinition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le champ de l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1 est l&apos;exploitation agricole, et plus prcisment la superficie agricole de l&apos;exploitation, c.--d. les terres utilises principalement pour la culture et l&apos;levage. Ce choix de champ est tout  fait cohrent avec l&apos;utilisation prvue de la superficie agricole d&apos;un pays comme dnominateur de l&apos;indicateur agrg. Plus prcisment, les lments suivants sont inclus dans le champ de l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1 :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Systmes de production de cultures et d&apos;levage intensifs et extensifs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agriculture de subsistance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Terres de l&apos;tat et communales lorsqu&apos;elles sont utilises exclusivement et gres par l&apos;exploitation agricole.&lt;/li&gt; 
  &lt;li&gt;Cultures alimentaires et non alimentaires et produits de l&apos;levage (p. ex., tabac, coton et laine de mouton). &lt;/li&gt; 
  &lt;li&gt;Cultures destines au fourrage ou  des fins nergtiques.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agroforesterie (arbres sur les zones agricoles de l&apos;exploitation). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aquaculture, dans la mesure o elle a lieu sur les terres agricoles (p. ex., la rizipisciculture et les systmes similaires). &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les lments suivants sont exclus du champ de l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1 :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Terres de l&apos;tat et communales non utilises exclusivement par l&apos;exploitation agricole.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pastoralisme nomade.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Production issue des jardins et arrire-cours. Production des fermes d&apos;agrment &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exploitations consacres exclusivement  l&apos;aquaculture. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exploitations consacres exclusivement  la sylviculture. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nourriture rcolte  l&apos;tat sauvage. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La revue littraire (Hayati, 2017) a identifi un grand nombre de thmes potentiels de durabilit dans les trois dimensions de la durabilit et, pour chaque thme, gnralement un grand nombre de sous-indicateurs possibles. Les considrations cls dans la slection des thmes sont la pertinence et la mesurabilit. En termes de pertinence, la relation entre le sous-indicateur associ et les rsultats de l&apos;agriculture durable au niveau de l&apos;exploitation doit tre forte. Suivant cette approche, seuls les sous-indicateurs qui rpondent aux politiques au niveau des exploitations visant  amliorer l&apos;agriculture durable sont pris en compte. En termes de mesurabilit, seul un ensemble de thmes et de sous-indicateurs  de base  pour lesquels des mesures et des rapports sont attendus dans la majorit des pays sont slectionns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Un aspect essentiel de toutes les approches de la mesure de l&apos;agriculture durable est la reconnaissance du fait que la durabilit est un concept multidimensionnel, et que ces multiples dimensions doivent tre refltes dans la construction de l&apos;indicateur. Cela implique que l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1 des ODD doit tre bas sur un ensemble de sous-indicateurs qui couvrent ces trois dimensions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Grce  un processus consultatif qui a dur plus de deux ans, 11 thmes et sous-indicateurs ont t identifis et constituent l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1 des ODD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;No.&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;Thmes&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;Sous-indicateurs&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Productivit des terres&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Valeur de production agricole par hectare&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Rentabilit&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Revenu net de la ferme&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Rsilience&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Mcanismes d&apos;attnuation de risques&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Sant des sols&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Prvalence de dtrioration des sols&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Utilisation de l&apos;eau&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Variation dans la disponibilit de l&apos;eau&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Risque de pollution par les engrais&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Gestion des engrais&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;7&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Risque des pesticides&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Gestion des pesticides&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;8&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Biodiversit&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Utilisation de pratiques propices  l&apos;agro-biodiversit&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;9&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Emploi dcent&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Taux de rmunration en agriculture&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;10&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Scurit alimentaire&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;chelle de scurit alimentaire fonde sur l&apos;exprience (FIES)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;11&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Rgime foncier&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Droits fonciers srs&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Veuillez consulter l&apos;annexe pour une description dtaille des sous-indicateurs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les pays dfiniront les fermes d&apos;agrment selon leurs critres nationaux et retireront ces exploitations de la population d&apos;intrt pour l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1 jusqu&apos; ce qu&apos;une dfinition internationale soit disponible. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pourcentage (%) : Les pays membres sont tenus de dclarer la proportion (pourcentage) de superficie des terres agricoles pour les 11 sous-indicateurs sparment par statut de durabilit. Lagrgation au niveau national est effectue pour chaque sous-indicateur indpendamment, en additionnant la superficie des terres agricoles de chaque exploitation agricole (slectionne  partir dun chantillon reprsentatif au niveau national) et en dclarant enfin le total national rsultant en pourcentage de la superficie totale des terres agricoles reprsentative au niveau national, pour les 11 sous-indicateurs dans un tableau de bord. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;La classification des terres est celle mise en uvre dans le questionnaire de la FAO sur l&apos;utilisation des terres, l&apos;irrigation et les pratiques agricoles (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fao.org/faostat/fr/#data/RL/metadata&quot;&gt;https://www.fao.org/faostat/fr/#data/RL/metadata&lt;/a&gt; ). Celle-ci est cohrente avec celle du Recensement de l&apos;agriculture et du Systme des comptes conomiques et environnementaux (SEEA).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diffrentes donnes sont recueillies via diffrents instruments. Souvent, les donnes environnementales sont recueillies par le biais de systmes de surveillance environnementale, y compris la tldtection. Pourtant, de nombreux pays n&apos;ont pas la capacit ou les ressources pour le faire, et par consquent ces donnes sont rares ou inexistantes. Afin de proposer une solution grable et rentable, une exigence souligne par plusieurs pays lors des consultations, la mthodologie offre un seul instrument de collecte de donnes pour tous les sous-indicateurs: l&apos;enqute agricole.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plusieurs pays ont suggr d&apos;utiliser des sources de donnes existantes ou des sources de donnes alternatives tant donn que ces instruments peuvent tre plus rentables et parfois fournir des rsultats plus fiables que les enqutes agricoles. Ces instruments comprennent la tldtection, les SIG, les modles, les enqutes agricoles, les enqutes auprs des mnages, les donnes administratives ou les systmes de surveillance environnementale. La mthodologie considre la possibilit d&apos;utiliser de tels instruments, sous rserve d&apos;une srie de critres pour assurer la qualit des donnes et la comparabilit internationale. D&apos;autres sources de donnes peuvent galement tre utilises pour complter et/ou valider les rsultats de l&apos;enqute agricole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La note mthodologique recommande galement que les pays compltent l&apos;enqute agricole par des systmes de surveillance permettant de mesurer l&apos;impact de l&apos;agriculture sur l&apos;environnement (pollution des sols, de l&apos;eau, des engrais et pesticides, biodiversit, etc.) et sur la sant (rsidus de pesticides dans la nourriture et le corps humain). Ceci fournira des informations supplmentaires et aidera  vrifier la robustesse de l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1 des ODD en ce qui concerne la dimension environnementale de la durabilit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Un questionnaire est envoy  tous les pays chaque anne depuis 2020 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fao.org/sustainable-development-goals/indicators/241/fr/&quot;&gt;https://www.fao.org/sustainable-development-goals/indicators/241/fr/&lt;/a&gt; ). En outre, afin de faciliter la collecte de donnes par pays, un module de donnes a t conu et il contient lensemble des questions de base ncessaires pour obtenir les donnes pour lODD 2.4.1. Si des enqutes agricoles existent dj dans un pays, ces questions peuvent tre intgres dans les instruments existants afin de rduire au minimum la charge pesant sur les bureaux nationaux de statistique (BNS). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toutes les activits de collecte de donnes seront effectues par lintermdiaire du BNS ou du bureau dsign pour recueillir des donnes pour cet indicateur. La FAO, en collaboration avec la Stratgie mondiale pour lamlioration des statistiques agricoles et rurales (GSARS), a cr le matriel de renforcement des capacits ncessaire pour cet indicateur, y compris un guide mthodologique, un manuel de recenseur, un document de calcul, des conseils d&apos;chantillonnage et un cours dapprentissage en ligne pour former les BNS des pays et dautres membres du personnel concerns au sujet de cet indicateur. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;La collecte des donnes dpendra des cycles de collecte de donnes existant actuellement pour les enqutes agricoles dans les pays. La FAO a intgr le module de questionnaire associ  cet indicateur dans le programme AGRISurvey et l&apos;initiative 50x2030.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bien que de nouvelles donnes ne soient pas disponibles  chaque anne pour chaque pays, toutes les nouvelles informations devraient tre diffuses chaque anne par lintermdiaire de FAOSTAT. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les bureaux nationaux de statistique ou les bureaux dsigns dans les pays seront chargs de recueillir des donnes pour cet indicateur. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les bureaux nationaux de statistique ou les bureaux dsigns dans les pays seront chargs de recueillir et de compiler les donnes pour cet indicateur. Ils rendront compte  leur tour  la FAO qui assurera le renforcement des capacits, effectuera le contrle de la qualit et diffusera linformation par lintermdiaire de FAOSTAT. La FAO fera  son tour rapport  la communaut statistique internationale et  la DSNU. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Larticle I de la constitution de la FAO exige que celle-ci recueille, analyse, interprte et diffuse des informations relatives  la nutrition,  lalimentation et  lagriculture &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/K8024F/K8024F.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/K8024F/K8024F.pdf&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les approches pour encadrer et dfinir l&apos;agriculture durable varient en termes de couverture des trois dimensions principales de la durabilit, c.--d. conomique, environnementale et sociale, et en termes d&apos;chelle utilise pour valuer la durabilit, c.--d.  l&apos;chelle du champ et de la ferme jusqu&apos;aux chelles nationale et mondiale. Certaines approches prennent en compte diffrentes caractristiques de la durabilit, par exemple si les pratiques actuelles sont conomiquement ralisables, respectueuses de l&apos;environnement et socialement souhaitables. D&apos;autres approches se concentrent sur des pratiques particulires telles que l&apos;agriculture biologique, rgnrative ou  faibles intrants et peuvent les assimiler  une agriculture durable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La conclusion d&apos;une revue de la littrature associe au dveloppement mthodologique de cet indicateur est que l&apos;approche multidimensionnelle dveloppe par la FAO en 1988 est un cadre significatif du concept. Ainsi, l&apos;agriculture durable peut tre considre comme  la gestion et la conservation de la base de ressources naturelles, et l&apos;orientation du changement technologique et institutionnel de manire  assurer la ralisation et la satisfaction continue des besoins humains des gnrations prsentes et futures. Un tel dveloppement (dans l&apos;agriculture, la foresterie et la pche, etc.) prserve la terre, l&apos;eau, les ressources gntiques vgtales et animales, sans dgradation de l&apos;environnement et est techniquement appropri, conomiquement viable et socialement acceptable.  (FAO, 1988)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Au cours des consultations entreprises, plusieurs pays ont soulign les difficults  combiner des donnes provenant de diffrentes sources et ont demand que cela soit vit dans la mesure du possible. D&apos;autres pays, relativement riches en donnes, ont au contraire insist sur la ncessit de permettre l&apos;utilisation des sources de donnes existantes. La mthodologie actualise rpond  ces deux proccupations : elle propose l&apos;enqute agricole comme instrument unique de collecte de donnes pour tous les sous-indicateurs, mais elle offre galement la possibilit d&apos;utiliser une combinaison de diffrentes sources de donnes comme option alternative, pour autant que certains critres soient satisfaits&lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;La dcision d&apos;utiliser l&apos;enqute agricole comme instrument de collecte de donnes pour cet indicateur est conforme aux efforts des pays, soutenus par la FAO, pour dvelopper les enqutes agricoles comme l&apos;outil le plus appropri pour gnrer des statistiques agricoles. Il bnficie galement des travaux de la FAO visant  dvelopper le programme d&apos;enqute intgre sur l&apos;agriculture (AGRIS), qui est mis en uvre dans le cadre d&apos;une nouvelle initiative appele &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.data4sdgs.org/50by2030&quot;&gt;50x2030&lt;/a&gt; (lien en anglais). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La dcision de se concentrer sur les enqutes agricoles a des implications sur le type d&apos;informations qu&apos;il est possible de saisir afin de couvrir les diffrentes dimensions de la durabilit. Si les enqutes agricoles sont bien adaptes pour mesurer la dimension conomique de la durabilit, elles ne sont peut-tre pas l&apos;outil idal pour mesurer la durabilit environnementale et sociale en termes d&apos;impact/rsultats. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gnralement, les impacts environnementaux de l&apos;agriculture sont mesurs par des systmes de surveillance tels que la tldtection, l&apos;chantillonnage du sol et de l&apos;eau, ou d&apos;autres outils associs  une zone spcifique, plutt qu&apos; une seule exploitation agricole. Pour plusieurs thmes environnementaux, il est peu probable que les agriculteurs soient en mesure d&apos;valuer l&apos;impact environnemental de leurs pratiques agricoles sur des questions telles que la pollution par les engrais ou l&apos;impact des pesticides. L&apos;utilisation d&apos;un instrument d&apos;enqute agricole, au lieu de systmes de surveillance environnementale, implique donc de passer de la mesure des rsultats/impacts  l&apos;valuation des pratiques des agriculteurs. Dans la mesure du possible, cependant, la mthodologie rvise continue de se concentrer sur la mesure des rsultats. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De mme, les sous-thmes de la dimension sociale sont gnralement mieux saisis par des enqutes auprs des mnages. Si, dans la majorit des cas, les exploitations agricoles sont troitement associes  un mnage donn, ce n&apos;est pas toujours le cas, et par consquent, la saisie de la dimension sociale de la durabilit par le biais d&apos;une enqute agricole, en particulier si elle n&apos;est pas conue pour couvrir les aspects sociaux, pourrait poser certains dfis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur est dfini par la formule suivante :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;O&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;D&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;D&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;2&lt;/mn&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;.&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;4&lt;/mn&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;.&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;1&lt;/mn&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;S&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;v&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;g&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;v&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;b&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;S&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;g&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ceci suppose qu&apos;on doit mesurer  la fois la superficie des terres consacres  une agriculture productive et durable (le numrateur),et la superficie des terres agricoles (le dnominateur).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Le &lt;em&gt;numrateur&lt;/em&gt; reflte les trois dimensions de la production durable : environnementale, conomique et sociale. Il correspond  la superficie des terres agricoles des fermes qui satisfont le critre de durabilit des 11 sous-indicateurs choisis dans les trois dimensions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Le &lt;em&gt;dnominateur&lt;/em&gt; est quant  lui la somme des surfaces agricoles (telles que dfinies par la FAO) utilises par les exploitations agricoles en proprit ( l&apos;exclusion de la location  autrui), en location, en fermage, en mtayage ou en emprunt. Les terres de l&apos;tat ou communales utilises par les exploitations agricoles ne sont pas incluses. Veuillez consulter le &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/ca7154en/ca7154en.pdf&quot;&gt;document mthodologique (en anglais)&lt;/a&gt; prpar par la FAO pour une explication plus dtaille&lt;/li&gt;. &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les tapes de calcul de l&apos;ODD 2.4.1 incluent:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dterminer la &lt;strong&gt;porte&lt;/strong&gt; de l&apos;indicateur: la porte de l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1 est l&apos;exploitation agricole, et plus prcisment la superficie agricole de l&apos;exploitation, c.--d. les terres utilises principalement pour les cultures et lever du btail. Les activits de foresterie, de pche et d&apos;aquaculture peuvent tre incluses dans la mesure o il s&apos;agit d&apos;activits secondaires menes sur la surface agricole de l&apos;exploitation, par exemple la rizipisciculture et les systmes similaires.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dterminer les &lt;strong&gt;dimensions&lt;/strong&gt;  couvrir : l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1 inclut les dimensions environnementales, conomiques et sociales dans l&apos;valuation de la durabilit. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choisir &lt;strong&gt;l&apos;chelle&lt;/strong&gt; pour l&apos;valuation de la durabilit: l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1 est au niveau de l&apos;exploitation avec une agrgation  des niveaux suprieurs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choisir le ou les &lt;strong&gt;instruments&lt;/strong&gt; de collecte de donnes. Il est recommand que les donnes de l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1 soient recueillies via une enqute agricole.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choisir les &lt;strong&gt;thmes&lt;/strong&gt; au sein de chaque dimension, et choisir un &lt;strong&gt;sous-indicateur&lt;/strong&gt; pour chaque thme. Les sous-indicateurs doivent satisfaire  un certain nombre de critres (dcrits  l&apos;annexe 1 pour chaque sous-indicateur, respectivement).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;valuer la &lt;strong&gt;performance de durabilit au niveau de l&apos;exploitation pour chaque sous-indicateur&lt;/strong&gt;: des &lt;strong&gt;critres&lt;/strong&gt; de durabilit spcifiques sont appliqus afin d&apos;valuer le niveau de durabilit de l&apos;exploitation pour chaque thme en fonction des sous-indicateurs. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dcider de la &lt;strong&gt;priodicit de suivi de l&apos;indicateur&lt;/strong&gt;. Il est recommand que la collecte soit au moins tous les trois ans.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modalit de dclaration de l&apos;indicateur&lt;/strong&gt; : l&apos;ensemble des sous-indicateurs est prsent sous la forme d&apos;un &lt;strong&gt;tableau de bord&lt;/strong&gt;. L&apos;approche du tableau de bord offre une rponse en termes de mesure de la durabilit au niveau de l&apos;exploitation et de son agrgation au niveau national. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La mthodologie propose de rendre compte de l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1  travers un tableau de bord au niveau national, prsentant les diffrents sous-indicateurs ensemble mais de faon indpendante. L&apos;approche du tableau de bord offre plusieurs avantages, notamment la possibilit de combiner des donnes provenant de diffrentes sources et l&apos;identification des problmes critiques de durabilit, facilitant la recherche d&apos;un quilibre entre les trois dimensions de la durabilit. En consquence, les pays peuvent facilement visualiser leurs performances en termes de diffrentes dimensions et thmes de durabilit, et comprendre o les efforts politiques peuvent tre concentrs pour des amliorations futures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le calcul des rsultats et la construction du tableau de bord sont effectus pour chaque sous-indicateur sparment en utilisant l&apos;approche du  feu de circultation  dj dfinie pour chaque sous-indicateur : l&apos;agrgation au niveau national est effectue pour chaque sous-indicateur indpendamment , en additionnant la superficie des terres agricoles de chaque exploitation agricole par catgorie de durabilit (rouge, jaune ou vert) et en rapportant le total national rsultant en pourcentage de la superficie nationale totale des terres agricoles de toutes les exploitations agricoles du pays. En pratique, la valeur dclare de l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1 est dtermine par les rsultats du sous-indicateur le plus limitatif en termes de performance de durabilit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les donnes font lobjet dun travail de validation complet qui couvre: la dtection des valeurs aberrantes, les erreurs de transmission et les contrles de cohrence des donnes. On invite les pays  examiner les rsultats diffuss pour leur pays et soit  confirmer quils sont corrects, soit  fournir des remarques et/ou  rviser les donnes sils identifient des erreurs. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Des ajustements  la superficie agricole nationale totale peuvent tre effectus pour corriger les zones communes qui sont hors de porte en ce qui concerne la mthodologie de l&apos;indicateur.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Au niveau national :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La non-rponse partielle au niveau individuel (exploitation agricole) sera impute  laide de techniques statistiques appropries, telles que des algorithmes du plus proche voisin. La dcision dimputer ou non et le choix de la mthode sont fonction de la nature de la variable  imputer et de la quantit et du type de donnes disponibles pour limputation, telles que la disponibilit de donnes auxiliaires provenant de diffrentes sources (p. ex., enqutes, informations administratives). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il est important de distinguer clairement les donnes manquantes des vnements qui ne s&apos;appliquent pas. Comme indiqu ci-dessus et dans les fiches mthodologiques des sous-indicateurs, certains sous-indicateurs peuvent tre enregistrs comme sans objet pour une exploitation agricole donne. Dans ce cas, lexploitation sera considre comme durable du point de vue des sous-indicateurs donns. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Au niveau national, si et quand les donnes sont fournies  laide dautres sources pour certains des sous-indicateurs, des notes pertinentes doivent tre fournies par le pays expliquant le type, la nature, la source et la priode des donnes dclares. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Aux niveaux rgional et mondial :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aucun traitement des valeurs manquantes ne sera effectu aux niveaux rgional et mondial. Les estimations rgionales et mondiales seront construites  partir des donnes des pays qui ont dclar les 11 sous-indicateurs et/ou de ceux qui ont dclar un sous-ensemble des 11 seulement si certains des sous-indicateurs sont sans objet ou non pertinents dans le contexte de ces pays. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ces donnes seront diffuses par lintermdiaire de FAOSTAT, la plus grande base de donnes de statistiques alimentaires et agricoles. Par consquent, la mthode de calcul suivra la norme internationale tablie par la base de donnes. Dans le cas de cet indicateur, les agrgats rgionaux et mondiaux seront calculs en pondrant les indicateurs nationaux en fonction de la superficie agricole du pays.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;La note mthodologique fournit une description dtaille du calcul de l&apos;indicateur sur la base de l&apos;enqute agricole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les valeurs pour dclarer l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1 peuvent tre calcules comme suit :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;msub&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;O&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;D&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;D&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mn&gt;241&lt;/mn&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/msub&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;munder&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;min&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;:&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;mn&gt;1&lt;/mn&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;-&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;mn&gt;11&lt;/mn&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/munder&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mo&gt;&amp;#x2061;&lt;/mo&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;(&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;S&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;I&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;)&lt;/mo&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mrow&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;o :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ODD241&lt;sub&gt;d &lt;/sub&gt;= proportion de la superficie des terres agricoles qui a atteint le niveau  dsir &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SI&lt;sub&gt;d n &lt;/sub&gt;= proportion du sous-indicateur n qui est classe dans le niveau  dsir &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;min fait rfrence au niveau minimum des SI&lt;sub&gt;d n&lt;/sub&gt; au niveau national pour l&apos;ensemble des 11 sous-indicateurs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ODD241&lt;sub&gt;d &lt;/sub&gt;est la proportion de la superficie des terres agricoles pour laquelle tous les sous-indicateurs sont verts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;msub&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;O&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;D&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;D&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mn&gt;241&lt;/mn&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/msub&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;munder&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;min&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;:&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;mn&gt;1&lt;/mn&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;-&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;mn&gt;11&lt;/mn&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/munder&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mo&gt;&amp;#x2061;&lt;/mo&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;msub&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mo&gt;(&lt;/mo&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;S&lt;/mi&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;I&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/msub&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;msub&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;S&lt;/mi&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;I&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/msub&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;)&lt;/mo&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mrow&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;o :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ODD241&lt;sub&gt;a+d &lt;/sub&gt;= proportion de la superficie des terres agricoles qui a atteint le niveau  dsir  (estime par excs, voir la note plus bas)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SI&lt;sub&gt;d n &lt;/sub&gt;= proportion du sous-indicateur n qui est classe dans le niveau  dsir &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SI&lt;sub&gt;a n &lt;/sub&gt;= proportion du sous-indicateur n qui est classe dans le niveau  acceptable &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;min fait rfrence au niveau minimum de (SI&lt;sub&gt;d n &lt;/sub&gt;+ SI&lt;sub&gt;a n&lt;/sub&gt;) au niveau national pour l&apos;ensemble des 11 sous-indicateurs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ODD241&lt;sub&gt;a+d &lt;/sub&gt;est la proportion de la superficie des terres agricoles pour laquelle tous les sous-indicateurs sont verts ou jaunes, une situation acceptable mais qui pourrait tre amliore. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;msub&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;O&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;D&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;D&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mn&gt;241&lt;/mn&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/msub&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;1&lt;/mn&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;-&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;O&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;msub&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;D&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;D&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mn&gt;241&lt;/mn&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/msub&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;munder&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;max&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;:&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;mn&gt;1&lt;/mn&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;-&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;mn&gt;11&lt;/mn&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/munder&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mo&gt;&amp;#x2061;&lt;/mo&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;(&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;S&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;I&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;)&lt;/mo&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mrow&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;o :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ODD241&lt;sub&gt;u &lt;/sub&gt;= proportion estime par dfaut de la superficie des terres agricoles qui est  non durable  (voir la note plus bas)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SI&lt;sub&gt;u n &lt;/sub&gt;= proportion du sous-indicateur n qui est classe  non durable &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;max fait rfrence  la valeur maximale des SI&lt;sub&gt;u n&lt;/sub&gt; pour l&apos;ensemble des 11 sous-indicateurs, au niveau national&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ODD241&lt;sub&gt;u &lt;/sub&gt; est la proportion de la superficie des terres agricoles pour laquelle au moins un des sous-indicateurs est non durable, et est par consquent classe non durable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les performances des pays dans le temps peuvent tre mesures par l&apos;volution de la valeur de ODD241&lt;sub&gt;d &lt;/sub&gt;et de ODD241&lt;sub&gt;a+d&lt;/sub&gt;. Une augmentation dans le temps indique une amlioraiton tandis qu&apos;une diminution indique une dtrioration. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;La gestion standard de la qualit de lensemble du processus de dclaration des donnes et des donnes elles-mmes sera effectue en troite coordination avec les pays afin de sassurer que les donnes dclares sont conformes  la mthodologie et aux normes internationales pertinentes. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;La FAO travaillera en troite collaboration avec les pays pour lassurance de la qualit. Non seulement la collecte de donnes pour lODD 2.4.1 respectera les normes internationales, mais elle respectera galement le cadre dassurance de la qualit des donnes de la FAO  Statistics Quality Assurance Framework  (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/statistics/standards/fr/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/statistics/standards/fr/&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Une valuation qualitative de la qualit globale des produits statistiques est fournie dans les rapports rguliers en rsumant les principaux points forts et les ventuelles lacunes en matire de qualit des donnes des pays, par sous-indicateur. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disponibilit des donnes :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lindicateur est actuellement dans la catgorie de niveau II parce que peu de pays sont en mesure de le dclarer. On sattend  ce que les donnes soient recueillies soit dans le cadre denqutes agricoles existantes, soit au moyen dautres sources de donnes telles que des systmes de surveillance de lenvironnement, des donnes administratives ou des enqutes auprs des mnages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des efforts globaux de renforcement des capacits (utilisant une combinaison de formations en personne, de formations en ligne en grand nombre et daide bilatrale) sont en cours pour renforcer les capacits des pays. Les donnes seront dclares dici la fin de 2022, une fois que la troisime et dernire ronde du cycle de collecte et de dclaration des donnes de 3 ans sera termine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sries chronologiques :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lindicateur 2.4.1 des ODD mesure les progrs vers une agriculture plus durable et productive sur une priodicit de trois ans, car pour de nombreux sous-indicateurs, il est probable que les changements seront relativement limits dune anne  lautre. En outre, la priodicit sur 3 ans permettra aux pays davoir trois points de donnes pour lindicateur avant 2030. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dsagrgation :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lindicateur 2.4.1 devrait tre recueilli au moyen denqutes auprs des exploitations agricoles et le rsultat devrait tre exprim en valeur nationale. Cependant, la mthodologie est indpendante de lchelle et peut tre adopte  nimporte quel niveau gographique. En outre, lindicateur peut tre ventil en fonction du type de systme agricole (culture, btail ou mixte) et dautres caractristiques de lexploitation, p. ex., le secteur des mnages/non-mnages, irrigu/non irrigu ou le sexe de lexploitant agricole. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources des divergences :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tant donn quil sagit dun indicateur de niveau II, il nexiste actuellement aucune donne pour cet indicateur. Il ny a donc pas de divergence entre les donnes nationales et infranationales.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FAO. 1988. Report of the FAO Council, 94e session, 1988. FAO, Rome, Italie.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FAO. 2014. Building a common vision for sustainable food and agriculture: Principles and approaches. FAO, Rome, Italie.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FAO. 2017. Report from the Expert Group Meeting on SDG indicator 2.4.1. April, 2017. FAO, Rome, Italie.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FAO, 2018. Classification de lutilisation des terres. Dans : SEEA Agriculture, Forestry and Fisheries, Annex I, pg. 120, 130-135. FAO et DSNU, Rome, Italie.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FAO. 2018. Report of the 26&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Committee on Agriculture, 1-5 octobre 2018. FAO, Rome, Italie.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Global Strategy for Improving Agricultural and Rural Statistics. 2017. Handbook on the Agricultural Integrated Survey. FAO, Rome, Italie. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FAO. 2020. SDG 2.4.1, methodological note. Juillet 2020. FAO, Rome, Italie.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hayati, D. 2017. Literature Review: A Literature Review on Frameworks and Methods for Measuring and Monitoring Sustainable Agriculture. Technical Report n.22. Global Strategy Technical Report. FAO, Rome, Italie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annexe : description des sous-indicateurs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Valeur de la production agricole par hectare&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension : &lt;/strong&gt;conomique&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thme : &lt;/strong&gt;productivit des terres&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La productivit des terres est une mesure de la valeur agricole des productions obtenues sur une superficie donne. Le maintien ou lamlioration de la production au fil du temps par rapport  la superficie des terres utilises est un aspect important de la durabilit pour diverses raisons. Au niveau de lexploitation, la productivit des terres reflte la technologie et les processus de production pour des conditions agro-cologiques donnes. Dans un sens plus large, une augmentation du niveau de productivit des terres permet une production plus leve tout en rduisant la pression sur les ressources foncires de plus en plus rares, gnralement lies  la dforestation et aux pertes associes de services cosystmiques et de biodiversit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Couverture : &lt;/strong&gt;tous les types d&apos;exploitations agricoles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le sous-indicateur est dcrit comme la valeur de la production agricole par hectare (exploitations qui produisent des cultures et du btail ou un mlange). Les informations sur les extrants des exploitations et les superficies agricoles devraient tre des informations standard disponibles dans les enqutes agricoles, fournissant ainsi une bonne base dvaluation au niveau des exploitations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Valeur de la production agricole : le volume de la production agricole au niveau de lexploitation tient gnralement compte de la production de plusieurs produits, p. ex. les types de cultures et les combinaisons de cultures et de btail, etc. tant donn que le volume des productions agricoles nest pas mesur en units proportionnelles (p. ex., toutes les productions ne sont pas mesures en tonnes et les tonnes de productions diffrentes reprsentent des produits diffrents), il est ncessaire dtablir un moyen appropri dagrgation, dans ce cas  laide dune unit montaire. Un moyen simple de permettre lagrgation consiste  reflter les multiples extrants produits par une mme exploitation en termes de valeurs (c.--d. la quantit multiplie par les prix). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Superficie des terres agricoles : dfinie comme la superficie des terres utilises pour lagriculture au sein de la ferme&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-3&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critres de durabilit : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distance par rapport au 90&lt;sup&gt;e&lt;/sup&gt; centile de la distribution nationale&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-4&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-4&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vert (souhaitable) : la valeur du sous-indicateur est &amp;#x2265; 2/3 du 90&lt;sup&gt;e&lt;/sup&gt; centile correspondant&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jaune (acceptable) : la valeur du sous-indicateur est &amp;#x2265; 1/3 et &amp;lt; 2/3 du 90&lt;sup&gt;e&lt;/sup&gt; centile correspondant&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rouge (non durable) : la valeur du sous-indicateur est &amp;lt; 1/3 du 90&lt;sup&gt;e&lt;/sup&gt; centile correspondant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lments de donnes :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Priode de rfrence : dernire anne civile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Quantits et prix  la ferme (ou valeur de la production) des 5 principales cultures et/ou produits animaux et sous-produits produits par lexploitation&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Quantits et prix  la ferme (ou valeur de la production) dautres produits agricoles (produits agroforestiers ou aquacoles, etc.) produits par lexploitation&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Superficie des terres agricoles de lexploitation&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Revenu agricole net&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension :&lt;/strong&gt; conomique&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thme :&lt;/strong&gt; rentabilit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Une partie importante de la durabilit de lagriculture est la viabilit conomique de lexploitation, tire dans une large mesure par sa rentabilit. La rentabilit est mesure  laide du revenu net que lagriculteur est en mesure de tirer des oprations agricoles. La disponibilit et lutilisation de linformation sur la performance conomique des exploitations agricoles, mesure  laide de la rentabilit, favoriseront une meilleure prise de dcision tant au niveau microconomique que macro-conomique. tant donn que les mesures du rendement dterminent le comportement, une meilleure information sur le rendement peut modifier le comportement et la prise de dcisions du gouvernement et des producteurs, tant dans l&apos;agriculture commerciale  grande chelle que dans l&apos;agriculture de subsistance  petite et moyenne chelle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Couverture : &lt;/strong&gt;tous les types d&apos;exploitations agricoles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le sous-indicateur mesure si l&apos;exploitation est constamment rentable sur une priode de trois ans. Ce sous-indicateur se concentre sur le revenu des oprations agricoles plutt que sur le revenu total du mnage agricole, qui peut inclure d&apos;autres sources de revenus comme, par exemple, l&apos;emploi d&apos;autres membres de la famille dans des entreprises locales, le tourisme, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Formule&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-5&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-5&quot;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;A&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;M&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;msub&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;Y&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;k&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/msub&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;-&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;D&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;E&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;-&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;A&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;m&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;V&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;V&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;S&lt;/mi&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;o :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RAN = Revenu agricole net&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RM = Recettes montaires agricoles totales, y compris les paiements directs de programmes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Y&lt;sub&gt;k&lt;/sub&gt; = Revenu en nature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DE = Dpenses totales d&apos;exploitation aprs remises (y compris les cots de la main-d&apos;uvre)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amo = Amortissements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;VVS = Valeur de la variation des stocks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dfinitions :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Le revenu agricole net dsigne la rmunration (montaire et non montaire) des exploitants agricoles pour leur travail, leur gestion et leur capital, aprs paiement de toutes les dpenses de production (c&apos;est--dire le revenu agricole brut moins les dpenses de production). Il comprend le revenu net de la production agricole, la valeur des produits consomms sur l&apos;exploitation, la dprciation et les variations de stocks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Le revenu agricole brut dsigne les revenus montaires et non montaires perus par l&apos;exploitation. Ses principales composantes comprennent les recettes montaires provenant de la vente de produits agricoles, les paiements directs de programmes aux producteurs, les autres revenus agricoles (tels que les revenus du travail  forfait), la valeur des aliments et du carburant produits et consomms sur la mme exploitation, et la variation de la valeur des stocks de fin d&apos;anne des cultures et du btail&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-6&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-6&quot;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les recettes montaires agricoles comprennent les recettes provenant de la vente de produits agricoles en units montaires locales qui incluent les ventes de cultures, de btail et de ses sous-produits.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les paiements directs de programmes aux producteurs inclus dans les recettes montaires agricoles reprsentent les montants verss dans le cadre de divers programmes gouvernementaux et privs aux personnes impliques dans la production agricole. Les paiements lis  la production agricole courante comprennent les subventions visant  encourager la production ou  compenser les producteurs pour les faibles rendements du march, les paiements visant  stabiliser les revenus et les paiements visant  compenser les producteurs pour les pertes de rcoltes ou de btail causes par des conditions climatiques extrmes, des maladies ou d&apos;autres raisons et les paiements d&apos;assurance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Le revenu en nature mesure la valeur des biens agricoles produits dans les exploitations agricoles et consomms par les familles des exploitants agricoles. Il est inclus pour mesurer la production agricole totale.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les dpenses d&apos;exploitation reprsentent les cots commerciaux encourus par les entreprises agricoles pour les biens et services utiliss dans le processus de production. Les dpenses comprennent  la fois les achats et la propre production,  savoir : les impts fonciers, le travail  forfait, les semences, le loyer, les engrais et la chaux, les produits chimiques, les rparations des machines et des btiments, l&apos;irrigation, le carburant pour le chauffage et les machines, les salaires, les intrts et la part de l&apos;entreprise dans les primes d&apos;assurance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les charges d&apos;amortissement tiennent compte de la dprciation conomique ou de la perte de la juste valeur marchande des immobilisations de l&apos;entreprise agricole. Calcule sur les btiments agricoles, les machines agricoles et la part de l&apos;entreprise agricole dans les automobiles, les camions et la maison de ferme, la dprciation est gnralement considre comme le rsultat du vieillissement, de l&apos;usure et de l&apos;obsolescence. Elle reprsente une diminution des avantages conomiques potentiels qui peuvent tre gnrs par l&apos;immobilisation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La valeur de la variation des stocks (VVS) mesure la valeur montaire de la variation physique des stocks appartenant aux producteurs. Ce concept est utilis pour valuer la production conomique agricole totale. Pour calculer la VIC, la variation des stocks appartenant aux producteurs (entre la fin et le dbut d&apos;une anne civile) est d&apos;abord calcule, puis multiplie par les prix annuels moyens des cultures ou la valeur par animal. Ce calcul est diffrent de l&apos;approche de la valeur comptable financire ou comptable, qui value les stocks de dbut et de fin, puis en dduit la variation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La VVS pour tous les principaux produits de base peut varier considrablement (en fonction de l&apos;ampleur de la variation des stocks et des prix). La VVS peut tre positive (lorsque les stocks sont plus importants  la fin de l&apos;anne par rapport aux niveaux du dbut de l&apos;anne) ou ngative (lorsque les stocks de fin d&apos;anne sont infrieurs aux niveaux du dbut de l&apos;anne). Si les niveaux de stocks sont les mmes au dbut et  la fin de l&apos;anne, la VVS sera nulle malgr les variations de prix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;estimation de la rentabilit au niveau d&apos;une exploitation agricole ncessite gnralement la compilation des registres financiers de base de l&apos;exploitation, c.--d. les transactions quotidiennes, hebdomadaires, mensuelles ou saisonnires de manire organise. En gnral, les grandes exploitations commerciales tiennent des registres financiers dtaills, mais dans le cas des exploitations d&apos;agriculture de subsistance  moyenne et petite chelle, la tenue de registres est rarement pratique et dans la plupart des pays, elle n&apos;existe pas du tout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dans le cas o des donnes dtailles ne sont pas disponibles au niveau de l&apos;exploitation, les estimations seront calcules sur la base des dclarations des agriculteurs concernant les quantits et les prix des produits et des intrants. Dans ces cas, la dprciation, la variation des stocks et les taxes peuvent tre ngliges. Ceci est dcrit ci-dessous comme l&apos;option simplifie (1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Une option simplifie (2) est galement propose, base sur la dclaration de l&apos;agriculteur concernant la rentabilit de l&apos;exploitation agricole au cours des trois dernires annes civiles. Il est recommand d&apos;utiliser cette option simplifie uniquement lorsque les deux autres options ne sont pas ralisables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critres de durabilit : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour qu&apos;une exploitation agricole soit rentable, le revenu agricole net doit tre plus grand que zro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vert (souhaitable) : plus grand que zro pour les trois dernires annes conscutives&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jaune (acceptable) : plus grand que zro pour au moins une des trois dernires annes conscutives&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rouge (non durable) : plus petit que zro pour l&apos;ensemble des trois dernires annes conscutives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lments de donnes :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Priode de rfrence : les trois dernires annes civiles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Option recommande :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les donnes des registres financiers de l&apos;exploitation, c.--d. les transactions quotidiennes, hebdomadaires, mensuelles ou saisonnires, sont recueillies de manire organise (en gnral, les grandes exploitations commerciales tiennent des registres financiers dtaills sur la base desquels le NFI peut tre calcul selon l&apos;quation ci-dessus).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Option simplifie (1) :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; utiliser lorsque les donnes dtailles ne sont pas disponibles au niveau de l&apos;exploitation (mieux adapte aux petits exploitants et au secteur des mnages).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quantit produite (c.--d. les cultures et le btail, ainsi que leurs produits et sous-produits, destins au march ou  l&apos;autoconsommation)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prix  la ferme des quantits produites ci-dessus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Frais d&apos;exploitation, y compris les quantits d&apos;intrants et leurs prix de march&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quantit/rendement des autres activits menes dans l&apos;exploitation et/ou des produits fabriqus dans l&apos;exploitation, p. ex. l&apos;aquaculture, l&apos;agroforesterie et autres&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prix  la ferme des autres activits/ produits de base de l&apos;exploitation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quantits et prix des intrants utiliss pour produire d&apos;autres extrants sur l&apos;exploitation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Option simplifie (2) :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dclaration du rpondant sur la rentabilit de l&apos;exploitation agricole au cours des 3 dernires annes civiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Mcanismes d&apos;attnuation des risques&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension : &lt;/strong&gt;conomique&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thme : &lt;/strong&gt;rsilience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La rsilience englobe les capacits d&apos;absorption, d&apos;anticipation et d&apos;adaptation et se rfre aux proprits d&apos;un systme qui permet aux exploitations de faire face aux chocs et aux stress, de persister et de continuer  bien fonctionner (dans le sens de fournir de la stabilit, des rgles prvisibles, de la scurit et d&apos;autres avantages  ses membres).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Couverture : &lt;/strong&gt;tous les types d&apos;exploitations agricoles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ce sous-indicateur mesure l&apos;incidence des mcanismes d&apos;attnuation suivants : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accs au crdit ou recours au crdit&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-7&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-7&quot;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accs  l&apos;assurance ou recours  celle-ci&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Diversification au sein de l&apos;exploitation (part d&apos;un seul produit agricole ne dpassant pas 66% de la valeur totale de la production de l&apos;exploitation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;accs au crdit et/ou  l&apos;assurance est dfini ici comme la disponibilit d&apos;un service donn et le fait que le dtenteur dispose de moyens suffisants pour obtenir ce service (documents requis, garanties, antcdents de crdit positifs, etc.). En gnral, l&apos;accs  un ou plusieurs des trois facteurs ci-dessus permettra  l&apos;exploitation de prvenir, de rsister, de s&apos;adapter et de se remettre des chocs externes tels que les inondations, les scheresses, les dfaillances du march (p. ex., les chocs de prix), les chocs climatiques et les maladies animales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critre de durabilit : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Une exploitation agricole est considre comme rsiliente si elle a utilis ou a les moyens d&apos;accder aux mcanismes d&apos;attnuation des risques comme suit :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vert (souhaitable) : Accs ou utilisation d&apos;au moins deux des mcanismes d&apos;attnuation des risques numrs ci-dessus.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jaune (acceptable) : Accs ou utilisation d&apos;au moins un des mcanismes d&apos;attnuation numrs ci-dessus.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rouge (non durable) : Aucun accs aux mcanismes d&apos;attnuation numrs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lments de donnes :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Priode de rfrence : dernire anne civile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.1. Exploitation agricole ayant accs ou ayant eu recours au crdit,  l&apos;assurance ou  d&apos;autres instruments financiers :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Crdit (formel et informel) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assurance &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.2 Liste des autres activits agricoles en dehors des cultures et de l&apos;levage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.3 Valeur de la production pour les activits/produits numrs de l&apos;exploitation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Prvalence de dtrioration des sols&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension : &lt;/strong&gt;environnementale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thme : &lt;/strong&gt;sant des sols &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De nombreux processus affectant la sant des sols sont dtermins par les pratiques agricoles. La FAO et le Groupe technique intergouvernemental sur les sols (ITPS) ont identifi 10 menaces principales pour les fonctions du sol : rosion du sol, pertes de carbone organique du sol, dsquilibre des nutriments, acidification, contamination, engorgement, compactage, impermabilisation du sol, salinisation et perte de biodiversit du sol. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Couverture : &lt;/strong&gt;tous les types d&apos;exploitations agricoles &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ce sous-indicateur mesure la mesure dans laquelle les activits agricoles affectent la sant des sols et reprsente donc un problme de durabilit. L&apos;examen des dix menaces pesant sur les sols montre que toutes sauf une (l&apos;impermabilisation des sols, qui est la perte de sols naturels au profit de la construction/urbanisation) sont potentiellement et principalement affectes par des pratiques agricoles inappropries. Dans l&apos;idal, il faudrait donc que tous les sols situs sous la surface agricole d&apos;un pays fassent l&apos;objet d&apos;une surveillance priodique afin d&apos;valuer l&apos;impact de l&apos;agriculture sur les sols. Cela ncessite des enqutes et des campagnes d&apos;chantillonnage dtailles, associes  des tests en laboratoire. Afin de proposer une solution grable tout en capturant les principales tendances du pays en termes de sant des sols, l&apos;enqute agricole se concentre sur les quatre menaces qui combinent les caractristiques les plus rpandues (pour la surveillance nationale, les pays peuvent choisir d&apos;ajouter l&apos;un des autres domaines indiqus ci-dessus, en fonction de la pertinence), et les plus faciles  valuer par le biais des enqutes agricoles :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;rosion des sols&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rduction de la fertilit du sol&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salinisation des terres irrigues&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engorgement&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Autre  Prcisez &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;enqute agricole permet de saisir les connaissances des agriculteurs sur la situation de l&apos;exploitation agricole en termes de dgradation des sols. L&apos;exprience a montr que les agriculteurs sont trs conscients de l&apos;tat de leurs sols, de leur sant et de leur niveau de dgradation. Les agriculteurs peuvent galement avoir l&apos;opportunit de mentionner d&apos;autres menaces que les quatre ci-dessus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D&apos;autres sources de donnes sur la sant des sols peuvent soit complter les informations collectes par l&apos;enqute agricole et offrir des possibilits de recoupement des rponses des agriculteurs, soit tre utilises comme sources alternatives de donnes. Avant l&apos;enqute agricole, une tude documentaire pourrait recueillir toutes les informations disponibles sur la sant des sols, notamment en utilisant les statistiques officielles nationales ou les statistiques disponibles auprs d&apos;agences internationales telles que la FAO. Il s&apos;agit gnralement de cartes, de modles, de rsultats d&apos;chantillonnage des sols, d&apos;analyses en laboratoire et d&apos;enqutes sur le terrain, ainsi que de tous les rapports existants sur la dtrioration des sols et des terres au niveau national. Sur la base de ces informations, des cartes ou des tableaux (selon les frontires administratives ou d&apos;autres divisions du pays) peuvent tre tablis, montrant les menaces pesant sur les sols selon les 4 catgories de menaces ci-dessus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critres de durabilit : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportion de la surface agricole de l&apos;exploitation affecte par la dtrioration des sols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vert (souhaitable) : La superficie combine affecte par l&apos;une des quatre menaces slectionnes pour la sant des sols est ngligeable (moins de 10% de la surface agricole totale de l&apos;exploitation).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jaune (acceptable) : La superficie combine affecte par l&apos;une des quatre menaces slectionnes pour la sant des sols se situe entre 10 % et 50 % de la superficie agricole totale de l&apos;exploitation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rouge (non durable) : La superficie combine affecte par l&apos;une des quatre menaces slectionnes pour la sant des sols est suprieure  50 % de la superficie agricole totale de l&apos;exploitation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lments de donnes :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Priode de rfrence : trois dernires annes civiles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.1 Liste des menaces de dtrioration des sols subies par l&apos;exploitation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;rosion du sol (perte de la couche arable par rosion olienne ou hydrique)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rduction de la fertilit des sols&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-8&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-8&quot;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salinisation des terres irrigues&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engorgement&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Autre  Prcisez&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aucun des lments ci-dessus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.2 Surface totale de l&apos;exploitation affecte par des menaces lies  la dgradation du sol&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Variation de la disponibilit en eau&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension : &lt;/strong&gt;environnementale &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thme : &lt;/strong&gt;utilisation de l&apos;eau &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;agriculture, et plus particulirement l&apos;agriculture irrigue, est de loin le principal secteur conomique utilisant les ressources en eau douce. Dans de nombreux endroits, le prlvement d&apos;eau dans les rivires et les aquifres souterrains dpasse ce qui peut tre considr comme cologiquement durable. Cette situation affecte  la fois les rivires et les aquifres souterrains. L&apos;agriculture durable exige donc que ce niveau d&apos;utilisation de l&apos;eau douce pour l&apos;irrigation reste dans des limites acceptables. Bien qu&apos;il n&apos;existe pas de normes internationalement reconnues en matire d&apos;utilisation durable de l&apos;eau, les signaux associs  une utilisation non durable de l&apos;eau comprennent gnralement la rduction progressive du niveau des eaux souterraines, l&apos;asschement des sources et des rivires, l&apos;augmentation des conflits entre les utilisateurs d&apos;eau.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Couverture : &lt;/strong&gt;tous les types d&apos;exploitations agricoles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ce sous-indicateur saisit la mesure dans laquelle l&apos;agriculture contribue  des modles non durables d&apos;utilisation de l&apos;eau. Idalement, le niveau de durabilit de l&apos;utilisation de l&apos;eau est mesur  l&apos;chelle du bassin fluvial ou de l&apos;aquifre d&apos;eau souterraine, car c&apos;est l&apos;effet combin de tous les utilisateurs partageant la mme ressource qui a un impact sur la durabilit de l&apos;eau. L&apos;enqute agricole saisit la conscience et le comportement des agriculteurs par rapport  la pnurie d&apos;eau, et les associe  trois niveaux de durabilit. Cette prise de conscience et ce comportement sont exprims en termes de :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;si l&apos;agriculteur utilise l&apos;eau pour irriguer les cultures sur au moins 10% de la surperficie agricole de l&apos;exploitation et pourquoi, si la rponse est ngative (n&apos;en a pas besoin, ne peut se le permettre);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;si l&apos;agriculteur est conscient des problmes de disponibilit de l&apos;eau dans la zone de l&apos;exploitation et s&apos;il remarque une rduction de la disponibilit de l&apos;eau au fil du temps;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;s&apos;il existe des organisations (organisations d&apos;utilisateurs d&apos;eau, autres) charges de rpartir l&apos;eau entre les utilisateurs et dans quelle mesure ces organisations fonctionnent efficacement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D&apos;autres sources de donnes peuvent soit complter l&apos;enqute agricole  propos de l&apos;utilisation de l&apos;eau et offrir des possibilits de recoupement des rponses des agriculteurs, soit tre utilises comme sources alternatives de donnes. Avant l&apos;enqute agricole, une tude documentaire doit recueillir toutes les informations disponibles sur le bilan hydrique, y compris les statistiques officielles nationales ou les statistiques disponibles auprs d&apos;agences internationales telles que la FAO. Les informations sur les ressources en eau et leur utilisation sont gnralement recueillies par les entits charges de la gestion ou de la surveillance de l&apos;eau et sont organises par entit hydrologique (bassin fluvial ou aquifre souterrain). Elles comprennent gnralement des relevs hydrologiques (dbit des cours d&apos;eau, niveaux des eaux souterraines), des modles et des cartes montrant l&apos;tendue de l&apos;utilisation de l&apos;eau par entit hydrologique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critres de durabilit : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La durabilit de l&apos;exploitation agricole par rapport  l&apos;utilisation de l&apos;eau sera value comme suit : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vert (souhaitable) : la disponibilit de l&apos;eau reste stable au fil des ans, pour les exploitations irriguant des cultures sur plus de 10 % de la surperficie agricole de l&apos;exploitation. Rsultat par dfaut pour les exploitations qui irriguent moins de 10 % de leur surperficie agricole.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jaune (acceptable) : utilise l&apos;eau pour irriguer des cultures sur au moins 10 % de la superficie agricole de l&apos;exploitation, ne sait pas si la disponibilit de l&apos;eau reste stable au fil des ans, ou connat une rduction de la disponibilit de l&apos;eau au fil des ans, mais il existe une organisation qui rpartit efficacement l&apos;eau entre les utilisateurs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rouge (non durable) : dans tous les autres cas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lments de donnes :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Priode de rfrence : les trois dernires annes civiles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.1 Superficie agricole irrigue de l&apos;exploitation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.2 Rduction de la disponibilit de l&apos;eau subie par l&apos;exploitation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.3 Existence d&apos;organisations s&apos;occupant de l&apos;allocation de l&apos;eau &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Gestion des engrais&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension : &lt;/strong&gt;environnementale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thme : &lt;/strong&gt;risque de pollution par les engrais&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;agriculture peut affecter la qualit de l&apos;environnement par une utilisation excessive ou une gestion inadquate des engrais. L&apos;agriculture durable implique que le niveau des produits chimiques dans le sol et dans les masses d&apos;eau reste dans des seuils acceptables. La gestion intgre des nutriments vgtaux prend en compte toutes les sources de nutriments (minraux et organiques) et leur gestion afin d&apos;obtenir le meilleur quilibre nutritif. La mesure de la qualit des sols et de l&apos;eau permet de connatre l&apos;tendue et les causes de la pollution, mais la mise en place de systmes de surveillance des sols et de l&apos;eau est coteuse et n&apos;est pas toujours ralisable dans les pays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note : la gestion des lments nutritifs des plantes aborde deux questions de durabilit : viter la pollution et maintenir un bon niveau de fertilit des sols. Ce sous-indicateur traite de la premire question, tandis que la seconde est traite dans le sous-indicateur 4  Sant des sols . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Couverture : &lt;/strong&gt;tous les types d&apos;exploitations agricoles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;approche propose est base sur des questions poses aux agriculteurs concernant leur utilisation d&apos;engrais, en particulier d&apos;engrais minraux ou synthtiques et de fumier animal, leur connaissance des risques environnementaux associs aux applications d&apos;engrais et de fumier, et leur comportement en termes de gestion des lments nutritifs des plantes&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-9&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-9&quot;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Les mesures de gestion considres comme contribuant  rduire le risque sont les suivantes : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Suivre les protocoles selon les indications des services de vulgarisation ou des points de vente ou selon les rglementations locales, sans dpasser les doses recommandes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Utiliser une source organique d&apos;lments nutritifs (y compris le fumier ou les rsidus de compostage) seule, ou en combinaison avec des engrais synthtiques ou minraux&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Utiliser les lgumineuses comme culture de couverture ou comme composante d&apos;un systme de multiculture ou de pturage pour rduire les apports d&apos;engrais&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rpartir l&apos;application d&apos;engrais synthtique ou minral sur la priode de croissance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tenir compte du type de sol et du climat&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-10&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-10&quot;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; pour dcider des doses et des frquences d&apos;application des engrais&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Utiliser des chantillons de sol au moins tous les 5 ans pour effectuer les calculs du bilan nutritif &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Effectuer une gestion des lments nutritifs spcifique au site ou une agriculture de prcision&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-11&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-11&quot;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Utiliser des bandes tampons le long des cours d&apos;eau.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critres de durabilit : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La durabilit de l&apos;exploitation par rapport au risque de pollution par les engrais sera value comme suit :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vert (souhaitable) : L&apos;exploitation prend des mesures spcifiques pour attnuer les risques environnementaux (au moins quatre de la liste ci-dessus). Rsultat par dfaut pour les exploitations n&apos;utilisant pas d&apos;engrais &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-12&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-12&quot;&gt; [11] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jaune (acceptable) : L&apos;exploitation utilise des engrais et prend au moins deux mesures de la liste ci-dessus pour attnuer les risques environnementaux.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rouge (non durable) : L&apos;exploitation utilise des engrais et ne prend aucune des mesures spcifiques ci-dessus pour attnuer les risques environnementaux lis  leur utilisation. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lments de donnes :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Priode de rfrence : dernire anne civile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.1 Utilisation d&apos;engrais synthtiques ou minraux ou de fumier/fumier animal par l&apos;exploitation agricole (O/N)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.2 Mesures spcifiques prises pour attnuer les risques environnementaux lis  l&apos;utilisation excessive ou abusive d&apos;engrais, selon la liste ci-dessous : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Suivre les protocoles selon les instructions des services de vulgarisation ou des dtaillants ou les rglementations locales, sans dpasser les doses recommandes&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Utiliser une source organique d&apos;lments nutritifs (y compris le fumier ou les rsidus de compostage) seule, ou en combinaison avec des engrais synthtiques ou minraux &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Utiliser les lgumineuses comme culture de couverture ou comme composante d&apos;un systme de multiculture ou de pturage pour rduire les apports d&apos;engrais&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Rpartir l&apos;application d&apos;engrais synthtiques ou minraux sur la priode de croissance &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Tenir compte du type de sol et du climat pour dcider des doses et des frquences d&apos;application des engrais &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Utiliser l&apos;chantillonnage du sol au moins tous les 5 ans pour effectuer les calculs de bilan nutritif &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Effectuer une gestion des lments nutritifs spcifique au site ou une agriculture de prcision &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Utiliser des bandes tampons le long des cours d&apos;eau &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Gestion des pesticides&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension : &lt;/strong&gt;environnementale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thme : &lt;/strong&gt;risque des pesticides&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les pesticides sont des intrants importants dans l&apos;agriculture moderne (culture et levage), mais s&apos;ils ne sont pas bien grs, ils peuvent nuire  la sant des gens ou  l&apos;environnement. Il existe des pratiques associes  la lutte intgre contre les ravageurs (IPM&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-13&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-13&quot;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) qui contribuent  minimiser les risques lis  l&apos;utilisation des pesticides et  limiter leur impact sur la sant humaine et sur l&apos;environnement. Le Code international de conduite sur la gestion des pesticides dfinit les meilleures pratiques en matire de gestion des pesticides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Couverture : &lt;/strong&gt;tous les types d&apos;exploitations agricoles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le sous-indicateur propos est bas sur des informations relatives  l&apos;utilisation de pesticides dans les exploitations, au type de pesticide utilis et au type de mesure(s) prise(s) pour attnuer les risques associs&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-14&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-14&quot;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Il envisage la possibilit que l&apos;exploitation utilise des pesticides dans le cadre d&apos;un programme de lutte intgre contre les parasites (IPM), ou adopte des mesures spcifiques pour contribuer  rduire les risques lis  l&apos;utilisation de pesticides. Liste des mesures possibles : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sant :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Respect du mode d&apos;emploi des pesticides figurant sur l&apos;tiquette (y compris l&apos;utilisation d&apos;quipements de protection lors de l&apos;application de pesticides)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Entretien et nettoyage de l&apos;quipement de protection aprs utilisation &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elimination sre des dchets (cartons, bouteilles et sacs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environment :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Respect du mode d&apos;emploi de l&apos;tiquette pour l&apos;application du pesticide &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adopter l&apos;une des bonnes pratiques suivantes : ajuster la priode de plantation, appliquer l&apos;espacement des cultures, la rotation des cultures, la culture mixte ou l&apos;interculture &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Effectuer une lutte biologique contre les parasites ou utiliser des biopesticides &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adopter la rotation des pturages pour supprimer les populations de parasites du btail &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;liminer systmatiquement les parties de la plante attaques par les ravageurs &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Entretien et nettoyage du matriel de pulvrisation aprs utilisation &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;N&apos;utiliser un pesticide pas plus de deux fois ou en mlange au cours d&apos;une saison pour viter la rsistance aux pesticides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critres de durabilit : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La durabilit de l&apos;exploitation en ce qui concerne les pesticides sera value comme suit : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vert (souhaitable) : L&apos;exploitation n&apos;utilise que des pesticides modrment ou lgrement dangereux &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-15&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-15&quot;&gt; [14] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; (classe II ou III de l&apos;OMS). Dans ce cas, elle respecte les trois mesures lies  la sant et au moins quatre des mesures lies  l&apos;environnement. Rsultat par dfaut pour les exploitations n&apos;utilisant pas de pesticides. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jaune (acceptable) : L&apos;exploitation n&apos;utilise que des pesticides modrment ou lgrement dangereux (classe II ou III de l&apos;OMS) et prend quelques mesures pour attnuer les risques pour l&apos;environnement et la sant (au moins deux de chacune des listes ci-dessus).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rouge (non durable) : L&apos;exploitation utilise des pesticides hautement ou extrmement dangereux (classe Ia ou Ib de l&apos;OMS), des pesticides illgaux &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-16&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-16&quot;&gt; [15] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt;, ou utilise des pesticides modrment ou lgrement dangereux sans prendre de mesures spcifiques pour attnuer les risques environnementaux ou sanitaires lis  leur utilisation (moins de deux de chacune des listes ci-dessus). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lments de donnes :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Priode de rfrence : dernire anne civile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7.1 Utilisation de pesticides pour les cultures ou le btail par l&apos;exploitation agricole (O/N) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7.2 Utilisation de pesticides trs ou extrmement dangereux par l&apos;exploitation agricole (O/N) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7.3 Mesures prises pour protger les personnes contre les risques sanitaires lis aux pesticides : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Respect du mode d&apos;emploi des pesticides figurant sur l&apos;tiquette, y compris l&apos;utilisation d&apos;quipements de protection individuelle (O/N) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Entretien et nettoyage de l&apos;quipement de protection aprs utilisation (O/N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elimination sre des dchets (cartons, bouteilles et sacs) (O/N) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7.4 Mesures prises pour viter les risques environnementaux lis aux pesticides : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Respect du mode d&apos;emploi de l&apos;tiquette pour l&apos;application du pesticide (O/N) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ajustement de la priode de plantation (O/N) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application de l&apos;espacement des cultures (O/N) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application de la rotation des cultures (O/N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application de la polyculture (O/N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application de l&apos;interculture (O/N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Effectuer une lutte biologique contre les nuisibles (O/N) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Utilisation de biopesticides (O/N) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adopter la rotation des pturages pour supprimer les populations de parasites du btail (O/N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;limination systmatique des parties de la plante attaques par les ravageurs (O/N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Entretien et nettoyage du matriel de pulvrisation aprs utilisation (O/N)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Utiliser un pesticide au maximum deux fois ou en mlange dans une saison pour viter la rsistance aux pesticides (O/N)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Utilisation de pratiques propices  l&apos;agro-biodiversit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension : &lt;/strong&gt;environnementale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thme : &lt;/strong&gt;biodiversit &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Convention sur la diversit biologique (CDB) souligne la relation troite entre les activits agricoles et la biodiversit, en considrant trois niveaux de biodiversit : la diversit au niveau gntique; l&apos;agrobiodiversit au niveau du systme de production; et la biodiversit au niveau de l&apos;cosystme (sauvage). La faon dont l&apos;agriculture est pratique influence ces trois niveaux. Les tentatives de dveloppement d&apos;indicateurs de biodiversit pour l&apos;agriculture considrent systmatiquement un grand nombre de sous-indicateurs, sans critres de durabilit universellement reconnus. Compte tenu de ces contraintes, et de l&apos;importance d&apos;aborder la biodiversit dans la construction de l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1, il est propos de dvelopper un sous-indicateur qui reflte les efforts vers une agriculture plus durable qui contribue mieux  la biodiversit, en identifiant une liste limite de pratiques qui sont favorables  la conservation de la biodiversit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Couverture : &lt;/strong&gt;tous les types d&apos;exploitations agricoles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ce sous-indicateur mesure le niveau d&apos;adoption de pratiques agricoles plus durables qui contribuent davantage  la biodiversit de l&apos;exploitation aux niveaux de l&apos;cosystme, des espces et de la gntique. Cet indicateur concerne  la fois les cultures et le btail. Plus prcisment, dans le cas de ce sous-indicateur, le champ d&apos;application est l&apos;ensemble de la zone de l&apos;exploitation agricole, par opposition  la zone agricole qui est utilise pour les 10 autres sous-indicateurs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En particulier, deux systmes de notation distincts en fonction de l&apos;applicabilit du critre de l&apos;agriculture biologique ont t proposs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selon l&apos;existence ou non d&apos;un systme de certification biologique, les pays choisiront l&apos;un des deux ensembles de critres proposs ci-dessous et seront donc valus/nots diffremment en termes de leur statut de durabilit. Selon cette formulation, pour obtenir le statut vert, les exploitations des pays ayant mis en place une certification biologique devront satisfaire 3 des 6 critres. Au contraire, les exploitations oprant dans des pays o aucune certification biologique n&apos;est en place, devront satisfaire 2 des 5 critres pour obtenir le statut vert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La formulation dtaille des critres pour les 2 systmes de notation est dcrite ci-dessous :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critres pour le groupe de pays ayant des systmes de certification biologique :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;L&apos;exploitation laisse au moins 10% de sa superficie agricole  la vgtation naturelle ou diversifie. Il peut s&apos;agir de pturages naturels, de bandes de fleurs sauvages, de tas de pierres et de bois, d&apos;arbres ou de haies, d&apos;tangs naturels ou de zones humides. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;L&apos;exploitation produit des produits agricoles certifis biologiques ou ses produits sont en cours de certification. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;L&apos;exploitation n&apos;utilise pas d&apos;antimicrobiens mdicalement importants comme facteurs de croissance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Au moins deux des lments suivants contribuent  la production agricole : 1) cultures temporaires, 2) pturages, 3) cultures permanentes, 4) arbres sur la ferme, 5) btail ou produits animaux, et 6) aquaculture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;L&apos;exploitation pratique une rotation des cultures ou des cultures/pturages impliquant au moins 2 cultures, ou des cultures/pturages sur au moins 80% de sa surperficie agricole ( l&apos;exclusion des cultures permanentes et des pturages permanents) sur une priode de 3 ans. Dans le cas d&apos;une rotation de deux cultures, les deux cultures doivent appartenir  des genres vgtaux diffrents, p. ex., une gramine et une lgumineuse, ou une gramine et un tubercule, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Le btail comprend des races adaptes localement&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-17&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-17&quot;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critres de durabilit :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vert (souhaitable) : L&apos;exploitation agricole rpond  au moins trois des critres ci-dessus &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jaune (acceptable) : L&apos;exploitation agricole rpond  un ou deux des critres ci-dessus &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rouge (non durable) : L&apos;exploitation agricole ne rpond  aucun des critres ci-dessus &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critres pour le groupe de pays n&apos;ayant pas de systmes de certification biologique :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;L&apos;exploitation laisse au moins 10% de sa superficie agricole  la vgtation naturelle ou diversifie. Il peut s&apos;agir de pturages naturels, de bandes de fleurs sauvages, de tas de pierres et de bois, d&apos;arbres ou de haies, d&apos;tangs naturels ou de zones humides. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;L&apos;exploitation n&apos;utilise pas d&apos;antimicrobiens mdicalement importants comme facteurs de croissance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Au moins deux des lments suivants contribuent  la production agricole : 1) les cultures temporaires, 2) les pturages, 3) les cultures permanentes, 4) les arbres de la ferme, 5) le btail ou les produits animaux, et 6) l&apos;aquaculture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;L&apos;exploitation pratique une rotation de cultures ou de cultures/pturages impliquant au moins 2 cultures ou des cultures/pturages sur au moins 80% de sa superficie cultive ( l&apos;exclusion des cultures permanentes et des pturages permanents) sur une priode de 3 ans. Dans le cas d&apos;une rotation de deux cultures, les deux cultures doivent appartenir  des genres vgtaux diffrents, p. ex., une gramine et une lgumineuse, ou une gramine et un tubercule, etc. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Le btail comprend des races adaptes localement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critres de durabilit :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vert (souhaitable) : L&apos;exploitation agricole rpond  au moins deux des critres ci-dessus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jaune (acceptable) : L&apos;exploitation agricole rpond  un des critres ci-dessus &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rouge (non durable) : L&apos;exploitation agricole ne rpond  aucun des critres ci-dessus &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lments de donnes :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Priode de rfrence : dernire anne civile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.1 Pourcentage de la superficie de l&apos;exploitation couverte par une vgtation naturelle ou diversifie (non cultive), y compris les pturages naturels ou les prairies, les bandes de fleurs sauvages, les tas de pierres ou de bois, les arbres ou les haies, les tangs naturels ou les zones humides&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.2 Produits agricoles (cultures et/ou btail) certifis biologiques (O/N) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.3 Produits agricoles (cultures et/ou btail) en cours de certification biologique (O/N)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.4 Indiquer le numro de certification biologique de l&apos;exploitation &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.5 Indiquer le nom de l&apos;organisme de certification biologique &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.6 Superficie sur laquelle les [CULTURES/LEVAGES] certifis biologiques ont t produits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.7 Utilisation d&apos;antimicrobiens mdicalement importants comme stimulateur de croissance pour le btail (O/N) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.8 Valeur de la production de l&apos;exploitation (couverte par le sous-indicateur 1) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cultures temporaires &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pturages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cultures permanentes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arbres sur la ferme &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Btail et produits d&apos;origine animale &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aquaculture &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.9 Pourcentage de la superficie cultive sur laquelle une rotation des cultures ou une rotation de cultures et de pturages impliquant au moins deux cultures ( l&apos;exclusion des cultures permanentes et des pturages permanents) de diffrents genres de plantes est pratique sur une priode de 3 ans&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.10 Superficie de l&apos;exploitation agricole couverte par les (jusqu&apos; 5) cultures principales numres pour le sous-indicateur 1 ( l&apos;exclusion des pturages)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.11 Liste des diffrentes races et croisements et pourcentage d&apos;animaux qu&apos;ils reprsentent pour chaque espce animale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Taux de rmunration en agriculture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension : &lt;/strong&gt;sociale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thme : &lt;/strong&gt;emploi dcent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le thme fournit des informations sur la rmunration des salaris travaillant pour l&apos;exploitation et appartenant au groupe de professions lmentaires, tel que dfini par la Classification internationale type des professions (CITP-08 - code 92). Il informe sur les risques conomiques encourus par les travailleurs non qualifis (ceux qui effectuent des tches simples et routinires) en termes de rmunration perue, cette dernire tant compare au salaire minimum fix au niveau national dans le secteur agricole. Ce sous-indicateur permet de distinguer les exploitations qui versent une rmunration quitable  leurs employs appartenant au groupe des professions lmentaires et celles qui leur versent une rmunration infrieure  la norme du salaire minimum. Dans ce dernier cas, les exploitations agricoles sont considres comme non viables car la rmunration verse n&apos;est pas suffisante pour assurer un niveau de vie dcent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Couverture : &lt;/strong&gt;ne s&apos;applique pas aux exploitations qui n&apos;emploient que de la main-d&apos;uvre familiale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le sous-indicateur mesure le taux de salaire journalier de la main d&apos;oeuvre non qualifie de l&apos;exploitation agricole en units montaires locales (UML). &lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;T&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;x&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;j&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;v&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;q&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;C&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;m&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;T&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;v&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;*&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;8&lt;/mn&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;o la compensation est  la fois montaire et en nature et exprime en units montaires locales (UML)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critres de durabilit :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La taux de rmunration de la main-d&apos;uvre non qualifie par rapport salaire minimum national ou du secteur agricole. S&apos;il n&apos;existe pas de salaire minimum national ou du secteur agricole, le seuil de pauvret national est utilis  la place : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vert (souhaitable) : si le taux de rmunration pay  la main-d&apos;uvre non qualifie est suprieur au salaire minimum national ou au salaire minimum du secteur agricole (si disponible). Rsultat par dfaut pour les exploitations n&apos;embauchant pas de main-d&apos;uvre. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jaune (acceptable) : si le taux de rmunration pay  la main-d&apos;uvre non qualifie est gal au salaire minimum national ou au salaire minimum du secteur agricole (si disponible). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rouge (non durable) : si le taux de rmunration pay  la main-d&apos;uvre non qualifie est infrieur au salaire minimum national ou au salaire minimum du secteur agricole (si disponible). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lments de donnes :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Priode de rfrence : dernire anne civile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9.1 Travailleurs non qualifis embauchs dans l&apos;exploitation agricole (O/N)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9.2 Rmunration moyenne en espces et/ou en nature verse  l&apos;ouvrier non qualifi engag par jour (de 8 heures)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9.3 Salaire minimum dans le secteur agricole (si disponible) ou salaire minimum national &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. chelle de scurit alimentaire fonde sur l&apos;exprience (FIES)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension : &lt;/strong&gt;sociale &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thme : &lt;/strong&gt;scurit alimentaire &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La FIES est une mesure de la gravit de l&apos;inscurit alimentaire au niveau des mnages qui repose sur les rponses directes (oui/non) des personnes  huit questions simples concernant leur accs  une alimentation adquate. Il s&apos;agit d&apos;une chelle de mesure statistique similaire  d&apos;autres chelles statistiques largement acceptes, conues pour mesurer des traits inobservables tels que l&apos;aptitude/l&apos;intelligence, la personnalit et un large ventail de conditions sociales, psychologiques et lies  la sant. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Couverture : &lt;/strong&gt;uniquement les exploitations agricoles familiales &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;chelle de scurit alimentaire fonde sur l&apos;exprience (FIES) permet de mesurer la gravit de l&apos;inscurit alimentaire vcue par des individus ou des mnages,  partir d&apos;entretiens directs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les questions de la FIES portent sur les expriences du rpondant ou de son mnage dans son ensemble. Les questions se concentrent sur les comportements et expriences autodclars lis  l&apos;alimentation et associs  des difficults croissantes d&apos;accs  la nourriture en raison de contraintes de ressources. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La FIES est drive de deux chelles largement utilises de scurit alimentaire fondes sur l&apos;exprience : le module d&apos;enqute sur la scurit alimentaire des mnages des tats-Unis et l&apos;chelle de scurit alimentaire de l&apos;Amrique latine et des Carabes (acronyme espagnol ELCSA). Il s&apos;agit d&apos;un ensemble de huit questions courtes de type oui/non poses directement aux personnes. Les questions portent sur les comportements et les expriences lis  l&apos;alimentation, rapports par les personnes elles-mmes et associs  des difficults croissantes d&apos;accs  la nourriture en raison de contraintes de ressources. La FIES est base sur une construction bien fonde de l&apos;exprience de l&apos;inscurit alimentaire compose de trois domaines : incertitude/anxit, changements dans la qualit de la nourriture et changements dans la quantit de nourriture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ce sous-indicateur est l&apos;indicateur 2.1.2 des ODD, contextualis pour une enqute agricole. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critres de durabilit : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Niveau sur l&apos;chelle FIES&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vert (souhaitable) : inscurit alimentaire lgre&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-18&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-18&quot;&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
  &lt;li&gt;Jaune (acceptable)&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-19&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-19&quot;&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; : inscurit alimentaire modre &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rouge (non durable) : inscurit alimentaire grave &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lments de donnes :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Priode de rfrence : 12 derniers mois&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10.1 Le rpondant se souvient qu&apos;il/elle (ou tout autre adulte du mnage) s&apos;est inquit(e) de ne pas avoir assez  manger par manque d&apos;argent ou d&apos;autres ressources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10.2 Le rpondant se souvient qu&apos;il/elle (ou tout adulte du mnage) n&apos;a pas pu manger des aliments sains et nutritifs par manque d&apos;argent ou d&apos;autres ressources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10.3 Le rpondant se souvient qu&apos;il/elle (ou tout adulte dans le mnage) n&apos;a mang que quelques types d&apos;aliments par manque d&apos;argent ou d&apos;autres ressources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10.4 Le rpondant se souvient qu&apos;il/elle (ou tout adulte dans le mnage) a d sauter un repas parce qu&apos;il n&apos;y avait pas assez d&apos;argent ou d&apos;autres ressources pour la nourriture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10.5 Le rpondant se souvient qu&apos;il/elle (ou tout adulte du mnage) a mang moins qu&apos;il/elle ne pensait qu&apos;il/elle devrait en raison du manque d&apos;argent ou d&apos;autres ressources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10.6 Le rpondant se souvient que son mnage a manqu de nourriture  cause d&apos;un manque d&apos;argent ou d&apos;autres ressources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10.7 Le rpondant se souvient qu&apos;il/elle (ou tout adulte du mnage) a eu faim mais n&apos;a pas mang  cause du manque d&apos;argent ou d&apos;autres ressources pour la nourriture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10.8 Le rpondant se souvient qu&apos;il/elle (ou tout adulte du mnage) n&apos;a pas mang pendant toute une journe en raison d&apos;un manque d&apos;argent ou d&apos;autres ressources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11. Droits fonciers srs (garantis)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimension: &lt;/strong&gt;sociale &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thme: &lt;/strong&gt;occupation des terres &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ce sous-indicateur permet d&apos;valuer la durabilit en termes de droits d&apos;utilisation des terres agricoles. Les terres agricoles tant un intrant cl pour la production agricole, le fait de disposer de droits srs sur les terres garantit que l&apos;exploitation agricole contrle cet actif cl et ne risque pas de perdre les terres utilises par l&apos;exploitation pour l&apos;agriculture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il est prouv que les agriculteurs ont tendance  tre moins productifs s&apos;ils ont un accs et un contrle limits aux ressources et services conomiques, en particulier la terre. Les ingalits de longue date en matire de ressources conomiques et financires ont dsavantag certains agriculteurs par rapport  d&apos;autres dans leur capacit  participer,  contribuer et  bnficier de processus de dveloppement plus larges. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ainsi, une distribution adquate des ressources conomiques, en particulier des terres, permet d&apos;assurer une croissance conomique quitable, contribue  l&apos;efficacit conomique et a un impact positif sur les rsultats cls du dveloppement, notamment la rduction de la pauvret, la scurit alimentaire et le bien-tre des mnages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ce sous-indicateur est l&apos;indicateur 5.a.1 des ODD, adapt  l&apos;indicateur 2.4.1 des ODD. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Couverture : &lt;/strong&gt;tous les types d&apos;exploitations agricoles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description : &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le sous-indicateur mesure la proprit ou les droits scuriss sur l&apos;utilisation des surperficies de terres agricoles en utilisant les critres suivants :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Document officiel dlivr par le registre foncier/l&apos;agence cadastrale &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nom du titulaire figurant comme propritaire/titulaire du droit d&apos;utilisation sur les documents lgalement reconnus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Droits de vendre l&apos;une des parcelles de l&apos;exploitation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Droits de lguer une partie quelconque de la parcelle de l&apos;exploitation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critres de durabilit : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Niveau de scurit de l&apos;accs  la terre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vert (souhaitable) : dispose d&apos;un document officiel portant le nom du dtenteur/de l&apos;exploitation, ou a le droit de vendre une partie de la parcelle de l&apos;exploitation, ou a le droit de lguer une partie de la parcelle de l&apos;exploitation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jaune (acceptable) : possde un document formel mme si le nom de l&apos;exploitant/de l&apos;exploitation n&apos;y figure pas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rouge (non durable) : aucune rponse positive  aucune des 4 questions ci-dessus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lments de donnes :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Priode de rfrence : dernire anne civile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11.1 Type de document officiel pour toute terre agricole de l&apos;exploitant/exploitation qu&apos;il dtient (alternativement possder, utiliser, occuper) dlivr par le registre foncier/l&apos;agence cadastrale&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Titre de proprit &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Certificat de tenure coutumire &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Certificat d&apos;occupation &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Testament enregistr ou certificat enregistr d&apos;acquisitions hrditaires &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Certificat enregistr de bail  perptuit /  long terme &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contrat de location enregistr &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Autre &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11.2 Nom de tout membre de l&apos;exploitation figurant comme propritaire ou dtenteur de droit d&apos;usage sur l&apos;un des documents lgalement reconnus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11.3 Le droit de l&apos;exploitant/de l&apos;exploitation de vendre l&apos;une des parcelles de l&apos;exploitation &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11.4 Le droit de l&apos;exploitant/de l&apos;exploitation de lguer une partie quelconque de la parcelle de l&apos;exploitation &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-3&quot;&gt;2 &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p&gt; Selon la classification SEEA-AFF et la classification du recensement agricole mondial 2020 &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-4&quot;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Le 90&lt;sup&gt;me&lt;/sup&gt; percentile et les seuils respectifs de 1/3 et 2/3 de la productivit sont calculs par systme de production principal (cultures, animaux, ou un mlange de cultures et d&apos;animaux ou, si possible, par grandes rgions agricoles du pays). Ensuite, la productivit de l&apos;exploitation individuelle est estime et compare aux seuils drivs des productivits d&apos;exploitations similaires. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-4&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-5&quot;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consulter le site de Statistique Canada au lien suivant : http://www.statcan.gc.ca/pub/21-010-x/21-010-x2014001-fra.pdf &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-5&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-6&quot;&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; La valeur locative des logements agricoles n&apos;est pas considre comme faisant partie du revenu agricole. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-6&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-7&quot;&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Inclure les prts en espces et les prts en nature (p. ex., les semences fournies par un autre agriculteur et rembourses avec une part de la rcolte, les semences, etc.) uniquement pour les investissements lis  l&apos;agriculture. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-7&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-8&quot;&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; La rduction de la fertilit du sol sera ressentie par les agriculteurs comme une rduction progressive du rendement et sera le rsultat d&apos;un bilan nutritif ngatif par lequel la quantit d&apos;application de nutriments (y compris par le biais d&apos;engrais minraux et organiques, de lgumineuses ou d&apos;engrais verts) est infrieure  la quantit qui est perdue et exporte par les cultures. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-8&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-9&quot;&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Afin de garder le questionnaire grable, le module ne prend pas en compte les diffrents types de cultures ou de pratiques. La mthode part donc du principe que si un agriculteur dclare des bonnes pratiques, celles-ci sont appliques sur l&apos;ensemble de son exploitation. Elle peut donc surestimer la superficie consacre aux bonnes pratiques. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-9&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-10&quot;&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Le type de sol, combin au climat, et en particulier  la frquence et  l&apos;intensit des vnements pluvieux, sont des lments importants  prendre en compte pour dcider des doses et des frquences d&apos;application des engrais. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-10&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-11&quot;&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; L&apos;agriculture de prcision est un concept de gestion agricole bas sur l&apos;observation, la mesure et la rponse  la variabilit inter et intra-champs des cultures. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-11&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-12&quot;&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Les engrais  prendre en compte sont les engrais minraux et synthtiques ainsi que le fumier animal. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-12&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-13&quot;&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; La lutte intgre contre les ravageurs (IPM) est une approche cosystmique de la production et de la protection des cultures qui combine diffrentes stratgies et pratiques de gestion pour obtenir des cultures saines et minimiser l&apos;utilisation de pesticides (FAO). &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-13&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-14&quot;&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Afin de garder le questionnaire grable, le module ne prend pas en compte les diffrents types de culture ou de btail. La mthode part donc du principe que si un agriculteur dclare des bonnes pratiques, celles-ci sont appliques sur l&apos;ensemble de son exploitation. Elle peut donc surestimer la superficie consacre aux bonnes pratiques. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-14&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-15&quot;&gt;14&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Pesticides de classe II ou III selon la classification de l&apos;OMS (https://www.who.int/fr/publications/i/item/97892400005662), ou classification nationale quivalente. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-15&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-16&quot;&gt;15&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; En principe, les pesticides illgaux font rfrence  tous les produits qui ne sont pas conformes  la rglementation nationale sur la gestion des pesticides, tels que non enregistrs, mal tiquets, imports illgalement, etc. Il ne couvre pas les  utilisations hors tiquette  qui pourraient tre considres comme une action d&apos;utilisation illgale. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-16&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-17&quot;&gt;16&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt;Races prsentes dans le pays depuis suffisamment longtemps pour tre gntiquement adaptes  un ou plusieurs systmes ou environnements de production traditionnels du pays. L&apos;expression suffisamment longtemps fait rfrence au temps pass dans un ou plusieurs systmes ou environnements de production traditionnels du pays. Compte tenu des aspects culturels, sociaux et gntiques, une priode de 40 ans et six gnrations de l&apos;espce respective pourrait tre considre comme une valeur guide pour un suffisamment longtemps, sous rserve de circonstances nationales spcifiques (dfinition des races adaptes localement adopte par la Quatorzime session ordinaire (avril 2013) de la Commission des ressources gntiques pour l&apos;alimentation et l&apos;agriculture de la FAO). &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-17&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-18&quot;&gt;17&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Le calcul du niveau d&apos;inscurit alimentaire est dcrit en dtail dans le cours d&apos;apprentissage lectronique sur l&apos;ODD 2.1.2 : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/elearning/#/elc/en/course/SDG212&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/elearning/#/elc/en/course/SDG212&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-18&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-19&quot;&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;u&gt;La terminologie  Acceptable  doit tre lue dans le contexte de l&apos;ODD 2.4.1; elle doit tre interprte comme une situation qui mrite nanmoins une attention et des actions visant  l&apos;amliorer.&lt;/u&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-19&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
