<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 2-a-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar">اخر تحديث
			</language>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 2: End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 2.a: Increase investment, including through enhanced international cooperation, in rural infrastructure, agricultural research and extension services, technology development and plant and livestock gene banks in order to enhance agricultural productive capacity in developing countries, in particular least developed countries&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 2.a.1: The agriculture orientation index for government expenditures&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last updated: March 2020&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Institutional information&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization(s):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Agriculture Orientation Index (AOI) for Government Expenditures is defined as the Agriculture share of Government Expenditure, divided by the Agriculture value added share of GDP, where Agriculture refers to the agriculture, forestry, fishing and hunting sector. The measure is a currency-free index, calculated as the ratio of these two shares. National governments are requested to compile Government Expenditures according to the Government Finance Statistics (GFS) and the Classification of the Functions of Government (COFOG), and Agriculture value added share of GDP according to the System of National Accounts (SNA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agriculture refers to the agriculture, forestry, fishing and hunting sector, or Division A of ISIC Rev 4 (equal to Division A+B of ISIC Rev 3.2). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Government Expenditure are all expense and acquisition of non-financial assets associated with supporting a particular sector, as defined in the Government Finance Statistics Manual (GFSM) 2014 developed by the International Monetary Fund (IMF). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Government Expenditure are classified according to the Classification of the Functions of Government (COFOG), a classification developed by the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) and published by the United Nations Statistical Division (UNSD). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agriculture value-added and GDP are based on the System of National Accounts (SNA). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data on government expenditures is collected from countries using an annual questionnaire administered by FAO. Since countries typically compile government expenditure data based on their financial systems, and is administrative data covering the entirely of government expenditures, particularly at the central government level, there is no sampling issue and no possibility of sampling error. For some countries that do not report such data to FAO, data may be obtained from the IMF GFS database (which includes similar data but covering more sectors, and with less disaggregation of COFOG 042) or from official national governmental websites. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data on agriculture value-added and GDP are based on the system of national accounts, which is an analytical framework that compiles national data from a mix of survey, census and administrative (e.g. tax) sources. This data is obtained from the UN Statistics Division, which provides national accounts estimates for 220 countries and territories.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collection process:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data for the denominator are annually collected from countries using the FAO questionnaire on Government Expenditure on Agriculture (GEA), developed in collaboration with the IMF. Data from countries may be supplemented, for missing countries, with data collected by the IMF, or published on official national governmental websites. The official counterpart(s) at country level are, depending on the country, from the national statistics office, the ministry of finance (or other central planning agency), or the ministry of agriculture. Validation and consultation were conducted through various FAO commissions and committees, including its two agricultural statistics commissions in Africa and the Asia and Pacific, its Committee on Agriculture and Livestock Statistics in Latin America and the Caribbean, and its Committee on Agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendar&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data collection:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2019 data collection of Government Expenditure on Agriculture will start in May 2020.. Due to time required to collect, compile and publish national data, very few countries will be able to provide 2019 reference year data for the FAO Spring 2020 data collection cycle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data release:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this data is largely compiled annually, the next release for this indicator is planned for November 2020, covering data up to reference year 2019 (for the countries for which data collection, compilation, release is more timely).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data providers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ministry of Finance, Central Planning Agency, National Statistics Office, and/or Ministry of Agriculture&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data compilers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food and Agriculture Organization of the UN (FAO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Agriculture Orientation Index (AOI) greater than 1 reflects a higher orientation towards the agriculture sector, which receives a higher share of government spending relative to its contribution to economic value-added. An AOI less than 1 reflects a lower orientation to agriculture, while an AOI equal to 1 reflects neutrality in a government&amp;#x2019;s orientation to the agriculture sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Government spending in agriculture includes spending on sector policies and programs; soil improvement and soil degradation control; irrigation and reservoirs for agricultural use; animal health management, livestock research and training in animal husbandry; marine/freshwater biological research; afforestation and other forestry projects; etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spending in these agricultural activities helps to increase sector efficiency, productivity and income growth by increasing physical or human capital and /or reducing inter-temporal budget constraints. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the private sector typically under-invests in these activities due to the presence of market failure (e.g. the public good nature of research and development; the positive externalities from improved soil and water conditions; lack of access to competitive credit due to asymmetric information between producers and financial institutions, etc.). Similarly, the high risk faced by agricultural producers, particular smallholders unable to hedge against risk, often requires government intervention in terms of income redistribution to support smallholders in distress following crop failures and livestock loss from pests, droughts, floods, infrastructure failure, or severe price changes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Government spending in agriculture is essential to address these market failures and the periodic need for income redistribution. This leads to several potential indicators for the SDGs, which include: a) the level of Government Expenditure on Agriculture (GEA); b) the Agriculture share of Government Expenditure, and c) the AOI for Government Expenditures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An indicator that measures GEA levels fails to take into account the size of an economy. If two countries, A and B, have the same level of GEA, and the same agriculture contribution to GDP, but country A&amp;#x2019;s economy is 10 times that of country B, setting the same target levels for GEA fails to take economic size into account. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An indicator that measures the Agriculture share of Government Expenditure fails to take into account the relative contributions of the agricultural sector to a country&amp;#x2019;s GDP. Consider two countries with the same economic size, C and D, where agriculture contributes 2 per cent to C&amp;#x2019;s GDP, and 10 per cent to country D&amp;#x2019;s GDP. If total Government Expenditures were equal in both countries, C would experience greater relative investment in Agriculture than D. If total Government Expenditures differed, the result could be magnified or diluted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AOI index takes into account a country&amp;#x2019;s economic size, Agriculture&amp;#x2019;s contribution to GDP, and the total amount of Government Expenditure. As such, it allows for the setting of a universal and achievable target. Nonetheless, it is useful to interpret the AOI in combination with its numerator and denominator separately: the Agriculture share of Government Expenditure and the Agriculture value-added Share of GDP&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments and limitations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the numerator of this data is based on administrative sources, there is no confidence interval or standard error associated with government expenditure data. For the denominator, national accounts data typically do not provide any standard error or confidence interval information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key limitation with this indicator is that it takes into account only central government expenditure. To the extent that some countries may have heavier intervention in agriculture by sub-national governments, this will not be taken into account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Computation method:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AOI = Agriculture Share of Government Expenditures/Agriculture Value Added Share of GDP &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agriculture Share of Government Expenditure =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Central Government Expenditure on Agriculture/Total Central Government Expenditure) * 100&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agriculture refers to COFOG category 042 (agriculture, forestry, fishing and hunting); and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agriculture Value Added Share of GDP =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Agriculture Value Added/GDP)* 100&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agriculture refers to the Division A of ISIC Rev 4 (agriculture, forestry, fishing and hunting), equal to Division A+B of ISIC Rev 3.2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treatment of missing values:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At country level:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The missing values of 2018 government expenditure in agriculture were imputed from the ones of 2017 data submitted from countries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At regional and global levels:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regional and global aggregates of 2018 are based on mixed data of normal data from countries for which data are available and imputed data for countries for which data are not available. For the other period from 2001 to 2017, the regional and global aggregates are based on those of countries for which data are available. This may result in users interpreting these aggregates as pertaining to all countries in the region, which is the equivalent of treating countries with missing data as if they were the same as those for which data are available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regional aggregates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global and regional estimates are compiled by first separately summing across countries the four individual components of the index: government expenditure on agriculture, total government expenditure, agriculture value-added, and GDP. These are added only for those countries in a region (or globally) for which all components are available, and the index then calculated for this larger region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data availability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are available for about 100 countries on a regular basis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2001 to 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this indicator is based on national accounts data and total central government expenditures, it does not allow for disaggregation by demographic characteristics or geographic location.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since FAO does not alter government expenditure data reported by countries, and uses the national accounts estimates published by the UN Statistics Division (where some national data may be imputed), there should be no difference between data reported by FAO and national figures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;www.fao.org&quot;&gt;www.fao.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAOSTAT domain of Government Expenditure on Agriculture &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/faostat/en/%23data/IG%20&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/faostat/en/#data/IG&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IMF Government Finance Statistics Manual 2014 &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imf.org/external/np/sta/gfsm/&quot;&gt;https://www.imf.org/external/np/sta/gfsm/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 2: Poner fin al hambre, lograr la seguridad alimentaria y la mejora de la nutrición y promover la agricultura sostenible&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 2.a: Aumentar, incluso mediante una mayor cooperación internacional, las inversiones en infraestructura rural, investigación y servicios de extensión agrícola, desarrollo tecnológico y bancos de genes de plantas y ganado a fin de mejorar la capacidad de producción agropecuaria en los países en desarrollo, particularmente en los países menos adelantados&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 2.a.1: Índice de orientación agrícola para el gasto público&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Última actualización: marzo de 2020 &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 2 : Éliminer la faim, assurer la sécurité alimentaire, améliorer la nutrition et promouvoir l’agriculture durable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 2.a : Accroître, notamment grâce au renforcement de la coopération internationale, l’investissement dans l’infrastructure rurale, les services de recherche et de vulgarisation agricoles et la mise au point de technologies et de banques de plantes et de gènes d’animaux d’élevage, afin de renforcer les capacités productives agricoles des pays en développement, en particulier des pays les moins avancés.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 2.a.1 : Indice d’orientation agricole des dépenses publiques&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Dernière mise à jour : Mars 2020 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Informations institutionnelles&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Organisation(s) :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Organisation des Nations Unies pour l’alimentation et l’agriculture (FAO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;Indice d’orientation agricole des dépenses publiques est défini comme la part de l&apos;agriculture dans les dépenses publiques, divisée par la part de la valeur ajoutée de l&apos;agriculture dans le produit intérieur brut (PIB), l&apos;agriculture désignant le secteur de l&apos;agriculture, de la sylviculture, de la pêche et de la chasse. La mesure est un indice exempt de devise, calculé comme le rapport entre ces deux parts. Les gouvernements nationaux sont tenus de calculer les dépenses publiques selon les statistiques de finances publiques (SFP) et la classification des fonctions des administrations publiques (CFAP), et la part de la valeur ajoutée de l&apos;agriculture dans le PIB selon le système de comptabilité nationale (SCN).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;agriculture désigne le secteur de l&apos;agriculture, de la sylviculture, de la pêche et de la chasse, ou la division A de la Classification internationale type par industrie (CITI) Rév. 4 (égale à la division A+B de la CITI Rév. 3.2). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les dépenses publiques sont toutes les dépenses et acquisitions d&apos;actifs non financiers associés au soutien d&apos;un secteur en particulier, tel que défini dans le Manuel des statistiques de finances publiques (GFSM) 2014 élaboré par le Fonds monétaire international (FMI). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les dépenses publiques sont classées selon la Classification des fonctions des administrations publiques (CFAP), une classification élaborée par l&apos;Organisation de coopération et de développement économiques (OCDE) et publiée par la Division statistique des Nations Unies (DSNU). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La valeur ajoutée agricole et le PIB sont basés sur le système de comptabilité nationale (SCN). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Sources de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sur les dépenses publiques sont collectées auprès des pays au moyen d&apos;un questionnaire annuel administré par la FAO. Étant donné que les pays compilent généralement les données sur les dépenses publiques en fonction de leurs systèmes financiers, et qu&apos;il s&apos;agit de données administratives couvrant la totalité des dépenses publiques, en particulier au niveau du gouvernement central, il n&apos;y a pas de problème d&apos;échantillonnage et aucune possibilité d&apos;erreur d&apos;échantillonnage. Pour certains pays qui ne communiquent pas de telles données à la FAO, les données peuvent être obtenues à partir de la base de données GFS du FMI (qui comprend des données similaires, mais couvrant davantage de secteurs, et avec moins de désagrégation du CFAP 042) ou à partir des sites web officiels des gouvernements nationaux. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sur la valeur ajoutée agricole et le PIB sont basées sur le système de comptabilité nationale, qui est un cadre analytique qui compile les données nationales à partir d&apos;une combinaison d&apos;enquêtes, de recensements et de sources administratives (par exemple, fiscales). Ces données sont obtenues auprès de la Division des statistiques des Nations Unies, qui fournit des estimations de comptabilité nationale pour 220 pays et territoires.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Processus de collecte :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données pour le dénominateur sont collectées chaque année auprès des pays à l&apos;aide du questionnaire de la FAO sur les GEA, élaboré en collaboration avec le FMI. Les données des pays peuvent être complétées, pour les pays manquants, par des données collectées par le FMI, ou publiées sur les sites web officiels des gouvernements nationaux. Les homologues officielles au niveau national sont, selon le pays, le bureau national des statistiques, le ministère des finances (ou une autre agence centrale de planification) ou le ministère de l&apos;agriculture. La validation et la consultation ont été menées par le biais de diverses commissions et comités de la FAO, notamment ses deux commissions de statistiques agricoles en Afrique et en Asie et Pacifique, son Comité des statistiques de l&apos;agriculture et de l&apos;élevage en Amérique latine et dans les Caraïbes, et son Comité de l&apos;agriculture. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendrier&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collecte de données :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La collecte des données de 2019 sur les dépenses publiques en matière d&apos;agriculture commencera en mai 2020. En raison du temps nécessaire pour collecter, compiler et publier les données nationales, très peu de pays seront en mesure de fournir les données de l&apos;année de référence 2019 pour le cycle de collecte de données du printemps 2020 de la FAO.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publication des données :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comme ces données sont en grande partie compilées annuellement, la prochaine publication de cet indicateur est prévue pour novembre 2020 et couvrira les données jusqu&apos;à l&apos;année de référence 2019 (pour les pays pour lesquels la collecte, la compilation et la publication des données sont plus rapides).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fournisseurs de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ministère des finances, agence centrale de planification, bureau national des statistiques et/ou ministère de l&apos;agriculture&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Compilateurs de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Organisation des Nations Unies pour l’alimentation et l’agriculture (FAO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Justification :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Un indice d’orientation agricole (IOA) supérieur à 1 reflète une orientation plus élevée vers le secteur agricole, qui reçoit une part plus élevée des dépenses publiques par rapport à sa contribution à la valeur ajoutée économique. Un IOA inférieur à 1 reflète une orientation plus faible vers l’agriculture, tandis qu’un IOA égal à 1 reflète la neutralité dans l’orientation d’un gouvernement vers le secteur agricole. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les dépenses publiques consacrées à l’agriculture comprennent les dépenses consacrées aux politiques et aux programmes sectoriels ; l’amélioration du sol et le contrôle de la dégradation des sols ; l’irrigation et les réservoirs à usage agricole ; la gestion de la santé animale, la recherche sur le bétail et la formation en élevage ; recherche biologique marine/d’eau douce ; le boisement et d’autres projets forestiers ; etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les dépenses consacrées à ces activités agricoles contribuent à accroître l’efficacité du secteur, la productivité et la croissance des revenus en augmentant le capital physique ou humain et/ou en réduisant les contraintes budgétaires inter-temporaires. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Toutefois, le secteur privé sous-investi généralement dans ces activités en raison de la présence d’une défaillance du marché (p. ex. la bonne nature de la recherche et du développement dans le secteur public, les externalités positives liées à l’amélioration des conditions du sol et de l’eau ; le manque d’accès au crédit concurrentiel en raison de l’information asymétrique entre les producteurs et les institutions financières, etc.). De même, le risque élevé auquel sont confrontés les producteurs agricoles, en particulier les petits exploitants incapables de se protéger contre les risques, exige souvent l’intervention du gouvernement en termes de redistribution des revenus pour soutenir les petits exploitants en détresse à la suite de mauvaises récoltes et de pertes de bétail causées par les ravageurs, les sécheresses, les inondations, les défaillances d’infrastructures ou les graves changements de prix. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les dépenses publiques consacrées à l’agriculture sont essentielles pour remédier à ces défaillances du marché et au besoin périodique de redistribution des revenus. Cela conduit à plusieurs indicateurs potentiels pour les Objectifs de développement durable, notamment : a) le niveau des dépenses publiques consacrées à l’agriculture (GEA) ; b) la part de l’agriculture dans les dépenses publiques, et c) l’AOI pour les dépenses publiques. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Un indicateur qui mesure les niveaux de GEA ne tient pas compte de la taille d’une économie. Si deux pays, A et B, ont le même niveau de GEA, et la même contribution agricole au PIB, mais que l’économie du pays A est 10 fois celle du pays B, fixer les mêmes niveaux cibles pour le GEA ne tient pas compte de la taille économique. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Un indicateur qui mesure du GEA ne tient pas compte des contributions relatives du secteur agricole au PIB d’un pays. Prenons deux pays de la même taille économique, C et D, où l’agriculture contribue à hauteur de 2 % au PIB de C, et de 10 % au PIB du pays D. Si les dépenses publiques totales étaient égales dans les deux pays, C ferait l’expérience d’un investissement relatif plus important dans l’agriculture que D. Si les dépenses publiques totales différaient, le résultat pourrait être amplifié ou dilué. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L’indice IOA tient compte de la taille économique d’un pays, de la contribution de l’Agriculture au PIB et du montant total des dépenses publiques. En tant que tel, il permet l’établissement d’une cible universelle et réalisable. Néanmoins, il est utile d’interpréter l’IOA en combinaison avec son numérateur et son dénominateur séparément, soit : la part de l’agriculture dans les dépenses publiques et la part à valeur ajoutée du PIB dans l’agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commentaires et limites : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comme le numérateur de ces données est basé sur des sources administratives, il n&apos;y a pas d&apos;intervalle de confiance ou d&apos;erreur type associé aux données sur les dépenses publiques. Pour le dénominateur, les données des comptes nationaux ne fournissent généralement aucune information sur l&apos;erreur type ou l&apos;intervalle de confiance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La principale limite de cet indicateur est qu&apos;il ne prend en compte que les dépenses du gouvernement central. Dans la mesure où certains pays peuvent avoir une intervention plus importante des gouvernements infranationaux dans l&apos;agriculture, cela ne sera pas pris en compte.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Méthodologie&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Méthode de calcul :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IOA = Part de l&apos;agriculture dans les dépenses publiques/part de la valeur ajoutée de l&apos;agriculture dans le PIB &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Où : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part de l&apos;agriculture dans les dépenses publiques = &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Dépenses du gouvernement central pour l&apos;agriculture/dépenses totales du gouvernement central) * 100 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;agriculture se réfère à la catégorie 042 du CFAP (agriculture, foresterie, pêche et chasse) ; et &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part de la valeur ajoutée agricole dans le PIB = &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Valeur ajoutée agricole/PIB)* 100 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L&apos;agriculture désigne la division A de la CITI Rév. 4 (agriculture, foresterie, pêche et chasse), égale à la division A+B de la CITI Rév. 3.2. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traitement des valeurs manquantes : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Au niveau national : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les valeurs manquantes des dépenses publiques dans l&apos;agriculture en 2018 ont été imputées à partir des données de 2017 fournies par les pays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aux niveaux régional et mondial : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les agrégats régionaux et mondiaux de 2018 sont basés sur des données mixtes de données normales de pays pour lesquels des données sont disponibles et de données imputées pour ceux dont les données ne sont pas disponibles. Pour la période de 2001 à 2017, les agrégats régionaux et mondiaux sont basés sur ceux des pays pour lesquels des données sont disponibles. Cela peut conduire les utilisateurs à interpréter ces agrégats comme se rapportant à tous les pays de la région, ce qui équivaut à traiter les pays dont les données sont manquantes comme s&apos;ils étaient les mêmes que ceux pour lesquels les données sont disponibles. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agrégats régionaux :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les estimations mondiales et régionales sont compilées en additionnant d&apos;abord séparément les quatre composantes individuelles de l&apos;indice, soit : les dépenses publiques pour l&apos;agriculture, les dépenses publiques totales, la valeur ajoutée de l&apos;agriculture et le PIB. Celles-ci sont ajoutées uniquement pour les pays d&apos;une région (ou du monde) pour lesquels toutes les composantes sont disponibles, et l&apos;indice est ensuite calculé pour cette région plus vaste.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilité des données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des données sont disponibles pour une centaine de pays sur une base régulière. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Séries chronologiques : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De 2001 à 2018&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Désagrégation :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comme cet indicateur est basé sur les données des comptes nationaux et sur les dépenses totales du gouvernement central, il ne permet pas la désagrégation selon les caractéristiques démographiques ou géographiques.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources des écarts : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comme la FAO ne modifie pas les données sur les dépenses publiques communiquées par les pays et utilise les estimations des comptes nationaux publiées par la Division des statistiques des Nations Unies (où certaines données nationales peuvent être imputées), il ne devrait pas y avoir de différence entre les données communiquées par la FAO et les chiffres nationaux.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Références&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;forte&gt;&lt;forte&gt;URL:&lt;/forte&gt;&lt;/forte&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;www.fao.org&quot;&gt;www.fao.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Références &lt;forte&gt;&lt;forte&gt;:&lt;/forte&gt;&lt;/forte&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAOSTAT domaine des dépenses publiques pour l&apos;agriculture &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/faostat/fr/%23data/IG%20&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/faostat/fr/#data/IG&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FMI Manuel des statistiques de finances publiques 2014 &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imf.org/external/Pubs/FT/GFS/Manual/2014/GFSM_2014_FRE.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.imf.org/external/Pubs/FT/GFS/Manual/2014/GFSM_2014_FRE.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 2: Ликвидация голода, обеспечение продовольственной безопасности и улучшение питания и содействие устойчивому развитию сельского хозяйства&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 2.a: Увеличить инвестирование, в том числе посредством активизации международного сотрудничества, в сельскую инфраструктуру, сельскохозяйственные исследования и агропропаганду, развитие технологий и создание генетических банков растений и животных в целях укрепления потенциала развивающихся стран, особенно наименее развитых стран, в области сельскохозяйственного производства&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 2.a.1: Индекс ориентированности на сельское хозяйство, определяемый по структуре государственных расходов&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Последнее обновление: март 2020 года &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Институциональная информация &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Организация (и): &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Продовольственная и сельскохозяйственная организация Объединенных Наций (ФАО) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Определение: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Индекс ориентированности на сельское хозяйство (ИОСХ), определяемый по структуре государственных расходов, рассчитывается как доля сельского хозяйства в государственных расходах, деленная на долю добавленной стоимости сельского хозяйства в ВВП, где под сельским хозяйством понимается сектор сельского, лесного хозяйства, охоты, рыболовства и рыбоводства. Этот показатель представляет собой безвалютный индекс, рассчитываемый как соотношение этих двух долей. Национальным правительствам предлагается составлять данные по государственным расходам в соответствии со статистикой государственных финансов (СГФ) и Классификацией функций органов государственного управления (КФОГУ), а также долей добавленной стоимости сельского хозяйства в ВВП в соответствии с Системой национальных счетов (СНС).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Понятия: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Под сельским хозяйством понимается сектор сельского, лесного хозяйства, охоты, рыболовства и рыбоводства или раздел A редакции 4 МСОК (соответствует разделу A + B редакции 3.2 МСОК). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Государственные расходы - это все расходы и приобретение нефинансовых активов, связанных с поддержкой определенного сектора, как это определено в Руководстве по статистике государственных финансов (РСГФ) 2014 года, разработанном Международным валютным фондом (МВФ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Государственные расходы классифицируются в соответствии с Классификацией функций органов государственного управления (КФОГУ), классификацией, разработанной Организацией экономического сотрудничества и развития (ОЭСР) и опубликованной Статистическим отделом Организации Объединенных Наций (СОООН).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Добавленная стоимость в сельском хозяйстве и ВВП основаны на Системе национальных счетов (СНС). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Описание: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Данные по государственным расходам собираются от стран с помощью ежегодного вопросника, который находится в ведении ФАО. Поскольку страны обычно составляют данные по государственным расходам на основе своих финансовых систем и они представляют собой данные из административных источников, которые полностью отражают государственные расходы, особенно на уровне центрального правительства, то не существует проблемы выборки и появления возможности ошибок выборочного обследования. Для некоторых стран, которые не предоставляют такую информацию в ФАО, данные могут быть получены из базы данных МВФ по статистике государственных финансов (СГФ) (которая включает аналогичные данные, но охватывает большее количество секторов и с меньшей степенью дезагрегирования КФОГУ) или с официальных национальных правительственных веб-сайтов. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные по добавленной стоимости в сельском хозяйстве и ВВП основаны на системе национальных счетов, представляющей из себя аналитическую основу для составления национальных данных из сочетания обследований, переписей и административных (например, налоговых) источников. Эти данные получены из Статистического отдела ООН, который предоставляет оценки национальных счетов для 220 стран и территорий.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные для знаменателя ежегодно собираются от стран с использованием вопросника ФАО по государственным расходам на сельское хозяйство (ГРСХ), разработанного в сотрудничестве с МВФ. Данные по странам, которые не представляют информацию, могут быть дополнены данными, собранными МВФ, или опубликованными на официальных национальных правительственных веб-сайтах. Официальными партнерами на страновом уровне являются, в зависимости от страны, национальное статистическое управление, министерство финансов (или другое центральное планирующее агентство ) или министерство сельского хозяйства. Валидация и консультации проводились различными комиссиями и комитетами ФАО, включая две комиссии по сельскохозяйственной статистике в Африке и Азиатско-Тихоокеанском регионе, Комитет по статистике сельского хозяйства и животноводства в Латинской Америке и Карибском бассейне и Комитет по сельскому хозяйству. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Календарь &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Сбор данных: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Сбор данных по государственным расходам на сельское хозяйство за 2019 год начнется в мае 2020 года. Принимая во внимание время, необходимое для сбора, составления и публикации национальных данных, очень немногие страны смогут предоставить данные за отчетный 2019 год для весеннего 2020 года цикла сбора данных ФАО. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Выпуск данных: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Поскольку эти данные в основном составляются ежегодно, следующий выпуск данных по этому показателю запланирован на ноябрь 2020 года, с охватом данных до отчетного 2019 года (для стран, которые соблюдают своевременность сбора, составления и публикации данных). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Поставщики данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Министерство финансов, центральное агентство планирования, национальное статистическое управление и / или министерство сельского хозяйства &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Составители данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Продовольственная и сельскохозяйственная организация ООН (ФАО) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Значение индекса ориентации сельского хозяйства (ИОСХ) больше 1 отражает более высокую степень ориентации на сельскохозяйственный сектор, на который приходится более высокая доля государственных расходов по сравнению с его вкладом в добавленную стоимость в экономике. Значение ИОСХ меньше 1 отражает более низкую ориентацию на сельское хозяйство, тогда как значение ИОСХ, равное 1, отражает беспристрастное отношение правительства к сельскохозяйственному сектору. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Государственные расходы на сельское хозяйство включают затраты на реализацию отраслевой политики и программ, улучшение почвы и борьба с деградацией почвы, ирригацию и водоемы сельскохозяйственного назначения, организацию деятельности ветеринарной службы, исследования в области животноводства и обучение животноводству, морские / пресноводные биологические исследования, облесение и другие лесохозяйственные проекты и т. д.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Затраты на эту сельскохозяйственную деятельность помогают повысить эффективность сектора, производительность и рост доходов за счет увеличения физического или человеческого капитала и / или сокращения динамические бюджетных ограничений. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Однако частный сектор, как правило, недостаточно инвестирует в эти виды деятельности из-за наличия сбоев рыночного механизма (например, природа общественного блага от исследований и разработок, положительные внешние эффекты от улучшения состояния почвы и воды, отсутствие доступа к конкурентным кредитам из-за асимметричной информации между производителями и финансовыми учреждениями и т. д.). Точно так же высокий риск, с которым сталкиваются сельхозпроизводители, особенно мелкие землевладельцы, неспособные застраховаться от рисков, часто требует государственного вмешательства с точки зрения перераспределения доходов для поддержки мелких фермеров, оказавшихся в бедственном положении вследствие неурожаев и потерь скота из-за вредителей, засух, наводнений, сбоев инфраструктуры или серьезных изменений цен.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Государственные расходы на сельское хозяйство имеют важное значение для устранения этих сбоев рыночного механизма и периодической необходимости перераспределения доходов. Это приводит к необходимости иметь несколько потенциальных показателей для ЦУР, которые включают: a) уровень государственных расходов на сельское хозяйство (ГРСХ); б) доля сельского хозяйства в государственных расходах и в) индекс ориентированности на сельское хозяйство (ИОСХ) для государственных расходов. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель, отражающий уровни ГРСХ, не учитывает размер экономики. Если две страны, A и B, имеют одинаковый уровень ГРСХ и одинаковый вклад сельского хозяйства в ВВП, но экономика страны A в 10 раз больше, чем страны B, то отражение одинаковых целевых уровней для ГРСХ не позволяет принять во внимание размер экономики. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель, отражающий долю сельского хозяйства в государственных расходах, не учитывает относительный вклад сельскохозяйственного сектора в ВВП страны. Рассмотрим две страны с одинаковыми размерами экономики C и D, где сельское хозяйство вносит 2 процента в ВВП страны C и 10 процентов в ВВП страны D. Если бы общие государственные расходы были равными в обеих странах, то относительные инвестиции в сельское хозяйство страны С были бы больше, чем в стране D. Если бы общие государственные расходы были разными, то результаты относительных инвестиций мог бы быть больше или меньше. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Индекс ИОСХ учитывает размер экономики страны, вклад сельского хозяйства в ВВП и общую сумму государственных расходов. Таким образом, он позволяет установить универсальную и достижимую цель. Тем не менее, полезно интерпретировать ИОСХ в сочетании с его числителем и знаменателем отдельно: доля сельского хозяйства в государственных расходах и доля добавленной стоимости сельского хозяйства в ВВП. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Учитывая, что числитель этих данных основан на данных из административных источников, доверительный интервал или стандартная ошибка, связанные с данными по государственным расходам, отсутствуют. Что касается знаменателя, то данные национальных счетов обычно не содержат информации о стандартной ошибке или доверительном интервале. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Ключевым ограничением этого показателя является то, что он учитывает расходы только центрального правительства. Поскольку в некоторых странах может происходить более интенсивное вмешательство в сельское хозяйство со стороны субнациональных правительств, то эти расходы не будут приниматься во внимание.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ИОСХ = Доля сельского хозяйства в государственных расходах / Доля добавленной стоимости сельского хозяйства в ВВП &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Где: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Доля сельского хозяйства в государственных расходах = &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; (Расходы центрального правительства на сельское хозяйство / Общие расходы центрального правительства) * 100 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Сельское хозяйство относится к категории 042 КФОГУ (Сельское хозяйство, лесное хозяйство, рыболовство и охота); и &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Доля добавленной стоимости сельского хозяйства в ВВП = &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; (Добавленная стоимость сельского хозяйства / ВВП) * 100 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Сельское хозяйство относится к разделу A версии 4 МСОК (сельское хозяйство, лесное хозяйство, рыболовство и охота), соответствующего разделу A + B версии 3.2 МСОК. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Отсутствующие значения государственных расходов на сельское хозяйство в 2018 году были вменены на основе данных за 2017 год, представленных странами. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Региональные и глобальные агрегированные показатели 2018 года основаны на смешанных данных, составленных из обычных данных стран, по которым данные доступны, и из вмененных данных стран, по которым данные недоступны. За другой период с 2001 по 2017 год региональные и глобальные агрегированные показатели основаны на показателях стран, по которым имеются данные. Это может привести к тому, что пользователи будут интерпретировать эти агрегированные показатели как относящиеся ко всем странам в регионе, что эквивалентно обработке стран с отсутствующими данными, как если бы они были такими же, как и те, по которым данные доступны.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Региональные агрегаты: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Глобальные и региональные оценки составляются сначала путем отдельного суммирования по странам четырех отдельных компонентов индекса: государственных расходов на сельское хозяйство, общих государственных расходов, добавленной стоимости в сельском хозяйстве и ВВП. Они суммируются только по тем странам в регионе (или во всем мире), у которых доступны все компоненты, а затем рассчитывается индекс для более крупного региона.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Описание: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные доступны примерно по 100 странам на регулярной основе. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; С 2001 по 2018 год &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Поскольку этот показатель основан на данных национальных счетов и общих расходах центрального правительства, он не позволяет дезагрегировать по демографическим характеристикам или географическому положению. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Поскольку ФАО не корректирует данные по государственным расходам, представляемые странами, и использует оценки национальных счетов, публикуемые Статистическим отделом ООН (где некоторые национальные данные могут быть вменены), то не должна возникать разница между данными, представляемыми ФАО, и национальными данными. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Ссылки&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;www.fao.org&quot;&gt;www.fao.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ссылки:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Домен FAOSTAT государственных расходов на сельское хозяйство &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/faostat/en/%23data/IG%20&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/faostat/en/#data/IG&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Руководство МВФ по статистике государственных финансов, 2014 г. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imf.org/external/np/sta/gfsm/&quot;&gt;https://www.imf.org/external/np/sta/gfsm/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
