<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 2-b-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar">اخر تحديث
			</language>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 2: End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 2.b: Correct and prevent trade restrictions and distortions in world agricultural markets, including through the parallel elimination of all forms of agricultural export subsidies and all export measures with equivalent effect, in accordance with the mandate of the Doha Development Round&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 2.b.1: Agricultural export subsidies&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last updated: March 2020&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Institutional information&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organization(s):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The World Trade Organization (WTO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agricultural export subsidies are defined as export subsidies budgetary outlays and quantities as notified by WTO Members in Tables ES:1 and supporting Tables ES:2 (following templates in document G/AG/2 dated 30 June 1995).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data cover:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Notifications by WTO Members with export subsidy reduction commitments included in part IV of their Schedules;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Notifications of export subsidies by developing country Members pursuant to the provisions of article 9.4 of the Agreement on Agriculture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other WTO Members are not entitled to use export subsidies and their notifications are therefore not recorded in the indicator series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Budgetary outlays and quantities are expressed in a currency (national or other) and in quantity units as per Member&amp;apos;s notification practices. For Members with export subsidy reduction commitments included in part IV of their Schedules, the currency used in the notifications is similar to the one used in the Schedules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are available by country and by products or groups of products, according to Members&amp;apos; schedules for Members with export subsidy reduction commitments included in part IV of their Schedules and according to Member&amp;apos;s notification practices in the case of developing country Members using export subsidies under the provisions of article 9.4 of the Agreement on Agriculture.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sources of data are WTO Members&amp;apos; notifications in their Table ES:1 and supporting table ES:2 notifications, pursuant to the notification requirements and formats adopted by the WTO Committee on Agriculture and contained in document G/AG/2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Collection process:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not relevant. Cf. previous replies&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendar&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Data collection:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are collected on a regular basis, following the timing of WTO Members&amp;apos; notification submissions. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Data release:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cf. above &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data providers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WTO Members&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Data compilers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Name:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WTO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WTO is receiving WTO Members notifications and compiling the information contained in these notifications to report on this indicator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Rationale:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this indicator is to give detailed information on the level of export subsidies applied annually per product or group of products, as notified by WTO Members.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comments and limitations:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quality of the indicator depends on WTO Members&amp;apos; timeliness and accuracy of their notifications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computation method:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The country level data come directly from Members&amp;apos; notifications to the WTO and are not subject to any computation by the WTO. Each WTO Member collects data following his own national practice to prepare his notification.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Treatment of missing values:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At country level:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Values are missing when a WTO Member has not submitted their notification. Missing values cannot be estimated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At regional and global levels:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not relevant. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Regional aggregates:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WTO does not calculate regional aggregates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An overall global indicator measuring the total annual applied export subsidies budgetary outlays is calculated by summing all the available data after having converted them into a single currency (US$).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data availability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cf. latest revision of WTO document series G/AG/GEN/86 (table under section 2.4 &amp;#x2013; Members with shaded cells) for a detailed description of data availability for export subsidies notified by Members with export subsidy reduction commitments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, 10 developing country Members notified since 1995 the use of export subsidies, pursuant to the provisions of article 9.4 of the Agreement on Agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrary to the information for developed country Members with export subsidy reduction commitments that is available for all notified years, information for developing country Members using export subsidies, pursuant to the provisions of article 9.4 of the Agreement on Agriculture is available only for the years during which these export subsidies were used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Time series:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 1995 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator gives country and product based information on the level of applied export subsidies, both in terms of budgetary outlays and quantities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WTO does not estimate data. Only data contained in WTO Members&amp;apos; notifications are used. Therefore, there is no difference between country produced data and data available at the WTO.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;www.wto.org&quot;&gt;www.wto.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://agims.wto.org/Pages/ES/ESSearchAnalyse.aspx?ReportId=1403&amp;amp;Reset=True&quot;&gt;http://agims.wto.org/Pages/ES/ESSearchAnalyse.aspx?ReportId=1403&amp;amp;Reset=True&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wto.org/english/tratop_e/agric_e/transparency_toolkit_e.htm&quot;&gt;https://www.wto.org/english/tratop_e/agric_e/transparency_toolkit_e.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Meta 2: Poner fin al hambre, lograr la seguridad alimentaria y la mejora de la nutrición y promover la agricultura sostenible&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 2.b: Corregir y prevenir las restricciones y distorsiones comerciales en los mercados agropecuarios mundiales, incluso mediante la eliminación paralela de todas las formas de subvención a las exportaciones agrícolas y todas las medidas de exportación con efectos equivalentes, de conformidad con el mandato de la Ronda de Doha para el Desarrollo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 2.b.1: Subsidios a la exportación de productos agropecuarios&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Última actualización: marzo de 2020 &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 2 : Éliminer la faim, assurer la sécurité alimentaire, améliorer la nutrition et promouvoir l’agriculture durable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 2.b : Corriger et prévenir les restrictions et distorsions entravant le fonctionnement des marchés agricoles mondiaux, y compris par l’élimination parallèle de toutes les formes de subventions aux exportations agricoles et de toutes les mesures à l’exportation ayant un effet équivalent, conformément au mandat du Cycle de négociations de Doha pour le développement&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 2.b.1 : Subventions à l’exportation dans le secteur agricole&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Dernière mise à jour : Mars 2020 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Informations institutionnelles&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Organisation(s) :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L’Organisation mondiale du commerce (OMC)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Définition : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les subventions agricoles à l&apos;exportation sont définies comme les dépenses budgétaires et les quantités de subventions à l&apos;exportation telles que notifiées par les membres de l&apos;OMC dans les tableaux ES:1 et les tableaux complémentaires ES:2 (selon les modèles figurant dans le document G/AG/2 du 30 juin 1995).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Couverture des données : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notifications des membres de l&apos;OMC ayant des engagements de réduction des subventions à l&apos;exportation inclus dans la partie IV de leurs listes ;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notifications de subventions à l&apos;exportation par les pays membres en développement conformément aux dispositions de l&apos;article 9.4 de l&apos;Accord sur l&apos;agriculture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les autres membres de l&apos;OMC ne sont pas autorisés à utiliser des subventions à l&apos;exportation et leurs notifications ne sont donc pas enregistrées dans la série d&apos;indicateurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les dépenses budgétaires et les quantités sont exprimées dans une monnaie (nationale ou autre) et en unités de quantité conformément aux pratiques de notification des membres. Pour les membres ayant des engagements de réduction des subventions à l&apos;exportation figurant dans la partie IV de leurs listes, la monnaie utilisée dans les notifications est similaire à celle utilisée dans les listes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont disponibles par pays et par produits ou groupes de produits, conformément aux listes des membres pour ceux ayant des engagements de réduction des subventions à l&apos;exportation inscrits dans la partie IV de leurs listes et conformément aux pratiques de notification du membre dans le cas des pays membres en développement qui utilisent des subventions à l&apos;exportation au titre des dispositions de l&apos;article 9.4 de l&apos;Accord sur l&apos;agriculture». &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Sources de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les sources de données sont les notifications des membres de l&apos;OMC dans leur tableau ES:1 et le tableau d&apos;appui ES:2, conformément aux exigences et formats de notification adoptés par le Comité de l&apos;agriculture de l&apos;OMC et figurant dans le document G/AG/2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Processus de collecte : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non pertinent. Cf. réponses précédentes. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendrier&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Collecte de données :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont collectées régulièrement, en fonction du calendrier des notifications des membres de l&apos;OMC. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publication des données :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Cf. ci-dessus &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fournisseurs de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Membres de l&apos;OMC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Compilateurs de données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nom : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OMC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;OMC reçoit les notifications des membres de l&apos;OMC et compile les informations contenues dans ces notifications pour faire rapport sur cet indicateur.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justification :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;objectif de cet indicateur est de donner des informations détaillées sur le niveau des subventions à l&apos;exportation appliquées annuellement par produit ou groupe de produits, telles que notifiées par les membres de l&apos;OMC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires et limites : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La qualité de l&apos;indicateur dépend de la ponctualité et de l&apos;exactitude des notifications des membres de l&apos;OMC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Méthodologie&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Méthode de calcul :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données au niveau des pays proviennent directement des notifications des membres à l&apos;OMC et ne sont soumises à aucun calcul par l&apos;OMC. Chaque membre de l&apos;OMC collecte les données selon sa propre pratique nationale pour préparer sa notification.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Traitement des valeurs manquantes : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Au niveau national : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les valeurs manquent lorsqu&apos;un membre de l&apos;OMC n&apos;a pas soumis sa notification. Les valeurs manquantes ne peuvent pas être estimées.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aux niveaux régional et mondial : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Non pertinent. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agrégats régionaux : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;OMC ne calcule pas d&apos;agrégats régionaux&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Un indicateur global global mesurant le total des dépenses budgétaires annuelles consacrées aux subventions à l&apos;exportation est calculé en additionnant toutes les données disponibles après les avoir converties en une seule monnaie (le dollar américain).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilité des données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Cf. la dernière révision de la série de documents de l&apos;OMC G/AG/GEN/86 (tableau de la section 2.4 &amp;#x2013; Membres avec cellules ombrées) pour une description détaillée de la disponibilité des données sur les subventions à l&apos;exportation notifiées par les Membres ayant des engagements de réduction des subventions à l&apos;exportation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En outre, 10 pays en développement Membres ont notifié depuis 1995 l&apos;utilisation de subventions à l&apos;exportation, conformément aux dispositions de l&apos;article 9.4 de l&apos;Accord sur l&apos;agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrairement aux renseignements concernant les pays développés Membres ayant des engagements de réduction des subventions à l&apos;exportation qui sont disponibles pour toutes les années notifiées, les renseignements concernant les pays en développement Membres utilisant des subventions à l&apos;exportation, conformément aux dispositions de l&apos;article 9.4 de l&apos;Accord sur l&apos;agriculture, ne sont disponibles que pour les années pendant lesquelles ces subventions à l&apos;exportation ont été utilisées.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Série chronologique : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depuis 1995 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Désagrégation :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur donne des informations par pays et par produit sur le niveau des subventions à l&apos;exportation appliquées, à la fois en termes de dépenses budgétaires et de quantités.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sources des divergences : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;OMC n&apos;estime pas les données. Seules les données contenues dans les notifications des membres de l&apos;OMC sont utilisées. Il n&apos;y a donc aucune différence entre les données produites par les pays et les données disponibles à l&apos;OMC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Références&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;www.wto.org&quot;&gt;www.wto.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Références : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://agims.wto.org/Pages/ES/ESSearchAnalyse.aspx?ReportId=1403&amp;amp;Reset=True&quot;&gt;http://agims.wto.org/Pages/ES/ESSearchAnalyse.aspx?ReportId=1403&amp;amp;Reset=True&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wto.org/english/tratop_e/agric_e/transparency_toolkit_e.htm&quot;&gt;https://www.wto.org/english/tratop_e/agric_e/transparency_toolkit_e.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 2: Ликвидация голода, обеспечение продовольственной безопасности и улучшение питания и содействие устойчивому развитию сельского хозяйства&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 2.b: Устранять и пресекать введение торговых ограничений и возникновение искажений на мировых рынках сельскохозяйственной продукции, в том числе посредством параллельной ликвидации всех форм субсидирования экспорта сельскохозяйственной продукции и всех экспортных мер, имеющих аналогичные последствия, в соответствии с мандатом Дохинского раунда переговоров по вопросам развития&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 2.b.1: Субсидирование экспорта сельскохозяйственной продукции&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Последнее обновление: март 2020 года &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Институциональная информация &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Организация (и): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Всемирная торговая организация (ВТО) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Субсидирование экспорта сельскохозяйственной продукции определяются как бюджетные расходы и объемы экспортных субсидий, как указано членами ВТО в таблицах ES: 1 и вспомогательных таблицах ES: 2 (следующие шаблоны в документе G / AG / 2 от 30 июня 1995 года)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Охват данных: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Уведомления членов ВТО об обязательствах по сокращению субсидирования экспорта, включенные в часть IV их Программ; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Уведомления о субсидировании экспорта развивающимися странами-членами в соответствии с положениями статьи 9.4 Соглашения по сельскому хозяйству&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Другие члены ВТО не имеют права использовать субсидирование экспорта и поэтому их уведомления не регистрируются в показателях. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Бюджетные расходы и количества выражаются в валюте (национальной или какой-либо другой) и в единицах количества в соответствии с практикой уведомления, используемой членами. Для стран-членов, по которым обязательства по сокращению субсидирования экспорта включены в часть IV их Программ, валюта, используемая в уведомлениях, аналогична валюте, используемой в Программах. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные доступны по странам и по продуктам или группам продуктов, в соответствии с членскими программами для стран-членов с обязательствами по сокращению субсидирования экспорта, включенными в часть IV их Программ, и в соответствии с практикой уведомления членов в случае развивающихся стран-членов, использующих субсидирование экспорта в соответствии с положениями статьи 9.4 Соглашения по сельскому хозяйству.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Источниками данных являются уведомления членов ВТО в их Таблице ES: 1 и вспомогательной таблице ES: 2 уведомления в соответствии с требованиями и форматами уведомлений, принятыми Комитетом ВТО по сельскому хозяйству и содержащимися в документе G / AG / 2. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Не применимо. Ср. предыдущие ответы &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Календарь &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Сбор данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные собираются на регулярной основе в соответствии со сроками подачи уведомлений членами ВТО. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Выпуск данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Ср. выше &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Поставщики данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Члены ВТО &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt; Составители данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Название: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ВТО &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ВТО получает уведомления членов ВТО и составляет информацию, содержащуюся в этих уведомлениях, для отчета по этому показателю. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Целью этого показателя является предоставление подробной информации об уровне субсидирования экспорта, применяемого ежегодно по продуктам или группам продуктов, согласно уведомлению членов ВТО. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Качество показателя зависит от своевременности представления и точности уведомлений членов ВТО. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные на страновом уровне поступают непосредственно из уведомлений членов в ВТО и не подлежат никаким расчетам со стороны ВТО. Каждый член ВТО собирает данные в соответствии со своей национальной практикой для подготовки своего уведомления. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Значения отсутствуют, если член ВТО не представил свое уведомление. Недостающие значения невозможно оценить. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Не применимо. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Региональные агрегаты:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ВТО не рассчитывает региональные агрегаты. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Общий глобальный показатель, отражающий общие ежегодные прикладные бюджетные расходы на субсидирование экспорта, рассчитывается путем суммирования всех имеющихся данных после их конвертирования в единую валюту (доллары США). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Ср. последнюю редакцию серии документов ВТО G / AG / GEN / 86 (таблица в разделе 2.4 «Члены с затенёнными ячейками») для подробного описания доступности данных по субсидированию экспорта, содержащихся в уведомлениях стран-членов с обязательствами по сокращению субсидирования экспорта. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Кроме того, 10 развивающихся стран-членов уведомили с 1995 года об использовании субсидирования экспорта в соответствии с положениями статьи 9.4 Соглашения по сельскому хозяйству. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В отличие от информации по развитым странам-членам с обязательствами по сокращению субсидирования экспорта, которая доступна за все годы, где есть уведомления, информация по развивающимся странам-членам, использующим субсидирование экспорта в соответствии с положениями статьи 9.4 Соглашения по сельскому хозяйству, доступна только для лет, в течение которых осуществлялось субсидирование экспорта. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; С 1995 года &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель дает информацию по странам и продуктам об уровне применяемого субсидирования экспорта, как с точки зрения бюджетных расходов, так и с точки зрения количества. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ВТО не оценивает данные. Используются только данные, содержащиеся в уведомлениях членов ВТО. Следовательно, нет никакой разницы между данными, предоставленными странами, и данными, доступными в ВТО. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; URL: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;www.wto.org&quot;&gt; www.wto.org &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Ссылки: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://agims.wto.org/Pages/ES/ESSearchAnalyse.aspx?ReportId=1403&amp;amp;Reset=True&quot;&gt; http://agims.wto.org/Pages/ES/ESSearchAnalyse.aspx?ReportId=1403 &amp;amp; Reset = True &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wto.org/english/tratop_e/agric_e/transparency_toolkit_e.htm&quot;&gt; https://www.wto.org/english/tratop_e/agric_e/transparency_toolkit_e.htm &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
