<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 3-2-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 3: Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 3.2: By 2030, end preventable deaths of newborns and children under 5 years of age, with all countries aiming to reduce neonatal mortality to at least as low as 12 per 1,000 live births and under-5 mortality to at least as low as 25 per 1,000 live births&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 3.2.2: Neonatal mortality rate &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable&lt;/p&gt;2022-03-31&lt;p&gt;3.2.1: Under-five mortality rate &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;United Nations Children&amp;apos;s Fund (UNICEF) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;United Nations Children&amp;apos;s Fund (UNICEF) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The neonatal mortality rate is the probability that a child born in a specific year or period will die during the first 28 completed days of life, if subject to age-specific mortality rates of that period, expressed per 1000 live births. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neonatal deaths (deaths among live births during the first 28 completed days of life) may be subdivided into early neonatal deaths, occurring during the first 7 days of life, and late neonatal deaths, occurring after the 7th day but before the 28th completed day of life. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The unit of measure is the number of deaths per 1,000 live births.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nationally representative estimates of child mortality can be derived from several different sources, including civil registration and sample surveys. Demographic surveillance sites and hospital data are excluded as they are not nationally representative. The preferred source of data is a civil registration system that records births and deaths on a continuous basis. If registration is complete and the system functions efficiently, the resulting estimates will be accurate and timely. However, many countries do not have well-functioning vital registration systems. In such cases household surveys, such as the UNICEF-supported Multiple Indicator Cluster Surveys (MICS), the USAID-supported Demographic and Health Surveys (DHS) and periodic population censuses have become the primary sources of data on under-five and neonatal mortality. These surveys ask women about the survival of their children, and it is these reports that provide the basis of child mortality estimates for a majority of low- and middle-income countries. These data are subject to sampling and non-sampling errors, which might be substantial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Civil registration &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Civil registration is the preferred data source for under-five, infant and neonatal mortality estimation. Neonatal mortality rates are calculated using the number of neonatal deaths and the number of live births over a period. For civil registration data, initially annual observations were constructed for all observation years in a country. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Population census and household survey data &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of survey data comes from the full birth history (FBH), whereby women are asked for the date of birth of each of their children, whether the child is still alive, and if not the age at death. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For neonatal mortality, UNICEF and the United Nations Inter-agency Group for Child Mortality Estimation (UN IGME) compile data from all available data sources, including household surveys, censuses, and vital registration data. UNICEF and the UN IGME compile these data whenever they are available publicly and then conduct data quality assessment. UNICEF also collects data through UNICEF country offices by reaching national counterpart(s). The UN IGME also collects vital registration data reported by Ministries of Health or other relevant agencies to WHO. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To increase the transparency of the estimation process, the UN IGME has developed a child mortality web portal, www.&lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\lyhel\Dropbox\UNICEF%20Work\Data%20Requests\UNSD%20-%20SDG\childmortality.org&quot;&gt;childmortality.org&lt;/a&gt;, which includes all available data and shows estimates for each country. Once the new estimates are finalized, the web portal will be updated to reflect all available data and the new estimates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UN IGME underlying database is continuously updated whenever new empirical data become available. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A new round of UN IGME estimates is released annually, usually in the 3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; or 4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; quarter. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The National Statistical Office or the Ministry of Health is the typical provider of data for generating neonatal mortality estimates at the national level. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UNICEF &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The United Nations Inter-agency Group for Child Mortality Estimation (UN IGME), led by the United Nations Children&amp;#x2019;s Fund (UNICEF) and including members from the World Health Organization (WHO), the World Bank Group and the United Nations Population Division, was established in 2004 to advance the work on monitoring progress towards the achievement of child survival goals and to augment country capacity to collect high quality data on and produce timely estimates of child mortality. Every year, the UN IGME estimates levels and trends in neonatal mortality at the global, regional and country level and provides an assessment of current progress towards the SDG targets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mortality rates among young children are a key output indicator for child health and well-being, and, more broadly, for social and economic development. It is a closely watched public health indicator because it reflects the access of children and communities to basic health interventions such as vaccination, medical treatment of infectious diseases and adequate nutrition. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A civil registration system that continuously records all births and deaths in a population is the preferred source of high-quality underlying data on under-five mortality but these systems are not well developed in many low- and middle-income countries. Instead, household surveys and population censuses are the primary sources of underlying data in these countries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reliance on multiple data sources, i.e. surveys and census conducted several years apart but producing retrospective time series, can result in disparate mortality rates from different sources, sometimes referring to the same time period. Available data also suffer from sampling and nonsampling errors, including misreporting of age and sex, survivor selection bias, underreporting of child deaths, and recall errors as data are collected retrospectively. Further misclassifications can also impact on the accuracy of data, for example early neonatal deaths may be classified as stillbirths. Thus, simply comparing two country data points from different sources and drawing a line between them is not a technically sound way to assess levels and trends. Given varying levels of data quality across different sources, this sort of trend assessment will provide misleading results. Hence, the UN IGME fits a statistical model to these data that takes into account these various data sources to produce annualized estimates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to keep these challenges in mind when looking at available country data and also when discrepancies between country data and the UN IGME estimates are being discussed. The following&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;points are important to highlight:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The UN IGME aims to minimize the errors for each estimate, harmonize trends over time and produce up-to-date and properly assessed estimates of child mortality. Thus, UN IGME estimates are derived from country data. Notably, UN IGME assesses the quality of underlying data sources and adjusts data when necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;National estimates may refer to an earlier calendar year than the UN IGME estimates. This is particularly the case where estimates from the most recent national survey are used as the national estimate, since the survey estimates derived from a birth history are retrospective and typically refer to a period before the year of the survey, which may be several years behind the target year for the UN IGME estimates. National estimates may also use a different combination of data sources, or different projection or calculation methods.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the absence of error-free data, there will always be uncertainty around data and estimates, both national and internationally. To allow for added comparability, the UN IGME generates such estimates with uncertainty bounds. When discussing the UN IGME estimates, it&amp;#x2019;s important to look at the uncertainty ranges, which might be fairly wide in the case of some countries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UN Inter-agency Group for Child Mortality Estimation (UN IGME) estimates are derived from nationally representative data from censuses, surveys or vital registration systems. The UN IGME does not use any covariates to derive its estimates (except in the case of neonatal mortality estimation, which incorporates the relatively more data-rich under-five mortality rate estimates in the modelling). It only applies a curve fitting method to good-quality empirical data to derive trend estimates after data quality assessment. In most cases, the UN IGME estimates are close to the underlying data. The UN IGME aims to minimize the errors for each estimate, harmonize trends over time and produce up-to-date and properly assessed estimates. The UN IGME produces neonatal mortality rate estimates with a Bayesian spline regression model which models the ratio of neonatal mortality rate / (under-five mortality rate - neonatal mortality rate). Estimates of NMR are obtained by recombining the estimates of the ratio with the UN IGME-estimated under-five mortality rate. See the references for details. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the underlying data mentioned above, the most frequently used methods are as follows: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Civil registration: The neonatal mortality rate can be calculated from the number of children who died during the first 28 days of life and the number of live births. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Censuses and surveys: Censuses and surveys often include questions on household deaths in the last 12 months, which can be used to calculate mortality estimates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surveys: A direct method is used based on a full birth history, a series of detailed questions on each child a woman has given birth to during her lifetime. Neonatal, post-neonatal, infant, child and under-five mortality estimates can be derived from the full birth history. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UN IGME conducts an annual country consultation whereby the draft UN IGME estimates, empirical data used to derive the estimates, and notes on methodology are sent to National Statistical Offices and to Ministries of Health or other relevant agencies for review. National Statistical Offices, Ministries of Health or other relevant agencies have the opportunity to provide feedback or comments on estimates and methods, as well as supply additional empirical data during this consultation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Direct estimates from survey data are adjusted in high prevalence HIV settings for under-reporting of under-five mortality due to &amp;#x2018;missing mothers,&amp;#x2019; i.e. women who have died from HIV/AIDS and cannot report on the mortality experience of their children. Furthermore, UN IGME estimates are also adjusted to capture rapidly changing mortality rates due to HIV/AIDS and crises/disasters that are not well captured in survey data. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At country level &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UN IGME estimates are based on underlying empirical data. If the empirical data refer to an earlier reference period than the end year of the period the estimates are reported, UN IGME extrapolates the estimates to the common end year. UN IGME does not use any covariates to derive the estimates (except in the case of neonatal mortality estimation, which incorporates the relatively more data-rich under-five mortality rate estimates in the modelling). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At regional and global levels &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To construct aggregate estimates of neonatal mortality before 1990, regional averages of mortality rates were used for country-years with missing information and weighted by the respective population in the country-year. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Global and regional estimates of neonatal mortality rates are derived using the aggregated number of country-specific neonatal deaths for a specific region or globally estimated by the UN IGME using a birth-week cohort approach and aggregated country-specific births from the United Nations Population Division. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Detailed methodological descriptions can be found at the following: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://childmortality.org/methods and &lt;a href=&quot;https://childmortality.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/UNICEF-2021-Child-Mortality-Report.pdf&quot;&gt;https://childmortality.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/UNICEF-2021-Child-Mortality-Report.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UN IGME applies a standard estimation method across all countries in the interest of comparability. This method aims to estimate a smooth trend curve of age-specific mortality rates, accounting for potential outliers and biases in data sources and averaging over the possibly many disparate data sources for a country. A more detailed descripition of the different phases of the statistical production process is available in the annual UN IGME report and at https://childmortality.org/methods.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quality is assured by applying standard statistical and demographic methods to all input data and conducting regular data quality assessments. Countries are also consulted on the draft estimates during the annual country consultation process. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UN IGME aims to produce transparent, timely and accurate annual estimates of under-five mortality. Data quality is critical to that end. UN IGME assesses data quality using both internal and external validaity checks and does not include data sources with substantial non-sampling errors or omissions as underlying empirical data in its statistical model.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator is available for countries from 1990 (or earlier depending on the availability of empirical data for each country before 1990) to 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to data limitations, neonatal mortality rates are not estimated for any conventional disaggregation at this time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UN IGME estimates are based on nationally representative data. Countries may use a single source as their official estimate or apply methods different from the UN IGME methods to derive official national estimates. The differences between the UN IGME estimates and national official estimates are usually not large if empirical data are high quality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many countries lack a single source of high-quality data covering the last several decades, instead relying on multiple data sources to estimate mortality. Data from different sources require different calculation methods and may suffer from different errors, for example random errors in sample surveys or systematic errors due to misreporting. As a result, different surveys often yield widely different estimates of under-five mortality for a given time period and available data collected by countries are often inconsistent across sources. It is important to analyse, reconcile and evaluate all data sources simultaneously for each country. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each new survey or data point must be examined in the context of all other sources, including previous data, and with respect to any sampling or non-sampling errors that may be present (such as misreporting of age and survivor selection bias; underreporting of child deaths is also common). UN IGME assesses the quality of underlying data sources and adjusts data when necessary. Furthermore, the latest data produced by countries often are not current estimates but refer to an earlier reference period. Thus, the UN IGME also extrapolates estimates to a common reference year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to reconcile these differences and take better account of the systematic biases associated with the various types of data inputs, the UN IGME has developed an estimation method to fit a smoothed trend curve to a set of observations and to extrapolate that trend to a defined time point. The UN IGME aims to minimize the errors for each estimate, harmonize trends over time and produce up-to-date and properly assessed estimates of child mortality. In the absence of error-free data, there will always be uncertainty around data and estimates. To allow for added comparability, the UN IGME generates such estimates with uncertainty bounds. Applying a consistent methodology also allows for comparisons between countries, despite the varied number and types of data sources. UN IGME applies a common methodology across countries and uses original empirical data from each country but does not report figures produced by individual countries using other methods, which would not be comparable to other country estimates. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All data sources, estimates and detailed methods are documented on the website &lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\lyhel\Dropbox\UNICEF%20Work\Data%20Requests\UNSD%20-%20SDG\childmortality.org&quot;&gt;childmortality.org&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.unicef.org/topic/child-survival/under-five-mortality/&quot;&gt;https://data.unicef.org/topic/child-survival/under-five-mortality/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations Inter-agency Group for Child Mortality Estimation (UN IGME). Levels and trends in child mortality. Report 2021. New York: UNICEF, 2021. Available at https://childmortality.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/UNICEF-2021-Child-Mortality-Report.pdf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations Inter-agency Group for Child Mortality Estimation (UN IGME). Subnational Under-five Mortality Estimates, 1990&amp;#x2013;2019 for 22 countries. New York: UNICEF, 2020. Available at https://childmortality.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/UN-IGME-Subnational-Under-five-Mortality-Estimates.pdf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexander, M. and L. Alkema, Global Estimation of Neonatal Mortality using a Bayesian Hierarchical Splines Regression Model Demographic Research, vol. 38, 2018, pp. 335&amp;#x2013;372. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alkema L, New JR. Global estimation of child mortality using a Bayesian B-spline bias-reduction method. The Annals of Applied Statistics. 2014; 8(4): 2122&amp;#x2013;2149. Available at: http://arxiv.org/abs/1309.1602 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alkema L, Chao F, You D, Pedersen J, Sawyer CC. National, regional, and global sex ratios of infant, child, and under-5 mortality and identification of countries with outlying ratios: a systematic assessment. The Lancet Global Health. 2014; 2(9): e521&amp;#x2013;e530. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pedersen J, Liu J. Child Mortality Estimation: Appropriate Time Periods for Child Mortality Estimates from Full Birth Histories. Plos Medicine. 2012;9(8). Available at: http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1001289 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silva R. Child Mortality Estimation: Consistency of Under-Five Mortality Rate Estimates Using Full Birth Histories and Summary Birth Histories. Plos Medicine. 2012;9(8). Available at: http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1001296 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walker N, Hill K, Zhao FM. Child Mortality Estimation: Methods Used to Adjust for Bias due to AIDS in Estimating Trends in Under-Five Mortality. Plos Medicine. 2012;9(8). Available at: http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1001298 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 3: Garantizar una vida sana y promover el bienestar de todos a todas las edades&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 3.2: De aquí a 2030, poner fin a las muertes evitables de recién nacidos y de niños menores de 5 años, logrando que todos los países intenten reducir la mortalidad neonatal al menos a 12 por cada 1.000 nacidos vivos y la mortalidad de los niños menores de 5 años al menos a 25 por cada 1.000 nacidos vivos&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 3.2.2: Tasa de mortalidad neonatal&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Última actualización: septiembre de 2019.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicadores relacionados a partir de febrero de 2020&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.2.1: Tasa de mortalidad de menores de cinco años&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Información institucional &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Organización (es): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Fondo de las Naciones Unidas para la Infancia (UNICEF) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La tasa de mortalidad neonatal es la probabilidad de que un niño nacido en un año o período específico muera durante los primeros 28 días completos de vida si está sujeto a las tasas de mortalidad específicas de ese período, expresada por cada 1000 nacidos vivos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las muertes neonatales (muertes entre los nacidos vivos durante los primeros 28 días completos de vida) pueden subdividirse en muertes neonatales tempranas, que ocurren durante los primeros 7 días de vida, y muertes neonatales tardías, que ocurren después del 7º día pero antes del 28º día completo de vida.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las estimaciones representativas a nivel nacional de la mortalidad infantil pueden obtenerse de diferentes fuentes, como el registro civil y las encuestas por muestreo. Se excluyen los sitios de vigilancia demográfica y los datos hospitalarios, ya que rara vez son representativos. La fuente de datos preferida es un sistema de registro civil que registre los nacimientos y las defunciones de forma continua. Si el registro es completo y el sistema funciona eficazmente, las estimaciones resultantes serán precisas y oportunas. Sin embargo, muchos países no tienen sistemas de registro civil que funcionen bien. En estos casos, las encuestas de hogares, como las Encuestas de Indicadores Múltiples por Conglomerados (MICS) apoyadas por UNICEF, las Encuestas Demográficas y de Salud (EDS) apoyadas por USAID y los censos de población periódicos se han convertido en las principales fuentes de datos sobre la mortalidad de menores de cinco años y neonatal. Estas encuestas preguntan a las mujeres sobre la supervivencia de sus hijos, y son estos informes los que proporcionan la base de las estimaciones de mortalidad infantil para la mayoría de los países de ingresos bajos y medios. Sin embargo, estos datos suelen estar sujetos a errores de muestreo o no muestreo, que pueden ser considerables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registro civil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos del registro civil son la fuente de datos preferida para la estimación de la mortalidad de los menores de cinco años, los niños y los neonatos. El cálculo de las tasas de mortalidad neonatal se deriva del número de muertes neonatales y del número de nacimientos durante un período. En el caso de los datos del registro civil (con datos disponibles sobre el número de defunciones y las poblaciones de mitad de año), se construyeron inicialmente observaciones anuales para todos los años de observación de un país.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Datos de los censos de población y de las encuestas de hogares&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La mayoría de los datos de las encuestas proceden de la historia completa de los nacimientos (HN), en la que se pregunta a las mujeres la fecha de nacimiento de cada uno de sus hijos, si el niño sigue vivo y, en caso contrario, la edad en el momento de la muerte.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Proceso de recolección:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para la mortalidad neonatal, UNICEF y el Grupo Interagencial para la Estimación de la Mortalidad Infantil de la ONU (UN-IGME, por sus siglas en inglés) recopilan datos de todas las fuentes de datos disponibles, incluidas las encuestas de hogares, los censos, los datos del registro civil, etc. UNICEF y el UN-IGME recopilan estos datos siempre que estén disponibles públicamente y luego realizan una evaluación de la calidad de los datos. UNICEF también recopila datos a través de las oficinas de país de UNICEF llegando a la(s) contraparte(s) nacional(es). El IGME de la ONU también recopila los datos del registro civil comunicados por los Ministerios de Salud u otros organismos pertinentes a la OMS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los ajustes de los datos empíricos se realizan en entornos de alta prevalencia del VIH para ajustar la infradeclaración de la mortalidad infantil debido a la ausencia de madres en los datos de la encuesta. A continuación, la UN-IGME aplica un método de ajuste de curvas a estos datos empíricos para obtener sus estimaciones de tendencia de las tasas de mortalidad neonatal. Dado que las muertes por crisis son difíciles de captar en los datos de las encuestas de hogares o de los censos, la UN-IGME ajusta las estimaciones de mortalidad neonatal para la mortalidad por crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A continuación, el UN-IGME lleva a cabo una consulta anual a los países enviando sus estimaciones, los datos empíricos utilizados para derivar esas estimaciones y las notas sobre la metodología, a las Oficinas Nacionales de Estadística y a los Ministerios de Salud o a los organismos pertinentes para que den su opinión sobre las estimaciones del UN-IGME y los datos empíricos. Los institutos nacionales de estadística, los ministerios de salud o los organismos pertinentes revisan las estimaciones del UN-IGME y los datos empíricos, envían sus comentarios y a veces proporcionan datos empíricos adicionales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para aumentar la transparencia del proceso de estimación, el IGME de la ONU ha desarrollado un portal web sobre mortalidad infantil: CME (www.childmortality.org). Incluye todos los datos disponibles y muestra las estimaciones para cada país. Una vez que se finalicen las nuevas estimaciones, el CME se actualizará para reflejar todos los datos disponibles y las nuevas estimaciones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendario&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recopilación de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La base de datos subyacente del IGME de la ONU se actualiza continuamente cada vez que se dispone de nuevos datos empíricos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publicación de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En 2020 se publicará una nueva ronda de estimaciones del IGME de la ONU; normalmente, la fecha de publicación es en el mes de septiembre. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Oficina Nacional de Estadística o el Ministerio de Salud participan mayoritariamente en la generación de datos de mortalidad neonatal a nivel nacional.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; UNICEF&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las tasas de mortalidad entre los niños pequeños son un indicador clave de los resultados de la salud y el bienestar infantil y, en general, del desarrollo social y económico. Es un indicador de salud pública muy vigilado porque refleja el acceso de los niños y las comunidades a intervenciones sanitarias básicas como la vacunación, el tratamiento médico de las enfermedades infecciosas y una nutrición adecuada.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las estimaciones del Grupo Interinstitucional de las Naciones Unidas para la Estimación de la Mortalidad Infantil (IGME) se derivan de datos representativos a nivel nacional procedentes de censos, encuestas o sistemas de registro civil. El IGME de la ONU no utiliza ninguna covariable para derivar sus estimaciones. Sólo aplica un método de ajuste de curvas a los datos empíricos de buena calidad para derivar las estimaciones de tendencias tras la evaluación de la calidad de los datos. En la mayoría de los casos, las estimaciones de la UN-IGME se aproximan a los datos subyacentes. El IGME de la ONU pretende minimizar los errores de cada estimación, armonizar las tendencias a lo largo del tiempo y producir estimaciones actualizadas y correctamente evaluadas. El IGME de la ONU produce estimaciones de la tasa de mortalidad neonatal con un modelo de regresión spline bayesiano que modela la relación de la tasa de mortalidad neonatal / (tasa de mortalidad de menores de cinco años - tasa de mortalidad neonatal). Las estimaciones de la tasa de mortalidad neonatal se obtienen recombinando las estimaciones del cociente con la tasa de mortalidad de menores de cinco años estimada por el IGME de las Naciones Unidas. Véanse las referencias para más detalles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para los datos subyacentes mencionados anteriormente, los métodos más utilizados son los siguientes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Registro civil&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Número de niños fallecidos durante los primeros 28 días de vida y número de nacimientos utilizados para calcular las tasas de mortalidad neonatal.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Censos y encuestas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Los censos y las encuestas suelen incluir preguntas sobre las muertes en los hogares en los últimos 12 meses, que pueden utilizarse para calcular las estimaciones de mortalidad.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Encuestas: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Se utiliza un método directo basado en la historia completa de los nacimientos, una serie de preguntas detalladas sobre cada uno de los hijos que una mujer ha dado a luz durante su vida. Las estimaciones de la mortalidad neonatal, posneonatal, infantil y de menores de cinco años pueden derivarse del módulo de historia de nacimientos completa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel de país:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las estimaciones del IGME de la ONU se basan en datos empíricos subyacentes. Si los datos empíricos se refieren a un periodo de referencia anterior al año final del periodo del que se informan las estimaciones, la UN-IGME extrapola las estimaciones al año final común. El UN-IGME no utiliza ninguna covariable para derivar las estimaciones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel regional y mundial:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para construir estimaciones agregadas de la mortalidad neonatal antes de 1990, se utilizaron los promedios regionales de las tasas de mortalidad para los países-año con información faltante y se ponderaron por la población respectiva en el país-año.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las estimaciones mundiales y regionales de las tasas de mortalidad neonatal se obtienen agregando el número de muertes neonatales específicas de cada país estimadas por el IGME de las Naciones Unidas y los nacimientos específicos de cada país de la División de Población de las Naciones Unidas, basándose en un enfoque de cohorte de semanas de nacimiento.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador está disponible para todos los países desde 1990 (o antes) hasta 2018, dependiendo de la disponibilidad de datos empíricos para cada país antes de 1990.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La desagregación común para los indicadores de mortalidad incluye la desagregación por sexo, edad (neonatal, infantil, niño), quintil de riqueza, residencia y educación de la madre. Los datos desagregados no siempre están disponibles. El desglose por ubicación geográfica suele hacerse a nivel regional o, como mínimo, a nivel provincial en el caso de los datos de encuestas o censos. Los datos de los sistemas de registro civil que funcionan bien pueden proporcionar más desgloses geográficos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Fuentes de discrepancia:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las estimaciones del IGME de la ONU se derivan a partir de datos nacionales. Los países suelen utilizar una única fuente como sus estimaciones oficiales o aplican métodos diferentes a los de la IGME de la ONU para derivar las estimaciones. Las diferencias entre las estimaciones del IGME de la ONU y las estimaciones oficiales nacionales no suelen ser grandes si los datos empíricos son de buena calidad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Muchos países carecen de una única fuente de datos de alta calidad que cubra las últimas décadas. Los datos de diferentes fuentes requieren diferentes métodos de cálculo y pueden sufrir diferentes errores, por ejemplo, errores aleatorios en las encuestas por muestreo o errores sistemáticos debidos a errores de información. En consecuencia, las distintas encuestas suelen arrojar estimaciones muy diferentes de la mortalidad neonatal para un periodo determinado y los datos disponibles recogidos por los países suelen ser incoherentes entre las distintas fuentes. Es importante analizar, conciliar y evaluar todas las fuentes de datos simultáneamente para cada país. Cada nueva encuesta o dato debe examinarse en el contexto de todas las demás fuentes, incluidos los datos anteriores. Los datos sufren errores de muestreo o no muestreo (como la notificación errónea de la edad y el sesgo de selección de los supervivientes; también es frecuente la notificación insuficiente de las muertes de niños). El UN-IGME evalúa la calidad de las fuentes de datos subyacentes y ajusta los datos cuando es necesario. Además, los últimos datos producidos por los países a menudo no son estimaciones actuales, sino que se refieren a un período de referencia anterior. Por ello, el UN-IGME también proyecta las estimaciones a un año de referencia común. Para conciliar estas diferencias y tener más en cuenta los sesgos sistemáticos asociados a los distintos tipos de datos, el UN-IGME ha desarrollado un método de estimación para ajustar una curva de tendencia suavizada a un conjunto de observaciones y extrapolar esa tendencia a un punto temporal definido. El UN-IGME pretende minimizar los errores de cada estimación, armonizar las tendencias a lo largo del tiempo y producir estimaciones actualizadas y correctamente evaluadas de la mortalidad infantil. A falta de datos sin errores, siempre habrá incertidumbre en torno a los datos y las estimaciones. Para permitir una mayor comparabilidad, el UN-IGME genera dichas estimaciones con límites de incertidumbre. La aplicación de una metodología coherente también permite realizar comparaciones entre países, a pesar de la variedad de fuentes de datos. El UN-IGME aplica una metodología común a todos los países y utiliza datos empíricos originales de cada país, pero no informa sobre las cifras elaboradas por países individuales con otros métodos, que no serían comparables con las estimaciones de otros países.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://childmortality.org&quot;&gt;http://childmortality.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.unicef.org/topic/child-survival/neonatal-mortality/&quot;&gt;https://data.unicef.org/topic/child-survival/neonatal-mortality/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Referencias:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grupo Interinstitucional de las Naciones Unidas para la Estimación de la Mortalidad Infantil (IGME). Niveles &amp;amp; tendencias de la mortalidad infantil. Informe 2019. Nueva York: UNICEF, 2019. Disponible &lt;a href=&quot;at%20https:/childmortality.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/UN-IGME-Child-Mortality-Report-2019.pdf&quot;&gt;en https://childmortality.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/UN-IGME-Child-Mortality-Report-2019.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexander, M. y L. Alkema, Global Estimation of Neonatal Mortality using a Bayesian Hierarchical Splines Regression Model Demographic Research, vol. 38, 2018, pp. 335&amp;#x2013;372.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alkema L, New JR. Estimación global de la mortalidad infantil utilizando un método bayesiano de reducción de sesgos B-spline. Los anales de la estadística aplicada. 2014; 8(4): 2122&amp;#x2013;2149. Disponible en: &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/1309.1602&quot;&gt;http://arxiv.org/abs/1309.1602&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alkema L, Chao F, You D, Pedersen J, Sawyer CC. National, regional, and global sex ratios of infant, child, and under-5 mortality and identification of countries with outlying ratios: a systematic assessment. The Lancet Global Health. 2014; 2(9): e521&amp;#x2013;e530.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pedersen J, Liu J. Child Mortality Estimation: Períodos de tiempo apropiados para las estimaciones de mortalidad infantil a partir de historias completas de nacimientos. Plos Medicine. 2012;9(8). Disponible en: &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1001289&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1001289&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silva R. Estimación de la mortalidad infantil: Consistencia de las estimaciones de la tasa de mortalidad de menores de cinco años utilizando historias de nacimiento completas e historias de nacimiento resumidas. Plos Medicine. 2012;9(8). Disponible en: &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1001296&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1001296&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walker N, Hill K, Zhao FM. Estimación de la mortalidad infantil: Métodos utilizados para ajustar el sesgo debido al SIDA en la estimación de las tendencias de la mortalidad de menores de cinco años. Plos Medicine. 2012;9(8). Disponible en: &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1001298&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1001298&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 3 : Permettre à tous de vivre en bonne santé et promouvoir le bien-être de tous à tout âge&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 3.2 : D’ici 2030, éliminer les décès évitables de nouveau-nés et d’enfants de moins de 5 ans, tous les pays devant chercher à ramener la mortalité néonatale à 12 pour 1 000 naissances vivantes au plus et la mortalité des enfants de moins de 5 ans à 25 pour 1 000 naissances vivantes au plus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 3.2.2 : Taux de mortalité néonatale&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2021-12-06&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3.2.1 : Taux de mortalité des enfants de moins de cinq ans&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fonds des Nations Unies pour l’enfance (UNICEF)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fonds des Nations Unies pour l’enfance (UNICEF)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le taux de mortalité néonatale est la probabilité qu&apos;un enfant qui est né au cours d&apos;une année ou d&apos;une période donnée meure au cours des 28 premiers jours complets de vie, s&apos;il est soumis aux taux de mortalité par âge de cette période, exprimés pour 1 000 naissances vivantes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les décès néonatals (décès parmi les naissances vivantes au cours des 28 premiers jours révolus de la vie) peuvent être subdivisés en décès néonatals précoces, survenant au cours des 7 premiers jours de la vie, et décès néonatals tardifs, survenant après le 7e jour mais avant le 28e jour de vie accompli. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L’unité de mesure est le nombre de décès pour 1 000 naissances vivantes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sans objet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Des estimations représentatives de la mortalité infantile au niveau national peuvent être obtenues à partir de différentes sources, notamment les données de l&apos;état civil et les enquêtes. Les sites de surveillance démographique et les données hospitalières sont exclus car ils sont rarement représentatifs. La source de données privilégiée est un système de registre de l&apos;état civil qui enregistre les naissances et les décès sur une base continue. Si l&apos;enregistrement est complet et que le système fonctionne efficacement, les estimations qui en résultent seront précises et livrées en temps opportun. Toutefois, de nombreux pays ne disposent pas de systèmes de registre de l’état civil qui fonctionnent bien. Dans de tels cas, les enquêtes auprès des ménages, telles que les enquêtes en grappes à indicateurs multiples (MICS) soutenues par l&apos;UNICEF, les enquêtes démographiques et de santé (EDS) soutenues par l&apos;Agence américaine pour le développement international (USAID) et les recensements périodiques de la population sont devenus les principales sources de données sur la mortalité des moins de cinq ans. Ces enquêtes interrogent les femmes sur la survie de leurs enfants, et ce sont ces rapports qui fournissent la base des estimations de la mortalité infantile pour une majorité de pays à faible et à moyen revenu. Cependant, ces données sont souvent sujettes à des erreurs qui peuvent être importantes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enregistrement à l&apos;état civil &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données de l&apos;état civil constituent la source de données privilégiée pour l&apos;estimation de la mortalité des moins de cinq ans, infantile et néonatale. Le calcul des taux de mortalité néonatale est dérivé du nombre de décès néonataux et du nombre de naissances sur une période. Pour les données d&apos;état civil (avec des données disponibles sur le nombre de décès et les populations en milieu d&apos;année), des observations initialement annuelles ont été construites pour toutes les années d&apos;observation dans un pays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Données de recensement de la population et des enquêtes auprès des ménages &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La majorité des données d’enquête proviennent de l’historique complet de naissance, selon lequel on demande aux femmes la date de naissance de chacun de leurs enfants, si l’enfant est encore en vie, et si ce n’est pas le cas, l’âge au décès. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pour la mortalité néonatale, l’UNICEF et le Groupe interorganisations des Nations Unies pour l&apos;estimation de la mortalité juvénile (UN IGME) compilent les données de toutes les sources de données disponibles, y compris les enquêtes auprès des ménages, les recensements et les données de l&apos;état civil. L’UNICEF et l’IGME compilent ces données chaque fois qu’elles sont accessibles au public, puis effectuent une évaluation de la qualité des données. L&apos;UNICEF recueille également des données par l&apos;intermédiaire de ses bureaux régionaux en contactant ses homologues nationaux. L&apos;IGME recueille également les données de l&apos;état civil communiquées à l&apos;Organisation mondiale de la Santé (OMS) par les ministères de la santé ou d&apos;autres organismes compétents. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afin d’accroître la transparence du processus d’estimation, l’IGME a développé un portail Web sur la mortalité infantile, &lt;a href=&quot;http://childmortality.org&quot;&gt;(en anglais) www.childmortality.org&lt;/a&gt;, qui comprend toutes les données disponibles et présente des estimations pour chaque pays. Une fois les nouvelles estimations finalisées, le portail Web sera mis à jour pour refléter toutes les données disponibles et les nouvelles estimations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;La base de données sous-jacente de l’IGME est continuellement mise à jour chaque fois que de nouvelles données empiriques deviennent disponibles. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Une nouvelle série d&apos;estimations de l’IGME est diffusée chaque année, habituellement au 3&lt;sup&gt;e&lt;/sup&gt; ou au 4&lt;sup&gt;e&lt;/sup&gt; trimestre.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Le Bureau national de statistique ou le ministère de la santé est le fournisseur typique de données servant à générer des estimations de la mortalité néonatale au niveau national.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UNICEF&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Le Groupe interorganisations des Nations Unies pour l&apos;estimation de la mortalité juvénile (UN IGME), dirigé par le Fonds des Nations Unies pour l’enfance (UNICEF) et comprenant des membres de l’Organisation mondiale de la Santé (OMS), du Groupe de la Banque mondiale et de la Division de la population des Nations Unies, a été créé en 2004 pour faire avancer les travaux de suivi des progrès accomplis dans la réalisation des objectifs de survie de l’enfant et pour renforcer la capacité des pays à recueillir des données de haute qualité sur les enfants et à produire des estimations de mortalité infantile en temps opportun. Chaque année, l’IGME estime les niveaux et les tendances de la mortalité néonatale aux niveaux mondial, régional et national et fournit une évaluation des progrès actuels en vue des cibles des ODD. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Le taux de mortalité des jeunes enfants est un indicateur clé de la santé et du bien-être des enfants et, plus largement, du développement social et économique. Il s&apos;agit d&apos;un indicateur de santé publique étroitement surveillé, car il reflète l&apos;accès des enfants et des communautés aux interventions sanitaires de base telles que la vaccination, le traitement médical des maladies infectieuses et une nutrition adéquate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Un système d&apos;état civil qui enregistre en permanence toutes les naissances et tous les décès d&apos;une population est la source préférée de données sous-jacentes de haute qualité sur la mortalité des moins de cinq ans, mais ces systèmes ne sont pas bien développés dans de nombreux pays à faible ou à moyen revenu. Au lieu de cela, les enquêtes auprès des ménages et les recensements de la population sont les principales sources de données sous-jacentes dans ces pays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le recours à de multiples sources de données, c&apos;est-à-dire des enquêtes et des recensements menés à plusieurs années d&apos;intervalle mais produisant des séries chronologiques rétrospectives, peut entraîner des taux de mortalité disparates provenant de différentes sources, se référant parfois à la même période. Les données disponibles souffrent également d&apos;erreurs d&apos;échantillonnage et non dues à l&apos;échantillonnage, notamment des déclarations erronées sur l&apos;âge et le sexe, un biais de sélection des survivants, une sous-déclaration des décès d&apos;enfants et des erreurs de rappel, car les données sont recueillies rétrospectivement. D&apos;autres erreurs de classification peuvent également avoir un impact sur l&apos;exactitude des données, par exemple les décès néonatals précoces peuvent être classés comme des mortinaissances. Ainsi, comparer simplement deux points de données d&apos;un pays provenant de sources différentes et tracer une ligne entre eux n&apos;est pas un moyen techniquement valable d&apos;évaluer les niveaux et les tendances. Étant donné les différents niveaux de qualité des données selon les différentes sources, ce type d&apos;évaluation des tendances fournira des résultats trompeurs. Par conséquent, l&apos;IGME adapte un modèle statistique à ces données qui tient compte de ces diverses sources de données pour produire des estimations annualisées. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il est important de garder ces défis à l&apos;esprit lors de l&apos;examen des données nationales disponibles et également lorsque les écarts entre les données nationales et les estimations de l&apos;IGME sont discutés. Il est important de souligner les points suivants :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;L&apos;IGME vise à minimiser les erreurs pour chaque estimation, à harmoniser les tendances dans le temps et à produire des estimations actualisées et correctement évaluées de la mortalité infantile. Ainsi, les estimations de l&apos;IGME sont dérivées des données nationales. Notamment, l&apos;IGME évalue la qualité des sources de données sous-jacentes et ajuste les données si nécessaire.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les estimations nationales peuvent faire référence à une année civile antérieure à celle des estimations de l&apos;IGME. C&apos;est particulièrement le cas lorsque les estimations de l&apos;enquête nationale la plus récente sont utilisées comme estimation nationale, puisque les estimations de l&apos;enquête dérivées d&apos;un historique des naissances sont rétrospectives et se réfèrent généralement à une période antérieure à l&apos;année de l&apos;enquête, qui peut avoir plusieurs années avant l&apos;année cible pour les estimations de l&apos;IGME. Les estimations nationales peuvent également utiliser une combinaison différente de sources de données, ou différentes méthodes de projection ou de calcul.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;En l&apos;absence de données sans erreur, il y aura toujours une incertitude autour des données et des estimations, tant nationales qu&apos;internationales. Pour permettre une meilleure comparabilité, l&apos;IGME génère de telles estimations avec des limites d&apos;incertitude. Lors de l&apos;examen des estimations de l&apos;IGME, il est important d&apos;examiner les intervalles d&apos;incertitude, qui peuvent être assez larges dans le cas de certains pays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les estimations du Groupe interorganisations des Nations Unies pour l&apos;estimation de la mortalité juvénile (UN IGME) sont dérivées de données représentatives à l’échelle nationale provenant de recensements, d’enquêtes ou de systèmes d’enregistrement de l&apos;état civil. L’IGME n’utilise aucune covariable pour établir ses estimations (sauf dans le cas de l&apos;estimation de la mortalité néonatale, qui intègre les estimations relativement plus riches en données du taux de mortalité des moins de cinq ans dans la modélisation). Il n’applique qu’une méthode d’ajustement de courbe aux données empiriques de bonne qualité pour obtenir des estimations de tendance après évaluation de la qualité des données. Dans la plupart des cas, les estimations de l’IGME sont similaires aux données sous-jacentes. L’IGME vise à minimiser les erreurs pour chaque estimation, à harmoniser les tendances au fil du temps et à produire des estimations actuelles et précises. L’IGME produit des estimations du taux de mortalité néonatale avec un modèle de régression spline bayésienne qui modélise le ratio du taux de mortalité néonatale (TMN) / (taux de mortalité des enfants de moins de cinq ans - taux de mortalité néonatale). Les estimations du TMN sont obtenues en recombinant les estimations du ratio avec le taux de mortalité des enfants de moins de cinq ans estimé par l’IGME. Voir les références pour plus de détails. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour les données sous-jacentes mentionnées ci-dessus, les méthodes les plus fréquemment utilisées sont les suivantes :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Etat civil : Le taux de mortalité néonatale peut être calculé à partir du nombre d&apos;enfants décédés au cours des 28 premiers jours de vie et du nombre de naissances. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recensements et enquêtes : les recensements et les enquêtes incluent souvent des questions sur les décès dans les ménages au cours des 12 derniers mois, qui peuvent être utilisées pour calculer les estimations de la mortalité. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enquêtes : une méthode directe est utilisée sur la base d&apos;un historique complet des naissances, une série de questions détaillées sur chaque enfant auquel une femme a donné naissance au cours de sa vie. Les estimations de la mortalité néonatale, post-néonatale, infantile, juvénile et des moins de cinq ans peuvent être dérivées de l&apos;historique complet des naissances. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L’IGME mène une consultation annuelle par pays au cours de laquelle les estimations provisoires de l’IGME, les données empiriques utilisées pour calculer les estimations et les notes sur la méthodologie sont envoyés aux bureaux nationaux de statistique et aux ministères de la santé ou à d’autres organismes compétents pour examen. Ceux-ci ont la possibilité de fournir de la rétroaction ou des commentaires sur les estimations et les méthodes, ainsi que de fournir des données empiriques supplémentaires au cours de cette consultation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les estimations directes des données d’enquête sont ajustées dans les contextes de prévalence élevée du VIH pour la sous-déclaration de la mortalité des moins de cinq ans due aux « mères disparues », c’est-à-dire aux femmes décédées du VIH/sida qui n&apos;ont pas pu déclarer l’expérience de mortalité de leurs enfants. En outre, les estimations de l’IGME sont également ajustées pour tenir compte de l’évolution rapide des taux de mortalité due au VIH/sida et aux crises/catastrophes qui ne sont pas bien prises en compte dans les données d’enquête. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Au niveau national :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les estimations de l&apos;IGME sont basées sur des données empiriques sous-jacentes. Si les données empiriques se réfèrent à une période de référence antérieure à celle pour laquelle les estimations doivent être produites, l&apos;IGME extrapolera les estimations. L&apos;IGME n&apos;utilise aucune covariable pour calculer les estimations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aux niveaux régional et mondial :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour construire des estimations globales de la mortalité néonatale avant 1990, des moyennes régionales des taux de mortalité ont été utilisées pour les années-pays pour lesquelles des informations manquaient, et ont été pondérées par la population respective de l&apos;année-pays.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les estimations mondiales et régionales des taux de mortalité néonatale sont calculées à l’aide du nombre agrégé de décès néonatals par pays pour une région spécifique ou estimée à l’échelle mondiale par l’IGME à l’aide d’une approche de cohorte de la semaine de naissance et d’un agrégat des naissances par pays de la Division de la population des Nations Unies. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Des descriptions méthodologiques détaillées peuvent être trouvées (en anglais) aux adresses : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.childmortality.org/methods&quot;&gt;www.childmortality.org/methods&lt;/a&gt; et &lt;a href=&quot;https://childmortality.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/UNICEF-2020-Child-Mortality-Report.pdf&quot;&gt;https://childmortality.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/UNICEF-2020-Child-Mortality-Report.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L’IGME applique une méthode d’estimation standard dans tous les pays dans un souci de comparabilité. Cette méthode vise à estimer une courbe de tendance lisse des taux de mortalité par âge, en tenant compte des valeurs aberrantes et des biais potentiels dans les sources de données et en faisant la moyenne des nombreuses sources de données disparates pour un pays. Une description plus détaillée des différentes phases du processus de production statistique est disponible dans le rapport annuel de l’IGME et à l&apos;adresse (en anglais) https://childmortality.org/methods. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;La qualité est assurée en appliquant des méthodes statistiques et démographiques standard à toutes les données d&apos;entrée et en procédant à des évaluations régulières de la qualité des données. On consulte également les pays à propos des estimations provisoires au cours du processus annuel de consultation des pays. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L’IGME vise à produire des estimations annuelles transparentes, opportunes et précises de la mortalité des moins de cinq ans. La qualité des données est essentielle à cette fin. L’IGME évalue la qualité des données à l’aide de contrôles de validation internes et externes et n’inclut pas dans son modèle statistique comme données empiriques sous-jacentes, des sources de données comportant des erreurs non dues à l’échantillonnage substantielles ou des omissions. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disponibilité des données : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur est disponible pour les pays de 1990 (ou plus tôt selon la disponibilité des données empiriques pour chaque pays avant 1990) à 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Désagrégation : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En raison des limites des données, les taux de mortalité néonatale ne sont pas estimés pour une désagrégation conventionnelle à l’heure actuelle. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources des divergences :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les estimations de l’IGME sont basées sur des données représentatives au niveau national. Les pays peuvent utiliser une source unique pour leurs estimations officielles ou appliquent des méthodes différentes de celles de l’IGME pour obtenir des estimations nationales officielles. Les différences entre les estimations de l’IGME et les estimations officielles nationales ne sont généralement pas importantes si les données empiriques sont de haute qualité.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De nombreux pays ne disposent pas d&apos;une source unique de données de haute qualité couvrant les dernières décennies, s&apos;appuyant plutôt sur plusieurs sources de données pour estimer la mortalité. Les données provenant de différentes sources nécessitent des méthodes de calcul différentes et peuvent inclure des erreurs différentes, telles que des erreurs aléatoires dans les enquêtes par échantillonnage ou des erreurs systématiques dues à des déclarations erronées. Ainsi, les différentes enquêtes donnent souvent des estimations très différentes de la mortalité des moins de cinq ans pour une période donnée et les données disponibles recueillies par les pays sont souvent incohérentes d&apos;une source à l&apos;autre. Il est important d&apos;analyser, de réconcilier et d&apos;évaluer simultanément toutes les sources de données pour chaque pays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chaque nouvelle enquête ou point de données doit être examiné dans le contexte de toutes les autres sources y compris les données antérieures et en tenant compte des erreurs d&apos;échantillonnage ou des erreurs non dues à l&apos;échantillonnage qui peuvent être présentes (telles que la déclaration erronée de l&apos;âge et le biais de sélection des survivants et la sous-déclaration des décès d&apos;enfants qui est également fréquente). L’IGME évalue la qualité des sources de données sous-jacentes et ajuste les données au besoin. De plus, les dernières données produites par les pays ne sont souvent pas des estimations actuelles mais se réfèrent à une période de référence antérieure. Ainsi, l’IGME projette également des estimations pour une année de référence commune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afin de concilier ces différences et de mieux prendre en compte les biais systématiques associés aux différents types de données, l’IGME a développé une méthode d&apos;estimation permettant d&apos;ajuster une courbe de tendance lissée à un ensemble d&apos;observations et d&apos;extrapoler cette tendance à un moment défini. L’IGME vise à minimiser les erreurs pour chaque estimation, à harmoniser les tendances dans le temps et à produire des estimations actuelles et précises de la mortalité infantile. En l&apos;absence de données exemptes d&apos;erreurs, il y aura toujours de l&apos;incertitude quant aux données et aux estimations. Pour permettre une meilleure comparabilité, l’IGME produit de telles estimations avec des niveaux de certitude limités. L&apos;application d&apos;une méthodologie cohérente permet d&apos;établir des comparaisons entre les pays, malgré le nombre et les types variés de sources de données. L’IGME applique une méthodologie commune à tous les pays et utilise des données empiriques originales de chaque pays. Il ne fait toutefois pas état des chiffres produits par chaque pays en utilisant d’autres méthodes, ce qui ne serait pas comparable aux autres estimations des pays.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Toutes les références sont en anglais)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL :&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toutes les sources de données, les estimations et les méthodes détaillées sont documentées sur les site Web (en anglais) &lt;a href=&quot;http://childmortality.org/&quot;&gt;childmortality.org&lt;/a&gt; et &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.unicef.org/topic/child-survival/under-five-mortality/&quot;&gt;https://data.unicef.org/topic/child-survival/under-five-mortality/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Références :&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Groupe interorganisations des Nations Unies pour l&apos;estimation de la mortalité juvénile (UN IGME). « Levels and trends in child mortality. Report 2020 ». New York: UNICEF, 2020. Disponible à l&apos;adresse : https://childmortality.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/UNICEF-2020-Child-Mortality-Report.pdf &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Groupe interorganisations des Nations Unies pour l&apos;estimation de la mortalité juvénile (UN IGME). « Subnational Under-five Mortality Estimates, 1990&amp;#x2013;2019 for 22 countries ». New York: UNICEF, 2020. Disponible à l&apos;adresse : https://childmortality.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/UN-IGME-Subnational-Under-five-Mortality-Estimates.pdf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexander M., Alkema L. « Global Estimation of Neonatal Mortality using a Bayesian Hierarchical Splines Regression Model ». Demographic Research, vol. 38, 2018, pp. 335–372. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alkema L, New JR. « Global estimation of child mortality using a Bayesian B-spline bias-reduction method ». The Annals of Applied Statistics. 2014; 8(4): 2122&amp;#x2013;2149. Disponible à l&apos;adresse : http://arxiv.org/abs/1309.1602 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alkema L, Chao F, You D, Pedersen J, Sawyer CC. « National, regional, and global sex ratios of infant, child, and under-5 mortality and identification of countries with outlying ratios: a systematic assessment ». The Lancet Global Health. 2014; 2(9): e521&amp;#x2013;e530. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pedersen J, Liu J. « Child Mortality Estimation: Appropriate Time Periods for Child Mortality Estimates from Full Birth Histories ». Plos Medicine. 2012;9(8). Disponible à l&apos;adresse : http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1001289 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silva R. « Child Mortality Estimation: Consistency of Under-Five Mortality Rate Estimates Using Full Birth Histories and Summary Birth Histories ». Plos Medicine. 2012;9(8). Disponible à l&apos;adresse : http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1001296 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walker N, Hill K, Zhao FM. « Child Mortality Estimation: Methods Used to Adjust for Bias due to AIDS in Estimating Trends in Under-Five Mortality ». Plos Medicine. 2012;9(8). Disponible à l&apos;adresse : http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1001298&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 3: Garantir o acesso á saude de qualidade e promover o bem-estar para todos, em todas as idades&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 3: Обеспечение здорового образа жизни и содействие благополучию для всех в любом возрасте&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 3.2: К 2030 году положить конец предотвратимой смертности новорожденных и детей в возрасте до пяти лет, при этом все страны должны стремиться уменьшить неонатальную смертность до не более 12 случаев на 1000 живорождений, а смертность в возрасте до пяти лет до не более 25 случаев на 1000 живорождений&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 3.2.2: Коэффициент неонатальной смертности&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Последнее обновление: сентябрь 2019 года&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Связанные показатели по состоянию на февраль 2020 года &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 3.2.1: Коэффициент смертности детей в возрасте до пяти лет &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Институциональная информация &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Организация (и): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Детский фонд Организации Объединенных Наций (ЮНИСЕФ)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Коэффициент неонатальной смертности - это вероятность того, что ребенок, родившийся в конкретный год или период, умрет в течение первых 28 полных дней жизни, если учитывать повозрастные коэффициенты смертности этого периода, в расчете на 1000 живорождений. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Неонатальные смерти (смерти среди живорожденных в течение первых 28 полных дней жизни) можно подразделить на ранние неонатальные смерти, происходящие в течение первых 7 дней жизни, и поздние неонатальные смерти, произошедшие после 7-го дня, но до наступления 28-х полных суток жизни. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Репрезентативные на национальном уровне оценки детской смертности могут быть получены из ряда различных источников, включая данные регистрации актов гражданского состояния и выборочные обследования. Сайты по демографическим наблюдениям и данные больниц исключаются, поскольку они редко бывают репрезентативными. Предпочтительным источником данных является система регистрации актов гражданского состояния, в которой осуществляется постоянная регистрация рождений и смертей. Если регистрация проводится в полном объеме и система функционирует эффективно, полученные оценки будут точными и своевременными. Однако во многих странах нет хорошо функционирующих систем регистрации актов гражданского состояния. В таких случаях обследования домашних хозяйств, такие как поддерживаемые ЮНИСЕФ Кластерные обследования по многим показателям (MICS), поддерживаемые Агентством США по международному развитию Обследования демографических характеристик и состояния здоровья (DHS) и периодические переписи населения становятся основными источниками данных по смертности детей в возрасте до пяти лет и неонатальной смертности. В этих обследованиях женщин спрашивают о выживании их детей и именно эти отчеты служат основой для оценок детской смертности для большинства стран с низким и средним уровнем доходов. Однако в этих данных часто встречаются ошибки выборки и / или ошибки, не связанные с выборкой, которые могут быть существенными. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;em&gt; Регистрация актов гражданского состояния &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные регистрации актов гражданского состояния являются предпочтительным источником данных для оценки младенческой и неонатальной смертности в возрасте до пяти лет. Расчет показателей неонатальной смертности производится на основе количества неонатальных смертей и количества рождений за какой-либо период. Что касается данных регистрации актов гражданского состояния (с имеющимися данными по количеству умерших и среднегодовой численности населения), первоначально годовые наблюдения организовывались для всех лет наблюдения в стране. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;em&gt; Данные переписи населения и обследований домашних хозяйств &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Большинство данных обследований поступает из полного анамнеза родов (FBH), когда женщин спрашивают о дате рождения каждого из их детей, о том, жив ли ребенок, а если нет, то о возрасте, при котором наступила смерть.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Что касается неонатальной смертности, ЮНИСЕФ и Межучрежденческая группа ООН по оценке детской смертности (UN IGME) собирают данные из всех доступных источников данных, включая обследования домашних хозяйств, переписи населения, данные регистрации актов гражданского состояния и т. д. ЮНИСЕФ и UN IGME собирают эти данные, когда они становятся общедоступными, а затем проводят оценку качества данных. ЮНИСЕФ собирает данные через страновые отделения ЮНИСЕФ, связываясь с национальными партнерами. UN IGME собирает данные регистрации актов гражданского состояния, представляемые в ВОЗ министерствами здравоохранения или другими соответствующими учреждениями. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Корректировки эмпирических данных проводятся для условий высокой распространенности ВИЧ с тем, чтобы внести поправку, связанную с занижением детской смертности из-за отсутствия данных по матерям в материалах обследования. UN IGME затем применяет метод подбора кривой к этим эмпирическим данным, чтобы получить оценки UN IGME, отражающие тенденции изменения уровней неонатальной смертности. Поскольку смертность в условиях кризиса трудно учесть в данных обследований домохозяйств или переписей населения, то UN IGME корректирует оценки неонатальной смертности с учетом кризисной смертности. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Затем UN IGME проводит ежегодные консультации со страной, отправляя произведенные UN IGME оценки, эмпирические данные, использованные для получения оценок UN IGME, и примечания по методологии в национальные статистические управления, а также в министерства здравоохранения или соответствующие агентства для организации обратной связи по обсуждению оценок UN IGME и эмпирических данных. Национальные статистические управления, министерства здравоохранения или соответствующие агентства проверяют оценки и эмпирические данные, подготовленные UN IGME, отправляют отзывы или комментарии, а иногда и предоставляют дополнительные эмпирические данные. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Чтобы повысить прозрачность процесса оценки, UN IGME разработала веб-портал по детской смертности: CME (оценки детской смертности - ОДС) (www.childmortality.org). Он включает все доступные данные и показывает оценки для каждой страны. Как только расчет новых оценок завершается, данные на веб-портале CME обновляются, чтобы отобразить все доступные данные и новые оценки.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Календарь &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Сбор данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; База исходных данных Межучрежденческой группы ООН по оценке детской смертности постоянно обновляется при появлении новых эмпирических данных. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Выпуск данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Новые данные раунда оценок Межучрежденческой группы ООН по оценке детской смертности будут выпущены в 2020 году; обычно данные выпускаются в сентябре. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Поставщики данных&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Национальное статистическое управление или министерство здравоохранения в основном участвуют в формировании данных по неонатальной смертности на национальном уровне. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Составители данных&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ЮНИСЕФ&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Обоснование:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Коэффициенты смертности среди детей младшего возраста являются ключевым показателем здоровья и благополучия детей и, в более широком смысле, социально-экономического развития. Этот показатель здравоохранения очень внимательно отслеживается, поскольку он отражает доступ детей и сообщества к основным медико-санитарным мероприятиям, таким как вакцинация, лечение инфекционных заболеваний и адекватное питание.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Оценки Межучрежденческой группы ООН по оценке детской смертности (UN IGME) получены на основе репрезентативных на национальном уровне данных переписей населения, обследований или информации систем записи актов гражданского состояния. UN IGME не использует никакие ковариаты для получения оценок. Группа применяет метод подбора кривой только к эмпирическим данным хорошего качества для получения оценок тенденций после оценки качества данных. В большинстве случаев оценки UN IGME близки к исходным данным. UN IGME стремится свести к минимуму ошибки для каждой оценки, согласовать тенденции в динамике и подготовить актуальные и должным образом рассчитанные оценки. UN IGME производит оценки уровня неонатальной смертности с помощью Байесовской сплайновой регрессионной модели, которая формирует коэффициент неонатальной смертности / (коэффициент смертности детей до пяти лет - коэффициент неонатальной смертности). Оценки уровней неонатальной смертности (УНС) получают путем рекомбинации оценок коэффициента с оценкой смертности детей в возрасте до пяти лет, подготовленной UN IGME. См. ссылки для получения более подробной информации.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для исходных данных, упомянутых выше, наиболее часто используются следующие методы: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Регистрация актов гражданского состояния &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: Количество
детей, умерших в течение первых 28 дней жизни, и количество рождений, используемых для расчета коэффициентов неонатальной смертности. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Переписи населения и обследования &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: Переписи
населения и обследования часто включают вопросы о смертности в домохозяйствах за последние 12 месяцев, данные по которым можно использовать для расчета оценок смертности. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Обследования: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Используется прямой метод, основанный
на полном анамнезе родов - ряде подробных вопросов по каждому ребенку, которого женщина родила в течение своей жизни. Оценки неонатальной, постнеонатальной, младенческой, детской смертности и смертности детей в возрасте до пяти лет могут быть получены из модуля полного анамнеза родов.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Оценки UN IGME основаны на исходных эмпирических данных. Если эмпирические данные относятся к более раннему отчетному периоду, чем год окончания периода, за который представлены оценки, Межучрежденческая группа ООН по оценке детской смертности экстраполирует оценки на конец общего года. UN IGME не использует никакие ковариаты для получения оценок. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для построения совокупных оценок неонатальной смертности до 1990 года использовались средние региональные коэффициенты смертности для стран-лет с отсутствующей информацией и взвешенные на соответствующее население в стране-годе. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Региональные агрегаты: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Глобальные и региональные оценки показателей смертности детей в возрасте до пяти лет производятся путем агрегирования количества смертей детей в возрасте до пяти лет по конкретным странам, рассчитанных UN IGME, и данных по рождению в конкретных странах, полученных из Отдела народонаселения ООН, основанных на когортном подходе исследования людей в разбивке по зафиксированным неделям, в которые они родились. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные по показателю имеются для всех стран в период с 1990 (или ранее) по 2018 год, в зависимости от наличия эмпирических данных по каждой стране до 1990 года.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Дезагрегирование:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Общее дезагрегирование показателей смертности включает дезагрегирование по полу, возрасту (новорожденный, младенец, ребенок), квинтилю благосостояния, месту жительства и образованию матери. Дезагрегированные данные не всегда доступны. Дезагрегирование по географическому местонахождению обычно осуществляется на региональном или минимальном муниципальном уровне для данных обследования или переписи населения. Данные из хорошо функционирующих систем регистрации актов гражданского состояния могут обеспечить получение дальнейших географических разрезностей.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Оценки Межучрежденческой группы ООН по оценке детской смертности (UN IGME) произведены на основе национальных данных. Страны часто используют единственный источник в качестве официальных оценок или применяют методы, отличные от методов UN IGME, для получения оценок. Различия между оценками UN IGME и национальными официальными оценками обычно невелики в случае, если эмпирические данные имеют хорошее качество.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Во многих странах отсутствует единственный источник высококачественных данных, охватывающий последние несколько десятилетий. Данные из различных источников требуют разных методов расчета и могут терять качество из-за разных ошибок, например случайных ошибок в выборочных обследованиях или систематических ошибок вследствие нарушения достоверности в отчетной информации. В результате различные обследования часто дают сильно различающиеся оценки смертности детей в возрасте до пяти лет за определенный период времени, а имеющиеся данные, собранные странами из различных источников, часто не соответствуют друг другу. Важно анализировать, согласовывать и оценивать все источники данных одновременно для каждой страны. Каждое новое обследование или элемент данных необходимо рассматривать в контексте всех других источников, включая предыдущие данные. Качество данных ухудшается из-за ошибок выборки или ошибок, не связанных с выборкой (например, неправильное указание возраста и систематическая ошибка отбора выживших; также распространено занижение сведений о детской смертности). UN IGME оценивает качество источников исходных данных и при необходимости корректирует данные. Более того, последние данные, представленные странами, часто не являются текущими оценками, а относятся к более раннему отчетному периоду. Таким образом, UN IGME также переносит оценки на общий базовый год. Чтобы согласовать эти различия и лучше учесть систематические ошибки, связанные с различными типами исходных данных, UN IGME разработала метод оценки, позволяющий подогнать сглаженную кривую тренда к набору наблюдений и экстраполировать этот тренд на определенный момент времени. UN IGME стремится свести к минимуму ошибки для каждой оценки, согласовать тренды в динамике и произвести актуальные и должным образом рассчитанные оценки детской смертности. При наличии ошибочных данных всегда будет возникать неопределенность в отношении данных и оценок. Чтобы обеспечить дополнительную сопоставимость, UN IGME производит такие оценки, имеющие диапазоны неопределенности. Применение последовательной методологии также позволяет проводить сравнения между странами, несмотря на различное количество и типы источников данных. UN IGME применяет единую методологию для разных стран и использует исходные эмпирические данные по каждой стране, но не представляет данные, полученные отдельными странами с использованием других методов, которые не были бы сопоставимы с оценками других стран. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://childmortality.org&quot;&gt; http://childmortality.org &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.unicef.org/topic/child-survival/neonatal-mortality/&quot;&gt; https://data.unicef.org/topic/child-survival/neonatal-mortality/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Ссылки: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Межучрежденческая группа Организации Объединенных Наций по оценке детской смертности (UN IGME). Тенденции уровней детской смертности. Отчет за 2019 год. Нью-Йорк: ЮНИСЕФ, 2019г. Доступно &lt;a href=&quot;at%20https:/childmortality.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/UN-IGME-Child-Mortality-Report-2019.pdf&quot;&gt; на https://childmortality.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/UN-IGME-Child-Mortality-Report-2019.pdf &lt;/a&gt; [ 653]
&lt;p&gt;Alexander, M. and L. Alkema, Global Estimation of Neonatal Mortality using a Bayesian Hierarchical Splines Regression Model Demographic Research, vol. 38, 2018, pp. 335&amp;#x2013;372.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alkema L, New JR. Global estimation of child mortality using a Bayesian B-spline bias-reduction method. The Annals of Applied Statistics. 2014; 8(4): 2122&amp;#x2013;2149. Доступно на: &lt;a href=&quot;http://arxiv.org/abs/1309.1602&quot;&gt;http://arxiv.org/abs/1309.1602&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alkema L, Chao F, You D, Pedersen J, Sawyer CC. National, regional, and global sex ratios of infant, child, and under-5 mortality and identification of countries with outlying ratios: a systematic assessment. The Lancet Global Health. 2014; 2(9): e521&amp;#x2013;e530.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pedersen J, Liu J. Child Mortality Estimation: Appropriate Time Periods for Child Mortality Estimates from Full Birth Histories. Plos Medicine. 2012;9(8). Доступно на: &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1001289&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1001289&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silva R. Child Mortality Estimation: Consistency of Under-Five Mortality Rate Estimates Using Full Birth Histories and Summary Birth Histories. Plos Medicine. 2012;9(8). Доступно на: &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1001296&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1001296&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walker N, Hill K, Zhao FM. Child Mortality Estimation: Methods Used to Adjust for Bias due to AIDS in Estimating Trends in Under-Five Mortality. Plos Medicine. 2012;9(8). Доступно на: &lt;a href=&quot;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1001298&quot;&gt;http://journals.plos.org/plosmedicine/article?id=10.1371/journal.pmed.1001298 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
