<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 3-3-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 3: Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 3.3: By 2030, end the epidemics of AIDS, tuberculosis, malaria and neglected tropical diseases and combat hepatitis, water-borne diseases and other communicable diseases&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 3.3.2: Tuberculosis incidence per 100,000 population&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable&lt;/p&gt;2022-03-31&lt;p&gt;Indicators associated with TB incidence: numbers: 1.1.1, 1.3.1, 2.1.1, 3.3.1, 3.4.1, 3.5.2, 3.a.1, 3.8.1, 3.8.2, 7.1.2, 8.1.1, 10.1.1, 11.1.1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;World Health Organization (WHO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;World Health Organization (WHO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tuberculosis incidence per 100 000 population is defined as the estimated number of new and relapse TB cases (all forms of TB, including cases in people living with HIV) arising in a given year, expressed as a rate per 100 000 population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Direct measurement requires high-quality surveillance systems in which underreporting is negligible, and strong health systems so that under-diagnosis is also negligible; otherwise indirect estimates are based on notification data and estimates of levels of underreporting and under-diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Number of cases per 100,000 population per year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Definitions and reporting framework for tuberculosis &amp;#x2013; 2013 revision (WHO/HTM/TB/2013.2). Geneva: World Health Organization; 2013 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241505345&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241505345&lt;/u&gt; &lt;/a&gt;accessed 4 January 2021).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Details about data sources and methods are available in annex 1 and the online technical annex published in the most recent WHO Global Tuberculosis Report at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://www.who.int/teams/global-&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;tuberculosis-programme/data&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National TB Programmes report their annual TB data to WHO every year between March and June using a standardized online data reporting system maintained at WHO. The system includes real-time checks for data consistency. Estimates of TB burden are prepared in July-August and communicated with countries. In selected countries with new survey data, estimates are updated separately during the year. All estimates are communicated in August-September and revisions are done based on feedback. The final set of estimates is reviewed in WHO before publication in October, for compliance with specific international standards and harmonization of breakdowns for age and sex groups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;April-June each year&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;October each year&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National TB Programmes, Ministries of Health&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;World Health Organization (WHO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several World Health Organization resolutions endorsed by Member States at different World Health Assemblies have given the World Health Organization responsibility for monitoring the burden of TB globally and reporting on the response:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global strategy and targets for tuberculosis prevention, care and control after 2015, World Health Organization, 67th World Health Assembly, Resolutions and decisions, Resolution WHA 67.11, Geneva, Switzerland, 2014. &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA67-REC1/A67_2014_REC1-en.pdf#page=25&quot;&gt;https://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA67-REC1/A67_2014_REC1-en.pdf#page=25&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prevention and control of multidrug-resistant tuberculosis and extensively drug-resistant tuberculosis, World Health Organization, 62nd World Health Assembly, Resolutions and decisions, Resolution WHA 62.15, Geneva, Switzerland, 2009. &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA62-REC1/WHA62_REC1-en-P2.pdf#page=25&quot;&gt;https://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA62-REC1/WHA62_REC1-en-P2.pdf#page=25&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuberculosis control: progress and long-term planning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World Health Organization. 60th World Health Assembly. Resolutions and decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resolution WHA 60.19. Geneva, Switzerland: WHO; 2007. &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHASSA_WHA60-Rec1/E/WHASS1_WHA60REC1-en.pdf#page=67&quot;&gt;https://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHASSA_WHA60-Rec1/E/WHASS1_WHA60REC1-en.pdf#page=67&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sustainable financing for tuberculosis prevention and control&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World Health Organization. 58th World Health Assembly. Resolutions and decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resolution WHA 58.14. Geneva, Switzerland: WHO; 2005. https://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA58-REC1/english/A58_2005_REC1-en.pdf#page=96&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop Tuberculosis Initiative&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World Health Organization. 53rd World Health Assembly. Resolutions and decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resolution WHA 53.1. Geneva, Switzerland: WHO; 2000. &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA53-REC1/WHA53-2000-REC1-eng.pdf#page=18&quot;&gt;https://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA53-REC1/WHA53-2000-REC1-eng.pdf#page=18&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuberculosis control programme&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World Health Organization. 44th World Health Assembly. Resolutions and decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resolution WHA44.8. Geneva, Switzerland: WHO, 1991.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pdf, 76kb&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following two years of consultations, a post-2015 global tuberculosis strategy was endorsed by the World Health Assembly in May 2014. Known as the End TB Strategy, it covers the period 2016-2035. The overall goal is to &amp;#x201C;End the global tuberculosis epidemic&amp;#x201D;, and correspondingly ambitious targets for reductions in tuberculosis deaths and cases are set for 2030 (80% reduction in incidence rate compared with the level of 2015) and 2035 (90% reduction in incidence rate), in the context of the SDGs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tuberculosis incidence rate was selected as an indicator for measuring reductions in the number of cases of disease burden. Although this indicator was estimated with considerable uncertainty in most countries in 2014, notifications of cases to national authorities provide a good proxy if there is limited under-reporting of detected cases and limited under or over-diagnosis of cases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;TB incidence has been used for over a century as a main indicator of TB burden, along with TB mortality. The indicator allows comparisons over time and between countries. Improvement in the quality of TB surveillance data result in reduced uncertainty about indicator values.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Estimates of TB incidence are produced through a consultative and analytical process led by WHO and are published annually. These estimates are based on annual case notifications, assessments of the quality and coverage of TB notification data, national surveys of the prevalence of TB disease and information from death (vital) registration systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimates of incidence for each country are derived, using one or more of the following approaches depending on available data: (i) incidence = case notifications/estimated proportion of cases detected; (ii) capture-recapture modelling, (iii) incidence = prevalence/duration of condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uncertainty bounds are provided in addition to best estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details are available from TB impact measurement: policy and recommendations for how to assess the epidemiological burden of TB and the impact of TB control (https:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241598828)&quot;&gt;//www.who&lt;/a&gt;.i&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241598828)&quot;&gt;nt/publications/i/item/9789241598828) &lt;/a&gt;and from the online technical appendix to the WHO global tuberculosis report at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&quot;&gt;programme/data.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Estimates of TB burden are prepared in July-August and communicated with countries. In selected countries with new survey data, estimates are updated separately during the year. All estimates are communicated in August-September and revisions are done based on feedback. The final set of estimates is reviewed in WHO before publication in October, for compliance with specific international standards and harmonization of breakdowns for age and sex groups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The final set of estimates is reviewed in WHO before publication in October, for compliance with specific international standards and harmonization of breakdowns for age and sex groups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details available in the technical appendix of each WHO Global Tuberculosis Report at https:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&quot;&gt;//www.who&lt;/a&gt;.i&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&quot;&gt;nt/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details available in the technical appendix of each WHO Global Tuberculosis Report at https:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&quot;&gt;//ww&lt;/a&gt;w&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&quot;&gt;.wh&lt;/a&gt;o&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&quot;&gt;.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Country estimates of case counts are aggregated. Uncertainty is propagated assuming independence of country estimates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Available at Definitions and reporting framework for tuberculosis &amp;#x2013; 2013 revision (WHO/HTM/TB/2013.2). Geneva: World Health Organization; 2013 (https:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241505345&quot;&gt;//www.who&lt;/a&gt;.i&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241505345&quot;&gt;nt/publications/i/item/9789241505345, &lt;/a&gt;accessed 4 January 2021).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All health statistics published by WHO undergo a systematic internal review process from the Data Division, including TB burden statistics. External review of specific statistics is conducted in various ways, including through country consultations and reviews by technical review bodies such as the WHO Task Force on TB Impact Measurement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The underlying TB data reported by WHO member states is carefully checked for completeness and internal consistency. Additional data sources are used in the process of disease burden estimation, including survey results, according to methods published in WHO documents mentioned in previous sections and cited in section 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;TB surveillance data are assessed systematically through so-called epidemiological reviews, which provide data quality scores used to update plans for strengthening TB surveillance and used in models to estimate the burden of TB. In addition, the data are reviewed internally for consistency. Data and estimates are published in the form of country profiles used in systematic consultations with countries, as mentioned in previous sections and cited in section 7. Results are published in detail in publicly available annual global TB reports&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All countries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2000 onwards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is disaggregated by country, sex and age group and five risk factors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Population denominators may differ between national sources and United Nations Population Division (UNPD). WHO uses UNPD population estimates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;URL:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;References:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest WHO Global Tuberculosis Report: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;programme/data&lt;/u&gt;, &lt;/a&gt;accessed 4 January 2021).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitions and reporting framework for tuberculosis &amp;#x2013; 2013 revision (WHO/HTM/TB/2013.2). Geneva: World Health Organization; 2013 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241505345&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241505345&lt;/u&gt; &lt;/a&gt;accessed 4 January 2021).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TB Impact measurement: Policy and recommendations for how to assess the epidemiological burden of TB and the impact of TB control (WHO/HTM/TB/2009.416). Geneva: World Health Organization; 2009 (https:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241598828)&quot;&gt;//www.who&lt;/a&gt;.i&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241598828)&quot;&gt;nt/publications/i/item/9789241598828).&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World Health Assembly governing body documentation: official records. Geneva: World Health Organization &lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gb/or/&quot;&gt;(ht&lt;/a&gt;t&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gb/or/&quot;&gt;ps://apps.who.int/gb/or/, &lt;/a&gt;accessed 21 June 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 3: Garantizar una vida sana y promover el bienestar de todos a todas las edades&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 3.3: De aquí a 2030, poner fin a las epidemias del SIDA, la tuberculosis, la malaria y las enfermedades tropicales desatendidas y combatir la hepatitis, las enfermedades transmitidas por el agua y otras enfermedades transmisibles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 3.3.2: Incidencia de la tuberculosis por cada 100.000 habitantes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Última actualización: 09 de enero de 2018&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Información institucional &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Organización (es): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Organización Mundial de la Salud (OMS) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La incidencia de la tuberculosis por cada 100.000 habitantes se define como el número estimado de casos de tuberculosis nuevos y de recaída (todas las formas de tuberculosis, incluidos los casos en personas que viven con el VIH) que surgen en un año determinado, expresado como una tasa por cada 100.000 habitantes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La medición directa requiere sistemas de monitoreo de alta calidad en los que el subregistro sea insignificante, y sistemas de salud fuertes para que el subdiagnóstico también sea insignificante; de lo contrario, las estimaciones indirectas se basan en datos de notificación y en estimaciones de los niveles de subregistro y subdiagnóstico.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los detalles sobre las fuentes de datos y los métodos están disponibles en el siguiente documento público:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/papers/1603/1603.00278.pdf&quot;&gt;https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/papers/1603/1603.00278.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proceso de recolección&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los programas nacionales de tuberculosis comunican cada año, entre marzo y junio, sus datos anuales sobre la tuberculosis a la OMS mediante un sistema estandarizado de comunicación de datos en línea mantenido en la OMS. El sistema incluye comprobaciones en tiempo real de la coherencia de los datos. Las estimaciones de la carga de tuberculosis se preparan en julio-agosto y se comunican a los países. En algunos países con nuevos datos de encuestas, las estimaciones se actualizan por separado durante el año. Todas las estimaciones se comunican en agosto-septiembre y se revisan en función de los comentarios recibidos. El conjunto final de estimaciones se revisa en la OMS antes de su publicación en octubre, para comprobar el cumplimiento de las normas internacionales específicas y la armonización de los desgloses por grupos de edad y sexo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendario&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recolección de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;actual: Marzo-junio de cada año&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publicación de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Octubre de cada año&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programas nacionales de tuberculosis, Ministerios de Salud&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OMS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tras dos años de consultas, la Asamblea Mundial de la Salud aprobó en mayo de 2014 una nueva estrategia mundial contra la tuberculosis post-2015. Conocida como la Estrategia para Acabar con la Tuberculosis, abarca el periodo 2016-2035. El objetivo general es &amp;#x201C;Poner fin a la epidemia mundial de tuberculosis&amp;#x201D;, y se fijaron las correspondientes metas ambiciosas de reducción de muertes y casos de tuberculosis para 2030 (reducción del 80% de la tasa de incidencia en comparación con el nivel de 2015) y 2035 (reducción del 90% de la tasa de incidencia), en el contexto de los ODS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La tasa de incidencia de la tuberculosis fue seleccionada como indicador para medir la reducción del número de casos de carga de morbilidad. Aunque este indicador se estimó con una incertidumbre considerable en la mayoría de los países en 2014, las notificaciones de casos a las autoridades nacionales proporcionan una buena aproximación si hay un subreporte limitado de los casos detectados y un subdiagnóstico o sobrediagnóstico limitado de los casos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La incidencia de tuberculosis se ha utilizado durante más de un siglo como principal indicador de la carga de tuberculosis, junto con la mortalidad por tuberculosis. El indicador permite comparaciones a lo largo del tiempo y entre países. La mejora de la calidad de los datos de monitoreo de la tuberculosis genera una menor incertidumbre sobre los valores de los indicadores. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las estimaciones de la incidencia de la tuberculosis se elaboran mediante un proceso consultivo y analítico dirigido por la OMS y se publican anualmente. Estas estimaciones se basan en las notificaciones anuales de casos, las evaluaciones de la calidad y la cobertura de los datos de notificación de la tuberculosis, las encuestas nacionales sobre la prevalencia de la enfermedad de la tuberculosis y la información de los sistemas de registro de defunciones (vitales).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Las estimaciones de incidencia para cada país se obtienen utilizando uno o más de los siguientes enfoques, según los datos disponibles: (i) incidencia = notificaciones de casos/proporción estimada de casos detectados; (ii) modelización de captura-recaptura, (iii) incidencia = prevalencia/duración de la enfermedad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Además de las mejores estimaciones se proporcionan los límites de incertidumbre . &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; Los detalles están disponibles en la &quot;Medición del impacto de la TB: política y recomendaciones sobre cómo evaluar la carga epidemiológica de la TB y el impacto del control de la TB &quot;y en el apéndice técnico en línea del &quot;Informe mundial sobre la tuberculosis de la OMS de 2017&quot; y &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1603.00278&quot;&gt; https: // arxiv.org/abs/1603.00278&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel de país:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detalles disponibles en el siguiente documento de acceso público:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/papers/1603/1603.00278.pdf&quot;&gt;https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/papers/1603/1603.00278.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel regional y mundial:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detalles disponibles en el siguiente documento de acceso público:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/papers/1603/1603.00278.pdf&quot;&gt;https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/papers/1603/1603.00278.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se agregan las estimaciones de los recuentos de casos de los países. La incertidumbre se distribuye asumiendo la independencia de las estimaciones de los países.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todos los países&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De 2000 en adelante&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador está desagregado por país, sexo y edad (niños vs adultos).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Fuentes de discrepancias:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Los denominadores de población pueden diferir entre las fuentes nacionales y la DPNU. La OMS utiliza estimaciones de población de la DPNU. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/tb/country/data/download/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/tb/country/data/download/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Referencias:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Informe mundial sobre la tuberculosis 2017 de la OMS: (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/tb/publications/global_report/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/tb/publications/global_report/en/&lt;/a&gt;, consultado el 09 de enero de 2018).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Métodos utilizados por la OMS para estimar la carga mundial de la enfermedad de tuberculosis: &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/papers/1603/1603.00278.pdf&quot;&gt;https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/papers/1603/1603.00278.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definiciones y marco de notificación de la tuberculosis &amp;#x2013; revisión de 2013 (WHO/HTM/TB/2013.2). Ginebra: Organización Mundial de la Salud; 2013 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/tb/publications/definitions/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/tb/publications/definitions/en/&lt;/a&gt;, consultado el 21 de junio de 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentación de los órganos deliberantes de la Asamblea Mundial de la Salud: actas oficiales. Ginebra: Organización Mundial de la Salud (&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gb/or/&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gb/or/&lt;/a&gt;, consultado el 21 de junio de 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 3 : Permettre à tous de vivre en bonne santé et promouvoir le bien-être de tous à tout âge&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 3.3 : D’ici 2030, mettre fin à l’épidémie de sida, à la tuberculose, au paludisme et aux maladies tropicales négligées et combattre l’hépatite, les maladies transmises par l’eau et d&apos;autres maladies transmissibles &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 3.3.2 : Incidence de la tuberculose pour 100 000 habitants &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sans objet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2022-03-31&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateurs associés à l&apos;incidence de la tuberculose : 1.1.1, 1.3.1, 2.1.1, 3.3.1, 3.4.1, 3.5.2, 3.a.1, 3.8.1, 3.8.2, 7.1.2, 8.1.1, 10.1.1, 11.1.1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organisation mondiale de la Santé (OMS)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organisation mondiale de la Santé (OMS)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;incidence de la tuberculose pour 100 000 habitants est définie comme le nombre estimé de nouveaux cas et de rechutes de tuberculose (toutes les formes de tuberculose, y compris les cas chez les personnes vivant avec le VIH) survenant au cours d&apos;une année donnée, exprimé en taux pour 100 000 habitants. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts :&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La mesure directe nécessite des systèmes de surveillance de haute qualité dans lesquels la sous-déclaration est négligeable, et des systèmes de santé solides de sorte que le sous-diagnostic soit également négligeable; sinon, les estimations indirectes sont basées sur les données de notification et les estimations des niveaux de sous-déclaration et de sous-diagnostic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nombre de cas pour 100 000 habitants par année.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Définitions et cadre de notification pour la tuberculose – Révision 2013 (WHO/HTM/TB/2013.2). Genève : Organisation mondiale de la Santé; 2013 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/fr/publications/i/item/9789241505345&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://www.who.int/fr/publications/i/item/9789241505345&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; consulté le 4 janvier 2021).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Des détails sur les sources de données et les méthodes sont disponibles dans l&apos;annexe 1 et l&apos;annexe technique en ligne publiées dans le dernier Rapport mondial sur la tuberculose de l&apos;OMS (en anglais) à l&apos;adresse &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les programmes nationaux de lutte antituberculeuse communiquent leurs données annuelles sur la tuberculose à l&apos;OMS chaque année entre mars et juin à l&apos;aide d&apos;un système normalisé de communication des données en ligne géré par l&apos;OMS. Ce système comprend des contrôles en temps réel de la cohérence des données. Les estimations du fardeau de la tuberculose sont préparées en juillet-août et communiquées aux pays. Dans certains pays disposant de nouvelles données d&apos;enquête, les estimations sont mises à jour séparément au cours de l&apos;année. Toutes les estimations sont communiquées en août-septembre et les révisions sont effectuées en fonction des réactions. La série finale d&apos;estimations est examinée par l&apos;OMS avant d&apos;être publiée en octobre, pour vérifier la conformité aux normes internationales spécifiques et l&apos;harmonisation des ventilations pour les groupes d&apos;âge et de sexe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Avril à juin de chaque année&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Octobre de chaque année&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Programmes nationaux de lutte contre la tuberculose, ministères de la Santé&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organisation mondiale de la Santé (OMS)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plusieurs résolutions de l’Organisation mondiale de la Santé (OMS) approuvées par les États Membres lors de différentes Assemblées mondiales de la Santé ont confié à l’OMS la responsabilité de surveiller le fardeau de la tuberculose à l’échelle mondiale et de rendre compte de la réponse :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Projet de stratégie mondiale et cibles pour la prévention de la tuberculose, les soins et la lutte après 2015, Organisation mondiale de la Santé, 67e Assemblée mondiale de la Santé, Résolutions et décisions, Résolution WHA 67.11, Genève, Suisse, 2014. &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA67-REC1/A67_2014_REC1-fr.pdf#page=25&quot;&gt;https://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA67-REC1/A67_2014_REC1-fr.pdf#page=25&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuberculose multirésistante et ultrarésistante : prévention et lutte, Organisation mondiale de la Santé, 62e Assemblée mondiale de la Santé, Résolutions et décisions, Résolution WHA 62.15, Genève, Suisse, 2009. &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA62-REC1/WHA62_REC1-fr-P2.pdf#page=25&quot;&gt;https://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA62-REC1/WHA62_REC1-fr-P2.pdf#page=25&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;« Tuberculosis control: progress and long-term planning », Organisation mondiale de la Santé, 60e Assemblée mondiale de la Santé, Résolutions et décisions, Résolution WHA 60.19. Genève, Suisse, 2007. &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHASSA_WHA60-Rec1/E/WHASS1_WHA60REC1-en.pdf#page=67&quot;&gt;https://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHASSA_WHA60-Rec1/E/WHASS1_WHA60REC1-en.pdf#page=67&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;« Sustainable financing for tuberculosis prevention and control », Organisation mondiale de la Santé, 58e Assemblée mondiale de la Santé, Résolutions et décisions, Résolution WHA 58.14. Genève, Suisse, 2005. https://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA58-REC1/english/A58_2005_REC1-en.pdf#page=96&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;« Stop Tuberculosis Initiative », Organisation mondiale de la Santé, 58e Assemblée mondiale de la Santé, Résolutions et décisions, Résolution WHA 53.1. Genève, Suisse, 2000. &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA53-REC1/WHA53-2000-REC1-eng.pdf#page=18&quot;&gt;https://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA53-REC1/WHA53-2000-REC1-eng.pdf#page=18&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;« Tuberculosis control programme », Organisation mondiale de la Santé, 44e Assemblée mondiale de la Santé, Résolutions et décisions, Résolution WHA44.8. Genève, Suisse, 1991.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Après deux ans de consultations, une stratégie mondiale de lutte contre la tuberculose pour l&apos;après-2015 a été approuvée par l&apos;Assemblée mondiale de la Santé en mai 2014. Connue sous le nom de stratégie pour mettre fin à la tuberculose, elle couvre la période de 2016 à 2035. L&apos;objectif global est « de mettre fin à l&apos;épidémie mondiale de tuberculose » et par le même effet viser l&apos;atteinte d&apos;objectifs ambitieux de réduction des décès et des cas de tuberculoses pour 2030 (80% de réduction du taux d&apos;incidence par rapport au niveau de 2015) et 2035 (90 % de réduction du taux d&apos;incidence), dans le cadre des objectifs de développement durable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le taux d&apos;incidence de la tuberculose a été choisi comme indicateur pour mesurer la réduction du nombre de cas du fardeau de cette maladie. Bien que cet indicateur ait été estimé avec une incertitude considérable dans la plupart des pays en 2014, les notifications de cas aux autorités nationales fournissent une bonne approximation s&apos;il y a une sous-déclaration limitée des cas détectés et un sous-diagnostic ou un surdiagnostic limité des cas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L’incidence de la tuberculose est utilisée depuis plus d’un siècle comme principal indicateur du fardeau de la tuberculose, ainsi que de la mortalité qui s&apos;y rattache. L’indicateur permet des comparaisons au fil du temps et entre les pays. L’amélioration de la qualité des données de surveillance de la tuberculose entraîne une réduction de l’incertitude quant à la valeur des indicateurs. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les estimations de l&apos;incidence de la tuberculose sont produites par un processus consultatif et analytique dirigé par l&apos;OMS et sont publiées chaque année. Ces estimations sont fondées sur les notifications annuelles de cas, les évaluations de la qualité et de la couverture des données de notification de la tuberculose, les enquêtes nationales sur la prévalence de la tuberculose et les informations provenant des systèmes d&apos;enregistrement des décès (état civil). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les estimations de l&apos;incidence pour chaque pays sont dérivées, en utilisant une ou plusieurs des approches suivantes selon les données disponibles : (i) incidence = notifications de cas/proportion estimée de cas détectés, (ii) modélisation par saisie-resaisie, (iii) incidence = prévalence/durée de l&apos;affection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les intervalles de confiance sont fournis en plus des meilleures estimations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des détails sont disponibles dans le document (en anglais) « TB impact measurement – Policy and recommendations for how to assess the epidemiological burden of TB and the impact of TB control » (https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241598828) et dans l&apos;annexe technique en ligne du rapport mondial de l&apos;OMS sur la tuberculose (en anglais) à l&apos;adresse &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les estimations du fardeau de la tuberculose sont préparées en juillet-août et communiquées aux pays. Dans certains pays disposant de nouvelles données d&apos;enquête, les estimations sont mises à jour séparément au cours de l&apos;année. Toutes les estimations sont communiquées en août-septembre et les révisions sont effectuées en fonction des rétroactions. La série finale d&apos;estimations est examinée par l&apos;OMS avant d&apos;être publiée en octobre, pour vérifier la conformité aux normes internationales spécifiques et l&apos;harmonisation des ventilations pour les groupes d&apos;âge et de sexe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;La série finale d&apos;estimations est examinée par l&apos;OMS avant sa publication en octobre, pour vérifier la conformité aux normes internationales spécifiques et l&apos;harmonisation des ventilations pour les groupes d&apos;âge et de sexe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; Au niveau national :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des détails sont disponibles dans l&apos;annexe technique de chaque Rapport mondial de l&apos;OMS sur la tuberculose (en anglais) à l&apos;adresse &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; Aux niveaux régional et mondial :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des détails sont disponibles dans l&apos;annexe technique de chaque Rapport mondial de l&apos;OMS sur la tuberculose (en anglais) à l&apos;adresse &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les estimations du nombre de cas par pays sont agrégées. L’incertitude se propage en supposant l’indépendance des estimations des pays.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disponible dans le document Définitions et cadre de notification pour la tuberculose – Révision 2013 (WHO/HTM/TB/2013.2). Genève : Organisation mondiale de la Santé; 2013 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/fr/publications/i/item/9789241505345&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/fr/publications/i/item/9789241505345&lt;/a&gt;, consulté le 4 janvier 2021). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Toutes les statistiques sanitaires publiées par l&apos;OMS font l&apos;objet d&apos;un examen interne systématique de la part de la Division des données, y compris les statistiques sur le fardeau de la tuberculose. L&apos;examen externe de statistiques spécifiques est effectué de diverses manières, notamment par le biais de consultations avec les pays et d&apos;examens par des organismes d&apos;examen technique tels que le groupe de travail de l&apos;OMS sur la mesure de l&apos;impact de la tuberculose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les données sur la tuberculose déclarées par les États membres de l&apos;OMS sont soigneusement vérifiées pour s&apos;assurer de leur exhaustivité et de leur cohérence interne. Des sources de données supplémentaires sont utilisées dans le processus d&apos;estimation du fardeau de morbidité, notamment les résultats d&apos;enquêtes, conformément aux méthodes publiées dans les documents de l&apos;OMS mentionnés dans les sections précédentes et cités à la section 7. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les données de surveillance de la tuberculose sont évaluées systématiquement par des examens dits épidémiologiques, qui fournissent des scores de qualité des données utilisés pour mettre à jour les plans de renforcement de la surveillance de la tuberculose et utilisés dans les modèles pour estimer le fardeau de la tuberculose. En outre, les données sont examinées à l&apos;interne pour en vérifier la cohérence. Les données et les estimations sont publiées sous la forme de profils nationaux utilisés dans les consultations systématiques avec les pays, tel que mentionné dans les sections précédentes et cité dans la section 7. Les résultats sont publiés en détail dans les rapports annuels mondiaux sur la tuberculose, accessibles au public.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disponibilité des données :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tous les pays &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Séries chronologiques :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;À partir de 2000 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Désagrégation :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur est désagrégé par pays, sexe et groupe d&apos;âge et cinq facteurs de risque.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources des divergences :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les dénominateurs de population peuvent différer entre les sources nationales et les données de la Division de la population des Nations Unies. L&apos;OMS utilise les estimations démographiques de celle-ci.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL : &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(en anglais)&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Références :&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le dernier Rapport mondial sur la tuberculose de l&apos;OMS (en anglais) : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/teams/global-tuberculosis-programme/data&lt;/a&gt;, consulté le 4 janvier 2021). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Définitions et cadre de notification pour la tuberculose – Révision 2013 (WHO/HTM/TB/2013.2). Genève : Organisation mondiale de la Santé; 2013 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/fr/publications/i/item/9789241505345&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/fr/publications/i/item/9789241505345&lt;/a&gt; consulté le 4 janvier 2021). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(en anglais) « TB Impact measurement – Policy and recommendations for how to assess the epidemiological burden of TB and the impact of TB control » (WHO/HTM/TB/2009.416). Genève : Organisation mondiale de la Santé; 2009 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241598828&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241598828&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation des organismes directeurs de l&apos;Assemblée mondiale de la Santé : Actes officiels. Genève : Organisation mondiale de la Santé (&lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.who.int/gb/or/f/index.html&quot;&gt;https://apps.who.int/gb/or/f/index.html&lt;/a&gt;, consulté le 21 juin 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 3: Garantir o acesso á saude de qualidade e promover o bem-estar para todos, em todas as idades&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 3: Обеспечение здорового образа жизни и содействие благополучию для всех в любом возрасте&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 3.3: К 2030 году положить конец эпидемиям СПИДа, туберкулеза, малярии и тропических болезней, которым не уделяется должного внимания, и обеспечить борьбу с гепатитом, заболеваниями, передаваемыми через воду, и другими инфекционными заболеваниями&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 3.3.2: Заболеваемость туберкулезом на 100 000 че­ловек&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Последнее обновление: 9 января 2018 года &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Институциональная информация &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Организация (и): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Всемирная организация здравоохранения (ВОЗ) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Заболеваемость туберкулезом на 100 000 человек населения, определяемая как оценочное количество новых случаев заболеваний и рецидивов ТБ (все формы ТБ, включая случаи у людей, живущих с ВИЧ), возникших в данном году, отражающая уровень заболеваемости на 100 000 человек населения. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для прямой подсчета требуется наличие высококачественных систем санэпиднадзора, в которых занижение информации является незначительным, и хорошо развитых систем здравоохранения, в которых занижение числа диагнозов также незначительно; в противном случае косвенные оценки должны основываться на данных уведомлений и оценках уровней неполной отчетности и заниженных данных диагностики. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Подробная информация об источниках данных и методах доступна в следующем общедоступном документе: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/papers/1603/1603.00278.pdf&quot;&gt; https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/papers/1603/1603.00278.pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Процесс сбора &lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Национальные программы по борьбе с туберкулезом ежегодно с марта по июнь представляют в ВОЗ свои годовые данные по туберкулезу, используя стандартизированную онлайн-систему отчетности, поддерживаемую ВОЗ. Система включает в себя проверку согласованности данных в реальном времени. Оценки бремени туберкулеза готовятся в июле-августе и доводятся до сведения стран. В отдельных странах, имеющих новые данные обследований, оценки обновляются отдельно в течение года. Все оценки доводятся до сведения стран в августе-сентябре, и изменения вносятся на основании полученных от них отзывов. Окончательный набор оценок рассматривается в ВОЗ перед публикацией в октябре на предмет соответствия конкретным международным стандартам и согласования разбивки по половозрастным группам. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Календарь &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Сбор данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В настоящее время: ежегодно в марте-июне &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Выпуск данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Ежегодно в октябре &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Поставщики данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Национальные программы по борьбе с туберкулезом, министерства здравоохранения &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Составители данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ВОЗ &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; После двух лет консультаций в мае 2014 года Всемирная ассамблея здравоохранения одобрила новую глобальную стратегию борьбы с туберкулезом на период после 2015 года. Эта стратегия, известная как Стратегия ликвидации туберкулеза, охватывает период 2016-2035 годов. Общая цель состоит в том, чтобы «положить конец глобальной эпидемии туберкулеза», и, соответственно, в ней установлены амбициозные цели по снижению смертности и заболеваемости туберкулезом на период до 2030 года (снижение заболеваемости на 80% по сравнению с уровнем 2015 года) и на 2035 год (снижение заболеваемости на 90%) в контексте ЦУР. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Уровень заболеваемости туберкулезом был выбран в качестве показателя для оценки сокращения числа случаев бремени болезни. Несмотря на то, что в 2014 году этот показатель в большинстве стран оценивался со значительной неопределенностью, уведомления о случаях в национальные органы являются хорошим косвенным показателем, если имеется случаи ограниченного числа занижения сведений о выявленных случаях, а также недоучтенных или переучтенных случаев диагностики. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Заболеваемость ТБ, наряду со смертностью от ТБ, использовалась более века в качестве основного показателя бремени ТБ. Показатель позволяет проводить сравнения в динамике и между странами. Повышение качества данных санэпиднадзора за туберкулезом приводит к снижению неопределенности в отношении значений показателей. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Оценки заболеваемости ТБ производятся в рамках консультативно-аналитического процесса под руководством ВОЗ и публикуются ежегодно. Эти оценки основаны на ежегодных уведомлениях о случаях заболевания, оценке качества и охвате данных уведомлений о ТБ, национальных исследованиях распространенности ТБ и информации из систем регистрации смертей (регистрации актов гражданского состояния). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Оценки заболеваемости для каждой страны производятся с использованием одного или нескольких из следующих подходов в зависимости от имеющихся данных: (i) заболеваемость = уведомления о случаях / расчетная доля выявленных случаев; (ii) моделирование выявления-повторного выявления, (iii) заболеваемость = распространенность / продолжительность состояния. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Границы неопределенности приводятся в дополнение к наилучшим оценкам. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Подробная информация доступна в разделе Оценка воздействия ТБ: политика и рекомендации по оценке эпидемиологического бремени ТБ и воздействия контроля за ТБ, а также в техническом приложении (в онлайн-режиме) к Глобальному докладу ВОЗ о туберкулезе за 2017 год и &lt;a href = &quot;https: //arxiv.org/abs/1603.00278&quot;&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/1603.00278&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Подробности изложены в следующем общедоступном документе: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/papers/1603/1603.00278.pdf&quot;&gt; https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/papers/1603/1603.00278.pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Подробности изложены в следующем общедоступном документе: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/papers/1603/1603.00278.pdf&quot;&gt; https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/papers/1603/1603.00278.pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Региональные агрегаты:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Страновые оценки количества случаев являются агрегированными. Неопределенность распространяется при условии независимости страновых оценок.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; По всем странам &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Начиная с 2000 года &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель дезагрегирован по странам, полу и возрасту (дети и взрослые). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Численность населения, применяемая в знаменатели, может отличаться в зависимости от того, чьи данные используются: из национальных источников или из Отдела народонаселения ООН. ВОЗ использует оценки численности населения из Отдела народонаселения ООН. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; URL: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/tb/country/data/download/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/tb/country/data/download/en &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Ссылки: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Глобальный доклад ВОЗ по туберкулезу, за 2017 год: (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/tb/publications/global_report/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/tb/publications/global_report/en/&lt;/a&gt;, по состоянию на 9 января 2018 года) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Методы, используемые ВОЗ для оценки глобального бремени ТБ: &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/papers/1603/1603.00278.pdf&quot;&gt;https://arxiv.org/ftp/arxiv/papers/1603/1603.00278.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Определения и структура отчетности по туберкулезу &amp;#x2013;, редакция 2013 года (WHO/HTM/TB/2013.2). Женева: Всемирная организация здравоохранения; 2013 год (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/tb/publications/definitions/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/tb/publications/definitions/en &lt;/a&gt;, по состоянию на 21 июня 2016 года) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Документы руководящего органа Всемирной ассамблеи здравоохранения: официальные отчеты. Женева: Всемирная организация здравоохранения (&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gb/or/&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gb/or &lt;/a&gt;, по состоянию на 21 июня 2016 года). &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
