<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 3-4-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 3: Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 3.4: By 2030, reduce by one third premature mortality from non-communicable diseases through prevention and treatment and promote mental health and well-being &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 3.4.1: Mortality rate attributed to cardiovascular disease, cancer, diabetes or chronic respiratory disease &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;March 2021&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;World Health Organization (WHO) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;World Health Organization (WHO)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Definitions: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mortality rate attributed to cardiovascular disease, cancer, diabetes or chronic respiratory disease. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probability of dying between the ages of 30 and 70 years from cardiovascular diseases, cancer, diabetes or chronic respiratory diseases, defined as the per cent of 30-year-old-people who would die before their 70th birthday from cardiovascular disease, cancer, diabetes, or chronic respiratory disease, assuming that s/he would experience current mortality rates at every age and s/he would not die from any other cause of death (e.g., injuries or HIV/AIDS). This indicator is calculated using life table methods (see further details in section 3.3). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concepts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probability of dying: The likelihood that an individual would die between two ages given current mortality rates at each age, calculated using life table methods. The probability of death between two ages may be called a mortality rate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life table: A table showing the mortality experience of a hypothetical group of infants born at the same time and subject throughout their lifetime to a set of age-specific mortality rates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cardiovascular disease, cancer, diabetes or chronic respiratory diseases: ICD-10 underlying causes of death I00-I99, COO-C97, E10-E14 and J30-J98. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Probability&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The four noncommunicable causes of death are defined in terms of the International Classification of Diseases, Tenth Revision (ICD-10) (See 2.a)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The preferred data source is death registration systems with complete coverage and medical certification of cause of death. Other possible data sources include household surveys with verbal autopsy, and sample or sentinel registration systems. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WHO conducts a formal country consultation process before releasing its cause-of-death estimates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WHO annually requests tabulated death registration data (including all causes of death) from Member States. Countries may submit annual cause-of-death statistics to WHO on an ongoing basis. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;End of 2020. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National statistics offices and/or ministries of health. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WHO &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Article 64 of its constitution, WHO is mandated to request each Member State to provide statistics on mortality. Furthermore, the WHO Nomenclature Regulations of 1967 affirms the importance of compiling and publishing statistics of mortality and morbidity in comparable form. Member States started to report mortality data to WHO since the early fifties and this reporting activity is continuing until today. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disease burden from non-communicable diseases (NCDs) among adults is rapidly increasing globally due to ageing and epidemiological transitions. Cardiovascular diseases, cancer, diabetes and chronic respiratory diseases are the four main causes of NCD burden. Measuring the risk of dying from these four major causes is important to assess the extent of burden from premature mortality due NCDs in a population. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cause of death estimates have large uncertainty ranges for some causes and some regions. Data gaps and limitations in high-mortality regions reinforce the need for caution when interpreting global comparative cause of death assessments, as well as the need for increased investment in population health measurement systems. The use of verbal autopsy methods in sample registration systems, demographic surveillance systems and household surveys provides some information on causes of death in populations without well-functioning death registration systems, but there remain considerable challenges in the validation and interpretation of such data, and in the assessment of uncertainty associated with diagnoses of underlying cause of death. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The methods used for the analysis of causes of death depend on the type of data available from countries: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For countries with a high-quality vital registration system including information on cause of death, the vital registration that member states submit to the WHO Mortality Database were used, with adjustments where necessary, e.g. for under-reporting of deaths, unknown age and sex, and ill-defined causes of deaths. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For countries without high-quality death registration data, cause of death estimates are calculated using other data, including household surveys with verbal autopsy, sample or sentinel registration systems, special studies and surveillance systems. In most cases, these data sources are combined in a modelling framework. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The probability of dying between ages 30 and 70 years from the four main NCDs was estimated using age-specific death rates of the combined four main NCD categories. Using the life table method, the risk of death between the exact ages of 30 and 70, from any of the four causes and in the absence of other causes of death, was calculated using the equation .provided in the document below. The ICD codes used are: Cardiovascular disease: I00-I99, Cancer: C00-C97, Diabetes: E10-E14, and Chronic respiratory disease: J30-J98 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Formulas to (1) calculate age-specific mortality rate for each five-year age group between 30 and 70, (2) translate the 5-year death rate into the probability of death in each 5-year age range, and (3) calculate the probability of death from age 30 to age 70, independent of other causes of death, can be found on page 6 of this document: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NCD Global Monitoring Framework: Indicator Definitions and Specifications. Geneva: World Health Organization, 2014 (http://www.who.int/nmh/ncd-tools/indicators/GMF_Indicator_Definitions_FinalNOV2014.pdf?ua=1) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The number of deaths were country consulted with country designated focal points (usually at the Ministry of Health or National Statistics Office) as part of the full set of causes of death prior to the release.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deaths of unknown sex were redistributed pro-rata within cause-age groups of known sexes, and then deaths of unknown age were redistributed pro-rata within cause-sex groups of known ages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At country level &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For countries with high-quality cause-of-death statistics, interpolation/extrapolation was done for missing country-years; for countries with only low-quality or no data on causes of death, modelling was used. Complete methodology may be found here: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHO methods and data sources for global causes of death, 2000&amp;#x2013;2019 (https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/gho-documents/global-health-estimates/ghe2019_cod_methods.pdf ) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At regional and global levels &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NA &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aggregation of estimates of deaths by cause, age and sex by country, and aggregation of population by age, sex and country as denominator where needed. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cause of death categories (including suicides) follow the definitions in terms of the International Classification of Diseases, Tenth Revision (ICD-10). Please see Annex Table A of the WHO methods and data sources for global causes of death, 2000&amp;#x2013;2019 (https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/gho-documents/global-health-estimates/ghe2019_cod_methods.pdf)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The World Health Organization (WHO) established a Reference Group on Health Statistics in 2013 to provide advice on population health statistics to WHO with a focus on methodological and data issues related to the measurement of mortality and cause-of-death patterns. The group facilitated interaction between multilateral development institutions and other independent academic groups with WHO expert groups in specific subject areas including methods to the estimation on causes of death&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The data principles of the World Health Organization (WHO) provide a foundation for continually reaffirming trust in WHO&amp;#x2019;s information and evidence on public health. The five principles are designed to provide a framework for data governance for WHO. The principles are intended primarily for use by WHO staff across all parts of the Organization in order to help define the values and standards that govern how data that flows into, across and out of WHO is collected, processed, shared and used. These principles are made publicly available so that they may be used and referred to by Member States and non-state actors collaborating with WHO.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All statements and claims made officially by WHO headquarters about population-level (country, regional, global) estimates of health status (e.g. mortality, incidence, prevalence, burden of disease), are cleared by the Department of Data and Analytics (DNA) through the executive clearance process. This includes the GATHER statement. GATHER promotes best practices in reporting health estimates using a checklist of 18 items that should be reported every time new global health estimates are published, including descriptions of input data and estimation methods. Developed by a working group convened by the World Health Organization, the guidelines aim to define and promote good practice in reporting health estimates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data availability: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost 70 countries currently provide WHO with regular high-quality data on mortality by age, sex and causes of death, and another 58 countries submit data of lower quality. However, comprehensive cause-of-death estimates are calculated by WHO systematically for all of its Member States (with a certain population threshold).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time series: 2000-2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disaggregation: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sex &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In countries with high quality vital registration systems, point estimates sometimes differ primarily for two reasons: 1) WHO redistributes deaths with ill-defined cause of death; and 2) WHO corrects for incomplete death registration. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.who.int/gho/en/ &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NCD Global Monitoring Framework: Indicator Definitions and Specifications. Geneva: World Health Organization, 2014 (http://www.who.int/nmh/ncd-tools/indicators/GMF_Indicator_Definitions_FinalNOV2014.pdf?ua=1) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHO indicator definition (http://apps.who.int/gho/indicatorregistry/App_Main/view_indicator.aspx?iid=3354) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHO methods and data sources for global causes of death, 2000&amp;#x2013;2019 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/gho-documents/global-health-estimates/ghe2019_cod_methods.pdf) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World Health Assembly Resolution, WHA66.10 (2014): Follow-up to the Political Declaration of the High-level Meeting of the General Assembly on the Prevention and Control of Non-communicable Diseases. Including Appendix 2: Comprehensive global monitoring framework, including 25 indicators, and a set of nine voluntary global targets for the prevention and control of noncommunicable diseases. (http://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA66/A66_R10-en.pdf?ua=1) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHO Global Action Plan for the Prevention and Control of Noncommunicable Diseases 2013-2020 (http://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/10665/94384/1/9789241506236_eng.pdf?ua=1) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 3: Garantizar una vida sana y promover el bienestar de todos a todas las edades&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 3.4: De aquí a 2030, reducir en un tercio la mortalidad prematura por enfermedades no transmisibles mediante su prevención y tratamiento, y promover la salud mental y el bienestar&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 3.4.1: Tasa de mortalidad atribuida a las enfermedades cardiovasculares, el cáncer, la diabetes o las enfermedades respiratorias crónicas&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Última actualización: 10 de febrero de 2017&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Información institucional &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Organización (es): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Organización Mundial de la Salud (OMS) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tasa de mortalidad atribuida a enfermedades cardiovasculares, cáncer, diabetes o enfermedades respiratorias crónicas. Probabilidad de morir entre los 30 y los 70 años por enfermedades cardiovasculares, cáncer, diabetes o enfermedades respiratorias crónicas, definida como el porcentaje de personas de 30 años que morirían antes de cumplir los 70 años por enfermedades cardiovasculares, cáncer, diabetes o enfermedades respiratorias crónicas, suponiendo que experimentara las tasas de mortalidad actuales a cada edad y que no muriera por ninguna otra causa de muerte (por ejemplo, lesiones o VIH/SIDA). Este indicador se calcula utilizando los métodos de la tabla de vida (ver más detalles en la sección 3.3).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probabilidad de morir: La probabilidad de que un individuo muera entre dos edades dadas las tasas de mortalidad actuales a cada edad, calculada mediante los métodos de la tabla de vida. La probabilidad de morir entre dos edades puede llamarse tasa de mortalidad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tabla de vida: Tabla que muestra la experiencia de mortalidad de un grupo hipotético de niños nacidos en el mismo momento y sometidos a lo largo de su vida a un conjunto de tasas de mortalidad específicas por edad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enfermedades cardiovasculares, cáncer, diabetes o enfermedades respiratorias crónicas: Causas de muerte subyacentes de la CIE-10 I00-I99, COO-C97, E10-E14 y J30-J98.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Descripción:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La fuente de datos preferida son los sistemas de registro de defunciones con cobertura completa y certificación médica de la causa de muerte. Otras fuentes de datos posibles son las encuestas de hogares con autopsia verbal y los sistemas de registro por muestreo o centinela.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Proceso de recolección:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La OMS lleva a cabo un proceso formal de consulta por país antes de publicar sus estimaciones de causa de muerte. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendario&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recolección de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La OMS envía un correo electrónico dos veces al año solicitando a los Estados miembros datos tabulados sobre el registro de defunciones (incluidas todas las causas de muerte). Los países envían a la OMS estadísticas anuales sobre las causas de defunción de forma continua. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publicación de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finales de 2016. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La carga de enfermedades no transmisibles (ENT) entre los adultos está aumentando rápidamente en los países en desarrollo debido al envejecimiento. Las enfermedades cardiovasculares, el cáncer, la diabetes y las enfermedades respiratorias crónicas son las cuatro causas principales de la carga de ENT. Medir el riesgo de morir por estas cuatro causas principales es importante para evaluar el alcance de la carga de mortalidad prematura debida a las ENT en una población.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las estimaciones de las causas de muerte tienen grandes rangos de incertidumbre para algunas causas y algunas regiones. Las brechas y limitaciones de los datos en las regiones de alta mortalidad refuerzan la necesidad de ser precavidos a la hora de interpretar las evaluaciones comparativas mundiales de las causas de muerte, así como la necesidad de aumentar la inversión en los sistemas de medición de la salud de la población. El uso de métodos de autopsia verbal en los sistemas de registro de muestras, los sistemas de vigilancia demográfica y las encuestas de hogares proporciona cierta información sobre las causas de muerte en poblaciones que no cuentan con sistemas de registro de defunciones que funcionen adecuadamente, pero sigue habiendo considerables problemas en la validación e interpretación de esos datos, así como en la evaluación de la incertidumbre asociada a los diagnósticos de la causa de muerte subyacente.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El cálculo de este indicador consta de 4 etapas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Estimación de las tablas de vida de la OMS, basadas en la revisión de las Perspectivas de la Población Mundial 2012 de la ONU. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Estimación de la distribución de las causas de muerte. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Cálculo de las tasas de mortalidad por edad de las cuatro principales ENT para cada rango de edad de cinco años entre 30 y 70 años. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. Cálculo de la probabilidad de morir entre los 30 y los 70 años por enfermedades cardiovasculares, cáncer, diabetes o enfermedades respiratorias crónicas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los métodos utilizados para el análisis de las causas de muerte dependen del tipo de datos disponibles de los países:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En el caso de los países con un sistema de registro civil de alta calidad que incluye información sobre la causa de la muerte, se utilizó el registro civil que los Estados miembros envían a la Base de Datos de Mortalidad de la OMS, con ajustes cuando fuera necesario, por ejemplo, para el subregistro de muertes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En los países que no disponen de datos de alta calidad sobre el registro de defunciones, las estimaciones de la causa de muerte se calculan utilizando otros datos, como las encuestas de hogares con autopsia verbal, los sistemas de registro por muestreo o centinela, los estudios especiales y los sistemas de vigilancia. En la mayoría de los casos, estas fuentes de datos se combinan en un marco de modelización.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La probabilidad de morir entre los 30 y los 70 años a causa de las cuatro principales ENT se estimó utilizando las tasas de mortalidad específicas por edad de las cuatro principales categorías de ENT combinadas. Utilizando el método de la tabla de vida, el riesgo de muerte entre las edades exactas de 30 y 70 años, por cualquiera de las cuatro causas y en ausencia de otras causas de muerte, se calculó utilizando la ecuación siguiente. Los códigos CIE utilizados son Enfermedades cardiovasculares: I00-I99, Cáncer: C00-C97, Diabetes: E10-E14, y Enfermedad respiratoria crónica: J30-J98 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las fórmulas para (1) calcular la tasa de mortalidad específica por edad para cada grupo de edad de cinco años entre 30 y 70 años, (2) traducir la tasa de mortalidad de cinco años en la probabilidad de muerte en cada rango de edad de cinco años, y (3) calcular la probabilidad de muerte desde los 30 hasta los 70 años, independientemente de otras causas de muerte, se pueden encontrar en la página 6 de este documento:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marco de Vigilancia Mundial de las ENT: Definiciones y especificaciones de los indicadores. Ginebra: Organización Mundial de la Salud, 2014 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/nmh/ncd-tools/indicators/GMF_Indicator_Definitions_FinalNOV2014.pdf?ua=1&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/nmh/ncd-tools/indicators/GMF_Indicator_Definitions_FinalNOV2014.pdf?ua=1&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de los valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel de país:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En los países con estadísticas de alta calidad sobre las causas de muerte, se realizó una interpolación/extrapolación para los años-país que faltaban; en los países con datos de baja calidad o sin datos sobre las causas de muerte, se utilizó modelización. La metodología completa puede encontrarse aquí:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Métodos y fuentes de datos de la OMS para las causas de defunción mundiales, 2000&amp;#x2013;2015 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/global_burden_disease/GlobalCOD_method_2000_2015.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/global_burden_disease/GlobalCOD_method_2000_2015.pdf&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel regional y mundial:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NA&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agregación de las estimaciones de muertes por causa, edad y sexo por país.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En la actualidad, unos 70 países proporcionan a la OMS datos regulares de alta calidad sobre la mortalidad por edad, sexo y causas de muerte, y otros 40 países presentan datos de menor calidad. Sin embargo, la OMS calcula sistemáticamente estimaciones exhaustivas de las causas de muerte para todos sus Estados miembros (con un determinado umbral de población) cada 3 años.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sexo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Fuentes de discrepancia:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En los países con sistemas de registro civil de alta calidad, las estimaciones puntuales a veces difieren principalmente por dos razones: 1) la OMS redistribuye las defunciones con causa de muerte mal definida; y 2) la OMS corrige los registros de defunción incompletos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/gho/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/gho/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Referencias:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marco de vigilancia mundial de las ENT: Definiciones y especificaciones de los indicadores. Ginebra: Organización Mundial de la Salud, 2014 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/nmh/ncd-tools/indicators/GMF_Indicator_Definitions_FinalNOV2014.pdf?ua=1&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/nmh/ncd-tools/indicators/GMF_Indicator_Definitions_FinalNOV2014.pdf?ua=1&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definición del indicador de la OMS (&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/indicatorregistry/App_Main/view_indicator.aspx?iid=3354&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/indicatorregistry/App_Main/view_indicator.aspx?iid=3354&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Métodos y fuentes de datos de la OMS para las causas mundiales de defunción, 2000&amp;#x2013;2015 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/global_burden_disease/GlobalCOD_method_2000_2015.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/global_burden_disease/GlobalCOD_method_2000_2015.pdf&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resolución de la Asamblea Mundial de la Salud, WHA66.10 (2014): Seguimiento de la declaración política de la reunión de alto nivel de la Asamblea General sobre la prevención y el control de las enfermedades no transmisibles. Incluye el Apéndice 2: Marco integral de seguimiento mundial, que incluye 25 indicadores, y un conjunto de nueve objetivos mundiales voluntarios para la prevención y el control de las enfermedades no transmisibles. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA66/A66_R10-en.pdf?ua=1&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA66/A66_R10-en.pdf?ua=1&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plan de acción mundial de la OMS para la prevención y el control de las enfermedades no transmisibles 2013-2020 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/10665/94384/1/9789241506236_eng.pdf?ua=1&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/10665/94384/1/9789241506236_eng.pdf?ua=1&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 3 : Permettre à tous de vivre en bonne santé et promouvoir le bien-être de tous à tout âge &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 3.4 : D’ici 2030, réduire d’un tiers, par la prévention et le traitement, le taux de mortalité prématurée due à des maladies non transmissibles et promouvoir la santé mentale et le bien-être &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 3.4.1 : Taux de mortalité attribué aux maladies cardiovasculaires, au cancer, au diabète ou aux maladies respiratoires chroniques &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mars 2021&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sans objet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organisation mondiale de la Santé (OMS) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organisation mondiale de la Santé (OMS)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Définition : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le taux de mortalité qui est attribué aux maladies cardiovasculaires, au cancer, au diabète ou aux maladies respiratoires chroniques. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probabilité de mourir entre 30 et 70 ans de maladies cardiovasculaires, de cancer, de diabète ou de maladies respiratoires chroniques, définie comme le pourcentage de personnes âgées de 30 ans qui mourraient avant leur 70e anniversaire de maladies cardiovasculaires, de cancer, de diabète ou de maladies respiratoires chroniques, en supposant qu&apos;elles connaissent les taux de mortalité actuels à chaque âge et qu&apos;elles ne meurent pas d&apos;une autre cause de décès (par exemple, de blessures ou du VIH/sida). Cet indicateur est calculé à l&apos;aide des méthodes des tables de survie (voir les détails au point 3.3). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concepts : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probabilité de décès : probabilité qu&apos;un individu décède entre deux âges, compte tenu des taux de mortalité actuels à chaque âge, calculés à l&apos;aide des méthodes des tables de survie. La probabilité de décès entre deux âges peut être appelée taux de mortalité. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table de survie : table montrant l&apos;expérience de mortalité d&apos;un groupe hypothétique de nourrissons nés au même moment et soumis tout au long de leur vie à un ensemble de taux de mortalité par âge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maladies cardiovasculaires, cancer, diabète ou maladies respiratoires chroniques : Classification internationale des maladies (CIM-10), causes sous-jacentes de décès I00-I99, COO-C97, E10-E14 et J30-J98. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Probabilité&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les quatre causes non transmissibles de décès sont définies en termes de Classification internationale des maladies, dixième révision (CIM-10) (voir 2.a).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;La source de données privilégiée est le système d&apos;enregistrement des décès avec une couverture complète et une certification médicale de la cause du décès. D&apos;autres sources de données possibles sont les enquêtes auprès des ménages avec autopsie verbale et les systèmes d&apos;enregistrement par échantillonnage ou sentinelle. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L&apos; OMS mène un processus formel de consultation des pays avant de publier ses estimations des causes de décès. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L’OMS demande chaque année aux États membres des données d’enregistrement des décès sous forme de tableau (incluant toutes les causes de décès). Les pays peuvent soumettre des statistiques annuelles sur les causes de décès à l’OMS sur une base continue. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fin 2020. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les bureaux nationaux de statistique et/ou les ministères de la santé. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;OMS &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conformément à l’article 64 de sa constitution, l’OMS est mandatée pour demander à chaque État membre de fournir des statistiques sur la mortalité. En outre, le Règlement de l’OMS sur la nomenclature de 1967 affirme l’importance de compiler et de publier des statistiques sur la mortalité et la morbidité sous une forme comparable. Les États membres ont commencé à déclarer des données sur la mortalité à l’OMS depuis le début des années cinquante et cette activité de notification se poursuit jusqu’à aujourd’hui. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Le fardeau de morbidité due aux maladies non transmissibles (MNT) chez les adultes augmente rapidement à l’échelle mondiale en raison du vieillissement et des transitions épidémiologiques. Les maladies cardiovasculaires, le cancer, le diabète et les maladies respiratoires chroniques sont les quatre principales causes du fardeau des MNT. Il est important de mesurer le risque de mourir de ces quatre causes principales pour évaluer l’ampleur du fardeau de la mortalité prématurée due aux MNT dans une population. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les estimations des causes de décès présentent de grandes incertitudes pour certaines causes et certaines régions. Les lacunes et les limites des données dans les régions à forte mortalité renforcent la nécessité de faire preuve de prudence dans l&apos;interprétation des évaluations comparatives des causes de décès au niveau mondial, ainsi que la nécessité d&apos;accroître les investissements dans les systèmes de mesure de la santé des populations. L&apos;utilisation de méthodes d&apos;autopsie verbale dans les systèmes d&apos;enregistrement d&apos;échantillons, les systèmes de surveillance démographique et les enquêtes auprès des ménages fournissent certaines informations sur les causes de décès dans les populations qui ne disposent pas de systèmes d&apos;enregistrement des décès qui fonctionnent et qui sont adéquats. Toutefois, il reste des défis considérables à relever en ce qui concerne la validation et l&apos;interprétation de ces données, ainsi que l&apos;évaluation de l&apos;incertitude associée aux diagnostics des causes de décès sous-jacentes. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les méthodes utilisées pour l’analyse des causes de décès dépendent du type de données disponibles dans les pays : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour les pays dotés d’un système d’enregistrement de l’état civil de haute qualité, y compris des informations sur la cause du décès, l’enregistrement de l’état civil que les États membres soumettent à la base de données de l’OMS sur la mortalité a été utilisé, avec des ajustements si nécessaire, par exemple pour la sous-déclaration des décès, l’âge et le sexe inconnus et les causes de décès mal définies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour les pays qui ne disposent pas de données d’enregistrement des décès de haute qualité, les estimations des causes de décès sont calculées à l’aide d’autres données, y compris des enquêtes auprès des ménages avec autopsie verbale, des systèmes d’enregistrement par échantillonnage ou sentinelle, des études spéciales et des systèmes de surveillance. Dans la plupart des cas, ces sources de données sont combinées dans un cadre de modélisation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La probabilité de mourir entre 30 et 70 ans des quatre principales MNT a été estimée à l’aide des taux de mortalité par âge des quatre principales catégories de MNT combinées. À l’aide de la méthode du tableau de survie, le risque de décès entre 30 et 70 ans, pour l’une des quatre causes et en l’absence d’autres causes de décès, a été calculé à l’aide de l’équation fournie dans le document ci-dessous. Les codes CIM utilisés sont les suivants : maladies cardiovasculaires : I00-I99, cancer : C00-C97, diabète : E10-E14 et maladies respiratoires chroniques : J30-J98 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des formules pour (1) calculer le taux de mortalité par âge pour chaque groupe d’âge de cinq ans entre 30 et 70 ans, (2) traduire le taux de mortalité sur 5 ans en probabilité de décès dans chaque tranche d’âge de 5 ans, et (3) calculer la probabilité de décès de 30 à 70 ans, indépendamment des autres causes de décès, se trouvent à la page 6 du présent document (en anglais) : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;« NCD Global Monitoring Framework: Indicator Definitions and Specifications ». Genève : Organisation mondiale de la Santé, 2014 (http://www.who.int/nmh/ncd-tools/indicators/GMF_Indicator_Definitions_FinalNOV2014.pdf?ua=1) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les points focaux désignés par le pays (généralement au ministère de la santé ou au bureau national de statistique) ont été consultés au sujet du nombre de décès, dans le cadre de l&apos;ensemble complet des causes de décès avant la publication.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les décès de sexe inconnu ont été redistribués au prorata au sein des groupes de cause-âge de sexe connu, puis les décès d’âge inconnu ont été redistribués au prorata dans les groupes de cause-sexe d’âge connu.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Au niveau national &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour les pays présentant des statistiques sur les causes de décès de grande qualité, une interpolation/extrapolation a été effectuée pour les années-pays manquants; pour les pays où les données sur les causes de décès sont de faible qualité ou inexistantes, la modélisation a été utilisée. La méthodologie complète peut être trouvée (en anglais) à l&apos;adresse : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;« WHO methods and data sources for global causes of death, 2000–2019 » (https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/gho-documents/global-health-estimates/ghe2019_cod_methods.pdf ) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aux niveaux régional et mondial &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sans objet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Agrégation des estimations des décès par cause, âge et sexe par pays, et agrégation de la population par âge, sexe et pays comme dénominateur, le cas échéant. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les catégories de causes de décès (y compris les suicides) suivent les définitions de la Classification internationale des maladies, dixième révision (CIM-10). Veuillez consulter le tableau A de l’annexe du document (en anglais) « WHO methods and data sources for global causes of death, 2000–2019 » (https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/gho-documents/global-health-estimates/ghe2019_cod_methods.pdf)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L’Organisation mondiale de la Santé (OMS) a créé un Groupe de référence sur les statistiques de la santé en 2013 pour fournir des conseils sur les statistiques de la santé de la population à l’OMS, en mettant l’accent sur les questions méthodologiques et de données liées à la mesure de la mortalité et aux tendances de cause de décès. Le groupe a facilité l’interaction entre les institutions multilatérales de développement et d’autres groupes universitaires indépendants avec des groupes d’experts de l’OMS dans des domaines spécifiques, y compris les méthodes d’estimation des causes de décès.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les principes de données de l’Organisation mondiale de la Santé (OMS) fournissent une base pour réaffirmer continuellement la confiance envers les informations et les preuves de l’OMS au sujet de la santé publique. Les cinq principes sont conçus pour fournir un cadre pour la gouvernance des données pour l’OMS. Les principes sont principalement destinés au personnel de l’OMS dans toutes les parties de l’Organisation afin d’aider à définir les valeurs et les normes qui régissent la manière dont les données qui entrent, circulent et sortent de l’OMS sont recueillies, traitées, partagées et utilisées. Ces principes sont rendus publics afin qu’ils puissent être utilisés et mentionnés par les États membres et les acteurs non étatiques collaborant avec l’OMS. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Toutes les déclarations et allégations faites officiellement par le Siège de l’OMS concernant les estimations de l’état de santé au niveau de la population (pays, région, monde – par exemple, la mortalité, l’incidence, la prévalence, le fardeau de morbidité) sont approuvées par le Département des données et de l’analyse (DDA) par le biais du processus d’autorisation exécutive. Cela inclut les instructions de « GATHER » qui fait la promotion des pratiques exemplaires en matière de déclaration des estimations de la santé à l’aide d’une liste de contrôle de 18 éléments qui devraient être déclarés chaque fois que de nouvelles estimations de la santé mondiale sont publiées, y compris des descriptions des données d’entrée et des méthodes d’estimation. Élaborées par un groupe de travail convoqué par l’Organisation mondiale de la Santé, les lignes directrices visent à définir et à promouvoir les bonnes pratiques en matière de déclaration des estimations de la santé.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disponibilité des données : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Près de 70 pays fournissent actuellement à l’OMS des données régulières de haute qualité sur la mortalité par âge, sexe et causes de décès, et 58 autres pays soumettent des données de qualité inférieure. Toutefois, l’OMS calcule systématiquement des estimations complètes de la cause du décès pour l’ensemble de ses États membres (avec un certain seuil de population).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Séries chronologiques : 2000-2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Désagrégation : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sexe &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sources des divergences : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dans les pays dotés de systèmes d&apos;enregistrement de l&apos;état civil de haute qualité, les estimations ponctuelles diffèrent parfois principalement pour deux raisons : 1) l&apos;OMS redistribue les décès dont la cause est mal définie; et 2) l&apos;OMS corrige les décès dont l&apos;enregistrement est incomplet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Toutes les références sont anglais)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;URL :&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.who.int/gho/en/ &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Références :&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;« NCD Global Monitoring Framework: Indicator Definitions and Specifications ». Genève : Organisation mondiale de la Santé, 2014 (http://www.who.int/nmh/ncd-tools/indicators/GMF_Indicator_Definitions_FinalNOV2014.pdf?ua=1) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Définition des indicateurs de l’OMS (http://apps.who.int/gho/indicatorregistry/App_Main/view_indicator.aspx?iid=3354) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;« WHO methods and data sources for global causes of death, 2000–2019 » &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/gho-documents/global-health-estimates/ghe2019_cod_methods.pdf) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Résolution de l&apos;Assemblée mondiale de la Santé, WHA66.10 (2014) : Follow-up to the Political Declaration of the High-level Meeting of the General Assembly on the Prevention and Control of Non-communicable Diseases. Incluant l&apos;annexe 2 : « Comprehensive global monitoring framework, including 25 indicators, and a set of nine voluntary global targets for the prevention and control of noncommunicable diseases ». (http://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA66/A66_R10-en.pdf?ua=1) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;« WHO Global Action Plan for the Prevention and Control of Noncommunicable Diseases 2013-2020 » (http://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/10665/94384/1/9789241506236_eng.pdf?ua=1) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 3: Garantir o acesso á saude de qualidade e promover o bem-estar para todos, em todas as idades&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 3: Обеспечение здорового образа жизни и содействие благополучию для всех в любом возрасте&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 3.4: К 2030 году уменьшить на треть преждевременную смертность от неинфекционных заболеваний посредством профилактики и лечения и поддержания психического здоровья и благополучия&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 3.4.1: Смертность от сердечно-сосудистых заболеваний, рака, диабета, хронических респираторных заболеваний&lt;/p&gt;Последнее обновление: 10 февраля 2017 года&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Институциональная информация &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Организация (и): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Всемирная организация здравоохранения (ВОЗ) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Уровень смертности от сердечно-сосудистых заболеваний, рака, диабета или хронических респираторных заболеваний. Вероятность смерти в возрасте от 30 до 70 лет от сердечно-сосудистых заболеваний, рака, диабета или хронических респираторных заболеваний, определяется как процент 30-летних людей, которые умрут до своего 70-летия от сердечно-сосудистых заболеваний, рака, диабета или хронического респираторного заболевания, предполагая, что в любом его/ее возрасте сохранятся текущие уровни смертности и он / она не умрет от какой-либо другой причины (например, травм или ВИЧ / СПИДа). Этот показатель рассчитывается методами с использованием таблицы дожития (подробнее см. раздел 3.3). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Вероятность смерти: вероятность того, что человек умрет в интервале между двумя возрастами с учетом сохранения текущих показателей смертности в каждом возрасте, рассчитанная методами с использованием таблицы дожития. Вероятность смерти в интервале между двумя возрастами можно назвать уровнем смертности. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Таблица дожития: таблица, показывающая уровень смертности гипотетической группы младенцев, родившихся в одно и то же время и при условии, что на протяжении всей их жизни сохранятся значения возрастных коэффициентов смертности. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Сердечно-сосудистые заболевания, рак, диабет или хронические респираторные заболевания: МКБ-10 основные причины смерти I00-I99, COO-C97, E10-E14 и J30-J98. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Описание: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Предпочтительным источником данных являются системы регистрации смерти с полным охватом и медицинским подтверждением причины смерти. Другие возможные источники данных включают обследования домашних хозяйств с проведением с вербальной аутопсии (опроса членов семьи и очевидцев об обстоятельствах смерти), а также выборочные или дозорные системы регистрации. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ВОЗ проводит официальные консультации со странами, прежде чем опубликовать свои оценки причин смерти. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Календарь &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Сбор данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ВОЗ два раза в год отправляет электронные письма, запрашивая государства-члены представить табличные данные регистрации случаев смерти (включая все причины смерти). Страны на постоянной основе представляют в ВОЗ ежегодные статистические данные по причинам смерти. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Выпуск данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Конец 2016 года. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Бремя неинфекционных заболеваний (НИЗ) среди взрослых быстро растет в развивающихся странах из-за старения населения. Сердечно-сосудистые заболевания, рак, диабет и хронические респираторные заболевания являются четырьмя основными причинами бремени НИЗ. Оценка риска смерти от этих четырех основных причин важна для определения степени тяжести преждевременной смертности из-за НИЗ среди населения. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Оценки причин смерти имеют большие диапазоны неопределенности для некоторых причин и некоторых регионов. Пробелы в данных и ограничения, действующие в регионах с высокой смертностью, усиливают необходимость осторожного подхода к интерпретации глобальных сравнительных оценок причин смерти, а также необходимость увеличения инвестиций в системы оценки здоровья населения. Использование методов вербальной аутопсии в системах выборочной регистрации, системах демографического надзора и обследованиях домашних хозяйств дает некоторую информацию о причинах смерти среди населения в условиях отсутствия хорошо функционирующих систем регистрации смерти, но остаются значительные проблемы в проверке и интерпретации таких данных, а также в оценке неопределенности, связанной с диагнозом первопричины смерти. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Расчет этого показателя осуществляется в 4 этапа: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 1. Анализ таблиц дожития ВОЗ на основе пересмотренной публикации ООН «Мировые демографические перспективы» 2012года. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 2. Анализ распределений причин смерти. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 3. Расчет возрастных коэффициентов смертности от четырех основных НИЗ для каждого пятилетнего возрастного диапазона в интервале от 30 до 70 лет. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 4. Расчет вероятности смерти в возрасте от 30 до 70 лет от сердечно-сосудистых заболеваний, рака, диабета или хронических респираторных заболеваний.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Методы, используемые для анализа причин смерти, зависят от типа доступных страновых данных: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для стран с высококачественной системой регистрации естественного движения населения, включающей информацию о причине смерти, использовались данные регистрации естественного движения населения, которые государства-члены представляют в базу данных ВОЗ по смертности, с корректировками, где это необходимо, например, связанными с занижением сведений о смертях. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для стран, не имеющих качественных данных регистрации смерти, оценки причин смерти рассчитываются с использованием других данных, включая полученные из обследований домашних хозяйств с вербальной аутопсией, выборочных или дозорных систем регистрации, специальных исследований и систем санэпиднадзора. В большинстве случаев эти источники данных объединяются в модельную структуру. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Вероятность смерти в возрасте от 30 до 70 лет от четырех основных НИЗ оценивалась с использованием возрастных коэффициентов смертности для четырех объединенных основных категорий НИЗ. Применяя метод, основанный на таблице смертности, был рассчитан риск смерти в возрасте от 30 до 70 лет от любой из четырех причин и при отсутствии других причин смерти с использованием приведенного ниже уравнения. Используемые коды МКБ: сердечно-сосудистые заболевания: I00-I99, рак: C00-C97, диабет: E10-E14 и хроническое респираторное заболевание: J30-J98 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Формулы для (1) расчета возрастного коэффициента смертности для каждой пятилетней возрастной группы от 30 до 70 лет, (2) преобразования 5-летнего коэффициента смертности в вероятность смерти в каждом пятилетнем возрастном диапазоне и (3) расчета вероятности смерти в возрасте от 30 до 70 лет, независимо от других причин смерти, можно найти на странице 6 этого документа: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Глобальная система мониторинга НИЗ: определения и спецификации показателей. Женева: Всемирная организация здравоохранения, 2014 год. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/nmh/ncd-tools/indicators/GMF_Indicator_Definitions_FinalNOV2014.pdf?ua=1&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/nmh/ncd-tools/sizes/GMF_Indicator_Definitions_FinalNOV2014.pdf? ua = 1&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для стран с высококачественной статистикой причин смерти интерполяция / экстраполяция была сделана для отсутствующих стран-лет; для стран с низкокачественными данными по причинам смерти или при их отсутствии использовалось моделирование. Полную методологию можно найти здесь: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Методы и источники данных ВОЗ по глобальным причинам смерти, 2000 год. &amp;#x2013; 2015 год. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/global_burden_disease/GlobalCOD_method_2000_2015.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/global_burden_disease/GlobalCOD_method_2000_2015.pdf&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Не применимо &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Региональные агрегаты:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Агрегирование оценок смертности по причинам, возрасту и полу по странам. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Около 70 стран в настоящее время предоставляют ВОЗ регулярные высококачественные данные по смертности в разбивке по возрасту, полу и причинам смерти, а еще 40 стран представляют данные более низкого качества. Однако всеобъемлющие оценки причин смерти систематически рассчитываются ВОЗ для всех ее государств-членов (с определенным порогом численности населения) каждые 3 года. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; По полу &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В странах с высококачественными системами регистрации актов гражданского состояния точечные оценки иногда различаются главным образом по двум причинам: 1) ВОЗ перераспределяет случаи смерти с неустановленной причиной смерти; и 2) ВОЗ корректирует информацию о неполной регистрации смертей. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/gho/en/&quot;&gt; http://www.who.int/gho/en/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Ссылки: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Глобальная система мониторинга НИЗ: определения и спецификации показателей. Женева: Всемирная организация здравоохранения, 2014 год. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/nmh/ncd-tools/indicators/GMF_Indicator_Definitions_FinalNOV2014.pdf?ua=1&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/nmh/ncd-tools/indicators/GMF_Indicator_Definitions_FinalNOV2014.pdf?ua=1&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Определение показателя ВОЗ (&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/indicatorregistry/App_Main/view_indicator.aspx?iid=3354&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/indicatorregistry/App_Main/view_indicator.aspx?iid=3354&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Методы и источники данных ВОЗ по глобальным причинам смерти, 2000 год. &amp;#x2013; 2015 год. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/global_burden_disease/GlobalCOD_method_2000_2015.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/healthinfo/global_burden_disease/GlobalCOD_method_2000_2015.pdf&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Резолюция Всемирной ассамблеи здравоохранения, WHA66.10 (2014 год): Последующие меры в связи с Политической декларацией совещания высокого уровня Генеральной Ассамблеи по профилактике неинфекционных заболеваний и борьбе с ними, включая Приложение 2: Комплексная глобальная система мониторинга, включающая 25 показателей и набор из девяти рекомендуемых глобальных задач по профилактике неинфекционных заболеваний и борьбе с ними. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA66/A66_R10-en.pdf?ua=1&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA66/A66_R10-en.pdf?ua=1&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Глобальный план действий ВОЗ по профилактике неинфекционных заболеваний и борьбе с ними на 2013–2020 годы. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/10665/94384/1/9789241506236_eng.pdf?ua=1&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/10665/94384/1/9789241506236_eng.pdf?ua=1[1735]&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
