<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 3-6-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 3: Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 3.6: By 2020, halve the number of global deaths and injuries from road traffic accidents&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 3.6.1: Death rate due to road traffic injuries&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last updated: 19 July 2016&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Related indicators as of February 2020&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.5, 11.2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Institutional information&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organization(s):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World Health Organization (WHO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death rate due to road traffic injuries as defined as the number of road traffic fatal injury deaths per 100,000 population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerator: Number of deaths due to road traffic crashes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolute figure indicating the number of people who die as a result of a road traffic crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Denominator: Population (number of people by country)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the road traffic deaths we have two sources of data. Data from Global Status Report on Road Safety survey and Vital registration or certificate deaths data that WHO receive every year from member states (ministries of health).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the population, we used data from the United Nations / Department of Economic and Social Affairs/ Population division.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Collection process:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The methodology involved collecting data from a number of different sectors and stakeholders in each country is as follows. National Data Coordinators (NDCs), who were nominated by their governments, were trained in the project methodology. As representatives of their ministries, they were required to identify up to eight other road safety experts within their country from different sectors (e.g. health, police, transport, nongovernmental organizations and/or academia) and to facilitate a consensus meeting of these respondents. While each expert responded to the questionnaire based on their expertise, the consensus meeting facilitated by NDCs allowed for discussion of all responses, and the group used this discussion to agree on one final set of information that best represented their country&amp;#x2019;s situation at the time (up to 2014, using the most recent data available). This was then submitted to the World Health Organization (WHO). More details are in the Global Status Report on Road Safety 2015. A guide to our questionnaire describing age groups and other dimensions was provided to countries in order to standardize data collected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendar&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Data collection:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next collection of data is planned for 2017, although the data collected on fatalities is likely to be 2015 or 2016 (we will ask for the most recent country data available). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Data release:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new data for this indicator will be published in early 2019.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data providers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The road traffic deaths data were provided nationally by mainly three ministries, namely, ministry of health, ministry of interior and ministry of transport&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data compilers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHO is the organization responsible for compilation and reporting on this indicator at the global level&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comments and limitations:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are no vital registration data for all countries to make comparison against the data received on the survey. We published only confidence intervals for countries that have poor completeness of vital registration data. Also we cannot collect road traffic data every year using this methodology outlined in the Global status report.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computation method:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our model is based on the quality of data we received. As a health organization, we rely primarily on the submission of vital registration data from countries&amp;#x2019; Ministries of Health to WHO (through the official channels). These data, on all causes of death, are then analysed by our colleagues in the Health Information Systems department to decide on how good the data are, that is, determining if there is good completeness and coverage of deaths for all causes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We classified the countries on 4 categories or groups namely,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Group 1: Countries with death registration data (good vital/ death registration data)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Group 2: Countries with other sources of information on causes of death&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Group 3: Countries with population less than 150 000&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Group 4: Countries without eligible death registration data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Health Information Systems department analyses the quality and the completeness of the data. For the road safety model, if the country is considered by WHO to have good vital registration (VR) data this means that the country is in group 1, then we don&amp;#x2019;t apply a regression model to come up with an estimate (we may, however, project forward if the vital registration data are dated). If the country is considered in group 4 then we apply a negative binomial regression where N is the total road traffic deaths , C is constant term, Xi are a set of explanatory covariates, Pop is the population for the country-year, and ? is the negative binomial error term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the countries from group 2, the regression method described above was used to project forward the most recent year for which an estimate of total deaths were available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the countries from group 3 which have a population less than 150,000 and did not have eligible death registration data, regression estimates were not used. Only the reported death were directly without adjustment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details about this estimation process in &lt;em&gt;Global Status Report on Road Safety 2015&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Treatment of missing values:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At country level:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treatment of missing data was carried out as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Identified missing values (or years) in vital registration (VR) data and looked for other sources in our case data from the questionnaire/survey (reported ) for these years. We then calculated the factor VR/Reported for the latest 3 years where VR and Reported data were available and used this factor to adjust Reported data to replace the missing value of VR data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) In the case where there is missing data in VR and Reported data, the missing values were imputed with a negative binomial regression of rate for each country if the regression converged or was significant. Otherwise we used the average rate of years with data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At regional and global levels:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same as the procedure described for 11.2 above&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Regional aggregates:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We used the WHO&amp;apos;s regional grouping and the average to calculate the rate for each region. This means sum of road traffic deaths for region (i) multiplied by 100,000 and divided by the population in region (i).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data availability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have data for 194 countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Time series:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2000 to 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We disaggregated the data by types of road users, age, sex, income groups and WHO regions&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHO&amp;apos;s estimation of road traffic rates are, in many countries, different to the official estimates for the reasons described above that relate to our methodology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also differences in the data used for population between the national data and the estimates produced by the United Nations department of population.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/violence_injury_prevention&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/violence_injury_prevention&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/violence_injury_prevention/road_safety_status/2015/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/violence_injury_prevention/road_safety_status/2015/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Meta 3: Garantizar una vida sana y promover el bienestar de todos a todas las edades&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 3.6: De aquí a 2020, reducir a la mitad el número de muertes y lesiones causadas por accidentes de tráfico en el mundo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 3.6.1: Tasa de mortalidad por lesiones debidas a accidentes de tráfico&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Última actualización: 19 de julio de 2016&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Indicadores relacionados a febrero de 2020&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.5, 11.2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Información institucional &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Organización (es): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Organización Mundial de la Salud (OMS) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definición:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tasa de mortalidad por accidentes de tránsito definida como el número de muertes causados por accidentes de tránsito por cada 100.000 habitantes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerador: Número de muertes debidas a accidentes de tráfico&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cifra absoluta que indica el número de personas que mueren como consecuencia de un accidente de tráfico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Denominador: Población (número de personas por país)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para las muertes por accidentes de tráfico tenemos dos fuentes de datos. Los datos de la encuesta del Informe sobre la situación mundial de la seguridad vial y los datos de los registros vitales o certificados de defunción que la OMS recibe cada año de los estados miembros (ministerios de salud).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para la población, utilizamos datos de las Naciones Unidas / Departamento de Asuntos Económicos y Sociales / División de Población.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Proceso de recolección:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La metodología de recolección de datos de diferentes sectores y partes interesadas en cada país es la siguiente. Los Coordinadores Nacionales de Datos (CND), que fueron nombrados por sus gobiernos, recibieron formación sobre la metodología del proyecto. Como representantes de sus ministerios, se les pidió que identificaran hasta otros ocho expertos en seguridad vial dentro de su país de diferentes sectores (por ejemplo, salud, policía, transporte, organizaciones no gubernamentales y/o academia) y que facilitaran una reunión de consenso de estos encuestados. Aunque cada experto respondió al cuestionario en función de su experiencia, la reunión de consenso facilitada por los CDN permitió debatir todas las respuestas, y el grupo utilizó este debate para acordar un conjunto final de información que representara mejor la situación de su país en ese momento (hasta 2014, utilizando los datos más recientes disponibles). Esta información se presentó a la Organización Mundial de la Salud (OMS). Encontrará más detalles en el Informe sobre la situación mundial de la seguridad vial 2015. Se proporcionó a los países una guía de nuestro cuestionario en la que se describen los grupos de edad y otras dimensiones, con el fin de normalizar los datos recopilados.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendario&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recolección de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La próxima recolección de datos está prevista para 2017, aunque es probable que los datos recogidos sobre las víctimas mortales sean de 2015 o 2016 (se pedirán los datos más recientes disponibles del país). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publicación de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los nuevos datos de este indicador se publicarán a principios de 2019.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Los datos de muertes por accidentes de tránsito fueron proporcionados a nivel nacional principalmente por tres ministerios, a saber, ministerio de Salud, Ministerio del Interior y ministerio de transporte&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La OMS es la organización responsable de la compilación y la presentación de informes sobre este indicador a nivel mundial&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No existen datos del registro civil de todos los países para realizar la comparación con los datos recibidos en la encuesta. Publicamos sólo intervalos de confianza para los países que tienen datos de registro civil poco completos. Además, no podemos recopilar datos sobre tránsito todos los años utilizando la metodología descrita en el Informe sobre la situación mundial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nuestro modelo se basa en la calidad de los datos que recibimos. Como organización sanitaria, nos basamos principalmente en la presentación de los datos del registro civil de los Ministerios de Salud de los países a la OMS (a través de los canales oficiales). Estos datos, sobre todas las causas de muerte, son analizados después por nuestros colegas del departamento de Sistemas de Información Sanitaria para decidir la calidad de los datos, es decir, determinar si hay una buena integridad y cobertura de las muertes por todas las causas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clasificamos los países en 4 categorías o grupos, a saber,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grupo 1: Países con datos de registro de defunciones (buenos datos vitales/de registro de defunciones)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grupo 2: Países con otras fuentes de información sobre las causas de defunción&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grupo 3: Países con una población inferior a 150.000 habitantes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grupo 4: Países sin datos de registro de defunciones admisibles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El departamento de Sistemas de Información Sanitaria analiza la calidad y la exhaustividad de los datos. Para el modelo de seguridad vial, si la OMS considera que el país tiene buenos datos de registro civil (RC), significa que el país está en el grupo 1, entonces no aplicamos un modelo de regresión para obtener una estimación (sin embargo, podemos proyectar hacia adelante si los datos de registro civil son antiguos). Si el país se considera en el grupo 4, entonces aplicamos una regresión binomial negativa en la que N es el total de muertes por accidentes de tráfico, C es el término constante, Xi es un conjunto de covariables explicativas, Pop es la población del país-año y ? es el término de error binomial negativo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para los países del grupo 2, se utilizó el método de regresión descrito anteriormente para proyectar hacia adelante el año más reciente para el que se disponía de una estimación del total de muertes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Por último, en los países del grupo 3 con una población inferior a 150.000 habitantes y que no disponían de datos de registro de defunciones, no se utilizaron las estimaciones de regresión. Sólo se utilizaron directamente las defunciones notificadas sin ajustarlas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Más detalles sobre este proceso de estimación en &lt;em&gt;Informe sobre la situación mundial de la seguridad vial 2015&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel de país:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El tratamiento de valores faltantes se realizó de la siguiente manera:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Se identificaron los valores (o años) que faltaban en los datos del registro civil (RC) y se buscaron otras fuentes, en nuestro caso los datos del cuestionario/encuesta (reportados) para esos años. A continuación, se calculó el factor RC/Reportado para los últimos 3 años en los que se disponía de datos de RC y Reportados y se utilizó este factor para ajustar los datos Reportados para sustituir el valor que faltaba de los datos de RC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) En el caso de que falten datos de RC y Reportados, los valores faltantes se imputaron con una regresión binomial negativa de la tasa para cada país si la regresión convergía o era significativa. En caso contrario, se utilizó la tasa media de los años con datos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel regional y mundial:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Igual que el procedimiento descrito para el 11.2 anterior&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utilizamos la agrupación regional de la OMS y la media para calcular la tasa de cada región. Esto significa la suma de las muertes por accidentes de tráfico de la región (i) multiplicada por 100.000 y dividida por la población de la región (i).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disponemos de datos para 194 países.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De 2000 a 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desagregamos los datos por tipos de usuarios de carretera, edad, sexo, grupos de ingresos y regiones de la OMS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Fuentes de discrepancia:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las estimaciones de la OMS sobre las tasas de tráfico son, en muchos países, diferentes a las estimaciones oficiales por las razones descritas anteriormente que se relacionan con nuestra metodología.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;También hay diferencias en los datos utilizados para la población entre los datos nacionales y las estimaciones elaboradas por el departamento de población de las Naciones Unidas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/violence_injury_prevention&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/violence_injury_prevention&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Referencias:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/violence_injury_prevention/road_safety_status/2015/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/violence_injury_prevention/road_safety_status/2015/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 3 : Permettre à tous de vivre en bonne santé et promouvoir le bien-être de tous à tout âge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 3.6: D’ici à 2020, diminuer de moitié à l’échelle mondiale le nombre de décès et de blessures dus à des accidents de la route&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 3.6.1: Taux de mortalité lié aux accidents de la route&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dernière mise à jour : 19 juillet 2016&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicateurs connexes depuis février 2020&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.5, 11.2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Information institutionnelle&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Organisation(s) : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Organisation mondiale de la Santé (OMS)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Concepts et définitions &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Définition : &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Taux de mortalité attribuable aux accidents de la route, défini comme le nombre de décès par accident de la route pour 100 000 habitants. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Concepts : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Numérateur : nombre de décès dus aux accidents de la route &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Chiffre absolu indiquant le nombre de personnes décédées à la suite d&apos;un accident de la route. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Dénominateur : Population (nombre de personnes par pays) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Sources de données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Pour les décès sur la route, nous disposons de deux sources de données. Données tirées du Rapport de situation sur la sécurité routière dans le monde et des données d&apos;état civil ou les certifications de décès que l&apos;OMS reçoit chaque année des États membres (ministères de la santé). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Pour la population, nous avons utilisé les données de l&apos;Organisation des Nations Unies / Département des affaires économiques et sociales / Division de la population. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Processus de collecte : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La méthodologie utilisée pour collecter des données auprès d&apos;internenants de divers secteurs dans chaque pays est la suivante. Les coordonnateurs nationaux des données (NDC), qui ont été désignés par leurs gouvernements, ont été formés à la méthodologie du projet. En tant que représentants de leurs ministères, ils ont été tenus d&apos;identifier jusqu&apos;à huit autres experts en sécurité routière dans leur pays de différents secteurs (par exemple, la santé, la police, les transports, les organisations non gouvernementales et / ou le milieu acdémiques) et de faciliter une réunion de consensus de ces répondants. Alors que chaque expert a répondu au questionnaire en fonction de son expertise, la réunion de consensus facilitée par les NDC,  permet de discuter de toutes les réponses, et au groupe de convenir d&apos;un ensemble final d&apos;informations qui représente le mieux la situation de leur pays à un temps donné (jusqu&apos;en 2014, en utilisant les données disponibles les plus récentes). Celui-ci a ensuite été soumis à l&apos;OMS. Plus de détails sont fournis dans le Rapport sur la situation mondiale de la sécurité routière 2015. Un guide de notre questionnaire décrivant les groupes d&apos;âge et d&apos;autres dimensions a été fourni aux pays afin de normaliser les données collectées.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Calendrier &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Collecte de données : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La prochaine collecte de données est prévue pour 2017, bien que les données collectées sur les décès datent probablement de 2015 ou de 2016 (nous demanderons les données nationales les plus récentes disponibles). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Diffusion des données : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les nouvelles données pour cet indicateur seront publiées début 2019. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Fournisseurs de données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les données sur les décès dus aux accidents de la route ont été fournies au niveau national principalement par trois ministères, à savoir le ministère de la santé, le ministère de l&apos;intérieur et le ministère des transports &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Compilateurs de données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L&apos;OMS est l&apos;organisation responsable de la compilation et de l&apos;établissement de rapports sur cet indicateur au niveau mondial. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Commentaires et limites : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Il n&apos;y a pas de données d&apos;état civil pour tous les pays permettant d&apos;effectuer une comparaison avec les données reçues dans le cadre de l&apos;enquête. Nous n&apos;avons publié que les intervalles de confiance pour les pays dont les données d&apos;état civil sont peu complètes. De plus, nous ne pouvons pas collecter des données sur le trafic routier chaque année en utilisant cette méthodologie décrite dans le rapport de situation mondial. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Méthodologie &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Méthode de calcul : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Notre modèle est basé sur la qualité des données que nous avons reçues. En tant qu&apos;organisation de santé, nous nous appuyons principalement sur la soumission des données d&apos;état civil des ministères de la Santé des pays &amp;#x2019; à l&apos;OMS (par les voies officielles). Ces données, sur toutes les causes de décès, sont ensuite analysées par nos collègues du département des Systèmes d&apos;Information Sanitaire pour décider de la qualité des données, c&apos;est-à-dire déterminer s&apos;il existe une bonne exhaustivité et une bonne couverture des décès toutes causes confondues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Nous avons classé les pays en 4 catégories ou groupes, à savoir &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Groupe 1: Pays disposant de données d&apos;enregistrement des décès (bonnes données d&apos;état civil / d&apos;enregistrement des décès) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Groupe 2: Pays disposant d&apos;autres sources d&apos;informations sur les causes de décès &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Groupe 3: Pays de moins de 150 000 habitants &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Groupe 4: Pays sans données d&apos;enregistrement des décès éligibles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Le service des systèmes d&apos;information sanitaire analyse la qualité et l&apos;exhaustivité des données. Pour le modèle de sécurité routière, si le pays est considéré par l&apos;OMS comme ayant de bonnes données d&apos;état civil (RV), cela signifie que le pays est dans le groupe 1, alors nous n&apos;appliquons &amp;#x2019; t un modèle de régression pour arriver à une estimation ( nous pouvons toutefois projeter vers l&apos;avant si les données d&apos;état civil sont datées). Si le pays est considéré dans le groupe 4, nous appliquons une régression binomiale négative où N est le nombre total de décès sur la route, C est un terme constant, Xi est un ensemble de covariables explicatives, Pop est la population pour le pays-année, et? est le terme d&apos;erreur binomial négatif. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Pour les pays du groupe 2, la méthode de régression décrite ci-dessus a été utilisée pour projeter l&apos;année la plus récente pour laquelle une estimation du nombre total de décès était disponible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Enfin, les pays du groupe 3 qui ont une population de moins de 150 000 habitants et ne disposaient pas de données d&apos;enregistrement des décès éligibles, les estimations de régression n&apos;ont pas été utilisées. Seuls les décès déclarés étaient directement sans ajustement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Plus de détails sur ce processus d&apos;estimation dans &lt;em&gt; Global Status Report on Road Safety 2015 &lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Traitement des valeurs manquantes: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Au niveau national : &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Le traitement des données manquantes a été effectué comme suit : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 1) Nous avons identifié des valeurs manquantes (ou des années) dans les données de l&apos;état civil (VR) et cherché d&apos;autres sources dans nos données de cas à partir du questionnaire / enquête (rapporté) pour ces années. Nous avons ensuite calculé le facteur VR / déclaré pour les 3 dernières années où les données VR et déclarées étaient disponibles et nous avons utilisé ce facteur pour ajuster les données déclarées afin de remplacer la valeur manquante des données VR. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 2) Dans le cas où il y avait des données manquantes dans les données VR et rapportées, les valeurs manquantes ont été imputées avec une régression binomiale négative du taux pour chaque pays si la régression convergeait ou était significative. Sinon, nous avons utilisé le taux moyen d&apos;années avec des données. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Aux niveaux régional et mondial : &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Identique à la procédure décrite pour 11.2 ci-dessus &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Agrégats régionaux : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Nous avons utilisé le groupement régional de l&apos;OMS et la moyenne pour calculer le taux pour chaque région. Cela signifie la somme des décès dus aux accidents de la route pour la région (i) multipliée par 100 000 et divisée par la population de la région (i). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Disponibilité des données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Nous avons des données pour 194 pays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Séries chronologiques : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; De 2000 à 2013 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Désagrégation : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Nous avons désagrégé les données par types d&apos;usagers de la route, âge, sexe, groupes de revenus et régions de l&apos;OMS &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sources des divergences :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les estimations des taux de trafic routier faites par l&apos;OMS, sont dans de nombreux pays, différentes des estimations officielles pour les raisons décrites ci-dessus se rapportant à notre méthodologie. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Il existe également des différences dans les données utilisées pour la population entre les données nationales et les estimations produites par le Département de la population des Nations Unies. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Références &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; URL : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/violence_injury_prevention&quot;&gt; http://www.who.int/violence_injury_prevention &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Références : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/violence_injury_prevention/road_safety_status/2015/fr/&quot;&gt; http://www.who.int/violence_injury_prevention/road_safety_status/2015/fr/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 3: Обеспечение здорового образа жизни и содействие благополучию для всех в любом возрасте&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 3.6: К 2020 году вдвое сократить во всем мире число смертей и травм в результате дорожно-транспортных происшествий&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 3.6.1: Смертность в результате дорожно-транспортных происшествий&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Последнее обновление: 19 июля 2016 года&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Связанные показатели по состоянию на февраль 2020 года &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 3,5, 11,2 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Институциональная информация &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Организация (и): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Всемирная организация здравоохранения (ВОЗ) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Определение: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Смертность в результате дорожно-транспортных происшествий определяется как количество дорожно-транспортных происшествий со смертельным исходом на 100 000 населения. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Числитель: Число погибших в результате дорожно-транспортных происшествий &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Абсолютное количество лиц, погибших в результате дорожно-транспортных происшествий. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Знаменатель: Численность населения (количество лиц по странам) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; По смертности в результате ДТП у нас есть два источника данных. Данные из глобального отчета о состоянии безопасности дорожного движения и данные регистрации естественного движения населения или свидетельств о смерти, которые ВОЗ ежегодно получает от государств-членов (министерств здравоохранения). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; По населению мы используем данные Отдела народонаселения ООН / Департамента по экономическим и социальным вопросам. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Методология, включающая сбор данных из ряда различных секторов и от заинтересованных сторон в каждой стране, выглядит следующим образом. Национальные координаторы данных (НКД), назначенные их правительствами, прошли обучение по методологии проекта. Как представители своих министерств, они должны были подобрать до восьми других экспертов по безопасности дорожного движения в своей стране из различных секторов (например, здравоохранения, полиции, транспорта, неправительственных организаций и / или академических кругов) и способствовать достижению консенсуса среди этих респондентов. Поскольку каждый эксперт отвечал на вопросник, основываясь на своем опыте, согласительное совещание, организованное национальными координаторами данных, позволило обсудить все ответы, и группа использовала это обсуждение, чтобы договориться об одном окончательном наборе информации, который наилучшим образом отражает ситуацию в их странах в это время (до 2014 года, по последним имеющимся данным). Затем этот набор был отправлен во Всемирную организацию здравоохранения (ВОЗ). Более подробная информация содержится в Докладе о состоянии безопасности дорожного движения в мире за 2015 год. Для стандартизации собранных данных странам было предоставлено руководство по нашему вопроснику с описанием возрастных групп и других параметров.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Календарь &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Сбор данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Следующий раунд сбора данных запланирован на 2017 год, хотя данные по смертельным случаям, скорее всего, будут собраны за 2015 или 2016 год (мы запросим самые последние доступные данные по стране). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Выпуск данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Новые данные по этому показателю будут опубликованы в начале 2019 года. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Поставщики данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные по смертности в результате дорожно-транспортных происшествий предоставляются на национальном уровне в основном тремя министерствами, а именно министерством здравоохранения, министерством внутренних дел и министерством транспорта &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Составители данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ВОЗ является организацией, ответственной за составление и представление отчетности по этому показателю на глобальном уровне &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Нет данных, относящихся к учёту естественного движения населения во всех странах, которые можно было бы сравнить с данными, полученными в ходе обследования. Мы опубликовали только доверительные интервалы для стран, которые имеют недостаточную полноту данных учета естественного движения населения. Также мы не можем собирать данные по дорожно-транспортным происшествиям каждый год, используя методологию, изложенную в Докладе о состоянии безопасности дорожного движения в мире. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Наша модель основана на качестве получаемых данных. Как организация здравоохранения, мы в первую очередь полагаемся на представление в ВОЗ (по официальным каналам) страновых данных регистрации естественного движения населения от министерств здравоохранения. Эти данные по всем причинам смерти затем анализируются нашими коллегами из отдела информационных систем здравоохранения, чтобы решить, насколько данные хорошего качества , то есть определить, отражают ли они достаточную полноту и охват смертности по всем причинам смертей. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Мы систематизировали страны по 4 категориям или группам, а именно: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Группа 1: страны с данными регистрации смертей (достоверные данные регистрации естественного движения населения / смертности) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Группа 2: страны с альтернативными источниками информации о причинах смертей &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Группа 3: страны с численностью населения менее 150 000 человек &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Группа 4: страны, в которых нет данных, соответствующих критериям, по регистрации смертей. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Отдел информационных систем здравоохранения анализирует качество и полноту данных. Для модели безопасности дорожного движения, если ВОЗ считает страну имеющей хорошие данные регистрации актов гражданского состояния (VR), это означает, что страна находится в группе 1, тогда мы не применяем регрессионную модель для получения оценки (мы можем , однако, если данные регистрации актов гражданского состояния датированы, сделать прогноз). Если страна входит в группу 4, мы применяем отрицательную биномиальную регрессию, где N - общее количество смертей в результате дорожно-транспортных происшествий, C - постоянный член, Xi - набор объясняющих ковариат, Pop - это население страны-года и ? отрицательный биномиальный параметр ошибки. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для стран из группы 2 описанный выше метод регрессии использовался для прогнозирования самого последнего года, для которого была доступна оценка общего числа смертей. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Наконец, в странах из группы 3 с населением менее 150 000 человек и отсутствием соответствующих данных регистрации смертей регрессионные оценки не использовались. Только зарегистрированные случаи смертей не корректировались. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Подробнее об этом процессе оценки см. в &lt;em&gt; Докладе о состоянии безопасности дорожного движения в мире за 2015 год.&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Обработка отсутствующих данных проводилась следующим образом: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 1) Выявление недостающих значений (или лет) в данных регистрации естественного движения населения (РЕДН) и поиск других источников данных для этих лет (вопросник / обследование (reported). Затем мы рассчитали коэффициент РЕДН/Reported за последние 3 года, по которым были доступны данные РЕДН и Reported, и использовали этот коэффициент для корректировки данных, чтобы вменить отсутствующее значение данных РЕДН. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 2) В случае отсутствия данных в РЕДН и Reported данных, недостающие значения были вменены с помощью отрицательной биномиальной регрессии уровня смертности для каждой страны, если регрессия сходилась или была значимой. В противном случае мы использовали средний уровень смертности за те года, данные по которым доступны. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; То же, что и процедура, описанная выше для пункта 11.2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Региональные агрегаты: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Мы использовали региональную группировку ВОЗ и среднее значение для расчета уровня смертности для каждого региона. Показатель представляет собой сумму смертей в результате дорожно-транспортных происшествий в регионе (i), умноженную на 100 000 человек и деленную на численность населения в регионе (i).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; У нас есть данные по 194 странам. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; С 2000 по 2013 год &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Мы дезагрегировали данные по типам участников дорожного движения, возрасту, полу, группам доходов и регионам ВОЗ &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Оценка ВОЗ уровней смертности от дорожно-транспортных происшествий во многих странах отличается от официальных оценок по причинам, описанным выше, которые связаны с нашей методологией. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Существуют также различия в данных по численности населения, используемых для расчета, между национальными данными и оценками, подготовленными Департаментом народонаселения ООН.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/violence_injury_prevention&quot;&gt; http://www.who.int/violence_injury_prevention &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Ссылки: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/violence_injury_prevention/road_safety_status/2015/en/&quot;&gt; http://www.who.int/violence_injury_prevention/road_safety_status/2015/en/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
