<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 3-c-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 3: Ensure healthy lives and promote well-being for all at all ages&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 3.c: Substantially increase health financing and the recruitment, development, training and retention of the health workforce in developing countries, especially in least developed countries and small island developing States&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 3.c.1: Health worker density and distribution &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2021-03-01&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;World Health Organization (WHO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;World Health Organization (WHO)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Health worker densities by occupation&lt;/u&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Density of medical doctors: &lt;/strong&gt;The density of medical doctors is defined as the number of medical doctors, including generalists and specialist medical practitioners per 10,000 population in the given national and/or subnational area. The International Standard Classification of Occupations (ISCO) unit group codes included in this category are 221, 2211 and 2212 of ISCO-08. &lt;br&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Density of nursing and midwifery personnel&lt;/strong&gt;: The density of nursing and midwifery personnel is defined as the number of nursing and midwifery personnel per 10,000 population in the given national and/or subnational area. The ISCO-08 codes included in this category are 2221, 2222, 3221 and 3222. &lt;br&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Density of dentists&lt;/strong&gt;: The density of dentists is defined as the number of dentists per 10,000 population in the given national and/or subnational area. The ISCO-08 codes included in this category are 2261. &lt;br&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Density of pharmacists:&lt;/strong&gt; The density of pharmacists is defined as the number of pharmacists per 10,000 population in the given national and/or subnational area. The ISCO-08 codes included in this category are 2262. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Health worker distribution by sex&lt;/u&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Percentage of male medical doctors&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Male doctors as percentage of all medical doctors at national level. The ISCO-08 codes included in this category are 221, 2211 and 2212. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Percentage of female medical doctors&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Female doctors as percentage of all medical doctors at national level. The ISCO-08 codes included in this category are 221, 2211 and 2212. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Percentage of male nursing personnel:&lt;/strong&gt; Male nursing personnel as percentage of all nursing personnel at national level. The ISCO-08 codes included in this category are 2221 and 3221. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Percentage of female nursing personnel:&lt;/strong&gt; Female nursing personnel as percentage of all nursing personnel at national level. The ISCO-08 codes included in this category are 2221 and 3221. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Health worker densities by occupation: Data is represented as Per 10,000 population&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Health worker distribution by sex: Data is presented in percentage&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;International Standard Classification of Occupations (ISCO-08)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In response to WHA69.19, an online National Health Workforce Accounts (NHWA) data platform was developed to facilitate national reporting. In addition to the reporting, the platform also serves as an analytical tool at the national/regional and global levels. Since Its launch in November 2017, Member States are called to use the NHWA data platform to report health workforce data. Complementing the national reporting through the NHWA data platform, additional sources such as the National Census, Labour Force Surveys and key administrative national and regional sources are also employed. Most of the data from administrative sources are derived from published national health sector reviews and/or official country reports to WHO offices. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ongoing process&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First quarter of 2021&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; NHWA focal point at national level &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WHO &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WHA69.19 urges Member States to share a core set of data to WHO, to increase the evidence base on health workforce statistics globally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For detailed metadata and definitions, refer to the National Health Workforce Accounts (NHWA) Handbook (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/nhwa/en/&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/nhwa/en/&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data on health workers tend to be more complete for the public health sector and may underestimate the active workforce in the private, military, nongovernmental organization and faith-based health sectors. In many cases, information maintained at the national regulatory bodies and professional councils are not updated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As data is not always published annually for each country, the latest available data has been used. Due to the differences in data sources, considerable variability remains across countries in the coverage, periodicity, quality and completeness of the original data. Densities are calculated using national population estimates from the United Nations Population Division&amp;apos;s World Population Prospects database and may vary from densities produced by the country. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Health worker densities by occupation&lt;/u&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figures for number of medical doctors (including generalist and specialist medical practitioners) depending on the nature of the original data source may include practising medical doctors only or all registered medical doctors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figures for number of nursing and midwifery include nursing personnel and midwifery personnel, whenever available. In many countries, nurses trained with midwifery skills are counted and reported as nurses. This makes the distinction between nursing personnel and midwifery personnel difficult to draw. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figures for number of dentists include dentists in the given national and/or subnational area. Depending on the nature of the original data source may include practising (active) only or all registered in the health occupation. The ISCO -08 codes included here are 2261. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figures for number of pharmacists include in the given national and/or subnational area. Depending on the nature of the original data source may include practising (active) only or all registered in the health occupation. The ISCO -08 codes that relate to this occupation is 2262. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, the denominator data for workforce density (i.e. national population estimates) are obtained from the United Nations Population Division&amp;apos;s World Population Prospects database. In cases where the official health workforce report provides density indicators instead of counts, estimates of the stock were then calculated using the population estimated from the United Nations Population Division&amp;apos;s World population prospects database (2017). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Health worker distribution by sex&lt;/u&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of male medical doctors as reported by the country is expressed as a percentage of total male and female medical doctors reported by the country&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of female medical doctors as reported by the country is expressed as a percentage of total male and female medical doctors reported by the country&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of male nursing personnel as reported by the country is expressed as a percentage of total male and female nursing personnel reported by the country&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of female nursing personnel as reported by the country is expressed as a percentage of total male and female nursing personnel reported by the country&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The data recorded in the NHWA data platform is validated by country focal points. Data quality checks and country consultation are employed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022;&lt;strong&gt; At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The global average density was estimated as the population weighted average of the national densities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the regional average density, data for the countries with missing values, if any in the last 5 years were first estimated with neighbouring comparable countries. Then the regional average was also computed as a weighted average by pooling these estimated values plus the available national densities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The population for estimating densities at regional and global level were extracted from the UN Population Division 2017. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Countries are requested to refer to the National Health Workforce Accounts (NHWA) Handbook (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/nhwa/en/&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/nhwa/en/&lt;/a&gt; ), for guidance on indicators and methodology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data available for 2000-2018. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web link to the database: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National level data &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sixty-ninth World Health Assembly Agenda Item 16.1. Global strategy on human resources for health: workforce 2030 (2016), available from (&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA69/A69_R19-en.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA69/A69_R19-en.pdf&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WHO (2014). Global strategy on human resources for health: Workforce 2030 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://who.int/hrh/resources/pub_globstrathrh-2030/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://who.int/hrh/resources/pub_globstrathrh-2030/en/&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;WHO Global Health Workforce Statistics.&amp;quot; World Health Organization, n.d. Web. Feb. 2018. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;WHO Global Health Workforce Statistics.&amp;quot; World Health Organization, n.d. Web. Feb. 2018. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.A1444?lang=en&amp;amp;showonly=HWF&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.A1444?lang=en&amp;amp;showonly=HWF&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WHO, National Health Workforce Accounts: A Handbook, n.d. Wed. Feb. 2018. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/nhwa/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/nhwa/en/&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WHO 13&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Global Programme of Work (https://www.who.int/about/what-we-do/gpw-thirteen-consultation/en/) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 3: Garantizar una vida sana y promover el bienestar de todos a todas las edades&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 3.c: Aumentar considerablemente la financiación de la salud y la contratación, el perfeccionamiento, la capacitación y la retención del personal sanitario en los países en desarrollo, especialmente en los países menos adelantados y los pequeños Estados insulares en desarrollo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 3.c.1: Densidad y distribución del personal sanitario&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Última actualización: 13 febrero 2020&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Información institucional &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Organización (es): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Organización Mundial de la Salud (OMS) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Densidad de trabajadores de la salud por ocupación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definición:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Densidad de médicos:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;La densidad de médicos se define como el número de médicos, incluidos los generalistas y los médicos especialistas, por cada 10.000 habitantes en un área nacional y/o subnacional determinada. Los códigos de grupos de unidades de la Clasificación Internacional Uniforme de Ocupaciones (CIUO) incluidos en esta categoría son 221, 2211 y 2212 de la CIUO-08.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Densidad de personal de enfermería y partería&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; La densidad de personal de enfermería y partería se define como el número de personal de enfermería y partería por cada 10.000 habitantes en el área nacional y/o subnacional dada. Los códigos CIUO-08 incluidos en esta categoría son 2221, 2222, 3221 y 3222.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Densidad de dentistas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt; La densidad de dentistas se define como el número de dentistas por cada 10.000 habitantes en el área nacional y/o subnacional dada. Los códigos CIUO-08 incluidos en esta categoría son 2261.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Densidad de farmacéuticos:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; La densidad de farmacéuticos se define como el número de farmacéuticos por cada 10.000 habitantes en el área nacional y/o subnacional dada. Los códigos CIUO-08 incluidos en esta categoría son 2262.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distribución del personal de salud por sexo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Porcentaje de médicos varones&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Médicos varones como porcentaje del total de médicos a nivel nacional. Los códigos CIUO-08 incluidos en esta categoría son 221, 2211 y 2212.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Porcentaje de mujeres médicas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Médicos mujeres como porcentaje de todos los médicos a nivel nacional. Los códigos CIUO-08 incluidos en esta categoría son 221, 2211 y 2212.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Porcentaje de personal de enfermería masculino:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Personal de enfermería masculino como porcentaje de todo el personal de enfermería a nivel nacional. Los códigos CIUO-08 incluidos en esta categoría son el 2221 y el 3221.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Porcentaje de personal de enfermería femenino:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Personal de enfermería femenino como porcentaje de todo el personal de enfermería a nivel nacional. Los códigos CIUO-08 incluidos en esta categoría son 2221 y 3221.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En respuesta a la WHA69.19, se desarrolló una plataforma de datos en línea de las Cuentas Nacionales del Personal Sanitario (NHWA, por sus siglas en inglés) para facilitar la presentación de informes nacionales. Además de la presentación de informes, la plataforma también sirve como herramienta analítica a nivel nacional/regional y mundial. Desde su lanzamiento en noviembre de 2017, los Estados miembros están llamados a utilizar la plataforma de datos NHWA para informar sobre los datos del personal sanitario. Como complemento a la notificación nacional a través de la plataforma de datos de la NHWA, también se emplean fuentes adicionales como el Censo Nacional, las Encuestas de Población Activa y las principales fuentes administrativas nacionales y regionales. La mayoría de los datos procedentes de fuentes administrativas proceden de exámenes nacionales del sector de la salud publicados y/o de informes oficiales de los países a las oficinas de la OMS. Los países con datos faltantes para el año 2016 (valor de referencia para la presentación de informes del 13º Programa Mundial de Trabajo de la OMS) se estimaron a partir de un modelo lineal de tendencia temporal de la densidad basado en al menos cinco observaciones que incluían una densidad notificada en el periodo 2011-2013.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Calendario&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Recolección de datos:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Proceso en curso&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publicación de datos:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Primer trimestre de 2020&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Punto focal de la NHWA a nivel nacional&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OMS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos sobre los trabajadores de la salud tienden a ser más completos para el sector de la salud pública y pueden subestimar la fuerza de trabajo activa en los sectores privado, militar, no gubernamental y religiosa. En muchos casos, la información mantenida en los órganos nacionales de reglamentación y los consejos profesionales no se actualiza. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Como los datos no siempre se publican anualmente para cada país, se han utilizado los últimos datos disponibles. Debido a las diferencias en las fuentes de datos, sigue habiendo una considerable variabilidad entre los países en cuanto a la cobertura, la periodicidad, la calidad y la exhaustividad de los datos originales. Las densidades se calculan utilizando estimaciones nacionales de población de la base de datos de perspectivas de población mundial de la División de Población de las Naciones Unidas y pueden variar de las densidades producidas por el país. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Densidad de trabajadores de la salud por ocupación:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las cifras del número de médicos (incluyendo médicos generalistas y especialistas), dependiendo de la naturaleza de la fuente de datos original, pueden incluir sólo a los médicos en ejercicio o a todos los médicos colegiados.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las cifras del número de enfermería y partería incluyen personal de enfermería y personal de partería, siempre que estén disponibles. En muchos países, el personal de enfermería formado con conocimientos de partería se contabilizan y notifican como personal de enfermería. Esto hace que la distinción entre el personal de enfermería y el de partería sea difícil de establecer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las cifras sobre el número de dentistas incluyen a los dentistas de la zona nacional y/o subnacional determinada. Dependiendo de la naturaleza de la fuente de datos original, pueden incluir sólo a los practicantes (activos) o a todos los registrados en la ocupación sanitaria. Los códigos CIUO -08 incluidos aquí son 2261.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las cifras del número de farmacéuticos incluyen el área nacional y/o subnacional dada. Dependiendo de la naturaleza de la fuente de datos original, puede incluir sólo a los que ejercen (activos) o a todos los registrados en la ocupación sanitaria. El código CIUO -08 que se refiere a esta ocupación es el 2262.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En general, los datos del denominador para la densidad de la fuerza de trabajo (es decir, estimaciones nacionales de población) se obtienen de la base de datos de perspectivas de población mundial de la División de Población de las Naciones Unidas. En los casos en los que el informe oficial sobre el personal de salud proporciona indicadores de densidad en lugar de recuentos, las estimaciones del stock se calcularon entonces utilizando la población estimada a partir de la base de datos Perspectivas de población mundial (2017) de la División de Población de las Naciones Unidas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distribución del personal sanitario por sexo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El número de médicos varones declarado por el país se expresa como porcentaje del total de médicos y médicas declarados por el país.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El número de mujeres médicas declarado por el país se expresa como porcentaje del total de médicos y médicas declarados por el país.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El número de personal de enfermería masculino notificado por el país se expresa como porcentaje del total de personal de enfermería masculino y femenino notificado por el país.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El número de personal de enfermería femenino notificado por el país se expresa como porcentaje del total de personal de enfermería masculino y femenino notificado por el país.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agregados regionales y globales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La densidad media mundial se estimó como la media ponderada por la población de las densidades nacionales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para la densidad media regional, los datos de los países con valores ausentes en el periodo 2013-2018 se estimaron primero con los países vecinos comparables. A continuación, la media regional también se calculó como una media ponderada mediante la agrupación de estos valores estimados más las densidades nacionales disponibles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La población para estimar las densidades a nivel regional y mundial se extrajo de la División de Población de las Naciones Unidas de 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Datos disponibles para 2000-2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enlace web a la base de datos: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Datos a nivel nacional&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Referencias:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sexagésima novena Asamblea Mundial de la Salud Punto 16.1 del orden del día. Estrategia mundial sobre recursos humanos para la salud: personal 2030 (2016), disponible en (&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA69/A69_R19-en.pdf&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA69/A69_R19-en.pdf&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OMS (2014). Estrategia mundial sobre recursos humanos para la salud: Workforce 2030 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://who.int/hrh/resources/pub_globstrathrh-2030/en/&quot;&gt;http://who.int/hrh/resources/pub_globstrathrh-2030/en/&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Estadísticas del personal sanitario mundial de la OMS.&amp;quot; Organización Mundial de la Salud, s.f. Web. Feb. 2018. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;WHO Global Health Workforce Statistics.&amp;quot; Organización Mundial de la Salud, s.f. Web. Feb. 2018. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.A1444?lang=en&amp;amp;showonly=HWF&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.A1444?lang=en&amp;amp;showonly=HWF&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OMS, Cuentas nacionales del personal sanitario: A Handbook, n.d. Wed. Feb. 2018. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/nhwa/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/nhwa/en/&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programa mundial de trabajo de la OMS 13&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/about/what-we-do/gpw-thirteen-consultation/en/&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/about/what-we-do/gpw-thirteen-consultation/en/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 3 : Permettre à tous de vivre en bonne santé et promouvoir le bien-être de tous à tout âge&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 3.c : Accroître considérablement le budget de la santé et le recrutement, le perfectionnement, la formation et le maintien en poste du personnel de santé dans les pays en développement, notamment dans les pays les moins développés et les petits États insulaires en développement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 3.c.1 : Densité et répartition du personnel de santé&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2021-03-01&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organisation mondiale de la Santé (OMS)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organisation mondiale de la Santé (OMS)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Densité du personnel de santé par profession&lt;/u&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Densité de médecins :&lt;/strong&gt; La densité de médecins est définie comme le nombre de médecins, y compris les généralistes et les médecins spécialistes pour 10 000 habitants dans la zone nationale et / ou infranationale donnée. Les codes de groupe d’unités de la Classification internationale type des professions (CITP) inclus dans cette catégorie sont 221, 2211 et 2212 de la CITP-08. &lt;br&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Densité du personnel infirmier et obstétrical :&lt;/strong&gt; La densité du personnel infirmier et obstétrical est définie comme le nombre de personnel infirmier et obstétrical pour 10 000 habitants dans la zone nationale et/ou infranationale donnée. Les codes CITP-08 inclus dans cette catégorie sont 2221, 2222, 3221 et 3222. &lt;br&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Densité de dentistes :&lt;/strong&gt; La densité de dentistes est définie comme le nombre de dentistes pour 10 000 habitants dans la zone nationale et / ou infranationale donnée. Le code CITP-08 inclus dans cette catégorie est 2261. &lt;br&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Densité de pharmaciens :&lt;/strong&gt; La densité de pharmaciens est définie comme le nombre de pharmaciens pour 10 000 habitants dans la zone nationale et/ou infranationale donnée. Le codes CITP-08 inclus dans cette catégorie est 2262. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Répartition du personnel de santé par sexe&lt;/u&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pourcentage de médecins de sexe masculin :&lt;/strong&gt; Médecins de sexe masculin en pourcentage de tous les médecins au niveau national. Les codes CITP-08 inclus dans cette catégorie sont 221, 2211 et 2212. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pourcentage de femmes médecins :&lt;/strong&gt; Femmes médecins en pourcentage de l’ensemble des médecins au niveau national. Les codes CITP-08 inclus dans cette catégorie sont 221, 2211 et 2212. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pourcentage de personnel infirmier masculin :&lt;/strong&gt; Personnel infirmier masculin en pourcentage de l’ensemble du personnel infirmier au niveau national. Les codes CITP-08 inclus dans cette catégorie sont 2221 et 3221. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pourcentage de femmes infirmières :&lt;/strong&gt; Personnel infirmier féminin en pourcentage de l’ensemble du personnel infirmier au niveau national. Les codes CITP-08 inclus dans cette catégorie sont 2221 et 3221. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Densités du personnel de santé par profession : les données sont représentées par 10 000 habitants&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Répartition du personnel de santé par sexe : les données sont présentées en pourcentage&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Classification internationale type des professions (CITP-08)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;En réponse à WHA69.19, une plateforme de données en ligne des comptes nationaux du personnel de santé (NHWA) a été développée pour faciliter la déclaration nationale. En plus des rapports, la plateforme sert également d&apos;outil analytique aux niveaux national/régional et mondial. Depuis son lancement en novembre 2017, les États membres sont invités à utiliser la plateforme de données des NHWA pour communiquer des données sur le personnel de santé. En complément du rapport national par le biais de cette plateforme, des sources supplémentaires telles que le recensement national, les enquêtes sur la population active et les principales sources administratives nationales et régionales sont également utilisées. La plupart des données provenant de sources administratives sont tirées d&apos;examens nationaux du secteur de la santé publiés et/ou de rapports officiels des pays aux bureaux de l&apos;OMS. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Processus en cours&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Premier trimestre 2021&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Point focal de la plateforme de données NHWA au niveau national &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;OMS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WHA69.19 exhorte les États membres à partager un ensemble de données de base avec l’OMS, afin d’accroître la base de données probantes de statistiques mondiales sur le personnel de santé. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pour obtenir des métadonnées et des définitions détaillées, reportez-vous au Manuel sur les comptes nationaux des personnels de santé (NHWA) (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/fr/publications/i/item/9789241513111&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/fr/publications/i/item/9789241513111&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les données sur les travailleurs de la santé ont tendance à être plus complètes pour le secteur de la santé publique et peuvent sous-estimer la main-d&apos;œuvre active dans les secteurs de la santé privé, militaire, des organisations non gouvernementales et confessionnel. Dans de nombreux cas, les informations conservées par les organismes nationaux de réglementation et par les conseils professionnels ne sont pas mises à jour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données n&apos;étant pas toujours publiées annuellement pour chaque pays, les dernières données disponibles ont été utilisées. En raison des différences entre les sources de données, une variabilité considérable subsiste entre les pays en ce qui concerne la couverture, la périodicité, la qualité et l&apos;exhaustivité des données originales. Les densités sont calculées à partir des estimations de la population nationale provenant de la base de données « World Population Prospects » de la Division de la population des Nations Unies et peuvent varier par rapport aux densités produites par le pays.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;u&gt;Densités du personnel de santé par profession&lt;/u&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les chiffres relatifs au nombre de médecins (y compris les médecins généralistes et spécialistes) en fonction de la nature de la source de données originale peuvent inclure uniquement les médecins en exercice ou tous les médecins enregistrés. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les chiffres relatifs au nombre de personnel de soins infirmiers et obstétricaux comprennent le personnel infirmier et le personnel obstétrical, lorsqu’ils sont disponibles. Dans de nombreux pays, les infirmières formées avec des compétences de sage-femme sont comptées et déclarées comme infirmières. Cela rend la distinction entre le personnel infirmier et le personnel sage-femme difficile à établir. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les chiffres relatifs au nombre de dentistes incluent les dentistes dans la zone nationale et/ou infranationale donnée. Selon la nature de la source de données originale, il peut s’agir de dentistes toujours actifs ou de tous ceux qui sont inscrits dans cette profession. Le code CITP-08 inclus est 2261. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les chiffres relatifs au nombre de pharmaciens incluent les pharmaciens dans la zone nationale et/ou infranationale donnée. Selon la nature de la source de données originale, il peut s’agir de pharmaciens toujours actifs ou de tous ceux qui sont inscrits dans cette profession. Le code CITP-08 inclus est 2262. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En général, les données du dénominateur de la densité de la main-d’œuvre (c’est-à-dire les estimations de la population nationale) sont obtenues à partir de la base de données « World Population Prospects » de la Division de la population des Nations Unies. Dans les cas où le rapport officiel sur le personnel de santé fournit des indicateurs de densité au lieu de dénombrements, les estimations du stock ont ensuite été calculées à l’aide de cette base de données. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;u&gt;Répartition du personnel de santé par sexe&lt;/u&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le nombre de médecins de sexe masculin tel que déclaré par le pays est exprimé en pourcentage du total des médecins masculins et féminins déclarés par le pays&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le nombre de femmes médecins tel que déclaré par le pays est exprimé en pourcentage du total des médecins masculins et féminins déclarés par le pays&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le nombre de personnel infirmier masculin tel que déclaré par le pays est exprimé en pourcentage du total du personnel infirmier masculin et féminin déclaré par le pays&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le nombre de femmes infirmières tel que déclaré par le pays est exprimé en pourcentage du total du personnel infirmier masculin et féminin déclaré par le pays&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les données enregistrées dans la plateforme de données NHWA sont validées par les points focaux nationaux. Des contrôles de la qualité des données et des consultations par pays sont utilisés. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; Au niveau national&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; Aux niveaux régional et mondial&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;La densité moyenne mondiale a été estimée comme la moyenne pondérée en fonction de la population des densités nationales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour la densité moyenne régionale, les données pour les pays avec des valeurs manquantes, s&apos;ils en ont au cours des 5 dernières années, ont d’abord été estimées avec des pays comparables voisins. Ensuite, la moyenne régionale a également été calculée comme une moyenne pondérée en mettant en commun ces valeurs estimées plus les densités nationales disponibles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La population pour l’estimation des densités aux niveaux régional et mondial a été extraite des « World Population Prospects » de la Division de la population des Nations Unies 2017. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les pays sont priés de consulter le Manuel sur les comptes nationaux des personnels de santé (NHWA) (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/fr/publications/i/item/9789241513111&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/fr/publications/i/item/9789241513111&lt;/a&gt;), pour obtenir des conseils sur les indicateurs et la méthodologie. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disponibilité des données &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Séries chronologiques : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Données disponibles pour la période 2000-2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lien internet vers la base de données : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Désagrégation :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Données au niveau national &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sources des divergences :&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL :&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Références :&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sixante-neuvième Assemblée mondiale de la Santé, item 16.1 de l&apos;ordre du jour.
Stratégie mondiale sur les ressources humaines pour la santé à l&apos;horizon 2030 (2016), disponible à l&apos;adresse (&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA69/A69_R19-fr.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA69/A69_R19-fr.pdf&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;« Global strategy on human resources for health: Workforce 2030 ». Organisation
mondiale de la Santé, 2014. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://who.int/hrh/resources/pub_globstrathrh-2030/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://who.int/hrh/resources/pub_globstrathrh-2030/en/&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;« WHO Global Health Workforce Statistics ». Organisation mondiale de la Santé,
consulté en février 2018. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;« WHO Global Health Workforce Statistics ». Organisation mondiale de la Santé,
consulté en février 2018. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.HWFGRP?lang=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.HWFGRP?lang=en&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manuel sur les comptes nationaux des personnels de santé. Organisation mondiale
de la Santé, 2017. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/fr/publications/i/item/9789241513111&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://www.who.int/fr/publications/i/item/9789241513111&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Projet de treizième programme général de travail, 2019-2023. Organisation
mondiale de la Santé. (https://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA71/A71_4-fr.pdf?ua=1) &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 3: Garantir o acesso á saude de qualidade e promover o bem-estar para todos, em todas as idades&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 3: Обеспечение здорового образа жизни и содействие благополучию для всех в любом возрасте&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 3.c: Существенно увеличить финансирование здравоохранения и набор, развитие, профессиональную подготовку и удержание медицинских кадров в развивающихся странах, особенно в наименее развитых странах и малых островных развивающихся государствах&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 3.c.1: Число медицинских работников на душу населения и их распределение&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Последнее обновление: 13 февраля 2020 года &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Институциональная информация &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Организация (и): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Всемирная организация здравоохранения (ВОЗ) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Концепции и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Численность медицинских работников на душу населения по профессиям: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Определение :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong &lt;em&gt; Численность врачей на душу населения: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Численность врачей на душу населения определяется как количество врачей, включая врачей общего профиля и практикующих врачей-специалистов, на 10 000 человек населения на данной национальной и / или субнациональной территории. Коды начальных групп Международной стандартной классификации занятий (МСКЗ), включенные в эту категорию, - 221, 2211 и 2212 МСКЗ-08. &lt;br&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong &lt;em&gt; Численность сестринского и акушерского персонала на душу населения&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Численность сестринского и акушерского персонала на душу населения определяется как количество медсестер и акушерок на 10 000 человек населения на данной национальной и / или субнациональной территории. Коды МСКЗ-08, включенные в эту категорию, - 2221, 2222, 3221 и 3222. &lt;br&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong &lt;em&gt; Численность стоматологов на душу населения&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; Численность стоматологов на душу населения определяется как количество стоматологов на 10 000 человек населения на данной национальной и / или субнациональной территории. Коды МСКЗ-08, включенные в эту категорию, - 2261. &lt;br&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Численность фармацевтов на душу населения: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Численность фармацевтов на душу населения определяется как количество фармацевтов на 10 000 человек населения на данной национальной и / или субнациональной территории. Коды МСКЗ-08, включенные в эту категорию, - 2262. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Распределение медицинских работников по полу &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&lt;em&gt; Доля врачей-мужчин &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Доля врачей-мужчин от всех врачей на национальном уровне. Коды МСКЗ-08, включенные в эту категорию, - 221, 2211 и 2212. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&lt;em&gt; Доля врачей-женщин &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Доля врачей-женщин от всех врачей на национальном уровне. Коды МСКЗ-08, включенные в эту категорию, - 221, 2211 и 2212. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&lt;em&gt; Доля среднего медицинского персонала-мужчин: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Доля среднего медперсонала мужского пола от всего среднего медицинского персонала на национальном уровне. Коды МСКЗ-08, включенные в эту категорию, - 2221 и 3221. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong &lt;em&gt; Доля медсестер-женщин: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Доля медсестринского персонала женского пола от всего сестринского персонала на национальном уровне. Коды МСКЗ-08, включенные в эту категорию, - 2221 и 3221. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Во исполнение резолюции WHA69.19 была разработана онлайн-платформа данных национальной системы учета кадров здравоохранения (НСУКЗ) для облегчения национальной отчетности. Помимо целей отчетности, платформа также служит аналитическим инструментом на национальном / региональном и глобальном уровнях. С момента запуска в ноябре 2017 года ВОЗ настоятельно просит государства-члены использовать платформу данных НСУКЗ для представления данных по учету кадров здравоохранения. В дополнение к национальной отчетности, реализуемой с помощью платформы данных НСУКЗ, также используются дополнительные источники данных, такие как национальная перепись населения, обследования рабочей силы и основные национальные и региональные источники административных данных. Большинство данных из административных источников получено из опубликованных национальных обзоров сектора здравоохранения и / или официальных страновых отчетов, представляемых в отделения ВОЗ. Значения для стран, у которых отсутствуют данные за 2016 год (базисное значение для отчетности 13-й Глобальной программы работы ВОЗ), были рассчитаны на основе линейной модели временного тренда численности работников на душу населения с использованием не менее пяти элементов данных, включая одно значение численности работников на душу населения, имеющееся в отчетах за период 2011-2013 годов.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Календарь &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Сбор данных: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Постоянный процесс &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Выпуск данных: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Первый квартал 2020 года &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Поставщики данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Координатор национальной системы учета кадров здравоохранения (НСУКЗ) на национальном уровне &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Составители данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ВОЗ &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Данные по медицинским работникам, как правило, являются более полными для сектора общественного здравоохранения и могут быть занижены в отношении активной рабочей силы в частном, военном, неправительственном и религиозном секторах здравоохранения. Во многих случаях информация, содержащаяся в национальных органах управления и профессиональных советах, не обновляется. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Поскольку данные не всегда публикуются ежегодно по каждой стране, то используются самые последние доступные данные. Из-за различий в источниках данных по странам сохраняется значительная вариативность в охвате, периодичности, качестве и полноте исходных данных. Численность работников на душу населения рассчитывается с использованием национальных оценок населения из базы данных &quot;Мировые демографические перспективы&quot; Отдела народонаселения Организации Объединенных Наций и может отличаться от значения численности работников на душу населения, рассчитанного страной.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Численность работников здравоохранения на душу населения по роду занятий: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Данные по количеству врачей (включая врачей общего профиля и практикующих врачей-специалистов) в зависимости от характера исходного источника данных могут включать только практикующих врачей или всех зарегистрированных врачей. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные по количеству медсестер и акушерок включают медперсонал и акушерский персонал, если таковой имеется. Во многих странах медсестры, обученные акушерским навыкам, считаются медсестрами. Из-за этого сложно провести различие между сестринским и акушерским персоналом. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные по количеству стоматологов включают стоматологов на данной национальной и / или субнациональной территории. В зависимости от характера исходных данных источник может включать только практикующих (активных) врачей или всех лиц, зарегистрированных по специальности здравоохранения. Коды МСКЗ-08, включенные здесь: 2261. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные по количеству фармацевтов указаны для данной национальной и / или субнациональной территории. В зависимости от характера исходных данных источник может включать только практикующих (активных) фармацевтов или всех лиц, зарегистрированных по специальности здравоохранения. Коды МСКЗ-08, относящиеся к этой профессии, - 2262. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;В целом, данные знаменателя для численности рабочей силы на душу населения (то есть национальные оценки населения) получают из базы данных &quot;Мировые демографические перспективы&quot; Отдела народонаселения Организации Объединенных Наций. В тех случаях, если в официальном отчете о кадровых ресурсах здравоохранения вместо количественных значений численности ресурсов представлены показатели численности рабочей силы на душу населения, то оценки численности затем рассчитывались с использованием численности населения, взятой из базы данных &quot;Мировые демографические перспективы&quot; (2017) Отдела народонаселения ООН. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Распределение медицинских работников по полу: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Количество врачей-мужчин по данным страны выражается в виде доли от общего количества врачей-мужчин и врачей-женщин, представленного в страновом отчете &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Количество врачей-женщин по данным страны выражается в виде доли от общего количества врачей-мужчин и врачей-женщин, представленного в страновом отчете &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Количество медицинских братьев по данным страны выражается в виде доли от общего количества медицинских сестер и медицинских братьев, представленного в страновом отчете &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Количество медицинских сестер по данным страны выражается в виде доли от общего количества медицинских сестер и медицинских братьев, представленного в страновом отчете. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Региональные и глобальные агрегаты: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Глобальная средняя численность работников на душу населения рассчитывается как взвешенное на население среднее значение национальных численностей работников на душу населения. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Что касается региональной средней численности работников на душу населения, то данные для стран, по которым отсутствовали значения за период 2013–2018 годов, сначала рассчитывались с использованием данных, имеющихся по сопоставимым соседним странам. Затем среднее значение по региону также было вычислено как средневзвешенное значение путем объединения этих оценочных значений и доступных национальных данных по численности работников на душу населения. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Численность населения для расчета численности работников на душу населения на региональном и глобальном уровнях была получена из данных Отдела народонаселения ООН за 2017 год. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные доступны за 2000-2018 годы. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Веб-ссылка на базу данных: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&quot;&gt; http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные национального уровня &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&quot;&gt; http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Ссылки: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Шестьдесят девятая сессия Всемирной ассамблеи здравоохранения, пункт 16.1. Глобальная стратегия для развития кадровых ресурсов здравоохранения: трудовые ресурсы 2030 года (2016 год), доступно по ссылке (&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA69/A69_R19-en.pdf&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gb/ebwha/pdf_files/WHA69/A69_R19-en.pdf&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ВОЗ (2014). Глобальная стратегия для развития кадровых ресурсов здравоохранения: трудовые ресурсы 2030 года (&lt;a href=&quot;http://who.int/hrh/resources/pub_globstrathrh-2030/en/&quot;&gt;http://who.int/hrh/resources/pub_globstrathrh-2030/en/&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &amp;quot;Глобальная статистика ВОЗ учета кадров здравоохранения.&amp;quot; Всемирная организация здравоохранения, без даты. Интернет. Февраль 2018 года (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/hwfstats/en/&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &amp;quot;Глобальная статистика ВОЗ учета кадров здравоохранения.&amp;quot; Всемирная организация здравоохранения, без даты. Интернет. Февраль 2018 года (&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.A1444?lang=en&amp;amp;showonly=HWF&quot;&gt;http://apps.who.int/gho/data/node.main.A1444?lang=en&amp;amp;showonly=HWF&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ВОЗ, Национальные система учета кадров здравоохранения: Руководство, без даты. Интернет. Февраль 2018 года (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/nhwa/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/hrh/statistics/nhwa/en/&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ВОЗ 13 &lt;sup&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; Глобальная программа работы ВОЗ (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/about/what-we-do/gpw-thirteen-consultation/en/&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/about/what-we-do/gpw-thirteen-consultation/en/&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
