<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 4-2-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 4: Ensure inclusive and equitable quality education and promote lifelong learning opportunities for all&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 4.2: By 2030, ensure that all girls and boys have access to quality early childhood development, care and pre-primary education so that they are ready for primary education&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 4.2.1: Proportion of children aged 24&amp;#x2013;59 months who are developmentally on track in health, learning and psychosocial well-being, by sex&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Proportion of children who are developmentally on track in at least three of the following domains: literacy-numeracy, physical development, social-emotional development, and learning&lt;/p&gt;2022-03-31&lt;p&gt;Indicator 4.2.2: Participation rate in organized learning (one year before the official primary entry age), by sex&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;United Nations Children&amp;apos;s Fund (UNICEF)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;United Nations Children&amp;apos;s Fund (UNICEF)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proportion of children aged 24 to 59 months who are developmentally on track in health, learning and psychosocial well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The domains included in the indicator for SDG indicator 4.2.1 include the following concepts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Health&lt;/strong&gt;: gross motor development, fine motor development and self-care.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning&lt;/strong&gt;: expressive language, literacy, numeracy, pre-writing, and executive functioning.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psychosocial well-being: &lt;/strong&gt;emotional skills, social skills, internalizing behavior, and externalizing behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recommended measure for SDG 4.2.1 is the Early Childhood Development Index 2030 (ECDI2030) which is a 20-item instrument to measure developmental outcomes among children aged 24 to 59 months in population-based surveys. The indicator derived from the ECDI2030 is the proportion of children aged 24 to 59 months who have achieved the minimum number of milestones expected for their age group, defined as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Children age 24 to 29 months are classified as developmentally on-track if they have achieved at least 7 milestones;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Children age 30 to 35 months are classified as developmentally on-track if they have achieved at least 9 milestones;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Children age 36 to 41 months are classified as developmentally on-track if they have achieved at least 11 milestones;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Children age 42 to 47 months are classified as developmentally on-track if they have achieved at least 13 milestones;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Children age 48 to 59 months are classified as developmentally on-track if they have achieved at least 15 milestones. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Percent (%)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2015, UNICEF initiated a process of methodological development that involved extensive consultations with experts, partner agencies and national statistical authorities. Over the following five years, a sequence of carefully planned technical steps were executed, incorporating both qualitative and quantitative methods to identify the best items to measure indicator 4.2.1. This process led to the development of the ECDI2030.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ECDI2030 addresses the need for nationally representative and internationally comparable data on early childhood development, collected in a standardized way. It captures the achievement of key developmental milestones by children between the ages of 24 and 59 months. Mothers or primary caregivers are asked 20 questions about the way their children behave in certain everyday situations, and the skills and knowledge they have acquired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ECDI2030 can be integrated into existing national data collection efforts, including international household survey programmes such as UNICEF-supported Multiple Indicator Cluster Surveys (MICS) and the Demographic and Health Surveys (DHS). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ECDI2030 is meant to replace the Early Childhood Development Index (or ECDI) which collects data on the proxy indicator for SDG 4.2.1 that has been in use since 2015. The former ECDI and the new ECDI2030 target different age groups and measure slightly different development domains. Therefore, the indicators generated by both instruments may not be fully comparable and caution is needed when interpreting estimates produced by the two measures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;UNICEF undertakes a wide consultative process of compiling and assessing data from national sources for the purposes of updating its global databases on the situation of children. Up until 2017, the mechanism UNICEF used to collaborate with national authorities on ensuring data quality and international comparability on key indicators of relevance to children was known as Country Data Reporting on the Indicators for the Goals (CRING).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of 2018, UNICEF launched a new country consultation process with national authorities on selected child-related global SDG indicators for which it is custodian or co-custodian to meet emerging standards and guidelines on data flows for global reporting of SDG indicators, which place strong emphasis on technical rigour, country ownership and use of official data and statistics. The consultation process solicits feedback directly from National Statistical Offices (NSOs), as well as other government agencies responsible for official statistics, on the compilation of the indicators, including the data sources used, and the application of internationally agreed definitions, classification and methodologies to the data from that source. Once reviewed, feedback is made available to countries on whether or not specific data points are accepted, and if not, the reasons why. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UNICEF will undertake an annual country consultation likely between December and January every year to allow for review and processing of the feedback received in order to meet global SDG reporting deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Updated data on 4.2.1 as measured by the ECDI2030 will be available in the SDG reporting period every February/March.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National Statistical Offices (in most cases)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;United Nations Children&amp;apos;s Fund (UNICEF)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UNICEF is responsible for global monitoring and reporting on the wellbeing of children. It provides technical and financial assistance to Member States to support their efforts to collect quality data on early childhood development (ECD), including through the UNICEF-supported MICS household survey programme. UNICEF also compiles ECD statistics with the goal of making internationally comparable datasets publicly available, and it analyses ECD statistics which are included in relevant data-driven publications, including in its flagship publication, &lt;em&gt;The State of the World&amp;#x2019;s Children.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Early childhood development (ECD) sets the stage for life-long thriving. Investing in ECD is one of the most critical and cost-effective investments a country can make to improve adult health, education and productivity in order to build human capital and promote sustainable development. ECD is equity from the start and provides a good indication of national development. Efforts to improve ECD can bring about human, social and economic improvements for both individuals and societies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;SDG 4.2.1 was initially classified as Tier 3 and was upgraded to Tier 2 in 2019; additionally, changes to the indicator were made during the 2020 comprehensive review. In light of this and given that the ECDI2030 was officially released in March 2020, it will take some time for country uptake and implementation of the new measure and for data to become available from a sufficiently large enough number of countries. Therefore, in the meantime, a proxy indicator (children aged 36-59 months who are developmentally on-track in at least three of the following four domains: literacy-numeracy, physical, social-emotional and learning) will be used to report on 4.2.1, when relevant. This proxy indicator has been used for global SDG reporting since 2015 but is not fully aligned with the definition and age group covered by the SDG indicator formulation. When the proxy indicator is used for SDG reporting on 4.2.1 for a country, it will be footnoted as such in the global SDG database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The number of children aged 24 to 59 months who are developmentally on track in health, learning and psychosocial well-being divided by the total number of children aged 24 to 59 months in the population multiplied by 100.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A wide consultative process is undertaken to compile, assess and validate data from national sources. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The consultation process solicits feedback directly from National Statistical Offices, as well as other government agencies responsible for official statistics, on the compilation of the indicators, including the data sources used, and the application of internationally agreed definitions, classification and methodologies to the data from that source. The results of this country consultation are reviewed by UNICEF as the custodian agency. Once reviewed, feedback is made available to countries on whether or not specific data points are accepted, and if not, the reasons why. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The estimates compiled and presented at global level come directly from nationally produced data and are not adjusted or recalculated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When data for a country are entirely missing, UNICEF does not publish any country-level estimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The regional average is applied to those countries within the region with missing values for the purposes of calculating regional aggregates only but are not published as country-level estimates. Regional aggregates are only published when at least 50 percent of the regional population for the relevant age group are covered by the available data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The global aggregate is a weighted average of all countries with available data. Global aggregates are published regardless of population coverage, but the number of countries and the proportion of the relevant population group represented by the available data are clearly indicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regional aggregates are weighted averages of all the countries within the region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Countries gather prevalence data on children&amp;#x2019;s developmental status through household surveys such as UNICEF-supported MICS or Demographic and Health Surveys.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The process behind the production of reliable statistics on ECD is well established within UNICEF. The quality and process leading to the production of the SDG indicator 4.2.1 is ensured by working closely with the statistical offices and other relevant stakeholders through a consultative process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UNICEF maintains the global database on ECD that is used for SDG and other official reporting. Before the inclusion of any data point in the database, it is reviewed by technical focal points at UNICEF headquarters to check for consistency and overall data quality. This review is based on a set of objective criteria to ensure that only the most recent and reliable information are included in the databases. These criteria include the following: data sources must include proper documentation; data values must be representative at the national population level; data are collected using an appropriate methodology (e.g., sampling); data values are based on a sufficiently large sample; data conform to the standard indicator definition including age group and concepts, to the extent possible; data are plausible based on trends and consistency with previously published/reported estimates for the indicator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of 2018, UNICEF undertakes an annual consultation with government authorities on 10 of the child-related SDG indicators in its role of sole or joint custodian, and in line with its global monitoring mandate and normative commitments to advancing the 2030 Agenda for children. This includes indicator 4.2.1. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data consistency and quality checks are regularly conducted for validation of the data before dissemination. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data on the indicator collected through implementation of the ECDI2030 are expected to become available, beginning in 2022. Comparable data collected by the ECDI are currently available for around 80 countries. Countries with data on the proxy indicator collected with the ECDI will continue to be used for global SDG reporting until new data using the ECDI2030 are available. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not available&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sex&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The estimates compiled and presented at global level come directly from nationally produced data and are not adjusted or recalculated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;data.unicef.org&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://data.unicef.org/ecd/development-status.html&quot;&gt;http://data.unicef.org/ecd/development-status.html&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 4 : Assurer l&apos;accès de tous à une éducation de qualité, sur un pied d&apos;égalité, et promouvoir les possibilités d&apos;apprentissage tout au long de la vie&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 4.2 : D’ici 2030, faire en sorte que toutes les filles et tous les garçons aient accès à des services de développement et de soins de la petite enfance et à une éducation préscolaire de qualité qui les préparent pour le cycle d&apos;éducation du primaire&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 4.2.1 : Proportion d’enfants âgés de 24 à 59 mois qui sont sur la bonne voie de développement en matière de santé, d’apprentissage et de bien-être psychosocial, selon le sexe&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2022-03-31&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 4.2.2 : Taux de participation à des activités d’apprentissage organisées (un an avant l’âge officiel de scolarisation dans le primaire), selon le sexe&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fonds des Nations Unies pour l’enfance (UNICEF)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fonds des Nations Unies pour l’enfance (UNICEF)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportion d&apos;enfants âgés de 24 à 59 mois dont le développement est sur la bonne voie en matière de santé, d&apos;apprentissage et de bien-être psychosocial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concept :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les domaines inclus dans l&apos;indicateur 4.2.1 des ODD incluent les concepts suivants :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Santé&lt;/strong&gt; : développement de la motricité globale, développement de la motricité fine et soins personnels&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apprentissage&lt;/strong&gt; : langage expressif, littératie, numératie, pré-écriture et fonctionnement exécutif&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bien-être psychosocial : &lt;/strong&gt;compétences émotionnelles, compétences sociales, comportement d&apos;intériorisation et comportement d&apos;extériorisation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La mesure recommandée pour l&apos;indicateur 4.2.1 des ODD est l&apos;Indice de développement de la petite enfance 2030 (ECDI2030), qui est un instrument à 20 éléments permettant de mesurer les résultats développementaux chez les enfants âgés de 24 à 59 mois dans des enquêtes basées sur la population. L&apos;indicateur issu de l&apos;ECDI2030 est la proportion d&apos;enfants âgés de 24 à 59 mois ayant atteint le nombre minimum d&apos;étapes attendues pour leur tranche d&apos;âge, défini comme suit :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les enfants âgés de 24 à 29 mois sont classés comme étant en bonne voie de développement s&apos;ils ont atteint au moins 7 étapes;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les enfants âgés de 30 à 35 mois sont classés comme étant en bonne voie de développement s&apos;ils ont atteint au moins 9 étapes;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les enfants âgés de 36 à 41 mois sont classés comme étant en bonne voie de développement s&apos;ils ont atteint au moins 11 étapes;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les enfants âgés de 42 à 47 mois sont classés comme étant en bonne voie de développement s&apos;ils ont atteint au moins 13 étapes;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les enfants âgés de 48 à 59 mois sont classés comme étant en bonne voie de développement s&apos;ils ont atteint au moins 15 étapes. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pourcentage (%)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sans objet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;En 2015, l’UNICEF a lancé un processus de développement méthodologique qui a impliqué de vastes consultations avec des experts, des organismes partenaires et des autorités statistiques nationales. Au cours des cinq années suivantes, une séquence d’étapes techniques soigneusement planifiées a été exécutée, incorporant des méthodes qualitatives et quantitatives pour identifier les meilleurs éléments pour mesurer l’indicateur 4.2.1. Ce processus a conduit à l’élaboration de l’ECDI2030. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’ECDI2030 répond au besoin de données représentatives à l’échelle nationale et comparables à l’échelle internationale sur le développement de la petite enfance, recueillies de manière normalisée. Il rend compte de l’atteinte des étapes clés du développement par les enfants âgés de 24 à 59 mois. On pose 20 questions aux mères ou aux principaux fournisseurs de soins sur la façon dont leurs enfants se comportent dans certaines situations quotidiennes, ainsi que sur les compétences et les connaissances qu’ils ont acquises. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’ECDI2030 peut être intégré aux efforts nationaux existants de collecte de données, y compris les programmes internationaux d’enquêtes auprès des ménages tels que le MICS soutenu par l’UNICEF et les enquêtes démographiques et de santé. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’ECDI2030 est destiné à remplacer l’indice de développement de la petite enfance (ou ECDI) qui recueille des données sur l’indicateur proxy de l’indicateur 4.2.1 des ODD utilisé depuis 2015. L’ancien ECDI et le nouvel ECDI2030 ciblent différents groupes d’âge et mesurent des domaines de développement légèrement différents. Par conséquent, les indicateurs générés par les deux instruments peuvent ne pas être entièrement comparables et il faut faire preuve de prudence lors de l’interprétation des estimations produites par les deux mesures. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;L’UNICEF entreprend un vaste processus consultatif de compilation et d’évaluation des données provenant de sources nationales aux fins de la mise à jour de ses bases de données mondiales sur la situation des enfants. Jusqu’en 2017, le mécanisme utilisé par l’UNICEF pour collaborer avec les autorités nationales afin d’assurer la qualité des données et la comparabilité internationale des indicateurs clés pertinents pour les enfants était connu sous le nom de rapport de données par pays sur les indicateurs pour les objectifs (Country Data Reporting on the Indicators for the Goals (CRING)). &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;À partir de 2018, l’UNICEF a lancé un nouveau processus de consultation par pays avec les autorités nationales sur certains indicateurs mondiaux des ODD liés aux enfants, pour lesquels il est dépositaire ou co-dépositaire, pour répondre aux normes et directives émergentes sur les flux de données pour la déclaration mondiale des indicateurs des ODD, qui mettent fortement l’accent sur la rigueur technique, l’appropriation par les pays et l’utilisation des données et statistiques officielles. Le processus de consultation a sollicité des commentaires directement des bureaux nationaux de statistique, ainsi que d’autres organismes gouvernementaux responsables des statistiques officielles, sur la compilation des indicateurs, y compris les sources de données utilisées, et l’application des définitions, classifications et méthodologies convenues au niveau international aux données provenant de ces sources. Une fois examinés, les pays peuvent faire part de leurs commentaires sur l’acceptation de points de données spécifiques et, dans le cas contraire, sur les raisons pour lesquelles ils ne sont pas acceptés. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;L’UNICEF entreprendra chaque année une consultation annuelle par pays, probablement entre décembre et janvier, afin de permettre l’examen et le traitement des commentaires reçus afin de respecter les échéances mondiales de déclaration des ODD. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les données mises à jour sur l&apos;indicateur 4.2.1 telles que mesurées par l’ECDI2030 seront disponibles au cours de la période de rapport des ODD tous les mois de février/mars. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bureaux nationaux de statistique (dans la plupart des cas)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fonds des Nations Unies pour l&apos;enfance (UNICEF)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L’UNICEF est responsable du suivi mondial et de l’établissement de rapports sur le bien-être des enfants. Il fournit une assistance technique et financière aux États membres pour les aider à recueillir des données de qualité sur le développement de la petite enfance (DPE), notamment par le biais du programme d’enquête auprès des ménages MICS soutenu par l’UNICEF. Celui-ci compile également des statistiques sur le DPE dans le but de rendre publics des ensembles de données comparables au niveau international, et il analyse les statistiques sur le DPE qui sont incluses dans les publications pertinentes fondées sur des données, y compris dans sa publication phare, &lt;em&gt;La situation des enfants dans le monde&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Le développement de la petite enfance (DPE) ouvre la voie à la prospérité tout au long de la vie. Investir dans le développement du jeune enfant est l’un des investissements les plus critiques et les plus rentables qu’un pays puisse faire pour améliorer la santé, l’éducation et la productivité des adultes afin de renforcer le capital humain et de promouvoir le développement durable. Le DPE est l’équité dès le départ et fournit une bonne indication du développement national. Les efforts visant à améliorer le DPE peuvent apporter des améliorations humaines, sociales et économiques pour les individus et les sociétés. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L’ODD 4.2.1 a été initialement classé comme niveau 3 et a été mis au niveau 2 en 2019; de plus, des modifications ont été apportées à l’indicateur au cours de l’examen exhaustif de 2020. À la lumière de cela et étant donné que l’ECDI2030 a été officiellement publié en mars 2020, il faudra un certain temps pour que les pays adoptent et mettent en œuvre la nouvelle mesure et pour que les données deviennent disponibles auprès d’un nombre suffisant de pays. Par conséquent, entre-temps, un indicateur indirect (les enfants âgés de 36 à 59 mois qui sont sur la bonne voie sur le plan du développement dans au moins trois des quatre domaines suivants : littératie, physique, socio-émotionnel et apprentissage) sera utilisé pour rendre compte de l&apos;indicateur 4.2.1, le cas échéant. Cet indicateur indirect est utilisé pour les rapports mondiaux sur les ODD depuis 2015, mais n’est pas entièrement aligné avec la définition et le groupe d’âge couverts par la formulation de l’indicateur des ODD. Lorsque l’indicateur de substitution est utilisé pour la déclaration de l&apos;indicateur des ODD 4.2.1 pour un pays, il sera noté en tant que tel dans la base de données mondiale des ODD. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Le nombre d’enfants âgés de 24 à 59 mois qui sont sur la bonne voie de développement en matière de santé, d’apprentissage et de bien-être psychosocial divisé par le nombre total d’enfants âgés de 24 à 59 mois dans la population, multiplié par 100. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Un vaste processus de consultation est entrepris pour compiler, évaluer et valider les données provenant de sources nationales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le processus de consultation a sollicité des commentaires directement des bureaux nationaux de statistique, ainsi que d&apos;autres agences gouvernementales responsables des statistiques officielles, sur la compilation des indicateurs, y compris les sources de données utilisées, et l&apos;application de définitions, de classifications et de méthodologies convenues au niveau international pour les données de ces sources. Les résultats de cette consultation nationale sont examinés par l&apos;UNICEF en tant qu&apos;agence dépositaire. Une fois examinés, des commentaires sont mis à la disposition des pays sur l&apos;acceptation ou non de points de données spécifiques et, s&apos;ils ne sont pas acceptés, sur les raisons. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; Au niveau national :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lorsque les données d’un pays sont totalement manquantes, l’UNICEF ne publie aucune estimation nationale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; Aux niveaux régional et mondial :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La moyenne régionale est appliquée aux pays de la région dont les valeurs sont manquantes aux fins du calcul des agrégats régionaux uniquement, mais n’est pas publiée en tant qu’estimations nationales. Les agrégats régionaux ne sont publiés que lorsqu’au moins 50 % de la population régionale du groupe d’âge concerné est couverte par les données disponibles. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L’agrégat mondial est une moyenne pondérée de tous les pays pour lesquels des données sont disponibles. Les agrégats globaux sont publiés indépendamment de la couverture de la population, mais le nombre de pays et la proportion du groupe de population pertinent représenté par les données disponibles sont clairement indiqués. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les agrégats régionaux sont des moyennes pondérées de tous les pays de la région. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les pays recueillent des données sur la prévalence de l’état de développement des enfants par le biais d’enquêtes auprès des ménages telles que les MICS ou les enquêtes démographiques et de santé soutenues par l’UNICEF. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Le processus qui sous-tend la production de statistiques fiables sur le développement de la petite enfance est bien établi au sein de l’UNICEF. La qualité et le processus menant à la production de l’indicateur 4.2.1 des ODD sont assurés en travaillant en étroite collaboration avec les bureaux de statistique et les autres parties prenantes concernées par le biais d’un processus consultatif. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L’UNICEF tient à jour la base de données mondiale sur le développement de la petite enfance qui est utilisée pour les ODD et d’autres rapports officiels. Avant l’inclusion d’un point de données dans la base de données, il est examiné par les points focaux techniques au siège de l’UNICEF pour vérifier la cohérence et la qualité globale des données. Cet examen est fondé sur un ensemble de critères objectifs visant à s’assurer que seules les informations les plus récentes et les plus fiables sont incluses dans les bases de données. Ces critères sont les suivants : les sources de données doivent inclure la documentation appropriée; les valeurs des données doivent être représentatives au niveau de la population nationale; les données sont recueillies à l’aide d’une méthodologie appropriée (p. ex., échantillonnage); les valeurs des données sont fondées sur un échantillon suffisamment grand; les données sont conformes à la définition de l’indicateur standard, y compris le groupe d’âge et les concepts, dans la mesure du possible; les données sont plausibles en fonction des tendances et de la cohérence avec les estimations précédemment publiées/déclarées pour l’indicateur. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depuis 2018, l’UNICEF entreprend une consultation annuelle avec les autorités gouvernementales sur 10 des indicateurs des ODD liés aux enfants dans son rôle de dépositaire ou co-dépositaire, et conformément à son mandat mondial de suivi et à ses engagements normatifs visant à faire progresser le Programme 2030 pour les enfants. Cela inclut l’indicateur 4.2.1. De plus amples détails sur le processus de consultation par pays sont présentés ci-dessous. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Des contrôles de cohérence et de qualité des données sont régulièrement effectués pour valider les données avant leur diffusion. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disponibilité des données :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sur l’indicateur recueillies dans le cadre de la mise en œuvre de l’ECDI2030 devraient être disponibles à partir de 2021. Des données comparables recueillies par l’ECDI sont actuellement disponibles pour près de 80 pays. Les pays dont les données sur l’indicateur de substitution ont été recueillies auprès de l’ECDI continueront d’être utilisés pour la déclaration mondiale des ODD jusqu’à ce que de nouvelles données utilisant l’ECDI2030 soient disponibles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Séries chronologiques :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non disponible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Désagrégation :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sexe&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources des divergences :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les estimations compilées et présentées au niveau mondial proviennent directement des données produites au niveau national et ne sont pas ajustées ou recalculées.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(en anglais) data.unicef.org&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Références :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(en anglais) http://data.unicef.org/ecd/development-status.html&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
