<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 4-5-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 4: Ensure inclusive and equitable quality education and promote lifelong learning opportunities for all&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 4.5: By 2030, eliminate gender disparities in education and ensure equal access to all levels of education and vocational training for the vulnerable, including persons with disabilities, indigenous peoples and children in vulnerable situations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 4.5.1: Parity indices (female/male, rural/urban, bottom/top wealth quintile and others such as disability status, indigenous peoples and conflict-affected, as data become available) for all education indicators on this list that can be disaggregated&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable&lt;/p&gt;2022-03-31&lt;p&gt;All equity targets and targets associated with the underlying indicators.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UNESCO Institute for Statistics (UIS)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UNESCO Institute for Statistics (UIS)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parity indices require data for the specific groups of interest. They represent the ratio of the indicator value for one group to that of the other. Typically, the likely more disadvantaged group is placed in the numerator. A value of exactly 1 indicates parity between the two groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See metadata for relevant underlying indicator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ratio. This indicator is expressed as the ratio of the value of the indicator for the likely more disadvantaged group to that of the likely more advantaged group. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sources are the same as for the underlying indicators for this goal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The same as the underlying indicator. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Depends on underlying indicator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Depends on underlying indicator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The same as the underlying indicator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UNESCO Institute for Statistics (UIS)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UNESCO Institute for Statistics (UIS) is the statistical branch of the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO). The Institute produces internationally comparable data and methodologies in the fields of education, science, culture and communication for countries at all stages of development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.moe.gov.bn/DocumentDownloads/Education%202030/Education2030.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Education 2030 Framework for Action &amp;#xA7;100&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has clearly stated that: &amp;#x201C;&lt;em&gt;In recognition of the importance of harmonization of monitoring and reporting, the UIS will remain the official source of cross-nationally comparable data on education. It will continue to produce international monitoring indicators based on its annual education survey and on other data sources that guarantee international comparability for more than 200 countries and territories. In addition to collecting data, the UIS will work with partners to develop new indicators, statistical approaches and monitoring tools to better assess progress across the targets related to UNESCO&amp;#x2019;s mandate, working in coordination with the SDG-Education 2030 SC&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To measure the general level of disparity between two sub-populations of interest with regard to a given indicator. The further from 1 the parity index lies, the greater the disparity between the two groups of interest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The indicator is not symmetrical about 1 but a simple transformation can make it so (by inverting ratios that exceed 1 and subtracting them from 2). This will make interpretation easier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The indicator value of the likely more disadvantaged group is divided by the indicator value of the other sub-population of interest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;D&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;P&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;I&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mfenced open=&quot;[&quot; close=&quot;]&quot; separators=&quot;|&quot;&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;msub&gt;
                  &lt;mrow&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
                  &lt;/mrow&gt;
                  &lt;mrow&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
                  &lt;/mrow&gt;
                &lt;/msub&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/mfenced&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;msub&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mfenced open=&quot;[&quot; close=&quot;]&quot; separators=&quot;|&quot;&gt;
              &lt;mrow&gt;
                &lt;msub&gt;
                  &lt;mrow&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
                  &lt;/mrow&gt;
                  &lt;mrow&gt;
                    &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
                  &lt;/mrow&gt;
                &lt;/msub&gt;
              &lt;/mrow&gt;
            &lt;/mfenced&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/msub&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DPI &lt;/em&gt;= the Dimension (Gender, Wealth, Location, etc.) Parity Index&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ind&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt; &lt;/em&gt;= the Education 2030 Indicator &lt;em&gt;i&lt;/em&gt; for which an equity measure is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;d&lt;/em&gt; = the likely disadvantaged group (e.g. female, poorest, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;a &lt;/em&gt;= the likely advantaged group (e.g. male, richest, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UNESCO Institute for Statistics shares all indicator values and notes on methodology with National Statistical Offices, Ministries of Education, or other relevant agencies in individual countries for their review, feedback and validation before the publication of the data. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The same as the underlying indicator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same as the underlying indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same as the underlying indicator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The same as the underlying indicator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UIS has elaborated guidance for the countries on the methodology that should be used to calculate this indicator. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quality management for this indicator is the same as quality management of the underlying indicators. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quality assurance for this indicator is the same as quality assurance of the underlying indicators.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quality assessment for this indicator is the same as quality assessment of the underlying indicators.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depends on underlying indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depends on underlying indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None because the parity indices directly compare two sub-populations of interest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same as the underlying indicator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uis.unesco.org&quot;&gt;http://www.uis.unesco.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See references for each underlying indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 4: Garantizar una educación inclusiva y equitativa de calidad y promover oportunidades de aprendizaje permanente para todos&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 4.5: De aquí a 2030, eliminar las disparidades de género en la educación y asegurar el acceso igualitario a todos los niveles de la enseñanza y la formación profesional para las personas vulnerables, incluidas las personas con discapacidad, los pueblos indígenas y los niños en situaciones de vulnerabilidad&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 4.5.1: Índices de paridad (entre mujeres y hombres, zonas rurales y urbanas, quintiles de riqueza superior e inferior y grupos como los discapacitados, los pueblos indígenas y los afectados por los conflictos, a medida que se disponga de datos) para todos los indicadores educativos de esta lista que puedan desglosarse&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Última actualización: 19 de julio de 2016&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicadores relacionados&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todos los objetivos de equidad y los objetivos asociados a los indicadores subyacentes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Información institucional &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Organización (es): &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Instituto de Estadística de la UNESCO (UNESCO-UIS) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Definición:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Los índices de paridad requieren datos para los grupos específicos de interés. Representan la relación entre el valor del indicador de un grupo y el del otro. Normalmente, el grupo probablemente más desfavorecido se coloca en el numerador. Un valor de exactamente 1 indica la paridad entre los dos grupos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Conceptos:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Consulte los metadatos del indicador subyacente relevante. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Descripción:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Las fuentes son las mismas que para los indicadores subyacentes para este objetivo. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Proceso de recolección:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Lo mismo que el indicador subyacente. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Calendario&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Recopilación de datos:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Depende del indicador subyacente. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Publicación de datos:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Depende del indicador subyacente. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lo mismo que el indicador subyacente.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Instituto de Estadística de la UNESCO&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Justificación: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Medir el nivel general de disparidad entre dos subpoblaciones de interés con respecto a un indicador determinado. Cuanto más lejos de 1 esté el índice de paridad, mayor será la disparidad entre los dos grupos de interés. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; El indicador no es simétrico sobre 1, pero una simple transformación puede hacerlo (invirtiendo relaciones que superan 1 y restándolas de 2). Esto facilitará la interpretación. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Método de cálculo:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; El valor del indicador del grupo probablemente más desfavorecido se divide por el valor del indicador de la otra subpoblación de interés. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; DPI = [Indi]d&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; [Indi]a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; donde:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; DPI = Índice de paridad de la dimensión (género, riqueza, ubicación, etc.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Indi = el Indicador de educación 2030 i para el que se necesita una medida de equidad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d = el grupo probablemente desfavorecido (por ejemplo, mujeres, más pobres, etc.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a = el grupo probablemente favorecido (por ejemplo, hombre, más rico, etc.) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; A nivel de país:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Lo mismo que el indicador subyacente. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; A nivel regional y mundial:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Lo mismo que el indicador subyacente. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lo mismo que el indicador subyacente.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depende del indicador subyacente &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ninguna porque los índices de paridad comparan directamente dos subpoblaciones de interés.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Fuentes de discrepancias:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Lo mismo que el indicador subyacente. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; URL:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uis.unesco.org/Pages/default.aspx&quot;&gt;http://www.uis.unesco.org/Pages/default.aspx&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Referencias:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Consulte las referencias de cada indicador subyacente. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 4 : Assurer l&apos;accès de tous à une éducation de qualité, sur un pied d&apos;égalité, et promouvoir les possibilités d&apos;apprentissage tout au long de la vie&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 4.5 : D&apos;ici 2030, éliminer les disparités entre les sexes dans l&apos;enseignement et assurer aux personnes vulnérables, notamment aux personnes handicapées, aux populations autochtones et aux enfants en situation vulnérable, l&apos;égalité d&apos;accès à tous les niveaux d&apos;enseignement et de formation professionnelle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 4.5.1 : Indices de parité (femmes/hommes, urbain/rural, quintile inférieur/supérieur de richesse et autres paramètres tels que le handicap, le statut d’autochtone et les situations de conflit, à mesure que les données deviennent disponibles) pour tous les indicateurs dans le domaine de l’éducation de cette liste pouvant être ventilés&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sans objet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2022-03-31&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tous les objectifs d&apos;équité et les objectifs associés aux indicateurs sous-jacents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Institut de statistique de l&apos;UNESCO (UNESCO-ISU)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Institut de statistique de l&apos;UNESCO (UNESCO-ISU)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les indices de parité nécessitent des données pour les groupes d&apos;intérêt spécifiques. Ils représentent le rapport entre la valeur de l&apos;indicateur pour un groupe et celle de l&apos;autre. Généralement, le groupe le plus défavorisé est placé dans le numérateur. Une valeur de 1 indique la parité entre les deux groupes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consulter les métadonnées pour l&apos;indicateur sous-jacent pertinent. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ratio. Cet indicateur est exprimé comme le rapport entre la valeur de l’indicateur pour le groupe probablement le plus défavorisé et celui du groupe probablement plus favorisé. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sans objet car les indices de parité comparent directement deux sous-populations d’intérêt. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les sources sont les mêmes que celles des indicateurs sous-jacents à cet objectif.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;La même que celle de l&apos;indicateur sous-jacent. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dépend de l&apos;indicateur sous-jacent. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dépend de l&apos;indicateur sous-jacent. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les mêmes que ceux de l&apos;indicateur sous-jacent. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Institut de statistique de l&apos;UNESCO (UNESCO-ISU)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L&apos;Institut de statistique de l&apos;UNESCO (ISU) est la branche statistique de l&apos;Organisation des Nations Unies pour l&apos;éducation, la science et la culture (UNESCO). L&apos;Institut produit des données et des méthodologies comparables au niveau international dans les domaines de l&apos;éducation, de la science, de la culture et de la communication pour les pays à tous les stades de développement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.moe.gov.bn/DocumentDownloads/Education%202030/Education2030.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;cadre (en anglais) « Education 2030 Framework for Action &amp;#xA7;100 »&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; a clairement indiqué que : « &lt;em&gt;Compte tenu de l&apos;importance de l&apos;harmonisation du suivi et de l&apos;établissement de rapports, l&apos;ISU restera la source officielle de données comparables au niveau transnational sur l&apos;éducation. Il continuera de produire des indicateurs de suivi internationaux basés sur son enquête annuelle sur l&apos;éducation et sur d&apos;autres sources de données qui garantissent la comparabilité internationale pour plus de 200 pays et territoires. En plus de la collecte de données, l&apos;ISU travaillera avec des partenaires pour développer de nouveaux indicateurs, des approches statistiques et des outils de suivi afin de mieux évaluer les progrès pour les cibles liées au mandat de l&apos;UNESCO, en travaillant en coordination avec le &quot;SDG-Education 2030 SC &quot;&lt;/em&gt; ».&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pour mesurer le niveau général de disparité entre deux sous-populations d&apos;intérêt par rapport à un indicateur donné. Plus l&apos;indice de parité est éloigné de 1, plus la disparité entre les deux groupes d&apos;intérêt est importante.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur n&apos;est pas symétrique par rapport à 1 mais une simple transformation peut le rendre tel (en inversant les ratios qui dépassent 1 et en les soustrayant de 2). Cela facilitera l&apos;interprétation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;La valeur de l&apos;indicateur du groupe probablement le plus défavorisé est divisée par la valeur de l&apos;indicateur de l&apos;autre sous-population concernée. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IPD = [Ind&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt;]&lt;sub&gt;d&lt;/sub&gt;/[Ind&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt;]&lt;sub&gt;a&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;où : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IPD = l&apos;indice de parité des dimensions (genre, richesse, lieu, etc.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ind&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt; = l&apos;indicateur i d&apos;Education 2030 pour lequel une mesure d&apos;équité est nécessaire &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d = le groupe probablement défavorisé (p. ex., les femmes, les plus pauvres, etc.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a = le groupe probablement avantagé (p. ex., les hommes, les plus riches, etc.) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L’Institut de statistique de l’UNESCO partage toutes les valeurs des indicateurs et les notes sur la méthodologie avec les bureaux nationaux de statistique, les ministères de l’éducation ou d’autres organismes compétents dans les différents pays pour leur examen, leur rétroaction et leur validation avant la diffusion des données. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les mêmes que ceux de l’indicateur sous-jacent. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; &lt;strong&gt;Au niveau national :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le même que celui de l&apos;indicateur sous-jacent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; &lt;strong&gt;Au niveau régional et mondial :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le même que celui de l&apos;indicateur sous-jacent. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les mêmes que ceux de l&apos;indicateur sous-jacent. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L’ISU a élaboré des conseils à l’intention des pays sur la méthodologie qui devrait être utilisée pour calculer cet indicateur. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;La gestion de la qualité de cet indicateur est la même que celle des indicateurs sous-jacents. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L’assurance de la qualité pour cet indicateur est la même que celle des indicateurs sous-jacents. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L’évaluation de la qualité de cet indicateur est la même que celle des indicateurs sous-jacents. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disponibilité des données :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dépend de l&apos;indicateur sous-jacent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Séries chronologiques :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Désagrégation :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aucune, car les indices de parité comparent directement deux sous-populations d&apos;intérêt. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources des divergences :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les mêmes que celles de l&apos;indicateur sous-jacent. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://uis.unesco.org/fr&quot;&gt;http://uis.unesco.org/fr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Références :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consulter les références pour chaque indicateur sous-jacent. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 4: Обеспечение всеохватного и справедливого качественного образования и поощрение возможности обучения на протяжении всей жизни для всех&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 4.5: К 2030 году ликвидировать гендерное неравенство в сфере образования и обеспечить равный доступ к образованию и профессионально-технической подготовке всех уровней для уязвимых групп населения, в том числе инвалидов, представителей коренных народов и детей, находящихся в уязвимом положении&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 4.5.1: Индексы равенства (женщин и мужчин, городских и сельских жителей, нижней и верхней квинтили достатка и других групп, например инвалидов, коренных народов и людей, затронутых конфликтами, в зависимости от наличия данных) по всем касающимся образования показателям в настоящем перечне, которые могут быть дезагрегированы&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Последнее обновление: 19 июля 2016 года&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Связанные показатели &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Все цели и задачи по обеспечению равенства, связанные с базовыми показателями. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Институциональная информация&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Организация(и):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Институт статистики ЮНЕСКО (ИСЮ)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Определение: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Для расчета индексов равенства требуются данные конкретных исследуемых групп. Индексы равенства представляют собой отношение величины показателя одной группы к величине показателя другой группы. Обычно в числитель помещается наиболее обездоленная группа. Значение индекса, ровное 1, указывает на равенство между двумя группами. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Понятия: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; См. метаданные для соответствующего базового показателя. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Описание: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Источники такие же, как и для основных показателей этой цели. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Тот же, что и для базового показателя. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Календарь &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Сбор данных: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Зависит от базового показателя. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Выпуск данных: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Зависит от базового показателя. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Поставщики данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Те же, что и для базового показателя. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Составители данных&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Институт статистики ЮНЕСКО&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для оценки общего уровня несоответствия между двумя исследуемыми подгруппами населения, касающегося данного показателя. Чем дальше от 1 находится индекс равенства, тем больше неравенство между двумя исследуемыми группами. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель не симметричен относительно 1, но простое преобразование может сделать его симметричным (путем инвертирования коэффициентов, превышающих 1, и вычитания их из 2). Это упростит интерпретацию. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Величина показателя наиболее уязвимой группы делится на величину показателя другой исследуемой подгруппы. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; DPI = [Indi]d &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; [Indi]а &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; где: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; DPI = размерность (пол, благосостояние, местоположение и т. д.) Индекс равенства &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Indi = Показатель образования 2030 i, для которого необходим показатель равенства. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; d = наиболее уязвимая группа (например, женщины, самые бедные и т. д.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; a = группа с вероятными преимуществами (например, мужчины, самые богатые и т. д.) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Так же, как и базовый показатель. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Так же, как и базовый показатель. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Региональные агрегаты: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Так же, как и базовый показатель. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Зависит от базового показателя &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Не производится, потому что индексы равенства напрямую сопоставляют две исследуемые подгруппы населения. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Так же, как и базовый показатель. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; URL: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uis.unesco.org/Pages/default.aspx&quot;&gt; http://www.uis.unesco.org/Pages/default.aspx &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Ссылки: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; См. ссылки для каждого базового показателя. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
