<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 5-5-1a, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 5: Achieve gender equality and empower all women and girls&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 5.5: Ensure women&amp;#x2019;s full and effective participation and equal opportunities for leadership at all levels of decision-making in political, economic and public life&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 5.5.1: Proportion of seats held by women in (a) national parliaments and (b) local governments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Number of seats held by women in national parliaments (number) SG_GEN_PARLN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current number of seats in national parliaments (number) SG_GEN_PARLNT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proportion of seats held by women in national parliaments (% of total number of seats) SG_GEN_PARL&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2021-08-24&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 16.7.1: Proportions of positions (by age group, sex, persons with disabilities and population groups) in public institutions (national and local), including (a) the legislatures; (b) the public service; and (c) the judiciary, compared to national distributions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inter-Parliamentary Union (IPU)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inter-Parliamentary Union (IPU)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proportion of seats held by women in (a) national parliaments, currently as at 1 January of reporting year, is currently measured as the number of seats held by women members in single or lower chambers of national parliaments, expressed as a percentage of all occupied seats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National parliaments can be bicameral or unicameral. This indicator covers the single chamber in unicameral parliaments and the lower chamber in bicameral parliaments. It does not cover the upper chamber of bicameral parliaments. Seats are usually won by members in general parliamentary elections. Seats may also be filled by nomination, appointment, indirect election, rotation of members and by-election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seats refer to the number of parliamentary mandates, or the number of members of parliament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seats refer to the number of parliamentary mandates, also known as the number of members of parliament. Seats are usually won by members in general parliamentary elections. Seats may also be filled by nomination, appointment, indirect election, rotation of members and by-election.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Number and percentage&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The data used are official statistics received from national parliaments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The data are provided by national parliaments and updated after an election or parliamentary renewal. National parliaments also transmit their data to the IPU at least once a year and when the numbers change significantly. IPU member parliaments provide information on changes and updates to the IPU secretariat. After each general election or renewal a questionnaire is dispatched to parliaments to solicit the latest available data. If no response is provided, other methods are used to obtain the information, such as from the electoral management body, parliamentary web sites or Internet searches. Additional information gathered from other sources is regularly crosschecked with parliament. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data are updated on a monthly basis, up to the last day of the month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data are updated on a monthly basis, up to the last day of the month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National parliaments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inter-Parliamentary Union (IPU)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Inter-Parliamentary Union (IPU) is the global organization of parliaments. It was founded in 1889 as the first multilateral political organization in the world, encouraging cooperation and dialogue between all nations. Today, the IPU comprises 179 national Member Parliaments and 13 regional parliamentary bodies. It promotes democracy and helps parliaments become stronger, younger, gender-balanced and more diverse. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IPU recognizes gender equality as a key component of democracy. It works to achieve equal participation of men and women in politics and supports parliaments in advancing gender equality. This includes the collection and dissemination of quantitative and qualitative data on women in politics. In particular, the IPU has tracked the percentage of women in national parliaments since 1945 and is the authority for this data. See historical and comparative data on women in parliament at &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.ipu.org/historical-women&quot;&gt;https://data.ipu.org/historical-women&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The indicator measures the degree to which women have equal access to parliamentary decision making. Women&amp;#x2019;s participation in parliaments is a key aspect of women&amp;#x2019;s opportunities in political and public life, and is therefore linked to women&amp;#x2019;s empowerment. Equal numbers of women and men in lower chambers would give an indicator value of 50 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A stronger presence of women in parliament allows new concerns to be highlighted on political agendas, and new priorities to be put into practice through the adoption and implementation of policies and laws. The inclusion of the perspectives and interests of women is a prerequisite for democracy and gender equality, and contributes to good governance. A representative parliament also allows the different experiences of men and women to affect the social, political and economic future of societies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changes in the indicator have been tracked over time. Although the international community has supported and promoted women&amp;#x2019;s participation in political decision-making structures for several decades, improvement in women&amp;#x2019;s access to parliament has been slow. This has led to the introduction of special policy and legal measures to increase women&amp;#x2019;s shares of parliamentary seats in several countries. Those countries that have adopted special measures generally have greater representation of women in parliament than countries without special measures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- The number of countries covered varies with suspensions or dissolutions of parliaments. As of 1 February 2016, 193 countries are included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- There can be difficulties in obtaining information on by-election results and replacements due to death or resignation. These changes are ad hoc events which are more difficult to keep track of. By-elections, for instance, are often not announced internationally as general elections are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- The data excludes the numbers and percentages of women in upper chambers of parliament. The information in available on the IPU website at &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.ipu.org/women-ranking&quot;&gt;https://data.ipu.org/women-ranking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Parliaments vary considerably in their internal workings and procedures, however, generally legislate, oversee government and represent the electorate. In terms of measuring women&amp;#x2019;s contribution to political decision making, this indicator may not be sufficient because some women may face obstacles in fully and efficiently carrying out their parliamentary mandate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The proportion of seats held by women in national parliament is derived by dividing the total number of seats occupied by women by the total number of seats in parliament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no weighting or normalising of statistics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;IPU member parliaments provide information on changes and updates to the IPU secretariat via IPU Groups within each parliamentary chamber or via the Parline Correspondent&amp;#x2019;s Network. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parline Correspondents are staff members of national parliaments who act as the IPU focal point for IPU&amp;#x2019;s Parline database within each chamber or parliament. Their main role is to make sure that all the data in Parline for their parliament is up&amp;#x2011;to&amp;#x2011;date and correct, including for this indicator. If no response is provided to questionnaires, other methods are used to obtain the information, such as from the electoral management body, parliamentary web sites or Internet searches. Additional information gathered from other sources is regularly crosschecked with parliaments. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No adjustments are made for missing values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regional aggregations are a simple sum of country and chamber level data. A weighting structure is not applied.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guidance is not required to provide information for this indicator (i.e. current number of members and total number of women members in a given single or lower chamber of a national parliament).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &amp;#x201C;Checklist for Parline Correspondents&amp;#x201D; is provided to remind parliaments to inform the IPU of changes to the number of seats or the total number of women in a parliamentary chamber, every time there is a change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data for this indicator is input and housed within the Parline database (data.ipu.org).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IPU has dedicated staff for data collection and management, a Network of Parline Correspondents to provide data updates, and a constant exchange with parliaments via IPU groups housed within member parliaments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is no significant statistical processing required for this indicator aside from checking coherence overtime. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;IPU data is housed within the Parline database which automatically generates calculations on the number and percentage of women to ensure accuracy. Exports from the database are utilised for SDG reporting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are available for 193 countries. Information is available in all countries where a national legislature exists and therefore does not include parliaments that have been dissolved or suspended for an indefinite period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the IPU website the data extraction has changed over time as follows;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2020 &amp;#x2013; Present As at 1 January&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2013 &amp;#x2013; 2019 As at 1 February&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1999 As at 5 February&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2002 As at 4 February&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2003, 2005 &amp;#x2013; 2007, 2009 - 2012 As at 31 January&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2001, 2004 As at 30 January&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2008 As at 29 January&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1998, 2000 As at 25 January&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1997 As at 1 January&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to 1997 Unknown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator can be disaggregated for analysis by geographical region and sub-region, legislature type (single or lower, parliamentary or presidential), the method of filling seats (directly elected, indirectly elected, appointed) and the use of special measures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are not adjusted for international comparability. Though, for international comparisons, generally only the single or lower house is considered in calculating the indicator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.ipu.org/women-ranking&quot;&gt;https://data.ipu.org/women-ranking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipu.org/wmn-e/classif-arc.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.ipu.org/wmn-e/classif-arc.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inter-parliamentary Union (2008). Equality in Politics: A Survey of Women and Men in Parliaments. Geneva. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipu.org/english/surveys.htm#equality08&quot;&gt;http://www.ipu.org/english/surveys.htm#equality08&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inter-parliamentary Union (2010). Is Parliament Open to Women? Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipu.org/PDF/publications/wmn09-e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ipu.org/PDF/publications/wmn09-e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inter-parliamentary Union (2011). Gender-Sensitive Parliaments. A Global Review of Good Practice. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipu.org/pdf/publications/gsp11-e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ipu.org/pdf/publications/gsp11-e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inter-parliamentary Union (2020). Women in parliament: 1995&amp;#x2013;2020 - 25 years in review. Available from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ipu.org/resources/publications/reports/2020-03/women-in-parliament-1995-2020-25-years-in-review&quot;&gt;https://www.ipu.org/resources/publications/reports/2020-03/women-in-parliament-1995-2020-25-years-in-review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inter-parliamentary Union and UN Women (2021). Women in Politics: 2021. Available from https://www.ipu.org/women-in-politics-2021&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 5: Lograr la igualdad de género y empoderar a todas las mujeres y las niñas&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 5.5: Asegurar la participación plena y efectiva de las mujeres y la igualdad de oportunidades de liderazgo a todos los niveles decisorios en la vida política, económica y pública&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 5.5.1: Proporción de escaños ocupados por mujeres en a) los parlamentos nacionales y b) los gobiernos locales&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Última actualización: 19 de febrero de 2020&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicadores relacionados a febrero de 2020&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicador 16.7.1: Proporciones de puestos (por grupo de edad, sexo, personas con discapacidad y grupos de población) en las instituciones públicas (nacionales y locales), incluyendo (a) las legislaturas; (b) la administración pública; y (c) el poder judicial, en comparación con las distribuciones nacionales. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Información institucional&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organización (es): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unión Interparlamentaria (UIP) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La proporción de escaños ocupados por mujeres en (a) los parlamentos nacionales, al 1 de enero del año que se informa, se mide actualmente como el número de escaños ocupados por mujeres en las cámaras únicas o bajas de los parlamentos nacionales, expresado como porcentaje de todos los escaños ocupados.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los parlamentos nacionales pueden ser bicamerales o unicamerales. Este indicador abarca la cámara única en los parlamentos unicamerales y la cámara baja en los parlamentos bicamerales. No cubre la cámara alta de los parlamentos bicamerales. Los escaños suelen ganarse en las elecciones parlamentarias generales. Los escaños también pueden ser ocupados por designación, nombramiento, elección indirecta, rotación de miembros y elecciones parciales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los escaños se refieren al número de mandatos parlamentarios, o al número de miembros del parlamento.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los escaños se refieren al número de mandatos parlamentarios, también conocidos como el número de miembros del parlamento. Los escaños suelen ganarse en las elecciones parlamentarias generales. Los escaños también pueden cubrirse por designación, nombramiento, elección indirecta, rotación de miembros y elecciones parciales.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos utilizados son estadísticas oficiales recibidas de los parlamentos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Proceso de recolección:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Los datos son proporcionados por los parlamentos nacionales y actualizados después de una elección o renovación parlamentaria. Los parlamentos nacionales también transmiten sus datos a la UIP al menos una vez al año y cuando las cifras cambian significativamente. Los parlamentos miembros de la UIP proporcionan información sobre los cambios y actualizaciones a la secretaría de la UIP. Después de cada elección o renovación general, se envía un cuestionario a los parlamentos para solicitar los últimos datos disponibles. Si no se proporciona respuesta, se utilizan otros métodos para obtener la información, como del organismo electoral, los sitios web parlamentarios o las búsquedas en Internet. La información adicional recopilada de otras fuentes se coteja regularmente con el parlamento. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendario&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recolección de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos se actualizan mensualmente, hasta el último día del mes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Publicación de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Los datos se actualizan mensualmente, hasta el último día del mes. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parlamentos miembros de la Unión Interparlamentaria (UIP)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Unión Interparlamentaria (UIP)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador mide el grado de igualdad de acceso de las mujeres a la toma de decisiones parlamentarias. La participación de las mujeres en los parlamentos es un aspecto clave de las oportunidades de las mujeres en la vida política y pública y, por lo tanto, está vinculada al empoderamiento de las mujeres. Un número igual de mujeres y hombres en las cámaras bajas daría un valor del indicador del 50%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Una mayor presencia de las mujeres en el parlamento permite que se destaquen nuevas preocupaciones en las agendas políticas, y que se pongan en práctica nuevas prioridades a través de la adopción y aplicación de políticas y leyes. La inclusión de las perspectivas e intereses de las mujeres es un requisito previo para la democracia y la igualdad de género, y contribuye a la buena gobernanza. Un parlamento representativo también permite que las diferentes experiencias de hombres y mujeres afecten al futuro social, político y económico de las sociedades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los cambios en el indicador se han seguido a lo largo del tiempo. Aunque la comunidad internacional ha apoyado y promovido la participación de las mujeres en las estructuras de toma de decisiones políticas durante varias décadas, la mejora del acceso de las mujeres al parlamento ha sido lenta. Esto ha llevado a la introducción de medidas políticas y legales especiales para aumentar la proporción de mujeres en los escaños parlamentarios en varios países. Los países que han adoptado medidas especiales suelen tener una mayor representación de mujeres en el parlamento que los países que no tienen medidas especiales.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;El número de países cubiertos varía con las suspensiones o disoluciones de los parlamentos. Al 1 de febrero de 2016, se incluyen 193 países.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Puede haber dificultades para obtener información sobre los resultados de las elecciones parciales y las sustituciones por fallecimiento o dimisión. Estos cambios son eventos ad hoc que son más difíciles de seguir. Las elecciones parciales, por ejemplo, no suelen anunciarse internacionalmente como las elecciones generales.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Los datos excluyen el número y el porcentaje de mujeres en las cámaras altas del parlamento. La información está disponible en el sitio web de la UIP en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipu.org/women-ranking&quot;&gt;http://www.ipu.org/women-ranking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Los parlamentos varían considerablemente en su funcionamiento interno y sus procedimientos, sin embargo, generalmente legislan, supervisan al gobierno y representan al electorado. En cuanto a la medición de la contribución de las mujeres a la toma de decisiones políticas, este indicador puede no ser suficiente, ya que algunas mujeres pueden enfrentarse a obstáculos para desempeñar plena y eficazmente su mandato parlamentario.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La proporción de escaños ocupados por mujeres en el parlamento nacional se obtiene dividiendo el número total de escaños ocupados por mujeres entre el número total de escaños del parlamento.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No hay ponderación ni normalización de las estadísticas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No se realizan ajustes para los valores faltantes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se dispone de datos para 193 países. La información está disponible en todos los países en los que existe una legislatura nacional y, por lo tanto, no incluye los parlamentos disueltos o suspendidos por tiempo indefinido.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Según el sitio web de la UIP, la extracción de datos ha cambiado a lo largo del tiempo de la siguiente manera;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2020 &amp;#x2013; Presente: Al 1 de enero&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2013 &amp;#x2013; 2019: Al 1 de febrero&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1999: Al 5 de febrero&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2002: Al 4 de febrero&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2003, 2005 &amp;#x2013; 2007, 2009 &amp;#x2013; 2012: Al 31 de enero&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2001, 2004: Al 30 de enero&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2008: Al 29 de enero&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1998, 2000: Al 25 de enero&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1997: Al 1 de enero&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antes de 1997: Desconocido&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador puede desagregarse para su análisis por región y subregión geográfica, tipo de legislatura (única o inferior, parlamentaria o presidencial), método de ocupación de los escaños (elección directa, elección indirecta, designación) y uso de medidas especiales.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Fuentes de discrepancias: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos no están ajustados para la comparabilidad internacional. Aunque, para las comparaciones internacionales, generalmente solo se considera la cámara única o la cámara baja para calcular el indicador. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://data/ipu.org/women-ranking&quot;&gt;https://data/ipu.org/women-ranking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipu.org/wmn-e/classif-arc.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.ipu.org/wmn-e/classif-arc.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Referencias:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unión Interparlamentaria (2008). La igualdad en la política: Una encuesta sobre las mujeres y los hombres en los parlamentos. Ginebra. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipu.org/english/surveys.htm#equality08&quot;&gt;http://www.ipu.org/english/surveys.htm#equality08&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unión Interparlamentaria (2010). ¿Está el Parlamento abierto a las mujeres? Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipu.org/PDF/publications/wmn09-e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ipu.org/PDF/publications/wmn09-e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unión Interparlamentaria (2011). Parlamentos sensibles al género. Una revisión global de buenas prácticas. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipu.org/pdf/publications/gsp11-e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ipu.org/pdf/publications/gsp11-e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fondo de Desarrollo de las Naciones Unidas para la Mujer (2009). El progreso de las mujeres en el mundo 2008/2009. Nueva York. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unifem.org/progress/2008.%20UN-Women&quot;&gt;http://www.unifem.org/progress/2008. ONU-Mujeres&lt;/a&gt; (2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONU-Mujeres (2011). El progreso de las mujeres del mundo 2011-2012. Nueva York. Disponible en &lt;a href=&quot;http://progress.unwomen.org/pdfs/EN-Report-Progress.pdf&quot;&gt;http://progress.unwomen.org/pdfs/EN-Report-Progress.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 5 : Parvenir à l’égalité des sexes et autonomiser toutes les femmes et les filles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 5.5 : Veiller à ce que les femmes participent pleinement et effectivement aux fonctions de direction à tous les niveaux de décision, dans la vie politique, économique et publique, et y accèdent à chance égale&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 5.5.1(a) : Proportion de sièges occupés par des femmes dans les parlements nationaux&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;19 février 2020&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 16.7.1 : Proportions de postes (selon le groupe d’âge, le sexe, les personnes handicapées et les groupes de population) dans les institutions publiques (nationales et locales), y compris a) les législatures; b) la fonction publique; c) le système judiciaire, par rapport aux distributions nationales. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Union interparlementaire (UIP) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Union interparlementaire (UIP)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Définition : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La proportion de sièges occupés par des femmes dans les parlements nationaux, actuellement au 1er janvier de l&apos;année de référence, est mesurée comme le nombre de sièges occupés par des femmes membres dans les chambres uniques ou basses des parlements nationaux, exprimé en pourcentage de tous les sièges occupés. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les parlements nationaux peuvent être bicaméraux ou monocaméraux. Cet indicateur couvre la chambre unique dans les parlements monocaméraux et la chambre basse dans les parlements bicaméraux. Il ne couvre pas la chambre haute des parlements bicaméraux. Les sièges sont généralement remportés par les membres lors d&apos;élections législatives générales. Les sièges peuvent également être pourvus par nomination, élection indirecte, rotation des membres et élection partielle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les sièges désignent le nombre de mandats parlementaires ou le nombre de députés. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concepts : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les sièges désignent le nombre de mandats parlementaires, également appelé nombre de parlementaires. Les sièges sont généralement remportés par les membres lors d&apos;élections législatives générales. Les sièges peuvent également être pourvus par nomination, élection indirecte, rotation des membres et élection partielle. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sans objet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les données utilisées sont des statistiques officielles reçues des parlements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les données sont fournies par les parlements nationaux et mises à jour après une élection ou un renouvellement parlementaire. Les parlements nationaux transmettent également leurs données à l’UIP au moins une fois par an et lorsque les chiffres changent considérablement. Les parlements membres de l’UIP fournissent des informations sur les changements et les mises à jour au secrétariat de l’UIP. Après chaque élection générale ou renouvellement, un questionnaire est envoyé aux parlements pour solliciter les dernières données disponibles. Si aucune réponse n’est fournie, d’autres méthodes sont utilisées pour obtenir l’information, par exemple auprès de l’organisme de gestion électorale, des sites Web parlementaires ou de recherches sur Internet. Les informations supplémentaires recueillies auprès d’autres sources sont régulièrement recoupées avec celles du parlement. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les données sont mises à jour sur une base mensuelle, jusqu&apos;au dernier jour du mois. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les données sont mises à jour sur une base mensuelle, jusqu&apos;au dernier jour du mois. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Parlements membres de l&apos;Union interparlementaire (UIP) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Union interparlementaire (UIP) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L’indicateur mesure dans quelle mesure les femmes ont un accès égal à la prise de décisions parlementaires. La participation des femmes aux parlements est un aspect clé des opportunités des femmes dans la vie politique et publique, et est donc liée à l’autonomisation des femmes. Un nombre égal de femmes et d’hommes dans les chambres basses donnerait une valeur indicative de 50 pour cent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Une présence plus forte des femmes au parlement permet de mettre en évidence de nouvelles préoccupations sur les agendas politiques, et de nouvelles priorités doivent être mises en pratique par l’adoption et la mise en œuvre de politiques et de lois. L’inclusion des perspectives et des intérêts des femmes est une condition préalable à la démocratie et à l’égalité des sexes et contribue à la bonne gouvernance. Un parlement représentatif permet également aux différentes expériences des hommes et des femmes d’influer sur l’avenir social, politique et économique des sociétés. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les changements dans l’indicateur ont été suivis au fil du temps. Bien que la communauté internationale ait soutenu et encouragé la participation des femmes aux structures décisionnelles politiques pendant plusieurs décennies, l’amélioration de l’accès des femmes au parlement a été lente. Cela a conduit à l’introduction de mesures politiques et juridiques spéciales visant à accroître la part des femmes dans les sièges parlementaires dans plusieurs pays. Les pays qui ont adopté des mesures spéciales ont généralement une plus grande représentation des femmes au parlement que les pays qui n’ont pas de mesures spéciales. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Le nombre de pays couverts varie avec les suspensions ou les dissolutions de parlements. Au 1er février 2016, 193 pays étaient inclus. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Il peut être difficile d’obtenir de l’information sur les résultats des élections partielles et les remplacements en raison d’un décès ou d’une démission. Ces changements sont des événements ponctuels qui sont plus difficiles à suivre. Les élections partielles, par exemple, ne sont souvent pas annoncées à l’échelle internationale comme le sont les élections générales. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les données excluent le nombre et le pourcentage de femmes dans les chambres hautes du parlement. Les informations sont disponibles sur le site Web de l’UIP à l’adresse &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.ipu.org/fr/women-ranking&quot;&gt;https://data.ipu.org/fr/women-ranking&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les parlements varient considérablement dans leurs fonctionnements et procédures internes, mais généralement ils légifèrent, supervisent le gouvernement et représentent l’électorat. Pour ce qui est de mesurer la contribution des femmes à la prise de décision politique, cet indicateur peut ne pas être suffisant parce que certaines femmes peuvent se heurter à des obstacles dans l’exercice complet et efficace de leur mandat parlementaire. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;La proportion de sièges occupés par des femmes au parlement national est obtenue en divisant le nombre total de sièges occupés par les femmes par le nombre total de sièges au parlement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il n’y a pas de pondération ou de normalisation des statistiques. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sans objet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aucun ajustement n’est effectué pour les valeurs manquantes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; Au niveau national&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2022; Aux niveaux régional et mondial&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disponibilité des données :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont disponibles pour 193 pays. Les informations sont disponibles dans tous les pays où il existe une législature nationale et n’incluent donc pas les parlements qui ont été dissous ou suspendus pour une durée indéterminée. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Séries chronologiques :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selon le site Web de l’UIP, l’extraction des données a évolué au fil du temps comme suit : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2020 – Présent, au 1er janvier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2013 – 2019, au 1er février&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1999, au 5 février&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2002, au 4 février&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2003, 2005 – 2007, 2009 – 2012, au 31 janvier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2001, 2004, au 30 janvier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2008, au 29 janvier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1998, 2000, au 25 janvier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1997, au 1er janvier&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avant 1997 Inconnu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Désagrégation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’indicateur peut être ventilé pour analyse par région géographique et sous-région, type de législature (chambre unique ou chambre basse, parlementaire ou présidentielle), méthode de pourvoir les sièges (élus au suffrage direct, élus au suffrage indirect, nommés) et utilisation de mesures spéciales. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sources des divergences :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données ne sont pas ajustées en fonction de la comparabilité internationale. Bien que, pour les comparaisons internationales, généralement seule la chambre unique ou basse est prise en compte dans le calcul de l’indicateur. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.ipu.org/fr/women-ranking&quot;&gt;https://data.ipu.org/fr/women-ranking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipu.org/wmn-f/classif-arc.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.ipu.org/wmn-f/classif-arc.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Références :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Union interparlementaire (2008). L’égalité en politique : enquête auprès des femmes et des hommes dans les parlements. Genève. Disponible à l&apos;adresse &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipu.org/french/surveys.htm#equality08&quot;&gt;http://www.ipu.org/french/surveys.htm#equality08&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Union interparlementaire (2010). Le Parlement est-il ouvert aux femmes ? Disponible à l&apos;adresse &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipu.org/PDF/publications/wmn09-f.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ipu.org/PDF/publications/wmn09-f.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Union interparlementaire (2011). Parlements sensibles au genre. Étude mondiale des bonnes pratiques. Disponible à l&apos;adresse &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipu.org/pdf/publications/gsp11-f.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ipu.org/pdf/publications/gsp11-f.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fonds de développement des Nations Unies pour la femme (2009). Le Progrès des femmes à travers le monde 2008/2009. New York. Disponible à l&apos;adresse https://www.unwomen.org/sites/default/files/Headquarters/Media/Publications/UNIFEM/POWW08_Report_Full_Text_fr.pdf. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONU Femmes (2011). Le Progrès des Femmes dans le monde 2011-2012. New York. Disponible à l&apos;adresse &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unwomen.org/sites/default/files/Headquarters/Attachments/Sections/Library/Publications/2011/ProgressOfTheWorldsWomen-2011-fr.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.unwomen.org/sites/default/files/Headquarters/Attachments/Sections/Library/Publications/2011/ProgressOfTheWorldsWomen-2011-fr.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 5: Обеспечение гендерного равенства и расширение прав и возможностей всех женщин и девочек&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 5.5: Обеспечить всестороннее и реальное участие женщин и равные для них возможности для лидерства на всех уровнях принятия решений в политической, экономической и общественной жизни&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 5.5.1: Доля мест, занимаемых женщинами в a) национальных парламентах и b) местных органах власти&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Последнее обновление: 19 февраля 2020 года&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Связанные показатели по состоянию на февраль 2020 года &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель 16.7.1: Доля должностей ( в разбивке по возрастным группам, полу, лицам с ограниченными возможностями и группам населения) в государственных учреждениях (национальных и местных), включая (а) законодательные органы; (б) государственную службу; и (c) судебную систему, в сравнении с национальным распределением. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Институциональная информация &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Организация (и): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Межпарламентский союз (МПС) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Доля мест, занимаемых женщинами в (а) национальных парламентах, на текущий момент по состоянию на 1 января отчетного года, на текущий момент определяется как количество мест, занимаемых женщинами-членами в однопалатных или нижних палатах национальных парламентов, выраженная в процентах от всех занятых мест. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Национальные парламенты могут быть двухпалатными или однопалатными. Этот показатель относится к однопалатному парламенту в системе однопалатных парламентов и нижней палате в системе двухпалатных парламентов. Он не распространяется на верхнюю палату в системе двухпалатных парламентов. Депутаты обычно завоевывают места на всеобщих парламентских выборах. Места также могут быть заполнены путем выдвижения, назначения, непрямых выборов, ротации членов и дополнительных выборов. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Количество мест означает количество депутатских мандатов или количество членов парламента. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Количество мест означает количество депутатских мандатов, также известное как количество членов парламента. Депутаты обычно завоевывают места на всеобщих парламентских выборах. Места также могут быть заполнены путем выдвижения, назначения, непрямых выборов, ротации членов и дополнительных выборов. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Использованные данные являются официальными статистическими данными, полученными из парламентов. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные предоставляются национальными парламентами и корректируются после выборов или обновления парламента. Национальные парламенты также передают свои данные в МПС не реже одного раза в год и при значительном изменении показателей. Парламенты-члены МПС предоставляют информацию об изменениях и обновлениях в секретариат МПС. Всякий раз после проведения всеобщих выборов или обновлений парламентам рассылается вопросник с запросом представить последние имеющиеся данные. Если ответа нет, то используются другие методы для получения информации, например, из органов по проведению выборов, с парламентских веб-сайтов или путем организации поиска в Интернете. Дополнительная информация, собранная из других источников, регулярно сверяется с парламентом. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Календарь &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Сбор данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные обновляются ежемесячно в срок до конца последнего дня месяца. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Выпуск данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные обновляются ежемесячно в срок до конца последнего дня месяца.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Поставщики данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Парламенты-члены Межпарламентского союза (МПС)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Составители данных&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Межпарламентский союз (МПС)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель отражает ситуацию, до какой степени женщины имеют равный доступ к принятию парламентских решений. Участие женщин в работе парламентов является ключевым аспектом возможностей женщин в политической и общественной жизни и, следовательно, связано с расширением прав и возможностей женщин. Значение показателя, равное 50 процентам, означало бы равное количество женщин и мужчин в нижних палатах. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Более широкое представительство женщин в парламенте позволяет обратить внимание на новые проблемы в политической повестке дня и воплощать в жизнь новые приоритеты посредством принятия и реализации политики и законов. Учет взглядов и интересов женщин является предпосылкой демократии и гендерного равенства и способствует эффективному управлению. Представительный парламент также делает возможным, используя различный опыт мужчин и женщин, оказывать влияние на социальное, политическое и экономическое будущее общества. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Изменения показателя отслеживаются с течением времени. Хотя международное сообщество уже в течение нескольких десятилетий поддерживало и поощряло участие женщин в структурах принятия политических решений, но положительные изменения в вопросе доступа женщин в парламент происходили медленно. Такая ситуация привела к принятию специальных политических и правовых мер, направленных на увеличение доли женщин в парламентах нескольких странах. Те страны, которые приняли специальные меры, обычно имеют большее представительство женщин в парламенте, чем страны, в которых специальные меры не были приняты. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Количество охваченных стран изменяется при временном прекращении деятельности или роспуске парламентов. По состоянию на 1 февраля 2016 года включены данные по 193 странам.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Могут возникнуть трудности с получением информации о результатах дополнительных выборов и замещениях в связи со смертью или отставкой депутата. Эти изменения являются несистематическими событиями, которые трудно отслеживать. Дополнительные выборы, например, часто не объявляются в международном масштабе, в отличие от всеобщих выборов. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Данные не включают количество и процент женщин в верхних палатах парламента. Информация доступна на веб-сайте МПС по адресу &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipu.org/women-ranking&quot;&gt; http://www.ipu.org/women-ranking &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Парламенты значительно различаются по своему внутреннему распорядку и процедурам, однако, как правило, они принимают законы, контролируют правительство и представляют электорат. Этого показателя может быть недостаточно для отражения вклада женщин в принятие политических решений , поскольку некоторые женщины могут сталкиваться с препятствиями при полной и эффективной реализации прав, предоставляемых парламентским мандатом. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Доля мест, занимаемых женщинами в национальном парламенте, определяется путем деления общего количества мест, занимаемых женщинами, на общее количество мест в парламенте. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Статистические данные не взвешиваются и не нормализуются. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Никаких корректировок отсутствующих значений не производится. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные доступны по 193 странам. Информация доступна по всем странам, где существует национальный законодательный орган, и поэтому не включает парламенты, которые были распущены или чья работа была приостановлена на неопределенный срок.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; По информации, размещенной на веб-сайте МПС, извлечение данных в динамике по времени изменилось следующим образом; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 2020 год - по настоящее время: по состоянию на 1 января &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 2013 - 2019 годы: по состоянию на 1 февраля &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 1999 год: по состоянию на 5 февраля &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 2002 год: по состоянию на 4 февраля &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 2003, 2005 -2013; 2007, 2009 -2013; 2012 годы: по состоянию на31 января &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 2001, 2004 годы: по состоянию на 30 января &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 2008 год: по состоянию на 29 января &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 1998, 2000 годы: по состоянию на 25 января &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 1997 год: по состоянию на1 января &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; До 1997 года: Неизвестно &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель может быть дезагрегирован для анализа по географическим регионам и субрегионам, типам законодательной власти (однопалатный парламент или нижняя палата парламента, парламентская или президентская форма правления), методу заполнения мест (избираемые прямым голосованием, избираемые косвенным образом, назначаемые) и использованию специальных мер. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные не корректируются для международной сопоставимости. Однако для международных сопоставлений, как правило, при расчете показателя рассматривается только однопалатный парламент или нижняя палата парламента. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://data/ipu.org/women-ranking&quot;&gt; https: //data/ipu.org/women-ranking &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipu.org/wmn-e/classif-arc.htm&quot;&gt; http://www.ipu.org/wmn-e/classif-arc.htm &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Ссылки: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Межпарламентский союз (2008 год). Равенство в политике: исследование наличия женщин и мужчин в парламентах. Женева. Доступно по адресу &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipu.org/english/surveys.htm#equality08&quot;&gt; http://www.ipu.org/english/surveys.htm#equality08 &lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Межпарламентский союз (2010 год). Открыт ли парламент для женщин? Доступно по адресу &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipu.org/PDF/publications/wmn09-e.pdf&quot;&gt; http://www.ipu.org/PDF/publications/wmn09-e.pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Межпарламентский союз (2011 год). Парламенты с учётом гендерного фактора. Глобальный обзор передовой практики. Доступно по адресу &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipu.org/pdf/publications/gsp11-e.pdf&quot;&gt; http://www.ipu.org/pdf/publications/gsp11-e.pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Фонд Организации Объединенных Наций для развития в интересах женщин (2009 год). Прогресс женщин мира 2008/2009 годы. Нью-Йорк. Доступно по адресу &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unifem.org/progress/2008.%20UN-Women&quot;&gt;http://www.unifem.org/progress/2008. UN-Women (2011). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Структура «ООН-женщины» (2011 год). Прогресс женщин мира 2011-2012 годы. Нью-Йорк. Доступно по адресу &lt;a href=&quot;http://progress.unwomen.org/pdfs/EN-Report-Progress.pdf&quot;&gt; http://progress.unwomen.org/pdfs/EN-Report-Progress.pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
