<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 6-1-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 6: Ensure availability and sustainable management of water and sanitation for all&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 6.1: By 2030, achieve universal and equitable access to safe and affordable drinking water for all&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 6.1.1: Proportion of population using safely managed drinking water services&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2021-12-20&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All targets under Goal 6, as well as targets 1.2, 1.4, 2.2, 3.2, 3.8, 3.9, 4a, 5.4 and 11.1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;World Health Organization (WHO)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations Children&amp;apos;s Fund (UNICEF)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;World Health Organization (WHO)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations Children&amp;apos;s Fund (UNICEF)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proportion of the population using safely managed drinking water services is defined as the proportion of population using an improved drinking water source which is accessible on premises, available when needed and free from faecal and priority chemical contamination. &amp;#x2018;Improved&amp;#x2019; drinking water sources include: piped supplies, boreholes and tubewells, protected dug wells, protected springs, rainwater, water kiosks, and packaged and delivered water. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;#x2018;drinking water source&amp;#x2019; refers to the point where people collect water for drinking and not the origin of the water supplied. For example, water collected from a distribution network that draws water from a surface water reservoir would be classified as piped water, while water collected directly from a lake or river would be classified as surface water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2018;Improved&amp;#x2019; drinking water sources include the following: piped water, boreholes or tubewells, protected dug wells, protected springs, rainwater, water kiosks, and packaged or delivered water. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2018;Unimproved&amp;#x2019; drinking water sources include: unprotected dug wells, unprotected springs, and surface water (rivers, reservoirs, lakes, ponds, streams, canals, and irrigation channels), all of which are by nature of their design and construction unlikely to deliver safe water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A water source is &amp;#x2018;accessible on premises&amp;#x2019; if the point of collection is within the dwelling, compound, yard or plot, or water is delivered to the household.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drinking water is &amp;#x2018;available when needed&amp;#x2019; if households report having &amp;#x2018;sufficient&amp;#x2019; water, or water is available &amp;#x2018;most of the time&amp;#x2019; (i.e. at least 12 hours per day or 4 days per week).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2018;Free from faecal and priority chemical contamination&amp;#x2019; requires that drinking water meets international standards for microbiological and chemical water quality specified in the WHO Guidelines for Drinking Water Quality. For the purposes of global monitoring the priority indicator of microbiological contamination is &lt;em&gt;E. coli&lt;/em&gt; (or thermotolerant coliforms), and the priority chemical contaminants are arsenic and fluoride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For detailed guidance on water quality, please refer to the most recent version of the WHO Guidelines for drinking water quality:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/teams/environment-climate-change-and-health/water-sanitation-and-health/water-safety-and-quality/drinking-water-quality-guidelines&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/teams/environment-climate-change-and-health/water-sanitation-and-health/water-safety-and-quality/drinking-water-quality-guidelines&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Proportion of population&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WHO/UNICEF Joint Monitoring Programme for Water Supply, Sanitation and Hygiene has established international standards for classification of drinking water facilities and service levels to benchmark and compare progress across countries (see washdata.org).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data sources included in the JMP database are: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Censuses, which in principle collect basic data from all people living within a country and are led by national statistical offices. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Household surveys, which collect data from a subset of households. These may target national, rural, or urban populations, or more limited project or sub-national areas. An appropriate sample design is necessary for survey results to be representative, and surveys are often led by or reviewed and approved by national statistical organizations. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Administrative data, which may consist of information collected by government or non-government entities involved in the delivery or oversight of services. Examples include water and sanitation inventories and databases, and reports of regulators. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Other datasets may be available such as compilations by international or regional initiatives (e.g. Eurostat), studies conducted by research institutes, or technical advice received during country consultations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Access to water, sanitation and hygiene are considered core socio-economic and health indicators, as well as key determinants of child survival, maternal, and children&amp;#x2019;s health, family wellbeing, and economic productivity. Drinking water, sanitation and hygiene facilities are also used in constructing wealth quintiles used by many integrated household surveys to analyse inequalities between rich and poor. Access to drinking water, sanitation and hygiene are therefore core indicators for many household surveys and censuses. In high-income countries where household surveys or censuses do not collect detailed information on the types of facilities used by households, the JMP relies on administrative records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data on availability and quality of drinking water are currently available from both household surveys and from government departments responsible for drinking water supply and regulators. In many low- and middle-income countries, existing water quality data from regulatory authorities is limited, especially for rural areas and populations using non-piped supplies. To complement regulatory data, an increasing number of low- and middle-income countries are collecting nationally representative data on drinking water quality through multi-topic household surveys. Beginning in 2012, a water quality module was developed standardized by the JMP in collaboration with UNICEF&amp;#x2019;s Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey (MICS) programme. Integration of water quality testing has become a feasible option due to the increased availability of affordable and accurate testing procedures and their adaptation for use by household survey experts. The growing interest in ensuring the implementation of water quality testing in these surveys can, to a large extent, be attributed to the incorporation of drinking water quality in the SDG global indicator for &amp;#x2018;safely managed drinking water services&amp;#x2019;. Data gaps will be reduced even more as regulation becomes more widespread in low- and middle-income countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some datasets available to the JMP are not representative of national, rural or urban populations, or may be representative of only a subset of these populations (e.g. the population using piped water supplies). The JMP enters datasets into the global database when they represent at least 20% of the national, urban or rural populations. However, datasets representing less than 80% of the relevant population, or which are considered unreliable or inconsistent with other datasets covering similar populations, are not used in the production of estimates (see section 2.6, Data Acceptance in JMP Methodology: 2017 update and SDG baselines).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The population data used by the JMP, including the proportion of the population living in urban and rural areas, are those routinely updated by the UN Population Division (World Population Prospects: &lt;a href=&quot;https://population.un.org/wpp/&quot;&gt;https://population.un.org/wpp/&lt;/a&gt;; World Urbanization Projects: &lt;a href=&quot;https://population.un.org/wup&quot;&gt;https://population.un.org/wup&lt;/a&gt;))&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The JMP team conducts regular data searches by systematically visiting the websites of national statistical offices, and key sector institutions such as ministries of water and sanitation, regulators of drinking water and sanitation services, etc. Other regional and global databases are also reviewed for new datasets. UNICEF and WHO regional and country offices provides support to identify newly available household surveys, censuses and administrative datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before publishing, all JMP estimates undergo rigorous country consultations facilitated by WHO and UNICEF country offices. Often these consultations give rise to in-country visits or virtual meetings about data on drinking water, sanitation and hygiene services and the monitoring systems that collect these data. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The JMP begins its biennial data collection cycle in October of even years and publishes estimates during the following year. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The SDG Progress Report and relevant data are published every two years since the publication of the baseline report in 2017, usually between March and July of odd years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National statistics offices; ministries of water, health, and environment; regulators of drinking water service providers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WHO/UNICEF Joint Monitoring Programme for Water Supply, Sanitation and Hygiene (JMP)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The WHO/UNICEF JMP was established in 1990 to monitor global progress on drinking water, sanitation and hygiene (see washdata.org).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Access to safe drinking water is essential for good health, welfare and productivity and is widely recognized as a human right. Drinking water may be contaminated with human or animal faeces containing pathogens or with chemical and physical contaminants, leading to harmful effects on health. While improving water quality is critical to prevent the transmission of many diseases (such as diarrhoea which exacerbates malnutrition and remains a leading global cause of child deaths), improving the accessibility and availability of drinking water is equally important for health and welfare, particularly for women and girls who often bear the primary responsibility for collecting drinking water from distant sources. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WHO/UNICEF Joint Monitoring Programme for Water Supply, Sanitation and Hygiene (JMP) uses a simple improved/unimproved facility type classification that has been refined over time. &amp;#x2018;Improved&amp;#x2019; water sources are those that have the potential to deliver safe water by nature of their design and construction, and this metric was used beginning in 2000 to track progress towards MDG target 7c. International consultations since 2011 have established consensus on the need to build on and address the shortcomings of this indicator; specifically, to address normative criteria of the human rights to water and sanitation (UN General Assembly Resolution A/RES/64/292) and concluded that global monitoring should go beyond the basic level of access. As a result, the SDG indicator 6.1.1 is designed to address safe management of drinking water services, including dimensions of accessibility, availability and quality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data are widely available on the type and location of drinking water sources used by households. Data on availability and safety of drinking water are increasingly available through a combination of household surveys and administrative sources including regulators, but definitions have yet to be standardized. The JMP has been collaborating with international survey programmes (such as the UNICEF Multiple Indicator Cluster Survey programme) and national survey programmes to develop standardized questions that address the SDG criteria for service levels, as well as a module for testing water quality in household surveys. The JMP gives high importance to extending these collaborations to reduce data gaps, ensure consistency and to progressively improve the quality and comparability of data used for national, regional and global estimates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The production of estimates follows a consistent series of steps, which are explained in this and following sections: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Identification of appropriate national datasets &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Extraction of data from national datasets into harmonized tables of data inputs &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Use of the data inputs to model country estimates &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. Consultation with countries to review the estimates &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. Aggregation of country estimates to create regional and global estimates&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JMP compiles national data on drinking water from a wide range of different data sources. Household surveys and censuses provide information on types of drinking water sources, and also indicate if sources are accessible on premises. These data sources often have information on the availability of water and increasingly on the quality of water at the household level, through direct testing of drinking water for faecal or chemical contamination. These data are combined with data on availability and compliance with drinking water quality standards (faecal and chemical) from administrative reporting or regulatory bodies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JMP uses original microdata to produce its own tabulations by using populations weights (or household weights multiplied by de jure household size), where possible. However, in many cases microdata are not readily accessible so relevant data are transcribed from reports available in various formats (PDFs, Word files, Excel spreadsheets, etc.) if data are tabulated for the proportion of the population, or household/dwelling. National data from each country, area, or territory are recorded in the JMP country files, with water, sanitation, and hygiene data recorded on separate sheets. Country files can be downloaded from the JMP website: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/data/downloads&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;https://washdata.org/data/downloads&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JMP calculates the proportion of population using improved water sources by fitting a linear regression line to all available data inputs within the reference period, starting from the year 2000. To calculate the proportion of the population using safely managed drinking water services, three ratios must be calculated: the proportion of the population using improved water supplies which are accessible on premises, have water available when needed, and are free from contamination. Those ratios are then multiplied with the proportion of the population using improved water sources, respectively. Safely managed drinking water services is taken as the minimum of these three indicators for any given year. National estimates are generated as weighted averages of the separate estimates for urban and rural areas, using population data from the most recent report of the United Nations Population Division.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details on JMP rules and methods, please refer to recent JMP progress reports and &amp;#x201C;JMP Methodology: 2017 update and SDG baselines&amp;#x201D;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-methodology-2017-update&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-methodology-2017-update&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every two years the JMP updates its global databases to incorporate the latest available national data for the global SDG indicators. National authorities are consulted on the estimates generated from national data sources through a country consultation process facilitated by WHO and UNICEF country offices. The country consultation aims to engage national statistical offices and other relevant national stakeholders to review the draft estimates and provide technical feedback to the JMP team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the consultation is not to compare JMP and national estimates of WASH coverage but rather to review the completeness or correctness of the datasets in the JMP country file and to verify the interpretation of national data in the JMP estimates. The JMP provides detailed guidance to facilitate country consultation on the estimates contained in JMP country files. The consultation focusses on three main questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the country file missing any relevant national sources of data that would allow for better estimates?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are the data sources listed considered reliable and suitable for use as official national statistics?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the JMP interpretation and classification of the data extracted from national sources accurate and appropriate?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JMP estimates are circulated for a 2 month period of consultation with national authorities starting in the fourth quarter of the year prior to publication (see https://washdata.org/how-we-work/jmp-country-consultation).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;See method of computation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JMP method uses a simple regression model to generate time series estimates for all years including for years without data points. The JMP then shares all its estimates using its country consultation mechanism to get consensus from countries before publishing its estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regional and global estimates for individual elements of safely managed services are calculated provided (non-imputed) data are available for at least 30% of the population using improved drinking water sources within the region. In order to produce estimates for regional or global levels, imputed estimates are produced for countries lacking data. Imputed country estimates are not published and only used for aggregation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For safely managed drinking water services, the proportions of the regional population using improved drinking water sources that are accessible on premises, available when needed and free from contamination are calculated as weighted averages amongst populations using improved drinking water sources. The resulting ratios are multiplied by the proportion of the population using improved drinking water sources in each region. Following the approach taken for countries, the proportion of the population using safely managed drinking water services is then calculated at regional and global levels by taking a minimum of the three elements, or of two elements if either accessibility or availability is missing. These proportions are calculated separately for urban and rural areas and, where possible, a weighted average is made of rural and urban populations to produce total estimates for the region or world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details on JMP rules and methods: JMP Methodology: 2017 update and SDG baselines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-methodology-2017-update&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-methodology-2017-update&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The JMP has published guidance on core questions and indicators for monitoring WASH in households, schools and health care facilities (see https://washdata.org/monitoring/methods/core-questions) and provides technical support through WHO and UNICEF regional and country offices to strengthen national monitoring of SDG indicators relating to drinking water, sanitation and hygiene. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The JMP has been instrumental in developing global norms to benchmark progress on drinking water, sanitation and hygiene, and has produced regular updates on country, regional, and global trends. The JMP regularly convenes expert task forces to provide technical advice on specific issues and methodological challenges related to WASH monitoring. WHO and UNICEF have also established a Strategic Advisory Group to provide independent advice on the continued development of the JMP as a trusted custodian of global WASH data (see https://washdata.org/how-we-work/about-jmp). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National statistical offices are primarily responsible for assuring the quality of national data sources. A key objective of JMP country consultations is to establish whether data sources are considered reliable and suitable for use as official national statistics. The JMP has established criteria for acceptance of national data sources based on representativeness, quality and comparability. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;See quality assurance. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of 1 July 2021, national estimates could be produced for 138 countries, areas and territories, including 114 UN member states, and covering 45% of the global population. Estimates were available for rural areas in countries representing 55% of the global rural population, and for urban areas in countries representing 56% of the global urban population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time series data are available for the basic level of drinking water service since 2000. These serve as the foundation for the safely managed drinking water service indicator. Some elements of safe management (e.g. water quality) were not collected during the MDG period (from 2000 to 2015) and for some countries and regions trend analysis is not possible for all years from 2000 to 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disaggregation by geographic location (urban/rural, sub-national regions, etc.) and by socioeconomic characteristics (wealth, education, ethnicity, etc) is possible in a growing number of countries. Drinking water services can also be disaggregated by service level (i.e. no services/surface water, unimproved, limited, basic, and safely managed services). Disaggregated data are more widely available for basic and lower levels of service than for safely managed services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disaggregation by individual characteristics (e.g. age, sex, disability, etc.) may also be made where data permit. Many of the datasets used for producing estimates are household surveys and censuses which collect information on drinking water at the household level. Such data cannot be disaggregated to provide information on intra-household variability (e.g. differential use of services by gender, age, or disability). The JMP seeks to highlight individual datasets which do allow assessment of intra-household variability, but these are not numerous enough to integrate into the main indicators estimated in JMP reports.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JMP estimates are based on national sources of data approved as official statistics. Differences between global and national figures arise due to differences in indicator definitions and methods used in calculating national coverage estimates. In some cases, national estimates are based on the most recent data point rather than from regression on all data points as done by the JMP. In order to generate national estimates, the JMP uses data that are representative of urban and rural populations and UN population estimates and projections (UN DESA World Population Prospects: &lt;a href=&quot;https://population.un.org/wpp/&quot;&gt;https://population.un.org/wpp/&lt;/a&gt;; World Urbanization Projects: &lt;a href=&quot;https://population.un.org/wup&quot;&gt;https://population.un.org/wup&lt;/a&gt;) which may differ from national population estimates. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;JMP Website: https://www.washdata.org/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JMP Data: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/data&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JMP Reports: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/reports&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/reports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JMP Methods: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/monitoring/methods&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/monitoring/methods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JMP Methodology: 2017 update and SDG baselines&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-methodology-2017-update&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-methodology-2017-update&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JMP Core questions on water, sanitation and hygiene for household surveys&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Available in English (EN), Spanish (ES), French (FR) and Russian (RU):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EN: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2018-core-questions-household-surveys&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2018-core-questions-household-surveys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ES: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2018-core-questions-household-surveys-es&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2018-core-questions-household-surveys-es&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2018-core-questions-household-surveys-fr&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2018-core-questions-household-surveys-fr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RU: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2018-core-questions-household-surveys-ru&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2018-core-questions-household-surveys-ru&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JMP Integrating water quality testing into household surveys&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Available in English (EN), Spanish (ES), and French (FR):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EN: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2020-water-quality-testing-household-surveys&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2020-water-quality-testing-household-surveys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ES: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2020-water-quality-testing-household-surveys-es&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2020-water-quality-testing-household-surveys-es&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FR: https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2020-water-quality-testing-household-surveys-fr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JMP Report: Progress on household drinking water, sanitation and hygiene 2000-2017: Special focus on inequalities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Available in English (EN), Spanish (ES), French (FR), Russian (RU) and Arabic (AR):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EN: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2019-wash-households&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2019-wash-households&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ES: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2019-wash-households-es&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2019-wash-households-es&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2019-wash-households-fr&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2019-wash-households-fr&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RU: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2019-wash-households-ru&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2019-wash-households-ru&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2019-wash-households-ar1&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2019-wash-households-ar1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHO Guidelines for Drinking Water Quality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/water-quality/guidelines/previous-guidelines/en/&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/water-quality/guidelines/previous-guidelines/en/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 4th edition, incorporating the first addendum (2017) is available in English (EN), Spanish (ES), and French (FR):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EN: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241549950&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ES: https://www.who.int/es/publications/i/item/9789241549950&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FR: https://www.who.int/fr/publications/i/item/9789241549950&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UN General Assembly Resolution A/RES/64/292 for the right to water and sanitation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.un.org/ga/search/view_doc.asp?symbol=A/RES/64/292&quot;&gt;https://www.un.org/ga/search/view_doc.asp?symbol=A/RES/64/292&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Human Right to Water and Sanitation Milestones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.un.org/waterforlifedecade/pdf/human_right_to_water_and_sanitation_milestones.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.un.org/waterforlifedecade/pdf/human_right_to_water_and_sanitation_milestones.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For queries: info@washdata.org&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 6 : Garantir l&apos;accès de tous à des services d&apos;alimentation en eau et d&apos;assainissement gérés de façon durable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 6.1 : D&apos;ici 2030, garantir un accès universel et équitable à une eau potable sûre et abordable pour tous&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 6.1.1 : Proportion de la population qui utilise des services d’eau potable gérés en toute sécurité&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2021-12-20&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Toutes les cibles de l’objectif 6, ainsi que les cibles 1.2, 1.4, 2.2, 3.2, 3.8, 3.9, 4a, 5.4 et 11.1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organisation mondiale de la Santé (OMS)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fonds des Nations Unies pour l’enfance (UNICEF) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organisation mondiale de la Santé (OMS)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fonds des Nations Unies pour l’enfance (UNICEF) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Définition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La proportion de la population qui utilise des services d’eau potable gérés en toute sécurité est définie comme la proportion de la population qui utilise une source d’eau potable améliorée qui est accessible sur place, qui est disponible au besoin et qui est exempte de contamination fécale et chimique prioritaire. Les sources d’eau potable « améliorées » comprennent : les approvisionnements par canalisations, les forages et les puits tubulaires, les puits creusés protégés, les sources protégées, l’eau de pluie, les kiosques à eau et l’eau emballée et livrée. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le terme « source d’eau potable » fait référence au point où les gens recueillent de l’eau pour la boire et non à l’origine de l’eau fournie. Par exemple, l’eau recueillie dans un réseau de distribution qui puise de l’eau dans un réservoir d’eau de surface serait classée comme eau courante, tandis que l’eau recueillie directement dans un lac ou une rivière serait classée comme eau de surface. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les sources d’eau potable « améliorées » comprennent les suivantes : eau courante, forages ou puits tubulaires, puits creusés protégés, sources protégées, eau de pluie, kiosques à eau et eau emballée ou livrée. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les sources d’eau potable « non améliorées » comprennent : les puits creusés non protégés, les sources non protégées et les eaux de surface (rivières, réservoirs, lacs, étangs, ruisseaux, canaux et canaux d’irrigation), qui sont tous peu susceptibles, de par leur conception et leur construction, de fournir de l’eau salubre. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Une source d’eau est « accessible sur place » si le point de collecte se trouve dans le logement, l’enceinte, la cour ou la parcelle, ou si de l’eau est livrée au ménage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’eau potable est « disponible en cas de besoin » si les ménages déclarent avoir « suffisamment d’eau » ou si de l’eau est disponible « la plupart du temps » (c’est-à-dire au moins 12 heures par jour ou 4 jours par semaine). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;« Exempte de contamination fécale et chimique prioritaire » exige que l’eau potable réponde aux normes internationales de qualité microbiologique et chimique de l’eau spécifiées dans le document (en anglais) « Guidelines for drinking-water quality » de l&apos;OMS. Aux fins de la surveillance mondiale, l’indicateur prioritaire de contamination microbiologique est &lt;em&gt;E. coli&lt;/em&gt; (ou coliformes thermotolérants), et les contaminants chimiques prioritaires sont l’arsenic et le fluorure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour des conseils détaillés sur la qualité de l’eau, veuillez consulter la version la plus récente du document (en anglais) « Guidelines for drinking-water quality » de l&apos;OMS :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/teams/environment-climate-change-and-health/water-sanitation-and-health/water-safety-and-quality/drinking-water-quality-guidelines&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/teams/environment-climate-change-and-health/water-sanitation-and-health/water-safety-and-quality/drinking-water-quality-guidelines&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Proportion de la population&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Le Programme commun OMS/UNICEF de suivi de l’approvisionnement en eau, de l’assainissement et de l’hygiène (JMP) a établi des normes internationales pour la classification des installations d’eau potable et des niveaux de service afin de comparer les progrès accomplis entre les pays (consulter le site (en anglais) washdata.org). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les sources de données incluses dans la base de données du JMP sont : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les recensements, qui recueillent en principe des données de base auprès de toutes les personnes vivant dans un pays et sont dirigés par les bureaux nationaux de statistique. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les enquêtes auprès des ménages, qui recueillent des données auprès d’un sous-ensemble de ménages. Ceux-ci peuvent cibler des populations nationales, rurales ou urbaines, ou des zones de projet ou infranationales plus limitées. Un plan d’échantillonnage approprié est nécessaire pour que les résultats des enquêtes soient représentatifs, et les enquêtes sont souvent menées par des organismes statistiques nationaux, examinées et approuvées par eux. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les données administratives, qui peuvent être des renseignements recueillis par des entités gouvernementales ou non gouvernementales participant à la prestation ou à la surveillance des services. Les exemples incluent les inventaires et les bases de données sur l’eau et l’assainissement, ainsi que les rapports des organismes de réglementation. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;D’autres ensembles de données peuvent être disponibles, tels que des compilations d’initiatives internationales ou régionales (p. ex., Eurostat), des études menées par des instituts de recherche ou des conseils techniques reçus lors de consultations par pays. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’accès à l’eau, à l’assainissement et à l’hygiène sont considérés comme des indicateurs socio-économiques et sanitaires de base, ainsi que des déterminants clés de la survie de l’enfant, de la santé maternelle et infantile, du bien-être de la famille et de la productivité économique. Les installations d’eau potable, d’assainissement et d’hygiène sont également utilisés dans la construction des quintiles de richesse utilisés par de nombreuses enquêtes intégrées auprès des ménages pour analyser les inégalités entre riches et pauvres. L’accès à l’eau potable, à l’assainissement et à l’hygiène sont donc des indicateurs essentiels pour de nombreuses enquêtes et recensements auprès des ménages. Dans les pays à revenu élevé où les enquêtes ou les recensements auprès des ménages ne recueillent pas d’informations détaillées sur les types d’installations utilisées par les ménages, le JMP s’appuie sur des dossiers administratifs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des données sur la disponibilité et la qualité de l’eau potable sont actuellement disponibles à la fois auprès des enquêtes auprès des ménages et des ministères responsables de l’approvisionnement en eau potable et des organismes de réglementation. Dans de nombreux pays à faible ou à moyen revenu, les données existantes sur la qualité de l’eau fournies par les autorités de réglementation sont limitées, en particulier pour les zones rurales et les populations utilisant des sources d’approvisionnement non canalisées. Pour compléter les données réglementaires, un nombre croissant de pays à faible ou à moyen revenu recueillent des données représentatives à l’échelle nationale sur la qualité de l’eau potable par le biais d’enquêtes multidisciplinaires auprès des ménages. À partir de 2012, un module standardisé sur la qualité de l’eau a été développé par le JMP en collaboration avec le programme d’enquête en grappes à indicateurs multiples (MICS) de l’UNICEF. L’intégration des tests de qualité de l’eau est devenue une option réalisable en raison de la disponibilité accrue de procédures d’essai abordables et précises et de leur adaptation à l’utilisation par les experts en enquêtes auprès des ménages. L’intérêt croissant pour la mise en œuvre d’analyses de la qualité de l’eau dans ces enquêtes peut, dans une large mesure, être attribué à l’intégration de la qualité de l’eau potable dans l’indicateur mondial des ODD pour des « services d’eau potable gérés en toute sécurité ». Les lacunes en matière de données seront encore plus réduites à mesure que la réglementation se généralisera dans les pays à faible ou à moyen revenu. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certains ensembles de données dont dispose le JMP ne sont pas représentatifs des populations nationales, rurales ou urbaines, ou peuvent n’être représentatifs que d’un sous-ensemble de ces populations (p. ex., la population utilisant des sources d’eau courante). Le JMP entre des ensembles de données dans la base de données mondiale lorsqu’ils représentent au moins 20% des populations nationales, urbaines ou rurales. Cependant, les ensembles de données représentant moins de 80 % de la population concernée, ou qui sont considérés comme peu fiables ou incompatibles avec d’autres ensembles de données couvrant des populations similaires, ne sont pas utilisés dans la production d’estimations (consulter la section 2.6 Data Acceptance dans le document (en anglais) « JMP Methodology: 2017 update and SDG baselines »). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données démographiques utilisées par le JMP, y compris la proportion de la population vivant dans les zones urbaines et rurales, sont celles régulièrement mises à jour par la Division de la population des Nations Unies (« World Population Prospects » : &lt;a href=&quot;https://population.un.org/wpp/&quot;&gt;https://population.un.org/wpp/&lt;/a&gt;; « World Urbanization Projects » : &lt;a href=&quot;https://population.un.org/wup&quot;&gt;https://population.un.org/wup&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L’équipe du Programme commun OMS/UNICEF de suivi (JMP) effectue régulièrement des recherches de données en visitant systématiquement les sites Web des bureaux nationaux de statistique et des institutions sectorielles clés telles que les ministères de l’eau et de l’assainissement, les régulateurs des services d’eau potable et d’assainissement, etc. D’autres bases de données régionales et mondiales sont également examinées pour détecter de nouveaux ensembles de données. L’UNICEF et les bureaux régionaux et nationaux de l’OMS fournissent un appui pour identifier les nouvelles enquêtes auprès des ménages, les recensements et les ensembles de données administratives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avant d’être publiées, toutes les estimations du JMP font l’objet de consultations rigoureuses auprès des pays facilitées par les bureaux nationaux de l’OMS et de l’UNICEF. Souvent, ces consultations donnent lieu à des visites dans le pays ou à des réunions virtuelles au sujet des données sur les services d’eau potable, d’assainissement et d’hygiène et les systèmes de surveillance qui recueillent ces données. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Le JMP commence son cycle biennal de collecte de données en octobre des années paires et publie des estimations au cours de l’année suivante. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Le rapport d’avancement sur les ODD et les données pertinentes sont publiés tous les deux ans depuis la publication du rapport de référence en 2017, généralement entre mars et juillet des années impaires. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les bureaux nationaux de statistique; les ministères de l’eau, de la santé et de l’environnement; les organismes de réglementation des fournisseurs de services d’eau potable. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Le Programme commun OMS/UNICEF de suivi de l’approvisionnement en eau, de l’assainissement et de l’hygiène (JMP)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Le Programme commun OMS/UNICEF (JMP) a été créé en 1990 pour suivre les progrès mondiaux en matière d’eau potable, d’assainissement et d’hygiène (consulter le site (en anglais) washdata.org). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L’accès à l’eau potable sûre et salubre est essentiel pour la santé, le bien-être et la productivité et est largement reconnu comme un droit de l’homme. L’eau potable peut être contaminée par des fèces humaines ou animales contenant des agents pathogènes ou par des contaminants chimiques et physiques, ce qui entraîne des effets nocifs sur la santé. Si l’amélioration de la qualité de l’eau est essentielle pour prévenir la transmission de nombreuses maladies (telles que la diarrhée qui exacerbe la malnutrition et reste l’une des principales causes mondiales de décès d’enfants), l’amélioration de l’accessibilité et de la disponibilité de l’eau potable est tout aussi importante pour la santé et le bien-être, en particulier pour les femmes et les filles qui portent souvent la responsabilité principale de la collecte de l’eau potable à partir de sources lointaines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Programme commun OMS/UNICEF de suivi de l’approvisionnement en eau, de l’assainissement et de l’hygiène (JMP) utilise une classification simple améliorée/non améliorée des types d’installations qui a été affinée au fil du temps. Les sources d’eau « améliorées » sont celles qui ont le potentiel de fournir de l’eau salubre par la nature de leur conception et de leur construction, et cette mesure a été utilisée à partir de 2000 pour suivre les progrès accomplis dans la réalisation de la cible 7c des OMD. Les consultations internationales menées depuis 2011 ont permis de parvenir à un consensus sur la nécessité de tirer parti de cet indicateur et d’y remédier; plus précisément, répondre aux critères normatifs des droits de l’homme à l’eau et à l’assainissement (Résolution A/RES/64/292 de l’Assemblée générale des Nations Unies) et conclure que la surveillance mondiale devrait aller au-delà du niveau d’accès de base. Par conséquent, l’indicateur 6.1.1 des ODD est conçu pour traiter de la gestion sécuritaire des services d’eau potable, y compris les dimensions de l’accessibilité, de la disponibilité et de la qualité. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les données sont largement disponibles sur le type et l’emplacement des sources d’eau potable utilisées par les ménages. Les données sur la disponibilité et la salubrité de l’eau potable sont de plus en plus disponibles au moyen d’une combinaison d’enquêtes auprès des ménages et de sources administratives, y compris les organismes de réglementation, mais les définitions n’ont pas encore été normalisées. Le JMP a collaboré avec des programmes d’enquête internationaux (tels que le programme d’enquête en grappes à indicateurs multiples de l’UNICEF) et des programmes d’enquête nationaux pour élaborer des questions normalisées qui traitent des critères des ODD pour les niveaux de service, ainsi qu’un module pour tester la qualité de l’eau dans les enquêtes auprès des ménages. Le JMP accorde une grande importance à l’extension de ces collaborations afin de réduire les lacunes en matière de données, d’assurer la cohérence et d’améliorer progressivement la qualité et la comparabilité des données utilisées pour les estimations nationales, régionales et mondiales. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;La production d’estimations suit une série cohérente d’étapes, qui sont expliquées dans cette section et dans les sections suivantes : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Identification des ensembles de données nationales appropriés &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Extraction des données des ensembles de données nationales dans des tableaux harmonisés d’entrées de données &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Utilisation des données saisies pour modéliser les estimations par pays &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. Consultation des pays pour l’examen des estimations &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. Agrégation des estimations par pays pour créer des estimations régionales et mondiales&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le JMP compile des données nationales sur l’eau potable à partir d’un large éventail de sources de données différentes. Les enquêtes auprès des ménages et les recensements fournissent des informations sur les types de sources d’eau potable et indiquent également si les sources sont accessibles sur place. Ces sources de données contiennent souvent des informations sur la disponibilité de l’eau et, de plus en plus, sur la qualité de l’eau au niveau des ménages, grâce à des tests directs de contamination fécale ou chimique dans l’eau potable. Ces données sont combinées avec des données sur la disponibilité et la conformité aux normes de qualité de l’eau potable (fécales et chimiques) provenant d’organismes de déclaration administratifs ou de réglementation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le JMP utilise des microdonnées originales pour produire ses propres tableaux en utilisant les pondérations des populations (ou les pondérations des ménages multipliées par la taille des ménages de jure), dans la mesure du possible. Cependant, dans de nombreux cas, les microdonnées ne sont pas facilement accessibles, de sorte que les données pertinentes sont transcrites à partir de rapports disponibles dans divers formats (PDF, fichiers Word, feuilles de calcul Excel, etc.) si les données sont compilées pour la proportion de la population, ou ménage/logement. Les données nationales de chaque pays, zone ou territoire sont enregistrées dans les fichiers de pays du JMP, avec des données sur l’eau, l’assainissement et l’hygiène enregistrées sur des feuilles séparées. Les fichiers de pays peuvent être téléchargés à partir du site Web (en anglais) de JMP : &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/data/downloads&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;https://washdata.org/data/downloads&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le JMP calcule la proportion de la population utilisant des sources d’eau améliorées en ajustant une ligne de régression linéaire à toutes les données disponibles au cours de la période de référence, à compter de l’an 2000. Pour calculer la proportion de la population utilisant des services d’eau potable gérés en toute sécurité, trois ratios doivent être calculés: la proportion de la population utilisant des approvisionnements en eau améliorés qui sont accessibles sur place, qui sont disponibles en cas de besoin et qui sont exempts de contamination. Ces ratios sont ensuite multipliés par la proportion de la population utilisant des sources d’eau améliorées, respectivement. Les services d’eau potable gérés en toute sécurité sont considérés comme le minimum de ces trois indicateurs pour une année donnée. Les estimations nationales sont produites sous forme de moyennes pondérées des estimations distinctes pour les zones urbaines et rurales, en utilisant les données démographiques du rapport le plus récent de la Division de la population des Nations Unies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour plus de détails sur les règles et méthodes du JMP, veuillez consulter les récents rapports d’avancement du JMP et le document (en anglais) « JMP Methodology: 2017 update and SDG baselines » à l&apos;adresse : &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-methodology-2017-update&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-methodology-2017-update&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tous les deux ans, le JMP met à jour ses bases de données mondiales pour intégrer les dernières données nationales disponibles pour les indicateurs mondiaux des ODD. Les autorités nationales sont consultées au sujet des estimations produites à partir de sources de données nationales dans le cadre d’un processus de consultation par pays facilité par les bureaux nationaux de l’OMS et de l’UNICEF. La consultation par pays vise à faire participer les bureaux nationaux de statistique et d’autres parties prenantes nationales concernées à l’examen des estimations provisoires et à fournir une rétroaction technique à l’équipe du JMP. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’objectif de la consultation n’est pas de comparer les estimations du JMP et les estimations nationales de la couverture au sujet de l&apos;eau, l&apos;assainissement et l&apos;hygiène (WASH), mais plutôt d’examiner l’exhaustivité ou l’exactitude des ensembles de données dans le fichier national du JMP et de vérifier l’interprétation des données nationales dans les estimations du JMP. Le JMP fournit des conseils détaillés pour faciliter la consultation des pays au sujet des estimations contenues dans les fichiers par pays du JMP. La consultation se concentre sur trois questions principales :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Le fichier national manque-t-il de sources nationales pertinentes de données qui permettraient de meilleures estimations ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les sources de données énumérées sont-elles considérées comme fiables et aptes à être utilisées comme statistiques nationales officielles ? &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;L’interprétation et la classification par le JMP des données extraites de sources nationales sont-elles exactes et appropriées ? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les estimations du JMP sont envoyées pour une période de consultation de 2 mois avec les autorités nationales à partir du quatrième trimestre de l’année précédant leur publication (consulter le lien (en anglais) https://washdata.org/how-we-work/jmp-country-consultation). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consulter la section Méthode de calcul. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Au niveau national :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La méthode du JMP utilise un modèle de régression simple pour générer des estimations de séries chronologiques pour toutes les années, y compris pour les années sans points de données. Le JMP partage ensuite toutes ses estimations en utilisant son mécanisme de consultation par pays pour obtenir un consensus des pays avant de publier ses estimations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aux niveaux régional et mondial :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des estimations régionales et mondiales pour les différents éléments des services gérés en toute sécurité sont calculées à condition que des données (non imputées) soient disponibles pour au moins 30 % de la population utilisant des sources d’eau potable améliorées dans la région. Afin de produire des estimations aux niveaux régional ou mondial, des estimations imputées sont produites pour les pays qui ne disposent pas de données. Les estimations nationales imputées ne sont pas publiées et ne sont utilisées qu’à des fins d’agrégation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pour les services d’eau potable gérés en toute sécurité, les proportions de la population régionale utilisant des sources d’eau potable améliorées qui sont accessibles sur place, disponibles au besoin et exemptes de contamination sont calculées en tant que moyennes pondérées parmi les populations utilisant des sources d’eau potable améliorées. Les ratios qui en résultent sont multipliés par la proportion de la population qui utilise des sources d’eau potable améliorées dans chaque région. Selon l’approche adoptée pour les pays, la proportion de la population utilisant des services d’eau potable gérés en toute sécurité est ensuite calculée aux niveaux régional et mondial en prenant le minimum des trois éléments, ou de deux éléments s’il manque l’accessibilité ou la disponibilité. Ces proportions sont calculées séparément pour les zones urbaines et rurales et, dans la mesure du possible, une moyenne pondérée est faite des populations rurales et urbaines pour produire des estimations totales pour la région ou le monde. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour plus de détails sur les règles et méthodes du JMP : « JMP Methodology: 2017 update and SDG baselines »:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-methodology-2017-update&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-methodology-2017-update&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Le JMP a publié des conseils sur les questions et indicateurs fondamentaux pour le suivi de l’eau, de l’assainissement et de l’hygiène dans les ménages, les écoles et les établissements de soins de santé (consulter le lien (en anglais) https://washdata.org/monitoring/methods/core-questions) et fournit un appui technique par l’intermédiaire des bureaux régionaux et nationaux de l’OMS et de l’UNICEF pour renforcer le suivi national des indicateurs des ODD relatifs à l’eau potable, à l’assainissement et à l’hygiène. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Le JMP a joué un rôle déterminant dans l’élaboration de normes mondiales pour comparer les progrès en matière d’eau potable, d’assainissement et d’hygiène, et a produit des mises à jour régulières sur les tendances nationales, régionales et mondiales. Le JMP réunit régulièrement des groupes de travail d’experts pour fournir des conseils techniques sur des questions spécifiques et des défis méthodologiques liés au suivi WASH. L’OMS et l’UNICEF ont également créé un Groupe consultatif stratégique chargé de fournir des conseils indépendants sur le développement continu du JMP en tant que dépositaire de confiance des données mondiales WASH (consulter le lien (en anglais) https://washdata.org/how-we-work/about-jmp). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Les bureaux nationaux de statistique sont les premiers responsables d’assurer la qualité des sources de données nationales. L’un des principaux objectifs des consultations par pays du JMP est de déterminer si les sources de données sont considérées comme fiables et aptes à être utilisées comme statistiques nationales officielles. Le JMP a établi des critères d’acceptation des sources de données nationales fondés sur la représentativité, la qualité et la comparabilité. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consulter la section Assurance de la qualité. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disponibilité des données :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Au 1er juillet 2021, des estimations nationales pouvaient être produites pour 138 pays, zones et territoires, dont 114 États membres de l’ONU, et couvrant 45% de la population mondiale. Des estimations étaient disponibles pour les zones rurales dans les pays représentant 55 % de la population rurale mondiale, et pour les zones urbaines dans les pays représentant 56 % de la population urbaine mondiale. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Séries chronologiques :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des données chronologiques sont disponibles pour le niveau de base du service d’eau potable depuis 2000. Celles-ci servent de base à l’indicateur de service d’eau potable géré en toute sécurité. Certains éléments de la gestion sécuritaire (p. ex., la qualité de l’eau) n’ont pas été recueillis pendant la période des OMD (de 2000 à 2015) et, pour certains pays et régions, l’analyse des tendances n’est pas possible pour toutes les années de 2000 à 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Désagrégation :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La désagrégation par situation géographique (urbaine/rurale, régions infranationales, etc.) et par caractéristiques socioéconomiques (richesse, éducation, ethnicité, etc.) est possible dans un nombre croissant de pays. Les services d’eau potable peuvent également être ventilés par niveau de service (c.-à-d. pas de services/eau de surface, services non améliorés, limités, de base et gérés en toute sécurité). Les données désagrégées sont plus largement disponibles pour les niveaux de service de base et inférieurs que pour les services gérés en toute sécurité. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La désagrégation en fonction des caractéristiques individuelles (p. ex., l’âge, le sexe, le handicap, etc.) peut également être effectuée lorsque les données le permettent. Bon nombre des ensembles de données utilisés pour produire des estimations sont des enquêtes auprès des ménages et des recensements qui recueillent des renseignements sur l’eau potable au niveau des ménages. Ces données ne peuvent pas être ventilées pour fournir des renseignements sur la variabilité intra-ménage (p. ex. utilisation différentielle des services selon le sexe, l’âge ou le handicap). Le JMP cherche à mettre en évidence des ensembles de données individuelles qui permettent d’évaluer la variabilité intra-ménage, mais ceux-ci ne sont pas assez nombreux pour être intégrés dans les principaux indicateurs estimés dans les rapports du JMP. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources des divergences :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les estimations du JMP sont basées sur des sources nationales de données approuvées en tant que statistiques officielles. Les différences entre les chiffres mondiaux et nationaux sont dues à des différences dans les définitions des indicateurs et les méthodes utilisées pour calculer les estimations de la couverture nationale. Dans certains cas, les estimations nationales sont fondées sur le point de données le plus récent plutôt que sur la régression sur tous les points de données, comme l’a fait le JMP. Afin de générer des estimations nationales, le JMP utilise des données représentatives des populations urbaines et rurales et des estimations et projections de la population des Nations Unies (« UN DESA World Population Prospects » : &lt;a href=&quot;https://population.un.org/wpp/&quot;&gt;https://population.un.org/wpp/&lt;/a&gt;; « World Urbanization Projects » : &lt;a href=&quot;https://population.un.org/wup&quot;&gt;https://population.un.org/wup&lt;/a&gt;) qui peuvent différer des estimations de la population nationale. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(À moins d&apos;indication contraire, les références sont en anglais)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Site Web du JMP : https://www.washdata.org/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Données du JMP : &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/data&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rapports du JMP : &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/reports&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/reports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Méthodologie du JMP : &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/monitoring/methods&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/monitoring/methods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;« JMP Methodology: 2017 update and SDG baselines »&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-methodology-2017-update&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-methodology-2017-update&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions essentielles sur l’approvisionnement en eau de boisson, l’assainissement et l’hygiène applicables aux enquêtes auprès des ménages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Document disponible en anglais (EN), espagnol (ES), français (FR) et russe (RU) :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EN: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2018-core-questions-household-surveys&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2018-core-questions-household-surveys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ES: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2018-core-questions-household-surveys-es&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2018-core-questions-household-surveys-es&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2018-core-questions-household-surveys-fr&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2018-core-questions-household-surveys-fr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RU: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2018-core-questions-household-surveys-ru&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2018-core-questions-household-surveys-ru&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intégrer la mesure de la qualité de l&apos;eau dans les enquêtes auprès des ménages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Document disponible en anglais (EN), espagnol (ES) et français (FR) :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EN: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2020-water-quality-testing-household-surveys&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2020-water-quality-testing-household-surveys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ES: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2020-water-quality-testing-household-surveys-es&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2020-water-quality-testing-household-surveys-es&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FR: https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2020-water-quality-testing-household-surveys-fr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Progrès en matière d&apos;eau, d&apos;assainissement et hygiène des ménages 2000-2017 : Gros plan sur les inégalités&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Document disponible en anglais (EN), espagnol (ES), français (FR), russe (RU) et arabe (AR) :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EN: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2019-wash-households&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2019-wash-households&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ES: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2019-wash-households-es&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2019-wash-households-es&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2019-wash-households-fr&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2019-wash-households-fr&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RU: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2019-wash-households-ru&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2019-wash-households-ru&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2019-wash-households-ar1&quot;&gt;https://washdata.org/report/jmp-2019-wash-households-ar1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Directives de qualité pour l&apos;eau de boisson (version précédente en anglais)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/water-quality/guidelines/previous-guidelines/en/&quot;&gt;https://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/water-quality/guidelines/previous-guidelines/en/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quatrième édition intégrant le premier addendum (2017). Document disponible en anglais (EN), espagnol (ES) et français (FR) :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EN: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241549950&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ES: https://www.who.int/es/publications/i/item/9789241549950&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FR: https://www.who.int/fr/publications/i/item/9789241549950&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Résolution adoptée par l’Assemblée générale le 28 juillet 2010 64/292. Le droit de l’homme à l’eau et à l’assainissement :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.un.org/ga/search/view_doc.asp?symbol=A/RES/64/292&amp;Lang=F&quot;&gt;https://www.un.org/ga/search/view_doc.asp?symbol=A/RES/64/292&amp;Lang=F&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;« The Human Right to Water and Sanitation Milestones » :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.un.org/waterforlifedecade/pdf/human_right_to_water_and_sanitation_milestones.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.un.org/waterforlifedecade/pdf/human_right_to_water_and_sanitation_milestones.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour faire des requêtes : info@washdata.org&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
