<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 6-4-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 6: Ensure availability and sustainable management of water and sanitation for all&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 6.4: By 2030, substantially increase water-use efficiency across all sectors and ensure sustainable withdrawals and supply of freshwater to address water scarcity and substantially reduce the number of people suffering from water scarcity&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 6.4.2: Level of water stress: freshwater withdrawal as a proportion of available freshwater resources&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Level of water stress: freshwater withdrawal as a proportion of available freshwater resources (%)&lt;/p&gt;2022-03-31&lt;p&gt;6.4.1: Change in water-use efficiency over time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.1.1: Proportion of population using safely managed drinking water services&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.3.1: Proportion of wastewater safely treated&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.6.1: Change in the extent of water-related ecosystems over time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.5.1: Degree of integrated water resources management implementation (0-100)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.4.1: Proportion of agricultural area under productive and sustainable agriculture&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15.3.1: Proportion of land that is degraded over total land area&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.5.1: Number of deaths, missing persons and persons affected by disaster per 100,000 people [a]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11.5.1: Number of deaths, missing persons and persons affected by disaster per 100,000 people [a]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The level of water stress: freshwater withdrawal as a proportion of available freshwater resources is the ratio between total freshwater withdrawn by all major sectors and total renewable freshwater resources, after taking into account environmental flow requirements. Main sectors, as defined by ISIC standards, include agriculture; forestry and fishing; manufacturing; electricity industry; and services. This indicator is also known as water withdrawal intensity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator provides an estimate of pressure by all sectors on the country&amp;#x2019;s renewable freshwater resources. A low level of water stress indicates a situation where the combined withdrawal by all sectors is marginal in relation to the resources, and has therefore little potential impact on the sustainability of the resources or on the potential competition between users. A high level of water stress indicates a situation where the combined withdrawal by all sectors represents a substantial share of the total renewable freshwater resources, with potentially larger impacts on the sustainability of the resources and potential situations of conflicts and competition between users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total renewable freshwater resources (TRWR) are expressed as the sum of internal and external renewable water resources. The terms &amp;#x201C;water resources&amp;#x201D; and &amp;#x201C;water withdrawal&amp;#x201D; are understood here as freshwater resources and freshwater withdrawal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internal renewable water resources are defined as the long-term average annual flow of rivers and recharge of groundwater for a given country generated from endogenous precipitation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;External renewable water resources refer to the flows of water entering the country, taking into consideration the quantity of flows reserved to upstream and downstream countries through agreements or treaties. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total freshwater withdrawal (TFWW) is the volume of freshwater extracted from its source (rivers, lakes, aquifers) for agriculture, industries and services&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. It is estimated at the country level for the following three main sectors: agriculture, services (including domestic water withdrawal) and industries (including cooling of thermoelectric plants). Freshwater withdrawal includes fossil groundwater. It does not include non-conventional water, i.e. direct use of treated wastewater, direct use of agricultural drainage water and desalinated water. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environmental flow requirements (EFR) are defined as the quantity and timing of freshwater flows and levels necessary to sustain aquatic ecosystems, which, in turn, support human cultures, economies, sustainable livelihoods, and wellbeing. Water quality and also the resulting ecosystem services are excluded from this formulation which is confined to water volumes. This does not imply that quality and the support to societies which are dependent on environmental flows are not important and should not be taken care of.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-3&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Methods of computation of EFR are extremely variable and range from global estimates to comprehensive assessments for river reaches. For the purpose of the SDG indicator, water volumes can be expressed in the same units as the TFWW, and then as percentages of the available water resources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; In AQUASTAT, Services water withdrawal is reported as Municipal water withdrawal. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-3&quot;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; They are indeed taken into account by other targets and indicators, such as 6.3.2, 6.5.1 and 6.6.1. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-3&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Percent (%)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The System of Environmental-Economic Accounting for Water: SEEA-Water for water resources and withdrawals (Available at https://seea.un.org/content/seea-water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The World Census of Agriculture 2020: WCA (Volume 1), for irrigation definitions (Available at: http://www.fao.org/world-census-agriculture).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data for this indicator are usually collected by national ministries and institutions having water-related issues in their mandate, such as national statistic offices, ministries of water resources, agriculture or environment. Official counterparts at country level are the national statistics office and/or the line ministry for water resources and irrigation. More specifically, FAO requests countries to nominate a National Correspondent to act as the focal point for the data collection and communication. Data are mainly published within national statistical yearbooks, national water resources and irrigation master plans and other reports (such as those from projects, international surveys or results and publications from national and international research centres).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data collection is done through FAO&amp;#x2019;s Global Information System on Water and Agriculture (AQUASTAT) and AQUASTAT questionnaire on water and agriculture. The data collection process relies on a network of National Correspondents, officially nominated by their respective countries, in charge of the provision of official national data to AQUASTAT. As at August 2020, 150 countries have nominated national correspondents as well as alternate correspondents from different agencies. Countries submit data through the annual AQUASTAT questionnaire on water and agriculture, which contains, among others, the information required for the calculation of SDG indicator 6.4.2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data are collected every year through the AQUASTAT network of National Correspondents. FAO has dispatched the questionnaires to the National Correspondents in July 2022.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data for the indicator are released every year, usually in February following the UNSD collection schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data come from governmental sources. The institutions responsible for data collection at national level vary according to countries. However, in general data for this indicator are provided by the Ministry of Agriculture, Ministry of Water, Ministry of Environment and other line Ministries. In many cases, data collection at country level is coordinated by the National Statistics office (NSO).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Calculation rules are predefined and use data referring to the same year to general aggregate values.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FAO has, as part of its mandate, the function of &amp;#x201C;collect, analyse, interpret and disseminate information relating to nutrition, food and agriculture&amp;#x201D;. (FAO Constitution, Article 1)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this indicator is to show the degree to which water resources are being exploited to meet the country&amp;apos;s water demand. It measures a country&amp;apos;s pressure on its water resources and therefore the challenge on the sustainability of its water use. It tracks progress regarding &amp;#x201C;withdrawals and supply of freshwater to address water scarcity&amp;#x201D;, i.e. the environmental component of target 6.4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator shows to what extent water resources are already used, and signals the importance of effective supply and demand management policies. It indicates the likelihood of increasing competition and conflict between different water uses and users in a situation of increasing water scarcity. Increased water stress, shown by an increase in the value of the indicator, has potentially negative effects on the sustainability of the natural resources and on economic development. On the other hand, low values of the indicator indicate that water does not represent a particular challenge for economic development and sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, extremely low values may indicate the inability of a country to use properly its water resources for the benefit of the population. In such cases, a moderate and controlled increase in the value of the indicator can be a sign of positive development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator provides an estimate of pressure by all sectors on the country&amp;#x2019;s renewable freshwater resources. A low level of water stress indicates a situation where the combined withdrawal by all sectors is marginal in relation to the resources, and has therefore little potential impact on the sustainability of the resources or on the potential competition between users. A high level of water stress indicates a situation where the combined withdrawal by all sectors represents a substantial share of the total renewable freshwater resources, with potentially larger impacts on the sustainability of the resources and potential situations of conflicts and competition between users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is computed based on three components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total renewable freshwater resources (TRWR)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total freshwater withdrawal (TFWW)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environmental flow requirements (EFR)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Freshwater withdrawal as a percentage of renewable freshwater resources is a good indicator of pressure on limited water resources, one of the most important natural resources. However, it only partially addresses the issues related to sustainable water management. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplementary indicators that capture the multiple dimensions of water management would combine data on water demand management, behavioural changes with regard to water use and the availability of appropriate infrastructure, and measure progress in increasing the efficiency and sustainability of water use, in particular in relation to population and economic growth. They would also recognize the different climatic environments that affect water use in countries, especially in agriculture, which is the main user of water. Sustainability assessment is also linked to the critical thresholds fixed for this indicator. Although there is no universal consensus on such thresholds, a proposal is presented below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trends in freshwater withdrawal show relatively slow patterns of change. Usually, three-five years are a minimum frequency to be able to detect significant changes, as it is unlikely that the indicator would show meaningful variations from one year to the other. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estimation of water withdrawal by sector may represent a limitation to the computation of the indicator. Few countries publish water withdrawal data on a regular basis by sector. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no universally agreed method for the computation of incoming freshwater flows originating outside of a country&amp;apos;s borders. Nor is there any standard method to account for return flows, the part of the water withdrawn from its source and which flows back to the river system after use. In countries where return flow represents a substantial part of water withdrawal, the indicator tends to underestimate available water and therefore overestimate the level of water stress. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other limitations that affect the interpretation of the water stress indicator include: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;difficulty to obtain accurate, complete and up-to-date data; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;potentially large variation of sub-national data; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;lack of account of historical (e.g., due to climate change and population growth) and seasonal variations in water resources;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;lack of consideration to the distribution among water uses; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;lack of consideration of water quality and its suitability for use; and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the indicator can be higher than 100 percent when water withdrawal non-renewable freshwater (fossil groundwater), when annual groundwater withdrawal is higher than annual replenishment (over-abstraction) or when freshwater withdrawal includes part or all the water set aside for environmental flow requirements. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these issues can be solved through disaggregation of the indicator at the level of hydrological units and by distinguishing between different use sectors. However, due to the complexity of water flows, both within a country and between countries, care should be taken not to double-count.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Computation Method:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Method of computation: The indicator is computed as the total freshwater withdrawn (TFWW) divided by the difference between the total renewable freshwater resources (TRWR) and the environmental flow requirements (EFR), multiplied by 100. All variables are expressed in km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;/year (10&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;/year).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;S&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mfenced separators=&quot;|&quot;&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;%&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfenced&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;T&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;F&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;W&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;W&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mfenced separators=&quot;|&quot;&gt;
          &lt;mrow&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;T&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;W&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mo&gt;-&lt;/mo&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;E&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;F&lt;/mi&gt;
            &lt;mi&gt;R&lt;/mi&gt;
          &lt;/mrow&gt;
        &lt;/mfenced&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;&amp;#xD7;&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;100&lt;/mn&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the experience of the initial five years of application of the indicator, and consistent with the approach taken during the MDG program, the threshold of 25% has been identified as the upper limit for a full and unconditional safety of water stress as assessed by the indicator 6.4.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means on one hand, that values below 25% can be considered safe in any instance (no stress); on the other, that values above 25% should be regarded as potentially and increasingly problematic, and should be qualified and/or reduced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above 25% of water stress, four classes have been identified to signal different levels of stress severity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NO STRESS &amp;lt;25% &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;LOW 25% - 50% &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MEDIUM 50% - 75% &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;HIGH 75-100%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CRITICAL &amp;gt;100% &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data validation is done in a few steps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the AQUASTAT questionnaire embeds automatic validation rules to allow National Correspondents to identify any data consistency errors while compiling the data.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the questionnaire is submitted, FAO thoroughly reviews the information reported, using the following tools:&lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Manual cross-variable check. This includes cross-comparison with similar countries as well as historic data for the countries. &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Time-series coherency by running an R-script to compare reported data with those corresponding to previous years&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Verification of the metadata, especially the source of the proposed data. The critical analysis of the compiled data gives preference to national sources and expert knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After this verification, exchanges between the National Correspondents and FAO take place to correct and confirm the collected data. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The last validation step is an automated validation routine included in the Statistical Working System (SWS), which uses almost 200 validation rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since national level data is frequently tailored to be useful at national level and not for international comparisons, data may be manipulated in order to maximize international comparability. Adjusted data is displayed with an appropriate qualifier. Data is rounded according to a specific methodology&lt;u&gt; &lt;/u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/databases/maindatabase/metadata/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/databases/maindatabase/metadata/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the Statistical Working System (SWS) has the correspondence among different international codes (FAOSTAT, UNSDM49, ISO2, ISO3) for geographic areas and is used to convert area codes in the external sources to UNSDM49 codes which is the standard used in the SWS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three types of imputation are made at country level to fill in missing years in the timeseries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linear imputation: between two available data-points.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carry forward: after the last available data-points and up to 10 years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vertical imputation: in case of available total freshwater withdrawal but missing disaggregation by sources, and if existing disaggregation existed for previous years, the respective ratio by sources is applied to the available total.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the imputation methods at country level, data will be available for the whole time series (unless the latest official value was obtained more than 10 years ago). Imputed data is displayed with an appropriate qualifier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regional and global estimates will be done by summing up the national figures on renewable freshwater resources and total freshwater withdrawal, considering only the internal renewable water resources of each country to avoid double counting, and the external renewable freshwater resources of the region, if any. In case of regional aggregation without physical continuity (such as income groupings or Least Developed Countries group, etc.), total renewable water resources are summed up. The EFR at regional level is estimated as the average of the countries&amp;#x2019; EFRs, in percentage, and applied to the regional water resources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A set of tools is available to countries for the compilation of the indicator. Among them, a step-by-step methodological guide, an interpretation paper, and an e-learning course. All the tools are available on the FAO web pages, at: http://www.fao.org/sustainable-development-goals/indicators/642/en/. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;During 2020,2021 and 2022, FAO has organized regional virtual trainings for Asia, Latin-America and the Caribbean and Africa on SDG 6.4. and contributed to global workshops on SDG 6. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FAO&amp;#x2019;s AQUASTAT team provides continued guidance to the countries thought the National Correspondents during the data collection time to ensure data is duly and timely compiled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The AQUASTAT questionnaire on water and agriculture, used for collecting information on SDG indicator 6.4.2, was endorsed by FAO&amp;#x2019;s Office of the Chief Statistician (OCS).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;During the reporting process, the OCS provides overall guidance, including on metadata reporting, based on the Metadata Dissemination Standard approved by the FAO IDWG-Statistics Technical Task Force.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data on Environmental flow requirements is reupdated only when detailed methodology and metadata are provided and when consistency in the values is ensured.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After revision and validation, data are submitted to the OCS who also ensures the quality of the data and results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;FAO is responsible for the quality of the internal statistical processes used to compile the published datasets. The FAO Statistics Quality Assurance Framework (SQAF), available at: http://www.fao.org/docrep/019/i3664e/i3664e.pdf, provides the necessary principles, guidelines and tools to carry out quality assessments. FAO is performing an internal bi-annual survey (FAO Quality Assessment and Planning Survey) designed to gather information on all of FAO&amp;#x2019;s statistical activities, notably to assess the extent to which quality standards are being implemented with a view to increasing compliance with the quality dimensions of SQAF, documenting best practices and prepare quality improvement plans, where necessary. Domain-specific quality assurance activities are carried out systematically (e.g. quality reviews, self-assessments, compliance monitoring).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall evaluation of data quality is based on standard quality criteria and follows FAO&amp;#x2019;s SQAF. It also includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A qualitative and quantitative manual cross-variable check after data is received. This consists of the verification that all the numbers are consistent based on the internal validation rules embedded in the questionnaire. Any issues identified are flagged and listed to be followed-up with the countries. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time-series coherency check done by running an R-script to compare reported data with those corresponding to previous years. Based on this, a scattered diagram is also made by variable and country to allow for a visual verification of historical data. The critical analysis of the compiled data gives preference to national sources and expert knowledge, unless these greatly diverge from historic data or in the case of drastic changes in methodologies used by countries with significant influence on the results. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Verification of the metadata, especially the source of the proposed data. When data sources were not provided, the questionnaire was added as the data source of a given value. For the &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data needed for the indicator are collected through AQUASTAT for 168 countries worldwide. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1961-2019 (Discontinuous, depending on country. Data are interpolated to create timelines.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sectoral disaggregated data are provided to show the respective contribution of the different sectors to the water stress level, and therefore the relative importance of actions needed to contain water demand in the different sectors (agriculture, services and industry). The contribution of the different sectors to the water stress level is calculated as the proportion of sectoral withdrawals over total freshwater withdrawals, after taking into account the EFR. sectors are defined following the United Nations International Standard Industrial Classification of All Economic Activities ISIC 4 coding, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;agriculture; forestry; fishing (ISIC A), hereinafter &amp;#x201C;agriculture&amp;#x201D;;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mining and quarrying; manufacturing; electricity, gas, steam and air conditioning supply; constructions (ISIC B, C, D and F), hereinafter &amp;#x201C;MIMEC&amp;#x201D;;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;all the service sectors (ISIC E and ISIC G-T), hereinafter &amp;#x201C;services&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At national level, water resources and withdrawals are estimated or measured at the level of appropriate hydrological units (river basins, aquifers). It is therefore possible to obtain a geographical distribution of water stress by hydrological unit, thus allowing for more targeted response in terms of water demand management.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Geographical: For national estimates incoming freshwater is counted as being part of the country&amp;#x2019;s available freshwater resources, while global estimates can only be done by adding up the internal renewable freshwater resources (water generated within the country) of all countries in order to avoid double counting. Moreover, external freshwater resources are computed according to treaties, if present, which may lead to different values with respect to the actual freshwater resources assessed through hydrology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over-time: time series are comparable across time. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Food and Agricultural Organization of the United Nations (FAO). AQUASTAT, FAO&amp;apos;s Global Water Information System. Rome. Website &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following resources of specific interest to this indicator are available on these sites: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AQUASTAT glossary (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/databases/glossary/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/databases/glossary/&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AQUASTAT Main country database (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/nr/water/aquastat/data/query/index.html?lang=en&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/nr/water/aquastat/data/query/index.html?lang=en&lt;/a&gt; ) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AQUASTAT Water use (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology/water-use/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology/water-use/&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AQUASTAT Water resources (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology/water-resources/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology/water-resources/&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AQUASTAT publications dealing with concepts, methodologies, definitions, terminologies, metadata, etc. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/resources/publications/reports/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/resources/publications/reports/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IWMI &amp;#x2013; Global environmental flows assessment &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eflows.iwmi.org/&quot;&gt;http://eflows.iwmi.org/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IWMI - Global Environmental Flow Information for the Sustainable Development Goals&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iwmi.cgiar.org/Publications/IWMI_Research_Reports/PDF/pub168/rr168.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.iwmi.cgiar.org/Publications/IWMI_Research_Reports/PDF/pub168/rr168.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNSD/UNEP Questionnaire on Environment Statistics &amp;#x2013; Water Section&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/qindicators.htm&quot;&gt;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/qindicators.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Framework for the Development of Environment Statistics (FDES 2013) (Chapter 3) &lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/FDES/FDES-2015-supporting-tools/FDES.pdf&quot;&gt;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/FDES/FDES-2015-supporting-tools/FDES.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OECD/Eurostat Questionnaire on Environment Statistics &amp;#x2013; Water Section &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/documents/1798247/6664269/Data-Collection-Manual-for-OECD_Eurostat-Questionnaire-on-Inland-Waters.pdf/f5f60d49-e88c-4e3c-bc23-c1ec26a01b2a?t=1611245054001&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several documents exist that can be used to support countries in the computation of this indicator. Among them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding AQUASTAT - FAO&amp;apos;s global water information system&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;This information note covers a twenty-year history of the collection and analysis of water-related data and its dissemination as an international public good, freely available to all. The process of collecting and checking the data has resulted in the establishment of a unique network of collaborators who provide data, use data from other countries for comparative purposes, and exchange views and experiences on how best to measure and account for water-related use. Users range from international private companies to non-governmental organizations, and virtually all significant reports related to water depend on the data provided by AQUASTAT.&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc817e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc817e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incorporating environmental flows into &amp;#x201C;water stress&amp;#x201D; indicator 6.4.2 - Guidelines for a minimum standard method for global reporting.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These guidelines are intended to assist countries to participate in the assessment of SDG 6.4.2 on water stress by contributing data and information on environmental flows (EF). They provide a minimum standard method, principally based on the Global Environmental Flows Information System (GEFIS), which is accessible via &lt;a href=&quot;http://eflows.iwmi.org&quot;&gt;http://eflows.iwmi.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unwater.org/app/uploads/2019/01/SDG6_EF_LOW2.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.unwater.org/app/uploads/2019/01/SDG6_EF_LOW2.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Renewable Water Resources Assessment - 2015 AQUASTAT methodology review&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc818e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc818e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global database on municipal wastewater production, collection, treatment, discharge and direct use in agriculture &lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;This paper describes the rationale and method to setup and feed the AQUASTAT database on municipal wastewater production, collection, treatment, discharge or direct use in agriculture. The best available sources of information have been reviewed, including peer-reviewed papers, proceedings of workshops, conferences and expert meetings, global or regional databases, as well as country briefs, national reports and direct communications by country government officials and experts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc823e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc823e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cooling water for energy generation and its impact on national-level water statistics &lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;This technical note, describing the issue of cooling water for energy generation and its impact on national-level water statistics, has two purposes: 1) to act as a general informational resource and 2) to encourage governmental agencies responsible for water usage to gather and report information disaggregated by sub-sector (keeping thermoelectric withdrawals separate from industrial and hydroelectric withdrawals), and to determine the point at which lower water withdrawal designs are more favourable, even if the required capital cost is higher.&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc822e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc822e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Municipal and industrial water withdrawal modelling for the years 2000 and 2005 using statistical methods &lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;This document describes the efforts to generate models that estimate the municipal and industrial water withdrawals for the years 2000 and 2005. &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc821e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc821e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disambiguation of water statistics &lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;The nomenclature surrounding water information is often confusing and gives rise to different interpretations and thus confusion. When discussing the way in which renewable water resources are utilized, the terms water use, usage, withdrawal, consumption, abstraction, extraction, utilization, supply and demand are often used without clearly stating what is meant. &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc816e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc816e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FAO-AQUASTAT questionnaire on water and agriculture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;These annual Guidelines and questionnaires have been prepared specifically designed to collect the SDG 6.4. related water variables, and therefore to update the core variables in AQUASTAT database.&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;International Recommendations for Water Statistics&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;The International Recommendations for Water Statistics (IRWS) were developed to help strengthen national information systems for water in support of design and evaluation of Integrated Water Resources Management (IWRM) policies.&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/EconStatKB/KnowledgebaseArticle10209.aspx&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/EconStatKB/KnowledgebaseArticle10209.aspx&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UNSD/UNEP Questionnaire on Environment Statistics &amp;#x2013; Water Section&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/questionnaire.htm&quot;&gt;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/questionnaire.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/qindicators.htm&quot;&gt;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/qindicators.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UNSD &amp;#x2018;National Accounts Main Aggregates Database&amp;#x2019;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/snaama/selbasicFast.asp&quot;&gt;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/snaama/selbasicFast.asp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FAO e-learning course on &lt;/strong&gt;SDG Indicator 6.4.2 - Level of water stress: https://elearning.fao.org/course/view.php?id=365 &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 6: Garantizar la disponibilidad y la gestión sostenible del agua y el saneamiento para todos&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 6.4: De aquí a 2030, aumentar considerablemente el uso eficiente de los recursos hídricos en todos los sectores y asegurar la sostenibilidad de la extracción y el abastecimiento de agua dulce para hacer frente a la escasez de agua y reducir considerablemente el número de personas que sufren falta de agua&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 6.4.2: Nivel de estrés hídrico: extracción de agua dulce en proporción a los recursos de agua dulce disponibles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Febrero de 2021 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicadores relacionados&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.4.1: Cambio en la eficiencia del uso del agua a lo largo del tiempo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.1.1: Proporción de la población que utiliza servicios de agua potable gestionados de forma segura&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.3.1: Proporción de aguas residuales tratadas de forma segura&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.6.1: Cambio en la extensión de los ecosistemas relacionados con el agua a lo largo del tiempo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.5.1: Grado de aplicación de la gestión integrada de los recursos hídricos (0-100)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.4.1: Proporción de la superficie agrícola dedicada a la agricultura productiva y sostenible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15.3.1: Proporción de tierras degradadas sobre la superficie total&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.5.1: Número de muertos, desaparecidos y afectados por desastres por cada 100.000 personas [a]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11.5.1: Número de muertos, desaparecidos y afectados por la catástrofe por cada 100.000 personas [a]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Información institucional&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organización(es):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organización de las Naciones Unidas para la Agricultura y la Alimentación (FAO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El nivel de estrés hídrico: la extracción de agua dulce como proporción de los recursos de agua dulce disponibles es la relación entre el total de agua dulce extraída por todos los sectores principales y el total de los recursos de agua dulce renovables, después de tener en cuenta los requisitos de flujo ambiental. Los principales sectores, según las normas de la CIIU, incluyen la agricultura, la silvicultura y la pesca, la industria manufacturera, la industria eléctrica y los servicios. Este indicador también se conoce como intensidad de extracción de agua.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Este indicador proporciona una estimación de la presión ejercida por todos los sectores sobre los recursos renovables de agua dulce del país. Un nivel bajo de estrés hídrico indica una situación en la que la extracción combinada de todos los sectores es marginal en relación con los recursos y, por lo tanto, tiene poco impacto potencial en la sostenibilidad de los recursos o en la posible competencia entre usuarios. Un nivel alto de estrés hídrico indica una situación en la que la extracción combinada de todos los sectores representa una parte sustancial del total de los recursos renovables de agua dulce, con un impacto potencialmente mayor en la sostenibilidad de los recursos y en posibles situaciones de conflicto y competencia entre usuarios. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los recursos totales de agua dulce renovable (RTAR ) se expresan como la suma de los recursos hídricos renovables internos y externos. Los términos &amp;#x201C;recursos hídricos&amp;#x201D; y &amp;#x201C;extracción de agua&amp;#x201D; se entienden aquí como recursos de agua dulce y extracción de agua dulce. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los recursos hídricos renovables internos se definen como el caudal medio anual a largo plazo de los ríos y la recarga de las aguas subterráneas de un país determinado, generados a partir de las precipitaciones endógenas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los recursos hídricos renovables externos se refieren a los flujos de agua que entran en el país, teniendo en cuenta la cantidad de flujos reservados a los países situados aguas arriba y aguas abajo mediante acuerdos o tratados. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La extracción total de agua dulce (ETAD) es el volumen de agua dulce que se extrae de su fuente (ríos, lagos, acuíferos) para la agricultura, las industrias y los servicios &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-1&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Se estima a nivel de país para los tres sectores principales siguientes: la agricultura, los servicios (incluida la extracción de agua doméstica) y las industrias (incluida la refrigeración de las centrales termoeléctricas). La extracción de agua dulce incluye las aguas subterráneas fósiles. No incluye el agua no convencional, es decir, el uso directo de aguas residuales tratadas, el uso directo de agua de drenaje agrícola y el agua desalinizada. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los requisitos de flujo ambiental (RFA) se definen como la cantidad y el momento de los flujos y niveles de agua dulce necesarios para mantener los ecosistemas acuáticos, que, a su vez, sustentan las culturas humanas, las economías, los medios de vida sostenibles y el bienestar. La calidad del agua y también los servicios ecosistémicos resultantes quedan excluidos de esta formulación, que se limita a los volúmenes de agua. Esto no implica que la calidad y el apoyo a las sociedades que dependen de los caudales ambientales no sean importantes y no deban cuidarse&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Los métodos de cálculo de los RFA son muy variables y van desde las estimaciones globales hasta las evaluaciones exhaustivas de los tramos fluviales. A efectos del indicador de los ODS, los volúmenes de agua pueden expresarse en las mismas unidades que la ETAD y, a continuación, como porcentajes de los recursos hídricos disponibles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; En AQUASTAT, la extracción de agua de servicio se informa como Extracción de agua municipal. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Sí se tienen en cuenta en otros objetivos e indicadores, como el 6.3.2, el 6.5.1 y el 6.6.1. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos para este indicador suelen ser recolectados por los ministerios e instituciones nacionales que tienen en su mandato cuestiones relacionadas con el agua, como las oficinas nacionales de estadística, los ministerios de recursos hídricos, de agricultura o de medio ambiente. Las contrapartes oficiales a nivel nacional son la oficina nacional de estadística y/o el ministerio competente en materia de recursos hídricos. Más concretamente, la FAO pide a los países que nombren a un corresponsal nacional que actúe como centro de coordinación para la recopilación y comunicación de datos. Los datos se publican principalmente en los anuarios estadísticos nacionales, en los planes maestros nacionales de recursos hídricos y de riego, y en otros informes (como los de proyectos, encuestas internacionales o resultados y publicaciones de centros de investigación nacionales e internacionales).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos del indicador se recogen mediante cuestionarios que deben responder las instituciones pertinentes de cada país. Se pueden encontrar ejemplos de los cuestionarios que se pueden utilizar en:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AQUASTAT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNSD/UNEP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/Questionnaires/q2013Water_English.xls&quot;&gt;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/Questionnaires/q2013Water_English.xls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OECD/Eurostat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/ramon/coded_files/OECD_ESTAT_JQ_Manual_version_2_21.pdf&quot;&gt;http://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/ramon/coded_files/OECD_ESTAT_JQ_Manual_version_2_21.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Proceso de recolección:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Las contrapartes oficiales a nivel nacional son el ministerio competente para los recursos hídricos y la oficina nacional de estadística. La FAO pide a los países que designe a un corresponsal nacional que actúe como centro de coordinación para la recopilación y comunicación de datos. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Se espera que los países pongan en marcha un proceso de control de calidad (CC), garantía de calidad (GC) y verificación de datos. El proceso debe llevarse a cabo internamente para la parte de control de calidad, asegurando que todos los pasos planificados se lleven a cabo correctamente en cada ronda de recopilación de datos. El control de calidad debe ser llevado a cabo por expertos independientes, ya sean nacionales o internacionales, para evaluar la consistencia y solidez de los datos producidos. Por último, siempre que sea posible, los datos resultantes deben verificarse en comparación con datos similares de otras fuentes. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Una vez reunidos los datos, será necesaria la armonización entre las posibles diferencias en las definiciones y agregaciones. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendario&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recolección de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anualmente&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publicación de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Está previsto que los datos del indicador se produzcan para la mayoría de los países con carácter anual desde 2018 y suelen publicarse en AQUASTAT cada año en enero.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oficinas nacionales de estadística a través de los corresponsales nacionales de AQUASTAT. Las instituciones responsables de la recolección de datos a nivel nacional varían según los países. Sin embargo, en general, los datos para este indicador los proporcionan el Ministerio de Agricultura, el Ministerio del Agua y el Ministerio de Medio Ambiente, así como otros ministerios competentes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organización de las Naciones Unidas para la Agricultura y la Alimentación (FAO) a través de AQUASTAT, su sistema mundial de información sobre el agua (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El objetivo de este indicador es mostrar el grado de explotación de los recursos hídricos para satisfacer la demanda de agua del país. Mide la presión que ejerce un país sobre sus recursos hídricos y, por tanto, el reto que supone la sostenibilidad de su uso del agua. Hace un seguimiento de los progresos realizados en relación con &amp;#x201C;las extracciones y el suministro de agua dulce para hacer frente a la escasez de agua&amp;#x201D;, es decir, el componente medioambiental de la meta 6.4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador muestra hasta qué punto se utilizan ya los recursos hídricos y señala la importancia de las políticas eficaces de gestión de la oferta y la demanda. Indica la probabilidad de que aumente la competencia y el conflicto entre los diferentes usos y usuarios del agua en una situación de creciente escasez de agua. Un mayor estrés hídrico, mostrado por un aumento del valor del indicador, tiene efectos potencialmente negativos sobre la sostenibilidad de los recursos naturales y sobre el desarrollo económico. Por otro lado, los valores bajos del indicador indican que el agua no representa un reto especial para el desarrollo económico y la sostenibilidad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sin embargo, los valores extremadamente bajos pueden indicar la incapacidad de un país para utilizar adecuadamente sus recursos hídricos en beneficio de la población. En estos casos, un aumento moderado y controlado del valor del indicador puede ser un signo de desarrollo positivo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La extracción de agua dulce como porcentaje de los recursos renovables de agua dulce es un buen indicador de la presión sobre los limitados recursos hídricos, uno de los recursos naturales más importantes. Sin embargo, sólo aborda parcialmente las cuestiones relacionadas con la gestión sostenible del agua. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Indicadores complementarios que captan las múltiples dimensiones de la gestión del agua combinarían datos sobre la gestión de la demanda de agua, los cambios de comportamiento con respecto al uso del agua y la disponibilidad de infraestructuras adecuadas, y medirían los avances en el aumento de la eficiencia y la sostenibilidad del uso del agua, en particular en relación con el crecimiento demográfico y económico. También reconocerían los diferentes entornos climáticos que afectan al uso del agua en los países, en particular en la agricultura, que es el principal usuario del agua. La evaluación de la sostenibilidad también está vinculada a los umbrales críticos fijados para este indicador. Aunque no existe un consenso universal sobre dichos umbrales, a continuación se presenta una propuesta. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Las tendencias en la extracción de agua dulce muestran patrones de cambio relativamente lentos. Por lo general, tres-cinco años son una frecuencia mínima para poder detectar cambios significativos, ya que es poco probable que el indicador muestre variaciones significativas de un año a otro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La estimación de la extracción de agua por sector puede representar una limitación para el cálculo del indicador. En realidad, pocos países publican regularmente datos sobre la extracción de agua por sector. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; No existe un método universalmente acordado para el cálculo de los flujos entrantes de agua dulce que se originan fuera de las fronteras de un país. Tampoco existe ningún método estándar para tener en cuenta los caudales de retorno, la parte del agua extraída de su fuente y que fluye de vuelta al sistema fluvial después de su uso. En los países donde el flujo de retorno representa una parte sustancial de la extracción de agua, el indicador tiende a subestimar el agua disponible y, por lo tanto, a sobrestimar el nivel de estrés hídrico. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Otras limitaciones que afectan la interpretación del indicador de estrés hídrico incluyen: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dificultad para obtener datos precisos, completos y actualizados; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;variación potencialmente grande de los datos subnacionales; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;falta de consideración de las variaciones estacionales de los recursos hídricos; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;falta de consideración de la distribución entre los usos del agua; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;falta de consideración de la calidad del agua y su idoneidad para el uso; y&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;el indicador puede ser superior al 100% cuando la extracción de agua no es renovable (aguas subterráneas fósiles), cuando la extracción anual de aguas subterráneas es superior a la reposición anual (sobreexplotación) o cuando la extracción de agua incluye parte o la totalidad del agua reservada para las necesidades hídricas medioambientales. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Algunas de estas cuestiones pueden resolverse mediante la desagregación del indicador a nivel de las unidades hidrológicas y la distinción entre los diferentes sectores de uso. Sin embargo, debido a la complejidad de los flujos de agua, tanto dentro de un país como entre países, se debe tener cuidado de no contar dos veces. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Método de cálculo: El indicador se calcula como el total de agua dulce extraída (ETAD) dividido por la diferencia entre el total de recursos de agua dulce renovables (RTAR) y los requerimientos de flujo ambiental (RFA), multiplicado por 100. Todas las variables se expresan en km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;/año (10&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;/año).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tensión (%) = ETAD / (RTAR - RFA) * 100&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tras la experiencia de los cinco primeros años de aplicación del indicador, y en consonancia con el enfoque adoptado durante el programa de los ODM, se ha identificado el umbral del 25% como límite superior para una seguridad total e incondicional del estrés hídrico evaluado por el indicador 6.4.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Esto significa, por un lado, que los valores por debajo del 25% pueden considerarse seguros en cualquier caso (sin estrés); por otro, que los valores por encima del 25% deben considerarse como potencialmente y cada vez más problemáticos, y deben ser matizados y/o reducidos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Por encima del 25% de estrés hídrico, se han identificado cuatro clases que señalan diferentes niveles de gravedad del estrés:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NO STRESS&amp;#xA0;&amp;lt;25%&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BAJO 25% - 50%&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MEDIO 50% - 75%&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ALTO 75-100%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CRITICO &amp;gt;100%&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Tratamiento de valores faltantes: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; A nivel de país: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Se realizan tres tipos de imputación a nivel de país para completar los años que faltan en la serie temporal: &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; Imputación lineal: entre dos puntos de datos disponibles &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; Transferencia hacia adelante: después de los últimos puntos de datos disponibles y hasta 10 años &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; Imputación vertical: en caso de que se disponga de la extracción total de agua dulce pero falte el desglose por fuentes, y si existe el desglose para los años anteriores, se aplica la proporción respectiva por fuentes al total disponible &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; A nivel regional y mundial: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Gracias a los métodos de imputación a nivel de país, se dispondrá de datos para toda la serie temporal (a menos que el último valor oficial se haya obtenido hace más de 10 años). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las estimaciones regionales y globales se harán sumando las cifras nacionales de recursos de agua dulce renovable y la extracción total de agua dulce, considerando sólo los recursos de agua renovable internos de cada país para evitar la doble contabilización, y los recursos de agua dulce renovable externos de la región en su conjunto, si los hubiera. En caso de agregación regional sin continuidad física (como las agrupaciones de ingresos o el grupo de países menos desarrollados, etc.), se suman los recursos hídricos renovables totales. El RFA a nivel regional se estima como la media de los RFA de los países, en porcentaje, y se aplica a los recursos hídricos regionales.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Métodos y directrices a disposición de los países para la compilación de los datos a nivel nacional:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Este indicador proporciona una estimación de la presión ejercida por todos los sectores sobre los recursos renovables de agua dulce del país. Un nivel bajo de estrés hídrico indica una situación en la que la extracción combinada de todos los sectores es marginal en relación con los recursos y, por lo tanto, tiene poco impacto potencial en la sostenibilidad de los recursos o en la posible competencia entre usuarios. Un nivel alto de estrés hídrico indica una situación en la que la extracción combinada de todos los sectores representa una parte sustancial del total de los recursos renovables de agua dulce, con impactos potencialmente mayores sobre la sostenibilidad de los recursos y posibles situaciones de conflicto y competencia entre usuarios.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;El indicador se calcula a partir de tres componentes:&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recursos totales de agua dulce renovable (RTAR)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extracción total de agua dulce (ETAD)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Requerimientos de flujo ambiental (RFA)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Estrés hídrico (%) = ETAD/(RTAR &amp;#x2013; RFA) *100&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Existen varios documentos que pueden servir de apoyo a los países para el cálculo de este indicador. Entre ellos:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comprensión de AQUASTAT - Sistema mundial de información sobre el agua de la FAO&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Esta nota informativa abarca una historia de veinte años de recopilación y análisis de datos relacionados con el agua y su difusión como un bien público internacional, de libre acceso para todos. El proceso de recolección y comprobación de los datos ha dado lugar a la creación de una red única de colaboradores que proporcionan datos, utilizan datos de otros países con fines comparativos e intercambian opiniones y experiencias sobre la mejor manera de medir y contabilizar el uso relacionado con el agua. Los usuarios van desde empresas privadas internacionales hasta organizaciones no gubernamentales, y prácticamente todos los informes importantes relacionados con el agua dependen de los datos proporcionados por AQUASTAT.&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc817e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc817e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incorporación de los caudales ambientales en el indicador de &amp;#x201C;estrés hídrico&amp;#x201D; 6.4.2 - Directrices para un método estándar mínimo para la elaboración de informes globales.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estas directrices pretenden ayudar a los países a participar en la evaluación del ODS 6.4.2 sobre el estrés hídrico aportando datos e información sobre los flujos ambientales (FA). Proporcionan un método estándar mínimo, basado principalmente en el Sistema Mundial de Información sobre Caudales Ambientales (GEFIS), al que se puede acceder a través de &lt;a href=&quot;http://eflows.iwmi.org&quot;&gt;http://eflows.iwmi.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unwater.org/app/uploads/2019/01/SDG6_EF_LOW2.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.unwater.org/app/uploads/2019/01/SDG6_EF_LOW2.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Evaluación de los recursos hídricos renovables - Revisión de la metodología AQUASTAT 2015&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc818e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc818e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Base de datos global sobre producción, recolección, tratamiento, vertido y uso directo de aguas residuales municipales en la agricultura&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Este documento describe los fundamentos y el método para configurar y alimentar la base de datos AQUASTAT sobre producción, recolección, tratamiento, vertido o uso directo de aguas residuales municipales en la agricultura. Se han revisado las mejores fuentes de información disponibles, entre las que se incluyen artículos revisados por expertos, actas de talleres, conferencias y reuniones de expertos, bases de datos mundiales o regionales, así como informes de países, informes nacionales y comunicaciones directas de funcionarios gubernamentales y expertos de los países&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc823e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc823e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Agua de refrigeración para la generación de energía y su impacto en las estadísticas del agua a nivel nacional&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Esta nota técnica, que describe el tema del agua de refrigeración para la generación de energía y su impacto en las estadísticas del agua a nivel nacional, tiene dos propósitos: 1) servir de recurso informativo general y 2) impulsar a los organismos gubernamentales responsables del uso del agua a recopilar y comunicar información desglosada por subsectores (manteniendo las extracciones termoeléctricas separadas de las industriales e hidroeléctricas), y determinar el punto en el que los diseños de extracción de agua más bajos son más favorables, aunque el coste de capital requerido sea mayor.&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc822e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc822e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Modelización de las extracciones de agua municipales e industriales para los años 2000 y 2005 mediante métodos estadísticos&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Este documento describe los esfuerzos para generar modelos que estimen las extracciones de agua municipales e industriales para los años 2000 y 2005 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc821e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc821e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Desambiguación de las estadísticas del agua&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;La nomenclatura que rodea a la información sobre el agua es a menudo confusa y da lugar a diferentes interpretaciones y, por tanto, a la confusión. Cuando se habla de la forma en que se utilizan los recursos hídricos renovables, a menudo se utilizan los términos uso, aprovechamiento, retiro, consumo, captación, extracción, utilización, oferta y demanda del agua sin indicar claramente lo que se quiere decir. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc816e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc816e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cuestionario FAO-AQUASTAT sobre el agua y la agricultura&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;Estas directrices y cuestionarios anuales se han elaborado específicamente para recoger las variables del agua relacionadas con el ODS 6.4. y, por tanto, para actualizar las variables principales de la base de datos AQUASTAT. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Recomendaciones Internacionales para las Estadísticas del Agua&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Las Recomendaciones Internacionales para las Estadísticas del Agua (IRWS) se desarrollaron para ayudar a fortalecer los sistemas nacionales de información sobre el agua en apoyo del diseño y la evaluación de las políticas de Gestión Integrada de los Recursos Hídricos (GIRH).&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/UNSD/envaccounting/irws/&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/UNSD/envaccounting/irws/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cuestionario del PNUD/PNUMA sobre estadísticas medioambientales &amp;#x2013; Sección del Agua&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/questionnaire.htm&quot;&gt;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/questionnaire.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/qindicators.htm&quot;&gt;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/qindicators.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Depuración de las Naciones Unidas &amp;#x2018;Base de datos de los principales agregados de las cuentas nacionales&amp;#x2019;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/snaama/selbasicFast.asp&quot;&gt;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/snaama/selbasicFast.asp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Garantía de calidad:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todos los datos de AQUASTAT pasan por un proceso de validación exhaustivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antes de cargarlos, los datos se comparan con otras variables para asegurarse de que son lógicamente correctos (en otras palabras: 1+2=3) y de que la referencia utilizada no conduce al propio AQUASTAT. En otras palabras, AQUASTAT encuentra con frecuencia datos de 2014, que en realidad son datos de AQUASTAT del año 2000 con el año cambiado (muy probablemente cuando se recogieron los datos).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Además, durante el proceso de validación, cada nueva observación se compara con otros datos ya disponibles para esta variable en otros años o en el mismo año. Si es imposible armonizar o reconciliar los diferentes datos, entonces uno u otro punto de datos tiene que ser eliminado de la base de datos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Durante la carga en la base de datos principal, tiene lugar otro proceso de validación, utilizando un conjunto de unas 300 reglas de validación. De ellas, unas 100 reglas son obligatorias, lo que significa que si el punto de datos no obedece a esta regla, el proceso de validación no puede continuar. Por ejemplo, la superficie cultivada de un país no puede ser mayor que la superficie total del país. El otro conjunto de unas 200 reglas de validación son señales de advertencia para la persona que realiza la validación. Por ejemplo, en general, la superficie equipada para el riego con tecnología de riego superficial es al menos la mitad de la superficie total equipada para el riego. Sin embargo, en algunos países la superficie de riego localizado o de riego por aspersión puede ser mayor que la superficie de riego superficial. Si este es el caso, aparece una advertencia durante la validación para que el analista compruebe si para este país es posible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Más allá de la validación habitual de AQUASTAT descrita anteriormente, en la compilación del indicador se alentará y apoyará a los países a que establezcan su propio sistema de control de calidad, garantizando que todos los datos utilizados en el cálculo se comprueben, y que se mantenga la coherencia a lo largo de los años para garantizar la comparabilidad y la identificación sólida de las tendencias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador requiere datos de diferentes sectores de experiencia. A nivel internacional, se dispone de diferentes conjuntos de datos de varias instituciones, como la FAO, la UNSD y el IWMI. Cada una de estas instituciones tiene su propio mecanismo establecido para consultar y validar los datos con los países.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En el caso de los datos procedentes de FAOSTAT y AQUASTAT, los datos se recogen en los países a través de encuestas que consisten en la recolección de datos y la descripción del país mediante un cuestionario detallado en el que se asocia la referencia de la fuente y los comentarios a cada valor, a través de personas de referencia nacionales designadas oficialmente. El análisis crítico de la información y el procesamiento de los datos lo realiza el personal de la FAO. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sin embargo, para el proceso de los ODS se pondrá en marcha un mecanismo específico, que consiste en la identificación en cada país, por parte del gobierno nacional, de un punto focal nacional y un equipo técnico, encargado de la recopilación y el cálculo del indicador, en estrecha consulta con la FAO. Este sistema ha sido probado con éxito durante la fase inicial del proyecto GEMI, llevado a cabo por la FAO y otras siete agencias de la ONU, coordinadas por ONU-Agua.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En el caso de los países que inicialmente podrían tener dificultades para compilar y calcular el indicador, la FAO proporcionará apoyo y, en última instancia, podrá producir el indicador a partir de los datos disponibles a nivel internacional. Sin embargo, no se hará público ningún dato sin la aprobación previa de las autoridades nacionales competentes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Países (2010 hasta la actualidad):&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asia y Pacífico 23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;África 18&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;América Latina y el Caribe 17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europa, América del Norte, Australia, Nueva Zelanda y Japón 41&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Países (2000-2009):&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asia y Pacífico 42&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;África 49&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;América Latina y el Caribe 27&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europa, América del Norte, Australia, Nueva Zelanda y Japón 47&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1961-2017 (discontinua, según el país) Los datos se interpolan para crear líneas temporales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aunque el indicador se basa en los volúmenes totales de agua, se necesitan datos sectoriales para poder desglosarlo con el fin de mostrar la contribución respectiva de los diferentes sectores al estrés hídrico del país y, por tanto, la importancia relativa de las acciones necesarias para contener la demanda de agua en los diferentes sectores (agricultura, servicios e industria). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; A nivel nacional, los recursos hídricos y las extracciones se estiman o miden a nivel de unidades hidrológicas apropiadas (cuencas fluviales, acuíferos). Por lo tanto, es posible obtener una distribución geográfica del estrés hídrico por unidad hidrológica, lo que permite una respuesta más específica en términos de gestión de la demanda de agua.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Fuentes de discrepancia:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las diferencias pueden deberse, entre otras cosas, a lo siguiente: Para las estimaciones nacionales, el agua dulce entrante se cuenta como parte de los recursos de agua dulce disponibles del país, mientras que las estimaciones globales sólo pueden hacerse sumando los recursos hídricos renovables internos (agua generada dentro del país) de todos los países para evitar la doble contabilización. Además, los recursos externos de agua dulce se computan según los tratados, si los hay, lo que puede dar lugar a valores diferentes con respecto a los recursos reales de agua dulce evaluados mediante la hidrología.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Referencias:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organización de las Naciones Unidas para la Agricultura y la Alimentación (FAO). AQUASTAT, Sistema mundial de información sobre el agua de la FAO. Roma. Sitio web &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En estos sitios están disponibles los siguientes recursos de interés específico para este indicador: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glosario de AQUASTAT (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/databases/glossary/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/databases/glossary/&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Base de datos de los principales países de AQUASTAT (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/nr/water/aquastat/data/query/index.html?lang=en&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/nr/water/aquastat/data/query/index.html?lang=en&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AQUASTAT Uso del agua (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology/water-use/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology/water-use/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AQUASTAT Recursos hídricos (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology/water-resources/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology/water-resources/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publicaciones de AQUASTAT sobre conceptos, metodologías, definiciones, terminologías, metadatos, etc. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/resources/publications/reports/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/resources/publications/reports/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IWMI Evaluación de los flujos ambientales globales &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eflows.iwmi.org/&quot;&gt;http://eflows.iwmi.org/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IWMI Información sobre flujos ambientales globales para los Objetivos de Desarrollo Sostenible &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iwmi.cgiar.org/Publications/IWMI_Research_Reports/PDF/pub168/rr168.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.iwmi.cgiar.org/Publications/IWMI_Research_Reports/PDF/pub168/rr168.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cuestionario de estadísticas medioambientales de la UNSD/PNUMA Sección del agua (&lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/qindicators.htm&quot;&gt;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/qindicators.htm&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marco para el desarrollo de estadísticas medioambientales (FDES 2013) (Capítulo 3) &lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/FDES/FDES-2015-supporting-tools/FDES.pdf&quot;&gt;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/FDES/FDES-2015-supporting-tools/FDES.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cuestionario de la OCDE/Eurostat sobre estadísticas medioambientales Sección del agua&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 6 : Garantir l&apos;accès de tous à des services d&apos;alimentation en eau et d&apos;assainissement gérés de façon durable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 6.4: D’ici à 2030, faire en sorte que les ressources en eau soient utilisées beaucoup plus efficacement dans tous les secteurs et garantir la viabilité des prélèvements et de l’approvisionnement en eau douce afin de remédier à la pénurie d’eau et de réduire nettement le nombre de personnes qui manquent d’eau&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 6.4.2: Niveau de stress hydrique : prélèvements d’eau douce en proportion des ressources en eau douce disponibles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2021-07-01&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicateurs connexes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.4.1 : Variation de l&apos;efficacité de l&apos;utilisation des ressources en eau&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.1.1 : Proportion de la population utilisant des services d&apos;alimentation en eau potable gérés en toute sécurité&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.3.1 : Proportion des eaux usées traitées sans danger&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.6.1 : Variation de l&apos;étendue des écosystèmes tributaires de l&apos;eau&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.5.1 : Degré de mise en œuvre de la gestion intégrée des ressources en eau (0-100)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.4.1 : Proportion des zones agricoles exploitées de manière productive et durable&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15.3.1 : Surface des terres dégradées, en proportion de la surface terrestre&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11.5.1 : Nombre de personnes décédées, disparues ou directement touchées lors de catastrophes, pour 100 000 personnes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organisation des Nations Unies pour l&apos;alimentation et l&apos;agriculture (FAO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organisation des Nations Unies pour l&apos;alimentation et l&apos;agriculture (FAO)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Définition : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Niveau de stress hydrique : le prélèvement d&apos;eau douce en proportion des ressources en eau douce disponibles est le rapport entre le total de l&apos;eau douce prélevée par tous les grands secteurs et le total des ressources renouvelables en eau douce, après avoir tenu compte des besoins environnementaux en eau. Les principaux secteurs, tels que définis par les normes de la Classification internationale type des industries (CITI), comprennent l&apos;agriculture, la sylviculture et la pêche, l&apos;industrie manufacturière, l&apos;industrie de l&apos;électricité et les services. Cet indicateur est également connu sous le nom d&apos;intensité des retraits d&apos;eau. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur fournit une estimation de la pression exercée par tous les secteurs sur les ressources renouvelables en eau douce d&apos;un pays. Un faible niveau de stress hydrique indique une situation où le prélèvement combiné de tous les secteurs est marginal par rapport aux ressources, et a donc peu d&apos;impact potentiel sur la durabilité des ressources ou sur la concurrence potentielle entre les utilisateurs. Un niveau élevé de stress hydrique indique une situation dans laquelle le prélèvement combiné de tous les secteurs représente une part substantielle de l&apos;ensemble des ressources renouvelables en eau douce, et a un impact potentiellement plus important sur la durabilité des ressources et sur des situations potentielles de conflits et de concurrence entre les utilisateurs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le total des ressources en eau douce renouvelables représente la somme des ressources en eau renouvelables internes et externes. Les termes ressources en eau et prélèvements d&apos;eau sont entendus ici comme ressources en eau douce et prélèvements d&apos;eau douce. &lt;/p&gt;
Les ressources en eau renouvelables internes sont définies comme le débit annuel moyen à long terme des rivières et la recharge des eaux souterraines pour un pays donné, générés par les précipitations endogènes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les ressources en eau renouvelables externes font référence aux débits d&apos;eau entrant dans le pays, en prenant en considération la quantité de débits réservés aux pays en amont et en aval selon les accords ou les traités.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le prélèvement total d&apos;eau douce est le volume d&apos;eau douce extrait de sa source (rivières, lacs, aquifères) pour l&apos;agriculture, les industries et les municipalités. Il est estimé au niveau national pour les trois principaux secteurs suivants : l&apos;agriculture, les municipalités (y compris le prélèvement d&apos;eau domestique) et les industries. Les prélèvements d&apos;eau douce comprennent l&apos;eau douce primaire (non prélevée auparavant), l&apos;eau douce secondaire (précédemment prélevée et retournée dans les rivières et les eaux souterraines, comme les eaux usées rejetées et les eaux de drainage agricole) et les nappes fossiles. Ils n&apos;incluent pas l&apos;eau non conventionnelle, c&apos;est-à-dire l&apos;utilisation directe des eaux usées traitées, l&apos;utilisation directe des eaux de drainage agricole et l&apos;eau dessalée. Le prélèvement total d&apos;eau douce est en général calculé comme étant la somme du prélèvement total d&apos;eau par secteur moins l&apos;utilisation directe des eaux usées, l&apos;utilisation directe des eaux de drainage agricole et l&apos;utilisation d&apos;eau dessalée. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les besoins environnementaux en eau correspondent aux quantités d&apos;eau nécessaires pour maintenir les écosystèmes d&apos;eau douce et estuariens. La qualité d&apos;eau et les services écosystémiques qui en résultent sont exclus de cette formulation, qui se limite aux volumes d&apos;eau. Cela ne signifie toutefois pas que la qualité et le soutien aux sociétés qui dépendent des débits environnementaux ne sont pas importants et ne doivent pas être pris en compte. Les méthodes de calcul des besoins environnementaux en eau sont extrêmement variables et vont des estimations mondiales aux évaluations complètes des tronçons de rivière. Pour les besoins de l&apos;indicateur des ODD, les volumes d&apos;eau peuvent être exprimés dans les mêmes unités que le prélèvement total d&apos;eau douce, puis en pourcentage des ressources en eau disponibles. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Sources de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données pour cet indicateur sont généralement collectées par les ministères et institutions nationales dont le mandat comprend des questions liées à l&apos;eau, comme les ministères des ressources en eau, de l&apos;agriculture ou de l&apos;environnement. Plus précisément, la FAO demande aux pays de nommer un correspondant national qui servira de point focal pour la collecte et la communication des données. Les données sont principalement publiées dans les annuaires statistiques nationaux, les plans directeurs nationaux sur les ressources en eau et l&apos;irrigation, et d&apos;autres rapports (tels que ceux des projets, des enquêtes internationales ou des résultats et publications des centres de recherche nationaux et internationaux).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données pour cet indicateur sont collectées par le biais de questionnaires auxquels doivent répondre les institutions concernées dans chaque pays. Des exemples de questionnaires pouvant être utilisés se trouvent aux adresses suivantes :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AQUASTAT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/nr/water/aquastat/sets/aq-5yr-quest_fra.xls&quot;&gt;www.fao.org/nr/water/aquastat/sets/aq-5yr-quest_fra.xls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DSNU/UNEP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/Questionnaires/q2013Water_French.xls&quot;&gt;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/Questionnaires/q2013Water_French.xls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OCDE/Eurostat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/ramon/coded_files/OECD_ESTAT_JQ_Manual_version_2_21.pdf&quot;&gt;http://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/ramon/coded_files/OECD_ESTAT_JQ_Manual_version_2_21.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Processus de collecte :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les homologues officiels au niveau national sont le ministère de tutelle des ressources en eau et le bureau national des statistiques.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les pays sont censés mettre en place un processus de contrôle de la qualité (CQ), d&apos;assurance de la qualité (AQ) et de vérification des données. Le processus doit être mené à l&apos;interne pour la partie CQ, en s&apos;assurant que toutes les étapes prévues sont correctement exécutées à chaque cycle de collecte de données. L&apos;AQ devrait être effectuée par des experts indépendants, nationaux ou internationaux, afin d&apos;évaluer la cohérence et la robustesse des données produites. Enfin, dans la mesure du possible, les données résultantes doivent être vérifiées par comparaison avec des données similaires provenant d&apos;autres sources.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Comme les données seront collectées au moyen de différents questionnaires, il faudra harmoniser les éventuelles différences de définitions et d&apos;agrégations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendrier&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Collecte de données :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annuellement&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publication des données :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il est prévu que les données de l&apos;indicateur soient produites pour la plupart des pays sur une base annuelle depuis 2018 et sont généralement publiées dans AQUASTAT chaque année en janvier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fournisseurs de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description :&lt;/h2&gt;
Les bureaux nationaux de statistiques par l&apos;intermédiaire des correspondants nationaux d&apos;AQUASTAT. Les institutions responsables de la collecte des données au niveau national varient selon les pays. Cependant, en général, les données pour cet indicateur sont fournies par le Ministère de l&apos;Agriculture, le Ministère de l&apos;Eau et le Ministère de l&apos;Environnement, et d&apos;autres ministères de tutelle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compilateur de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organisation des Nations unies pour l&apos;alimentation et l&apos;agriculture (FAO) par le biais d&apos;AQUASTAT, son système mondial d&apos;information sur l&apos;eau (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/fr/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/fr/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justification :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;objectif de cet indicateur est de montrer dans quelle mesure les ressources en eau sont exploitées afin de répondre à la demande en eau d&apos;un pays. Il mesure la pression exercée par un pays sur ses ressources en eau et, par conséquent, le défi que représente la durabilité de son utilisation de l&apos;eau. Il suit les progrès réalisés en ce qui concerne &amp;#x201C;les prélèvements et l&apos;approvisionnement en eau douce afin de remédier à la pénurie d&apos;eau&amp;#x201D;, c&apos;est-à-dire la composante environnementale de l&apos;objectif 6.4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur montre dans quelle mesure les ressources en eau sont déjà utilisées, et signale l&apos;importance de politiques efficaces de gestion de l&apos;offre et de la demande. Il indique la probabilité d&apos;une concurrence et d&apos;un conflit croissants entre les différents usages et utilisateurs de l&apos;eau dans une situation de pénurie d&apos;eau croissante. Un stress hydrique accru illustré par une augmentation de la valeur de l&apos;indicateur, a des effets potentiellement négatifs sur la durabilité des ressources naturelles et sur le développement économique. D&apos;autre part, un faible stress hydrique indique que l&apos;eau ne représente pas un défi particulier pour le développement économique et la durabilité d&apos;un pays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cependant, des valeurs extrêmement basses peuvent indiquer l&apos;incapacité d&apos;un pays à utiliser correctement ses ressources en eau au profit de la population. Dans ce cas, une augmentation modérée et contrôlée de la valeur de l&apos;indicateur peut être un signe de développement positif.&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires et limites : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le prélèvement d&apos;eau en pourcentage des ressources renouvelables en eau est un bon indicateur de la pression exercée sur des ressources en eau limitées, l&apos;une des ressources naturelles les plus importantes. Cependant, le tout ne répond que partiellement aux enjeux liés à la gestion durable de l&apos;eau. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des indicateurs supplémentaires qui englobent les multiples dimensions de la gestion de l&apos;eau combineraient des données sur la gestion de la demande en eau, les changements de comportement en matière d&apos;utilisation de l&apos;eau et la disponibilité d&apos;infrastructures appropriées, et mesureraient les progrès réalisés dans l&apos;amélioration de l&apos;efficacité et de la durabilité de l&apos;utilisation de l&apos;eau, notamment en fonction de la croissance démographique et économique. Ils permettraient également de reconnaître les différents environnements climatiques qui affectent l&apos;utilisation de l&apos;eau dans chaque pays, et en particulier dans le secteur de l&apos;agriculture, le principal utilisateur d&apos;eau. L&apos;évaluation de la durabilité est également liée aux seuils critiques fixés pour cet indicateur, mais il n&apos;existe pas de consensus universel à ce chapitre. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les tendances en matière de prélèvement d&apos;eau montrent des changements relativement lents. Habituellement, une période de trois à cinq ans est la fréquence minimale pour pouvoir détecter des changements significatifs, car il est peu probable que l&apos;indicateur montre des variations significatives d&apos;une année à l&apos;autre. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;estimation des prélèvements d&apos;eau par secteur est la principale limite au calcul de l&apos;indicateur. En effet, peu de pays publient régulièrement des données sur l&apos;utilisation de l&apos;eau par secteur. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les ressources en eau renouvelables comprennent toutes les ressources en eau de surface et en eau souterraine qui sont disponibles sur une base annuelle, sans tenir compte de la capacité à récolter et à utiliser cette ressource. Les ressources en eau exploitables, qui désignent le volume d&apos;eau de surface ou d&apos;eau souterraine disponible 90 % du temps, sont considérablement inférieures aux ressources en eau renouvelables, mais il n&apos;existe aucune méthode universelle pour évaluer les ressources en eau exploitables. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il n&apos;existe pas de méthode universellement reconnue pour le calcul des débits d&apos;eau douce entrants provenant de l&apos;extérieur des frontières d&apos;un pays. Il n&apos;existe pas non plus de méthode standard pour comptabiliser les débits de retour, c&apos;est-à-dire la partie de l&apos;eau prélevée à la source qui retourne au système fluvial après utilisation. Dans les pays où le débit de retour représente une partie substantielle du prélèvement d&apos;eau, l&apos;indicateur tend à sous-estimer l&apos;eau disponible et donc à surestimer le niveau de stress hydrique. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parmi les autres limitations qui affectent l&apos;interprétation de cet indicateur, on retrouve : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;difficulté d&apos;obtenir des données exactes, complètes et à jour ; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;variation potentiellement importante des données infranationales ; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;manque de considération des variations saisonnières des ressources en eau
; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;manque de considération de la répartition entre les utilisations de l&apos;eau
; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;manque de considération de la qualité de l&apos;eau et de son adéquation à l&apos;utilisation
; et &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;l&apos;indicateur peut être supérieur à 100 % lorsque le prélèvement d&apos;eau comprend
de l&apos;eau douce secondaire (eau prélevée précédemment et retournée au système), de l&apos;eau non renouvelable (nappes fossiles), lorsque le prélèvement annuel d&apos;eaux souterraines est supérieur à la réalimentation annuelle (surexploitation) ou lorsque le prélèvement d&apos;eau comprend une partie ou la totalité de l&apos;eau mise en réserve pour les besoins environnementaux en eau. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certains de ces problèmes peuvent être résolus par la désagrégation  de l&apos;indice au niveau des unités hydrologiques et en distinguant les différents secteurs d&apos;utilisation. Cependant, en raison de la complexité des débits d&apos;eau, tant à l&apos;intérieur d&apos;un pays qu&apos;entre les pays, il faut veiller à ne pas faire de double comptage. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Méthodologie &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Méthode de calcul : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Méthode de calcul : L&apos;indicateur est calculé comme le total de l&apos;eau douce prélevée (TFWW) divisé par la différence entre le total des ressources renouvelables en eau douce (TRWR) et les besoins en débit environnemental (EFR), multiplié par 100. Toutes les variables sont exprimées en km&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;/an (10&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; m&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;/an).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stress (%) = TFWW / (TRWR - EFR) * 100&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suite à l&apos;expérience des cinq premières années d&apos;application de l&apos;indicateur, et conformément à l&apos;approche adoptée au cours du programme des OMD, le seuil de 25% a été identifié comme la limite supérieure pour une sécurité totale et inconditionnelle du stress hydrique tel qu&apos;évalué par l&apos;indicateur 6.4.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cela signifie d&apos;une part que les valeurs inférieures à 25% peuvent être considérées comme sûres dans tous les cas (pas de stress) ; d&apos;autre part, que les valeurs supérieures à 25% doivent être considérées comme potentiellement et de plus en plus problématiques, et doivent être nuancées et/ou réduites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Au-dessus de 25% de stress hydrique, quatre classes ont été identifiées pour signaler différents niveaux de sévérité du stress :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NO STRESS&amp;#xA0;&amp;lt;25%&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FAIBLE 25% - 50%&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MOYENNE 50% - 75%&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ÉLEVÉE 75-100%&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CRITICAL &amp;gt;100%&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Traitement des valeurs manquantes: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Au niveau national :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trois types d&apos;imputation sont effectués au niveau du pays pour combler les années manquantes dans les séries chronologiques : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Imputation linéaire : entre deux points de données disponibles&lt;/li&gt;.
      &lt;li&gt;Report : après les derniers points de données disponibles et jusqu&apos;à 10 ans.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Imputation verticale : en cas de prélèvement total d&apos;eau douce disponible mais de désagrégation par source manquante, et si la désagrégation existante existait pour les années précédentes, le ratio respectif par source est appliqué au total disponible.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Aux niveaux régional et mondial :&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grâce aux méthodes d&apos;imputation au niveau national, les données seront disponibles pour l&apos;ensemble de la série chronologique (sauf si la dernière valeur officielle a été obtenue il y a plus de 10 ans).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agrégats régionaux :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les estimations régionales et mondiales seront effectuées en additionnant les chiffres nationaux sur les ressources en eau douce renouvelables et le prélèvement total d&apos;eau douce, en considérant uniquement les ressources en eau renouvelables internes de chaque pays afin d&apos;éviter un double comptage, et les ressources en eau douce renouvelables externes de la région dans son ensemble, le cas échéant. En cas d&apos;agrégation régionale sans continuité physique (comme les groupes de revenus ou le groupe des pays les moins avancés, etc.), les ressources en eau renouvelables totales sont additionnées. L&apos;EFR au niveau régional est estimé comme la moyenne des EFR des pays en pourcentage, et appliqué aux ressources en eau régionales.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Méthodes et instructions à la disposition des pays pour la compilation des données au niveau national :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur fournit une estimation de la pression exercée par tous les secteurs sur les ressources renouvelables en eau douce du pays. Un faible niveau de stress hydrique indique une situation où le prélèvement combiné de tous les secteurs est marginal par rapport aux ressources, et a donc peu d&apos;impact potentiel sur la durabilité des ressources ou sur la concurrence potentielle entre les utilisateurs. Un niveau élevé de stress hydrique indique une situation où le prélèvement combiné de tous les secteurs représente une part substantielle des ressources renouvelables totales en eau douce, avec des impacts potentiellement plus importants sur la durabilité des ressources et des situations potentielles de conflits et de concurrence entre les utilisateurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur est calculé sur la base de trois composantes :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total des ressources en eau douce renouvelables (TRWR)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total des prélèvements d&apos;eau douce (TRWR)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Besoins en débit environnemental (EFR)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stress hydrique (%) = TFWW/(TRWR &amp;#x2013 ; EFR) *100&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Il existe plusieurs documents qui peuvent être utilisés pour aider les pays dans le calcul de cet indicateur. Parmi eux :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comprendre AQUASTAT - le système mondial d&apos;information sur l&apos;eau de la FAO&amp;apos;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Cette note d&apos;information couvre une histoire de vingt ans de collecte et d&apos;analyse de données relatives à l&apos;eau et de leur diffusion en tant que bien public international, librement accessible à tous. Le processus de collecte et de vérification des données a abouti à la création d&apos;un réseau unique de collaborateurs qui fournissent des données, utilisent des données d&apos;autres pays à des fins de comparaison et échangent des points de vue et des expériences sur la meilleure façon de mesurer et de comptabiliser l&apos;utilisation de l&apos;eau. Les utilisateurs vont des entreprises privées internationales aux organisations non gouvernementales, et pratiquement tous les rapports importants liés à l&apos;eau dépendent des données fournies par AQUASTAT.&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc817e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc817e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intégration des flux environnementaux dans l&apos;indicateur de &amp;#x201C;stress hydrique&amp;#x201D ; 6.4.2 - Lignes directrices pour une méthode standard minimale pour les rapports mondiaux.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;Ces lignes directrices visent à aider les pays à participer à l&apos;évaluation de l&apos;ODD 6.4.2 sur le stress hydrique en fournissant des données et des informations sur les flux environnementaux (FE). Elles fournissent une méthode standard minimale, principalement basée sur le système d&apos;information mondial sur les flux environnementaux (GEFIS), accessible via &lt;a href=&quot;http://eflows.iwmi.org&quot;&gt;http://eflows.iwmi.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unwater.org/app/uploads/2019/01/SDG6_EF_LOW2.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.unwater.org/app/uploads/2019/01/SDG6_EF_LOW2.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Évaluation des ressources en eau renouvelables - revue méthodologique AQUASTAT 2015&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc818e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc818e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Base de données mondiale sur la production, la collecte, le traitement, le rejet et l&apos;utilisation directe en agriculture des eaux usées municipales&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Ce document décrit le raisonnement et la méthode pour mettre en place et alimenter la base de données AQUASTAT sur la production, la collecte, le traitement, le rejet ou l&apos;utilisation directe en agriculture des eaux usées municipales. Les meilleures sources d&apos;information disponibles ont été examinées, notamment les articles évalués par des pairs, les comptes rendus d&apos;ateliers, de conférences et de réunions d&apos;experts, les bases de données mondiales ou régionales, ainsi que les notes d&apos;information sur les pays, les rapports nationaux et les communications directes des responsables gouvernementaux et des experts des pays&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc823e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc823e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;L&apos;eau de refroidissement pour la production d&apos;énergie et son impact sur les statistiques sur l&apos;eau au niveau national&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Cette note technique, qui décrit la question de l&apos;eau de refroidissement pour la production d&apos;énergie et son impact sur les statistiques sur l&apos;eau au niveau national, a deux objectifs : 1) servir de ressource informative générale et 2) encourager les agences gouvernementales responsables de l&apos;utilisation de l&apos;eau à recueillir et à communiquer des informations désagrégées par sous-secteur (en maintenant les prélèvements thermoélectriques séparés des prélèvements industriels et hydroélectriques), et à déterminer le point à partir duquel des conceptions de prélèvement d&apos;eau plus faibles sont plus favorables, même si le coût d&apos;investissement requis est plus élevé.&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc822e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc822e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Modélisation des prélèvements d&apos;eau municipaux et industriels pour les années 2000 et 2005 à l&apos;aide de méthodes statistiques&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Ce document décrit les efforts déployés pour générer des modèles qui estiment les prélèvements d&apos;eau municipaux et industriels pour les années 2000 et 2005.&amp;#xA0;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc821e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc821e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Désambiguïsation des statistiques sur l&apos;eau&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;La nomenclature entourant les informations sur l&apos;eau est souvent confuse et donne lieu à différentes interprétations et donc à de la confusion. Lorsqu&apos;il s&apos;agit de discuter de la manière dont les ressources en eau renouvelables sont utilisées, les termes d&apos;utilisation de l&apos;eau, d&apos;usage, de prélèvement, de consommation, d&apos;abstraction, d&apos;extraction, d&apos;utilisation, d&apos;offre et de demande sont souvent utilisés sans que la signification soit clairement indiquée.&amp;#xA0;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc816e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc816e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Questionnaire de la FAO-AQUASTAT sur l&apos;eau et l&apos;agriculture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;Ces directives et questionnaires annuels ont été préparés spécifiquement pour recueillir les variables relatives à l&apos;eau liées à l&apos;ODD 6.4, et donc pour mettre à jour les variables de base dans la base de données AQUASTAT.&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Recommandations internationales pour les statistiques de l&apos;eau&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Les recommandations internationales pour les statistiques de l&apos;eau (IRWS) ont été élaborées pour aider à renforcer les systèmes d&apos;information nationaux sur l&apos;eau à l&apos;appui de la conception et de l&apos;évaluation des politiques de gestion intégrée des ressources en eau (GIRE).&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/UNSD/envaccounting/irws/&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/UNSD/envaccounting/irws/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Questionnaire de l&apos;UNSD/PNUE sur les statistiques de l&apos;environnement &amp;#x2013 ; Section eau&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/questionnaire.htm&quot;&gt;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/questionnaire.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/qindicators.htm&quot;&gt;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/qindicators.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;UNSD &amp;#x2018;Base de données des principaux agrégats des comptes nationaux&amp;#x2019;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/snaama/selbasicFast.asp&quot;&gt;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/snaama/selbasicFast.asp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;.&lt;h2&gt;Assurance de la qualité :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Toutes les données d’AQUASTAT passent par un processus de validation approfondi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avant le téléchargement, les données sont comparées à d’autres variables pour s’assurer qu’elles sont logiquement correctes (en d’autres termes : 1 + 2 = 3) et que la référence utilisée ne conduit pas à AQUASTAT elle-même. En d’autres termes, AQUASTAT trouve fréquemment des données pour 2014, qui sont en fait des données AQUASTAT pour 2000 avec l’année changée (très probablement par l&apos;année lorsque les données ont été extraites d’AQUASTAT).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Au cours du téléchargement dans la base de données principale, un autre processus de validation a lieu, utilisant un ensemble d’environ 300 règles de validation. De ce nombre, environ 100 règles sont des règles obligatoires, ce qui signifie que si l&apos;observation n’obéit pas à cette règle, le processus de validation ne peut pas continuer. Par exemple, la superficie cultivée d’un pays ne peut pas être plus grande que la superficie totale du pays. L’autre ensemble d’environ 200 règles de validation sont des signes avant-coureurs pour la personne qui effectue la validation. Par exemple, en général, la zone équipée pour l’irrigation à l’aide de la technologie d’irrigation de surface est d’au moins la moitié de la superficie totale équipée pour l’irrigation. Cependant, dans certains pays, la zone d’irrigation localisée ou la zone d’irrigation par gicleurs peut être plus grande que la zone d’irrigation de surface. Si c’est le cas, alors un avertissement apparaît pendant la validation pour que l’analyste vérifie si pour ce pays, cela est possible. Également, pendant le processus de validation chaque nouvelle observation est comparée à d’autres données déjà disponibles pour cette variable (de d’autres années ou de la même année). S’il est impossible d’harmoniser ou de concilier les différentes données, l’une ou l’autre des observations doit être supprimée de la base de données. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/nr/water/aquastat/sets/WhyDBisEmpty_eng.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/nr/water/aquastat/sets/WhyDBisEmpty_eng.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/nr/water/aquastat/About_us/index3.stm&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/nr/water/aquastat/About_us/index3.stm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En plus de la validation habituelle décrite ci-dessus, chaque pays est encouragé et soutenu dans la mise en place de son propre système de contrôle de la qualité, afin que toutes les données utilisées dans le calcul soient vérifiées, et que la cohérence soit maintenue au fil des ans pour assurer la comparabilité et l’identification robuste de tendances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L’indicateur nécessite des données provenant de différents secteurs d’expertise. À l’échelle internationale, elles sont disponibles dans différents ensembles de données provenant de diverses institutions, telles que la FAO, la DSNU et l’Institut international de gestion de l&apos;eau. Chacune de ces institutions dispose de son propre mécanisme de consultation et de validation des données avec les pays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données provenant de FAOSTAT et AQUASTAT sont recueillies dans les pays par le biais d’enquêtes détaillées, qui contiennent des commentaires associés à chaque valeur, et sont transmises par l’intermédiaire de personnes-ressources. Une analyse critique de l’information et du traitement des données est effectuée par la FAO. Les données sont ensuite organisées dans des tableaux de données standard, et la rétroaction et l’approbation sont demandées aux institutions nationales avant la publication et la diffusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toutefois, pour le processus des ODD, un mécanisme spécifique a été mis en place. Ce dernier consiste en l’identification dans chaque pays, par le gouvernement national, d’un point focal national et d’une équipe technique en charge de la collecte et du calcul de l’indicateur, le tout en étroite consultation avec la FAO. Ce système a été testé avec succès au cours de la phase initiale du projet GEMI, réalisé par la FAO et sept autres agences des Nations unies, et coordonné par ONU-Eau.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour les pays qui pourraient initialement avoir des difficultés à compiler et à calculer l’indicateur, la FAO apportera son soutien et, ultimement, sera en mesure de produire l’indicateur à partir de données disponibles à l’échelle internationale. Toutefois, aucune donnée ne sera rendue publique sans l’approbation au préalable des autorités nationales compétentes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilité des données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pays (2010 à aujourd&apos;hui) :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asie et Pacifique 23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afrique 18&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amérique latine et Caraïbes 17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe, Amérique du Nord, Australie, Nouvelle-Zélande et Japon 41&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pays (2000-2009) :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asie et Pacifique 42&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afrique 49&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amérique latine et Caraïbes 27&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe, Amérique du Nord, Australie, Nouvelle-Zélande et Japon 47&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Séries chronologiques :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1961-2017 (Discontinue, selon le pays)Les données sont interpolées pour créer des chronologies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Désagrégation :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour calculer cet indicateur, des données sectorielles sont nécessaires. L&amp;#8217indicateur peut être désagrégé pour montrer la contribution respective des différents secteurs au stress hydrique du pays, et donc l&amp;#8217importance relative des actions nécessaires pour contenir la demande en eau dans les différents secteurs (agriculture, municipalités et industrie). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bien que l&apos;indicateur soit basé sur les volumes d&apos;eau totaux, des données sectorielles sont nécessaires pour pouvoir le désagréger afin de montrer la contribution respective des différents secteurs au stress hydrique du pays, et donc l&apos;importance relative des actions nécessaires pour contenir la demande en eau dans les différents secteurs (agriculture, services et industrie).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Au niveau national, les ressources en eau et les prélèvements sont estimés ou mesurés au niveau d&apos;unités hydrologiques appropriées (bassins versants, aquifères). Il est donc possible d&apos;obtenir une répartition géographique du stress hydrique par unité hydrologique, permettant ainsi une réponse plus ciblée en termes de gestion de la demande en eau.&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sources de divergences  :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des écarts pourraient se produire en raison, entre autres, des éléments suivants : pour les estimations nationales, l’eau entrante fait partie des ressources en eau disponibles dans le pays, tandis que les estimations mondiales ne peuvent être faites qu’en additionnant les ressources internes en eau renouvelable (eau produite dans le pays) de tous les pays afin d’éviter le double comptage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Références &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; URL : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/fr/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/fr/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Références : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Organisation des Nations unies pour l&apos;alimentation et l&apos;agriculture (FAO). AQUASTAT, le Système mondial d&apos;information sur l&apos;eau de la FAO. Rome. Site Web &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/fr/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/fr/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les ressources suivantes présentent un intérêt particulier pour cet indicateur : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Glossaire AQUASTAT &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/nr/water/aquastat/data/glossary/search.html?lang=fr&quot;&gt; http://www.fao.org/nr/water/aquastat/data/glossary/search.html?lang=fr&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Base de données nationales d&apos;AQUASTAT &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/nr/water/aquastat/data/query/index.html?lang=fr&quot;&gt; http://www.fao.org/nr/water/aquastat/data/query/index.html?lang=fr&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Utilisation de l&apos;eau d&apos;AQUASTAT &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/fr/overview/methodology/water-use&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/fr/overview/methodology/water-use&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Ressources en eau d&apos;AQUASTAT &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/fr/overview/methodology/water-use&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/fr/overview/methodology/water-use&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Publications AQUASTAT traitant des concepts, méthodologies, définitions, terminologies, métadonnées, etc. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/fr/&quot;&gt; http://www.fao.org/aquastat/fr/&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Pour les eaux de surface, les bases de données sur les besoins environnementaux en eau comprennent : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://waterdata.iwmi.org/apps/flow_management_classes/&quot;&gt; http://waterdata.iwmi.org/apps/flow_management_classes/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iwmi.cgiar.org/resources/models-and-software/environmental-flow-calculators/&quot;&gt; http://www.iwmi.cgiar.org/resources/models-and-software/environmental-flow-calculators/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://waterdata.iwmi.org/Applications/Global_Assessment_Environmental_Water_Requirements_Scarcity/&quot;&gt; http://waterdata.iwmi.org/Applications/Global_Assessment_Environmental_Water_Requirements_Scarcity/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Questionnaire DSNU / PNUE sur les statistiques de l&apos;environnement &amp;#x2013; Section de l&apos;eau (&lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/qindicators.htm&quot;&gt; http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/qindicators.htm &lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Cadre pour le développement des statistiques de l&apos;environnement (FDES 2013) (Chapitre 3) &lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/FDES/FDES-2015-supporting-tools/FDES.pdf&quot;&gt; http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/FDES/FDES-2015-supporting-tools/FDES.pdf &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Questionnaire OCDE / Eurostat sur les statistiques de l&apos;environnement &amp;#x2013; Section de l&apos;eau &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Recommandations internationales pour les statistiques de l&apos;eau (IRWS) (&lt;a href=&quot;2012)%20http:/unstats.un.org/unsd/envaccounting/irws/&quot;&gt; 2012) http://unstats.un.org/unsd/envaccounting/irws/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 6: Обеспечение наличия и рационального использования водных ресурсов и санитарии для всех&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 6.4: К 2030 году существенно повысить эффективность водопользования во всех секторах и обеспечить устойчивый забор и подачу пресной воды для решения проблемы нехватки воды и значительного сокращения числа людей, страдающих от нехватки воды&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 6.4.2: Уровень нагрузки на водные ресурсы: забор пресной воды в процентном отношении к имеющимся запасам пресной воды&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Последнее обновление: 5 августа 2020 года&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Связанные показатели &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.4.1: Динамика изменения эффективности водопользования&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.1.1: Доля населения, пользующегося услугами водоснабжения, организованного с соблюдением требований безопасности&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.3.1: Доля безопасно очищаемых сточных вод &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.6.1: Динамика изменения площади связанных с водой экосистем&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.5.1: Степень внедрения комплексного управления водными ресурсами (от 0 до 100)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.4.1: Доля площади сельскохозяйственных угодий, на которых применяются продуктивные и неистощительные методы ведения сельского хозяйства&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15.3.1: Площадь деградировавших земель в процентном отношении к общей площади суши&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.5.1: Число погибших, пропавших без вести и пострадавших непосредственно в результате бедствий на 100 000 человек [a] &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11.5.1: Число погибших, пропавших без вести и пострадавших непосредственно в результате бедствий на 100 000 человек [a]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Институциональная информация &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Организация (и): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Продовольственная и сельскохозяйственная организация Объединенных Наций (ФАО) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Уровень нагрузки на водные ресурсы: забор пресной воды, выраженный в виде доли доступных ресурсов пресной воды - это соотношение между общим объемом пресной воды, забранным всеми основными секторами, и общими возобновляемыми ресурсами пресной воды с учетом требований экологического стока. Основные секторы, определенные стандартами МСОК, включают сельское хозяйство, лесоводство и рыболовство; обрабатывающую промышленность; снабжение электроэнергией, газом, паром и кондиционированным воздухом; и услуги. Этот показатель также известен как интенсивность водозабора.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Этот показатель дает оценку воздействия всех секторов на возобновляемые ресурсы пресной воды в стране. Низкий уровень нагрузки на водные ресурсы указывает на ситуацию, когда совокупный забор всеми секторами является незначительным по отношению к ресурсам и, следовательно, оказывает незначительное потенциальное влияние на устойчивость ресурсов или на потенциальную конкуренцию между пользователями. Высокий уровень нагрузки на водные ресурсы указывает на ситуацию, когда совокупный водозабор всеми секторами представляет собой значительную долю от общего объема возобновляемых ресурсов пресной воды, что может оказать более значительное воздействие на устойчивость ресурсов и на создание потенциальных ситуаций, приводящих к конфликтам и конкуренции между пользователями.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Общие возобновляемые ресурсы пресной воды (ОВРПВ) выражаются как сумма внутренних и внешних возобновляемых ресурсов пресной воды. Термины &quot;ресурсы воды&quot; и &quot;водозабор&quot; понимаются здесь как ресурсы и забор пресной воды. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Внутренние возобновляемые водные ресурсы определяются как долгосрочный среднегодовой сток рек и пополнение для данной страны грунтовых вод эндогенного (глубинного) отложения. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Внешние возобновляемые водные ресурсы означают стоки воды, поступающие в страну, с учетом количества стоков, зарезервированных для стран, расположенных в верховьях и низовьях рек, на основании соглашений или договоров.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Общий забор пресной воды (ОЗПВ) - это объем пресной воды, извлеченной из ее источника (реки, озера, водоносные горизонты) для сельского хозяйства, промышленности и сферы услуг. &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href= &quot;#footnote-1&quot;id=&quot;footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;[1] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; Он оценивается на страновом уровне для следующих трех основных секторов: сельское хозяйство, услуги (включая водозабор для бытовых нужд) и промышленность (включая охлаждение ТЭЦ). Забор пресной воды включает ископаемые подземные воды. Он не включает нетрадиционные источники воды, т.е. прямое использование очищенных сточных вод, прямое использование сельскохозяйственных дренажных вод и опресненной воды. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Оптимальный экологический дебит (ОЭД) определяются как количество и время поступления пресной воды и уровни, необходимые для поддержания аквариальных экосистем, которые, в свою очередь, поддерживают человеческую культуру, экономику, устойчивые средства к существованию и благополучие. Качество воды, а также связанные с этим экосистемные услуги исключаются из этой формулировки, которая связана с объемами воды. Это не означает, что качество и поддержка обществ, зависящих от экологических потоков, не важны и о них не следует заботиться. &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot;id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt; [2] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; Методы расчета ОЭД чрезвычайно разнообразны и варьируются от глобальных оценок до всеобъемлющих оценок для участков рек. Для показателя ЦУР объемы воды могут быть выражены в тех же единицах, что и ОВРПВ, а также в долях от доступных водных ресурсов. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot;id=&quot;footnote-1&quot;&gt; 1 &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p&gt; В AQUASTAT забор воды для сектора услуг отражается как забор воды для муниципальных нужд. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot;id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt; 2 &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p&gt; Они несомненно учитываются в других целях и показателях, таких как 6.3.2, 6.5.1 и 6.6.1.&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt; &amp;#x2191; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Данные для этого показателя обычно собираются национальными министерствами и учреждениями, в компетенции которых входят вопросы, связанные с водными ресурсами, такими как национальные статистические управления, министерства водных ресурсов, сельского хозяйства или окружающей среды. Официальными партнерами на страновом уровне являются национальное статистическое управление и / или отраслевое министерство водных ресурсов. В частности, ФАО просит страны назначить национального корреспондента, который будет выполнять функции координатора сбора и передачи данных. Данные в основном публикуются в национальных статистических ежегодниках, национальных генеральных планах по водным ресурсам и ирригации и других отчетах (например, по проектам, международным исследованиям или результатам и публикациям национальных и международных исследовательских центров). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные для показателя собираются с помощью вопросников, на которые отвечают соответствующие учреждения в каждой стране. Примеры вопросников, которые могут быть использованы, можно найти по адресам: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; AQUASTAT &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/nr/water/aquastat/sets/aq-5yr-quest_eng.xls&quot;&gt;www.fao.org/nr/water/aquastat/sets/aq-5yr-quest_eng.xls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Статистический отдел ООН/Программа ООН по окружающей среде&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/Questionnaires/q2013Water_English.xls&quot;&gt; http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/Questionnaires/q2013Water_English.xls &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ОЭСР/Евростат &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/ramon/coded_files/OECD_ESTAT_JQ_Manual_version_2_21.pdf&quot;&gt; http://ec.europa.eu/eurostat/ramon/coded_files/OECD_ESTAT_JQ_Manual_version_2_21.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Официальными партнерами на страновом уровне являются отраслевое министерство
водных ресурсов и национальное статистическое управление. ФАО просит страны назначить национального корреспондента, который будет выполнять функции координатора сбора и передачи данных. &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Ожидается, что страны введут в действие процесс контроля качества (КК),
обеспечения качества (ОК) и проверки данных. Для компонента контроля качества процесс должен выполняться внутри компании, гарантируя, что все запланированные шаги должным образом выполняются на каждом этапе сбора данных. Компонент обеспечения качества должен проводиться независимыми экспертами, национальными или международными, для оценки согласованности и надежности сформированных данных. Наконец, полученные данные, по возможности, следует проверять путем сравнения с аналогичными данными из других источников. &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; После сбора данных потребуется согласование возможных различий в определениях
и агрегированных данных.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Календарь &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Сбор данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ежегодно&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Выпуск данных:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Планируется, что данные по показателю на ежегодной основе будут выпускаться по большинству стран с 2018 года и по обыкновению публиковаться в AQUASTAT ежегодно в январе. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Поставщики данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Национальные статистические управления через национальных корреспондентов AQUASTAT. Учреждения, ответственные за сбор данных на национальном уровне, различаются в зависимости от страны. Однако в целом данные по этому показателю предоставляются Министерством сельского хозяйства, Министерством водных ресурсов и Министерством окружающей среды, а также другими отраслевыми министерствами.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Составители данных&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Продовольственная и сельскохозяйственная организация Объединенных Наций (ФАО) с использованием AQUASTAT, ее глобальной информационной системы по водным ресурсам (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/&quot;&gt; http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Цель этого показателя - отразить, в какой мере используются водные ресурсы для удовлетворения потребностей страны в воде. Показатель оценивает страновую нагрузку на водные ресурсы и, следовательно, проблему устойчивости системы водопользования. Показатель отслеживает прогресс в отношении &quot;забора и поставки пресной воды для решения проблемы нехватки воды&quot;, то есть экологического компонента задачи 6.4. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Показатель отражает, в какой степени водные ресурсы уже используются, и свидетельствует о важности эффективной политики управления спросом и предложением. Он указывает на вероятность усиления конкуренции и конфликтов между различными водопользователями и пользователями в ситуации растущего дефицита воды. Повышенная нагрузка на водные ресурсы, о которой свидетельствует увеличение значения показателя, потенциально отрицательно сказывается на устойчивости природных ресурсов и на экономическом развитии. С другой стороны, низкие значения показателя указывают на то, что водные ресурсы не представляют особой проблемы для экономического развития и устойчивости. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Однако чрезвычайно низкие значения могут указывать на неспособность страны правильно использовать свои водные ресурсы на благо населения. В таких случаях умеренное и контролируемое увеличение значения показателя может быть признаком положительного развития.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Забор пресной воды, выраженный в долях от возобновляемых ресурсов пресной воды, является хорошим показателем нагрузки на ограниченные водные ресурсы, являющихся одними из наиболее важных природных ресурсов. Однако он лишь частично решает вопросы, связанные с устойчивым управлением водными ресурсами. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Дополнительные показатели, охватывающие множество аспектов управления водными ресурсами, будут объединять данные об управлении спросом на воду, изменениях поведения в отношении водопользования и наличия соответствующей инфраструктуры, а также отражать прогресс в повышении эффективности и устойчивости водопользования, в частности в отношении населения и экономического роста. Они также будут выявлять различные климатические условия, которые влияют на водопользование в странах, в частности в сельском хозяйстве, которое является основным пользователем воды. Оценка устойчивости также связана с критическими порогами, установленными для этого показателя. Хотя универсального консенсуса по таким пороговым значениям нет, но предложение изложено ниже. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Тенденции забора пресной воды показывают относительно медленные изменения. Обычно период от трех до пяти лет - это минимальная периодичность, чтобы можно было обнаружить существенные изменения, поскольку маловероятно, что показатель будет демонстрировать значимые колебания от года к году.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Оценка забора воды по секторам может ограничивать расчет показателя. Немногие страны фактически публикуют данные по водозабору по секторам на регулярной основе. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Не существует универсально согласованного метода расчета входящих потоков пресной воды, возникающих за пределами границ страны. Также не существует стандартного метода учета возвратных стоков, части воды, забираемой из источника и возвращаемой в речную систему после использования. В странах, где возвратный сток составляет значительную часть забора воды, показатель имеет тенденцию занижать доступные водные ресурсы и, следовательно, переоценивать уровень нагрузки на водные ресурсы. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; К другим ограничениям, влияющим на интерпретацию показателя нагрузки на водные ресурсы, относятся:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; сложность получения точных, полных и актуальных данных; &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; потенциально большой разброс субнациональных данных; &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; отсутствие учета сезонных колебаний водных ресурсов; &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; недостаточное внимание к распределению воды между водопользователями; &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; отсутствие внимания к качеству воды и ее пригодности для использования;
и &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; показатель может быть выше 100 процентов, когда происходит водозабор невозобновляемой
воды (ископаемые подземные воды), когда годовой забор подземных вод превышает годовое пополнение (чрезмерный отбор) или когда водозабор включает часть или весь набор водных ресурсов, не беря в расчёт оптимальный экологический дебит воды. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Некоторые из этих проблем можно решить путем дезагрегирования показателя на уровне гидрологических единиц и проведения различия между различными секторами использования. Однако из-за сложности водных потоков, как внутри страны, так и между странами, следует проявлять осторожность, чтобы избежать двойного учета.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Метод расчета: показатель рассчитывается как общий объем забора пресной воды (ООЗПВ), поделенный на разницу между общими возобновляемыми ресурсами пресной воды (ОВРПВ) и оптимальными экологическими дебитами (ОЭД), умноженный на 100. Все переменные выражаются в куб. км / год (10 &lt;sup&gt; 9 &lt;/sup&gt; м &lt;sup&gt; 3 &lt;/sup&gt; / год). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Нагрузка (%) = ООЗПВ/ (ОВРПВ - ОЭД) * 100 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Исходя из опыта первых пяти лет применения показателя и в соответствии с подходом, принятым в рамках программы ЦРТ, порог в 25% был определен как верхний предел для полной и безоговорочной безопасности нагрузки на водные ресурсы, как оценивается показателем 6.4.2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Это означает, что, с одной стороны, значения ниже 25% можно считать безопасными в любом случае (отсутствие нагрузки); с другой стороны, значения выше 25% следует рассматривать как потенциально проблематичные и становящиеся все более проблематичными, и их следует уточнять и / или снижать. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для уровней нагрузки на водные ресурсы выше 25% были определены четыре класса, которые сигнализируют о различных уровнях серьезности нагрузки: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ОТСУТСТВИЕ НАГРУЗКИ &lt;25% &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; НИЗКИЙ УРОВЕНЬ 25% - 50% &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; СРЕДНИЙ УРОВЕНЬ 50% - 75% &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ВЫСОКИЙ УРОВЕНЬ 75 - 100% &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; КРИТИЧЕСКИЙ УРОВЕНЬ &gt;100% &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; На страновом уровне используются три типа условного исчисления для заполнения отсутствующих данных по годам во временных рядах: &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; Линейное вменение: между двумя доступными элементами данных &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; Перенос на будущий период: после последних имеющихся данных и до периода в 10 лет &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; Вертикальное вменение: в случае имеющихся данных по общему забору пресной воды, но без разбивки по источникам, и если существующая разбивка имеется за предыдущие годы, то соответствующий коэффициент по источникам применяется к имеющемуся общему забору пресной воды. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Благодаря методам вменения на страновом уровне данные будут доступны для всех временных рядов (если только последнее официальное значение не было получено более 10 лет назад). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Региональные агрегаты: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Региональные и глобальные оценки будут производиться путем суммирования национальных показателей по возобновляемым ресурсам пресной воды и общему объему забора пресной воды с учетом только внутренних возобновляемых водных ресурсов каждой страны во избежание двойного учета, а также внешних возобновляемых ресурсов пресной воды региона в целом, если таковые имеются. В случае регионального агрегирования без физической непрерывности (например, группировки по доходам или группа наименее развитых стран и т. д.), общие возобновляемые водные ресурсы суммируются. Оптимальный экологический дебит (ОЭД) на региональном уровне оценивается как среднее по странам значение ОЭД, выраженное в процентах, и применяется к региональным водным ресурсам.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Доступные странам методы и руководства для составления данных на национальном уровне: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Этот показатель дает оценку нагрузки всех секторов на возобновляемые ресурсы пресной воды страны. Низкий уровень нагрузки на водные ресурсы указывает на ситуацию, когда комбинированный водозабор всеми секторами является несущественным по отношению к ресурсам и, следовательно, имеет небольшое потенциальное влияние на устойчивость водных ресурсов или на потенциальную конкуренцию между пользователями. Высокий уровень нагрузки на водные ресурсы указывает на ситуацию, когда комбинированный забор всеми секторами представляет собой значительную долю от общих возобновляемых ресурсов пресной воды, что оказывает потенциально большее влияние на устойчивость ресурсов и создает ситуации, при которых возможны конфликты и конкуренция между пользователями. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель рассчитывается на основе трех компонентов: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Общие возобновляемые ресурсы пресной воды (ОВРПВ) &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Общий объем забора пресной воды (ООЗПВ) &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Оптимальный экологический дебит (ОЭД) &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt; Нагрузки на водные ресурсы (%) = ООЗПВ/ (ОВРПВ - ОЭД) * 100 &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Существует несколько документов, которые можно использовать для помощи странам при расчете этого показателя. Среди них: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&lt;em&gt; Понимание AQUASTAT - глобальной системы информации о водных ресурсах ФАО &lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Эта информационная заметка охватывает двадцатилетнюю историю сбора и анализа данных, связанных с водными ресурсами, и их распространения в качестве международного общественного блага в свободном доступе для всех. Процесс сбора и проверки данных привел к созданию уникальной сети сотрудников, которые предоставляют данные, используют данные из других стран для сравнительных целей и обмениваются мнениями и опытом о том, как лучше всего определять и учитывать использование по вопросам, относящимся к водным ресурсам. Пользователи варьируются от международных частных компаний до неправительственных организаций, и практически все важные отчеты, касающиеся водных ресурсов, зависят от данных, предоставленных AQUASTAT. &lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a- bc817e.pdf &quot;&gt; http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc817e.pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Включение экологических стоков в &quot;нагрузку на водные ресурсы&quot; показателя 6.4.2 - Рекомендации по минимальному стандартному методу глобальной отчетности. &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Это руководство призвано помочь странам принять участие в оценке показателя ЦУР 6.4.2, касающейся нагрузки на водные ресурсы, путем предоставления данных и информации по экологическим стокам (ЭС). В нем предлагается минимальный стандартный метод, основанный на Глобальной системы информации об экологических стоках (ГСИЭС), доступ к которому можно получить через &lt;a href=&quot;http://eflows.iwmi.org&quot;&gt; http://eflows.iwmi.org &lt;/а&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unwater.org/app/uploads/2019/01/SDG6_EF_LOW2.pdf&quot;&gt; https://www.unwater.org/app/uploads/2019/01/SDG6_EF_LOW2 .pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Оценка возобновляемых водных ресурсов - обзор методологии AQUASTAT, 2015 год &lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc818e. pdf &quot;&gt; http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc818e.pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Глобальная база данных по производству, сбору, очистке, сбросу и прямому использованию муниципальных сточных вод в сельском хозяйстве &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; В этом документе описываются обоснование и метод создания и использования базы данных AQUASTAT по производству, сбору, обработке, сбросу или прямому использованию городских сточных вод в сельском хозяйстве. Были проанализированы наилучшие доступные источники информации, в том числе рецензируемые статьи, протоколы семинаров, конференций и совещаний экспертов, глобальные или региональные базы данных, а также краткие справки по странам, национальные отчеты и прямые контакты с государственными должностными лицами и экспертами стран. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc823e.pdf&quot;&gt; http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc823e.pdf &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&lt;em&gt; Охлаждающая вода, используемая для производства энергии, и ее влияние на национальную статистику водных ресурсов &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Эта техническая записка, описывающая проблему охлаждающей воды, используемой при производстве энергии, и ее влияние на национальную статистику водных ресурсов, преследует две цели: 1) действовать в качестве общего информационного ресурса и 2) побуждать правительственные учреждения, ответственные за водопользование, собирать и представлять информацию с разбивкой по подсекторам (отделение заборов водопотребления для нужд теплоэлектроэнергетики от водозаборов для промышленных целей и гидроэлектростанций), а также для определения точки, в которой проекты с меньшим водозабором более предпочтительны, даже если требуемые капитальные затраты выше. &lt;br&gt; &lt;a href = &quot;http://www.fao.org/3 /a-bc822e.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc822e.pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&lt;em&gt; Моделирование водозабора муниципальных и промышленных предприятий на 2000 и 2005 годы с использованием статистических методов &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; В этом документе описываются усилия по созданию моделей, которые оценивают водозабор муниципальных и промышленных предприятий на 2000 и 2005 годы.&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc821e.pdf&quot;&gt; http: //www.fao .org /3/a-bc821e.pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&lt;em&gt; Устранение неоднозначности определений статистики водных ресурсов &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Номенклатура, относящаяся к информации о водных ресурсах, часто вносит путаницу и приводит к различным толкованиям и, следовательно, к недоразумениям. При обсуждении способа использования возобновляемых водных ресурсов часто используются термины «водопользование, использование, водозабор, потребление, забор, извлечение, использование, предложение и спрос» без четкого указания того, что имеется в виду.&lt;a href= &quot;http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc816e.pdf&quot;&gt; http://www.fao.org/3/a-bc816e.pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Вопросник ФАО-AQUASTAT по водным ресурсам и сельскому хозяйству &lt;/strong&gt;Эти ежегодные Руководящие принципы и вопросники были подготовлены специально для сбора данных по ЦУР 6.4. связанных с водными переменными, и, следовательно, для обновления основных переменных в базе данных AQUASTAT. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology/&quot;&gt; http://www.fao .org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Международные рекомендации по статистике водных ресурсов &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Международные рекомендации по статистике водных ресурсов (МРСВР) были разработаны, чтобы помочь укрепить национальные информационные системы по водным ресурсам в поддержку проектирования и оценки политики интегрированного управления водными ресурсами (ИУВР). &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/UNSD/envaccounting/irws/&quot;&gt; https://unstats.un.org/UNSD/envaccounting/irws/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Вопросник СОООН / ЮНЕП по статистике окружающей среды &amp; # 203; Водный сектор &lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/questionnaire.htm&quot;&gt; http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/questionnaire.htm &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/qindicators.htm&quot;&gt; http://unstats.un.org /unsd/environment/qindicators.htm &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; &amp;#x2018; База данных СОООН по основным агрегатам национальных счетов &amp;#x2019; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href = &quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/snaama/selbasicFast.asp &quot;&gt; http://unstats.un.org/unsd/snaama/selbasicFast.asp &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Гарантия качества:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Все данные в AQUASTAT проходят тщательный процесс валидации.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Перед загрузкой данные сравниваются с другими переменными, чтобы убедиться, что они логически верны (другими словами: 1 + 2 = 3) и не ведет ли используемая ссылка к самому AQUASTAT. Другими словами, AQUASTAT часто находит данные за 2014 год, которые на самом деле являются данными AQUASTAT за 2000 год с измененным годом (скорее всего, когда данные были собраны). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Также в процессе валидации каждая новая единица данных сравнивается с другими данными, уже имеющимися для этой переменной в другие годы или в том же году. Если невозможно согласовать или увязать разные данные, то какой-либо элемент данных необходимо удалить из базы данных. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Во время загрузки в основную базу данных выполняется еще один процесс валидации с использованием набора из примерно 300 правил валидации. Из них около 100 правил являются обязательными, что означает, что, если конкретный элемент данных не подчиняется этому правилу, процесс валидации не может продолжаться. Например, посевная площадь страны не может превышать общую площадь страны. Другой набор из примерно 200 правил валидации - это предупреждающие знаки для человека, выполняющего валидацию. Например, в целом площадь, оборудованная для орошения с использованием технологии поверхностного орошения, составляет не менее половины общей площади, оборудованной для орошения. Однако в некоторых странах площадь локального орошения или площадь орошения дождеванием может быть больше площади поверхностного орошения. Если это так, то во время валидации появляется предупреждение, чтобы аналитик мог проверить, возможно ли это для данной страны.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Помимо обычной валидации AQUASTAT, описанной выше, при составлении показателей страны будут призывать и оказывать им поддержку в создании их собственной системы контроля качества, гарантирующей, что все данные, используемые в расчетах, будут проверены, и что согласованность сохраняется в течение многих лет, чтобы гарантировать сопоставимость и надежное выявление тенденций. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для показателя необходимы данные из разных областей знаний. На международном уровне они доступны из различных наборов данных от различных организаций, таких как ФАО, СОООН и Международного института управления водными ресурсами (ИВМИ). У каждого из этих институтов есть собственный установленный механизм для консультаций и валидации данных со странами. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные, полученные из FAOSTAT и AQUASTAT, собираются в странах посредством обследований, состоящих из сбора данных и странового описания с помощью подробных вопросников, где ссылка на источник и комментарии связаны с каждым значением, а сбор информации осуществляется через официально назначенных национальных консультантов. Критический анализ информации и обработка данных проводится сотрудниками ФАО. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Однако для процесса достижения ЦУР будет введен в действие конкретный механизм, состоящий в назначении в каждой стране национальным правительством национального координатора и технической группы, отвечающей за сбор и расчет показателя, в тесной консультации с ФАО. Эта система была успешно протестирована на начальном этапе проекта GEMI (Глобальная инициатива по управлению окружающей средой), осуществляемого ФАО и другими семью агентствами ООН при координации со стороны Механизма «ООН – Водные ресурсы». &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Тем странам, которые первоначально могут столкнуться с трудностями при составлении и расчете показателя, ФАО окажет поддержку и в конечном итоге сможет разработать показатель, исходя из данных, доступных на международном уровне. Однако никакие данные не будут публиковаться без получения предварительного разрешения соответствующих национальных органов.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Страны (с 2010 года по настоящее время): &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Азиатско-Тихоокеанский регион 23 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Африка 18 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Латинская Америка и Карибский бассейн 17 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Европа, Северная Америка, Австралия, Новая Зеландия и Япония 41 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Страны (2000–2009 годы): &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Азиатско-Тихоокеанский регион 42 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Африка 49 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Латинская Америка и Карибский бассейн 27 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Европа, Северная Америка, Австралия, Новая Зеландия и Япония 47 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные за1961–2017 годы (прерванные ряды, в зависимости от страны) интерполируются для создания временных рамок. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Хотя показатель основан на общем объеме водных ресурсов, необходимы отраслевые данные для его дезагрегирования с тем, чтобы показать соответствующий вклад различных секторов в нагрузку на водные ресурсы страны, и, следовательно, относительную важность действий, необходимых для сдерживания потребности в воде в различных секторах (сельское хозяйство, сфера услуг и промышленность). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; На национальном уровне водные ресурсы и водозаборы оцениваются или измеряются на уровне соответствующих гидрологических единиц (бассейны рек, водоносные горизонты). Таким образом, можно получить географическое распределение нагрузки на водные ресурсы по гидрологическим единицам, что позволит более целенаправленно осуществлять регулирование спроса на водные ресурсы. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Различия могут возникать, в частности, из-за следующего: для национальных оценок поступающая пресная вода считается частью имеющихся пресноводных ресурсов страны, в то время как глобальные оценки могут быть выполнены только путем суммирования внутренних возобновляемых водных ресурсов (водных ресурсов, образовавшихся в стране) всех стран во избежание двойного счета. Более того, внешние ресурсы пресной воды рассчитываются в соответствии с договорами, если таковые имеются, что может привести к различным значениям по сравнению с фактическими ресурсами пресной воды, оцененными с помощью гидрологических исследований. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;www.fao.org/nr/aquastat&quot;&gt; www.fao.org/nr/aquastat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Ссылки: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Продовольственная и сельскохозяйственная организация Объединенных Наций (ФАО). AQUASTAT, Глобальная информационная система ФАО по водным ресурсам. Рим. Веб-сайт &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;На этих сайтах доступны следующие ресурсы, представляющие особый интерес для этого показателя: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Глоссарий AQUASTAT (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/databases/glossary/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/databases/glossary/&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AQUASTAT Основная база данных по странам (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/nr/water/aquastat/data/query/index.html?lang=en&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/nr/water/aquastat/data/query/index.html?lang=en&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AQUASTAT Использование воды (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology/water-use/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology/water-use/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AQUASTAT Водные ресурсы (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology/water-resources/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/overview/methodology/water-resources/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AQUASTAT Публикации, касающиеся концепций, методологий, определений, терминологии, метаданных и т. д. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/resources/publications/reports/&quot;&gt;http://www.fao.org/aquastat/en/resources/publications/reports/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ИВМИ: Оценка глобальных экологических стоков &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eflows.iwmi.org/&quot;&gt;http://eflows.iwmi.org/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Международный институт управления водными ресурсами (ИВМИ) - Информация о глобальных экологических стоках для достижения целей в области устойчивого развития&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iwmi.cgiar.org/Publications/IWMI_Research_Reports/PDF/pub168/rr168.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.iwmi.cgiar.org/Publications/IWMI_Research_Reports/PDF/pub168/rr168.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Вопросник СОООН / ЮНЕП по статистике окружающей среды: Раздел о водных ресурсах (&lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/qindicators.htm&quot;&gt;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/qindicators.htm&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Базовые принципы развития статистики окружающей среды (ПРСОС 2013) (Глава 3) &lt;a href=&quot;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/FDES/FDES-2015-supporting-tools/FDES.pdf&quot;&gt;http://unstats.un.org/unsd/environment/FDES/FDES-2015-supporting-tools/FDES.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Вопросник ОЭСР / Евростата по статистике окружающей среды: Раздел о водных ресурсах&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
