<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 6-5-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 6: Ensure availability and sustainable management of water and sanitation for all&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 6.5: By 2030, implement integrated water resources management at all levels, including through transboundary cooperation as appropriate&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 6.5.1: Degree of integrated water resources management&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable (this metadata applies to all series under this indicator). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2021-02-02&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As it measures the degree of implementation of an enabling environment for better water resources management, it directly supports the other outcome targets under SDG 6 (6.1 &amp;#x2013; 6.6). It does this by providing further information to countries on the context and possible explanation for the progress on other targets, and points to barriers and enablers to obtaining the other targets. It also directly supports the means of implementation targets 6.a and 6.b, as disaggregation is possible to provide data on financing (6.a) and stakeholder participation (6.b). Beyond SDG 6, indicator 6.5.1 has linkages with a number of other targets across the SDGs, as integrated water resources management is concerned with integrating the demands and impacts on water resources and water-related ecosystems from a number of different SDGs and their targets, including: poverty (1.4); agriculture (2.3); education (4.7); gender (5.5); energy (7.1); work (8.5); equality (10.2); urban areas (11.3); climate change (13.2); ecosystems (15.9); governance (16.3, 16.5 &amp;#x2013; 16.7) (UN-Water 2016).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;United Nations Environment Programme (UNEP)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;United Nations Environment Programme (UNEP)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator 6.5.1 is &amp;#x2018;degree of integrated water resources management implementation&amp;#x2019;. It measures the stages of development and implementation of Integrated Water Resources Management (IWRM), on a scale of 0 to 100, in six categories (see Rationale section). The indicator score is calculated from a country survey with 33 questions, with each question scored on the same scale of 0-100. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The definition of IWRM is based on an internationally agreed definition, and is universally applicable. IWRM was officially established in 1992 and is defined as &amp;#x201C;a process which promotes the coordinated development and management of water, land and related resources in order to maximise economic and social welfare in an equitable manner without compromising the sustainability of vital ecosystems.&amp;#x201D; (GWP 2010). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The method builds on official UN IWRM status reporting, from 2008 and 2012, of the Johannesburg Plan of Implementation from the UN World Summit for Sustainable Development (1992).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of IWRM is measured in 4 main sections, each representing key dimension of IWRM: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enabling environment: this includes the policies, laws, plans and strategies which create the &amp;#x2018;enabling environment&amp;#x2019; for IWRM. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Institutions and participation: includes the range and roles of political, social, economic and administrative institutions that help to support the implementation of IWRM. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Management Instruments: The tools and activities that enable decision-makers and users to make rational and informed choices between alternative actions. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Financing: Budgeting and financing made available and used for water resources development and management from various sources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is based on a national survey structured around these four main sections. Each section is split into two parts: questions concerning the &amp;#x2018;National level&amp;#x2019; and &amp;#x2018;Other levels&amp;#x2019; respectively. &amp;#x2018;Other levels&amp;#x2019; includes sub-national (including provinces/states for federated countries), basin level, and the transboundary level as appropriate. These two parts address the wording of Target 6.5 &amp;#x2018;implement [IWRM] at all levels &amp;#x2026;&amp;#x2019;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The indicator is measured as a percentage (0-100).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The concepts and methodology are broadly accepted by the international community, having been developed over at least five decades. However, there are no international standards per se. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monitoring progress on meeting SDG 6.5 is owned by and is the responsibility of the national government. The government assigns a ministry with the primary responsibility for overseeing this survey, which then takes on the responsibility of coordinating the national IWRM monitoring and reporting process. As water management issues cut across a wide number of sectors, often overseen by different ministries and other administrative bodies at national or other levels, the process should be inclusive. Major stakeholders should be involved in order to contribute to well informed and objective answers to the survey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ministry is invited to nominate a national &amp;#x201C;IWRM focal point&amp;#x201D;, who may or may not be a government official. The UN provides support where needed and possible. The following steps are suggested as guidance only, as it is up to countries to decide which process or processes would best serve their needs. It should also be noted that the following steps represent a &amp;#x2018;ladder&amp;#x2019; approach, in that completing all the steps will generally lead to a more robust indicator. However, it may not be possible or necessary for all countries to complete all steps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The responsible ministry or IWRM focal point contacts other relevant ministries/agencies to compile responses to the questionnaire. Each possible response option has a score which is used to calculate the overall indicator score.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The completed draft survey is reviewed by government stakeholders. These stakeholders could include those involved in water-relevant sectors, such as agriculture, energy, water supply and environment, as well as water management at different administrative levels. This process may be electronic (e.g. via email) and/or through workshops. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The revised draft survey is validated at a multi-stakeholder workshop. Apart from government representatives these stakeholders could include water user associations, private sector, interest groups concerned with e.g. environment, agriculture, poverty, and academia. The suggested process is through a workshop but alternative means of consultation e.g. email or online call for public submissions could be considered. Note that steps 2 and 3 could be combined if desired. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The responsible ministry or IWRM focal point discusses with relevant officials and consolidates the input into a final version. This version is the basis for calculating the degree of IWRM implementation (0-100) for global reporting. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The responsible ministry submits the final indicator score to the national statistics office responsible for compiling all national SDG target data. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the national survey, UN-Water periodically prepares synthesis reports for regional and global levels to provide overall progress on meeting SDG target 6.5. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Temporal Coverage: A reporting cycle of three years is recommended.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Official counterparts at the country level oversee the validation and consultation process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey has been designed so that the indicator is comparable between countries and time periods. No adjustments are foreseen. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data is collected approximately every 3-4 years. The baseline dataset was collected in 2017, with the second data collection round in 2020. Subsequent data collection rounds are expected in 2023-24, 2026-27, and 2030. Each data collection round spans approximately 9-12 months. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data is released approximately 3 months after the close of each data collection round. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The information required to complete the survey is expected to be held by government officials responsible for water resources management in the country, supported by official documentation. E.g. Ministry of Water in coordination with Ministry of Environment, Ministry of Finance, Ministry of Planning, Ministry of Lands and Agriculture, Ministry of Industry and Mining etc. See also &amp;#x2018;data sources&amp;#x2019; section above. As a minimum, a small group of officials may be able to complete the survey. However, these government officials may belong to various government authorities, and coordination is required to determine and validate the responses to each question. Increased government and non-government stakeholder participation in validating the question scores will lead to a more robust indicator score and facilitate tracking progress over time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UNEP and UN-Water partners, under the UN-Water initiative on integrated monitoring of SDG 6.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UNEP is the designated Custodian Agency for the indicator. Support on the collection, processing, and dissemination of statistics for this indicator is provided by the UNEP-DHI Centre on Water and Environment, the Global Water Partnership (GWP), and Cap-Net. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The indicator provides a direct progress measurement of the first part of Target 6.5 &amp;#x201C;&amp;#x2026;implement integrated water resources management at all levels &amp;#x2026;&amp;#x201D;. The indicator score provides an easy and understandable way of measuring progress towards the target, with &amp;#x2018;0&amp;#x2019; interpreted as no implementation of IWRM, and &amp;#x2018;100&amp;#x2019; interpreted as IWRM being fully implemented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To further aid interpretation and comparison, the indicator results can be categorized as follows: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Degree of implementation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Score range&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;General interpretation for overall IWRM score&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Very high&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;91 - 100&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Vast majority of IWRM elements are fully implemented, with objectives consistently achieved, and plans and programmes periodically assessed and revised.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;High&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;71 - 90&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;IWRM objectives of plans and programmes are generally met, and geographic coverage and stakeholder engagement is generally good.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Medium-high&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;51 - 70&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Capacity to implement elements of IWRM is generally adequate, and elements are generally being implemented under long-term programmes.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Medium-low&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;31 - 50&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Elements of IWRM are generally institutionalized, and implementation is underway.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Low&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;11 - 30&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Implementation of elements of IWRM has generally begun, but with limited uptake across the country, and potentially low engagement of stakeholder groups.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Very low&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;0 - 10&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Development of elements of IWRM has generally not begun, or has stalled.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of the survey is that it provides sufficient information to be of real value to the countries in determining their progress towards the target, and through this, various aspects of IWRM. A balance has been sought between providing sufficient information to cover the core principles of IWRM, and thus providing a robust indicator value, and not overburdening countries with unnecessary reporting requirements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Countries are encouraged to provide additional information on each question, which may help to qualify their choice of score, and/or put that score into their national context. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator 6.5.1 is supported by indicator 6.5.2 &amp;#x201C;Proportion of transboundary basin area with an operational arrangement for water cooperation&amp;#x201D;, which directly addresses the portion of Target 6.5 &amp;#x201C;&amp;#x2026;, including through transboundary cooperation as appropriate.&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The challenge of subjectivity in responses associated with this type of survey is being addressed in a number of ways: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Draft responses are reviewed by a number of governmental and non-governmental stakeholders in an open, inclusive and transparent process. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Countries are encouraged to provide further information to qualify their responses and/or set them in the national context. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Guidelines are provided for each of the four main sections, each question, and each of the six thresholds for every single question, to ensure responses are as objective as possible, and are comparable both between countries, and between reporting periods. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To achieve robust indicator results requires a country process involving a wide range of stakeholders which requires a certain amount of time and resources. The advantage of this is that it puts in place a process that addresses the integrated and indivisible nature of the SDG targets, as well as stressing the importance of &amp;#x201C;leaving no on behind&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The survey contains 33 questions divided into the four main sections described above. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each question is given a score between 0 and 100, in increments of 10, guided by threshold descriptions for the following 6 categories:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Very low (0)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Low (20)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Medium-low (40)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Medium-high (60)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High (80)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Very high (100)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that guidance is provided for each threshold for each question, to ensure objective and comparable results. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The un-weighted average of the question scores within each of the four sections is calculated to give a score of 0 &amp;#x2013; 100 for each section, rounded to the nearest whole number. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The section scores (rounded to the nearest whole number), are averaged (un-weighted), and rounded to the nearest whole number, to give the indicator score, expressed as a number between 0 and 100.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a dedicated SDG 6.5.1 Help Desk for ensuring the quality of the statistical results. Firstly, the data goes through any national quality assurance and approval processes, before being submitted to the Help Desk. The Help Desk then undertakes the Quality Assurance procedure described in section 4.j. All issues are discussed between the Help Desk and the Focal Point(s). Only when all issues are resolved, are the data finalised and entered into the Help Desk Database. The data is then submitted to the UNEP SDG focal point, who collates all indicator data for which UNEP is the Custodian Agency, where a further quality check is undertaken, prior to submission to the SDGs Indicator Database. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once the validation process described above is complete, no further adjustments are made. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator and survey have been designed for all countries to be able to submit an indicator value, and the number of country responses under the SDG process is in excess of 90%. Estimates for countries not responding to the survey are therefore not made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the number of country responses is in excess of 90%, this coverage of data is deemed to be representative of regional and global aggregates. Estimates for countries not responding to the survey are therefore not made.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following the Agenda 2030 principle of &amp;#x201C;leaving no one behind&amp;#x201D;, regional and global values are based on simple, un-weighted averages of country scores. The country scores are presented as a whole number, and regional and global averages are also presented as a whole number. Global averages are based on country values, not regional averages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regional values may be assembled by regional bodies responsible for water resources in the region, such as the African Ministerial Council on Water (AMCOW), the European Environment Agency (EEA), and the United Nations Economic and Social Commission for West Asia (ESCWA).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;National focal points selected by each country. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;National focal points are responsible for coordinating a national process to engage governmental and non-governmental stakeholders, as appropriate in the context of each country, to develop draft responses and finalise responses. This may be via email, workshops, and online notices. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The following materials are available for national focal points in 7 languages (English, Spanish, French, Arabic, Russian, Chinese, Portuguese), at &lt;a href=&quot;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&lt;/a&gt;: the survey (MS Word); a detailed monitoring guide; and a PowerPoint presentation and video recording. In addition, focal points may access the following materials: the 2017 baseline surveys and 2-page results summaries (for 172 countries); and 2017 workshop reports (for 36 countries). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In addition, an &amp;#x201C;SDG 6.5.1 Facilitator&amp;#x2019;s Training Course&amp;#x201D; is available online via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gwp.org/en/sdg6support/consultations/stage-1-activities/training-of-facilitators/&quot;&gt;www.gwp.org/en/sdg6support/consultations/stage-1-activities/training-of-facilitators/&lt;/a&gt; , through the SDG 6 IWRM Support Programme. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A more comprehensive &amp;#x201C;IWRM Stage 1 Support Package&amp;#x201D; is available for a limited number of countries (approximately 60 countries in 2020). The Support Package includes seed funding to engage a Facilitator to support the stakeholder consultation process. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extensive explanations are provided in the monitoring guide and in the survey itself. The survey contains: an overall introduction and explanation; a glossary; an introduction and glossary in each of the four sections; threshold descriptions for six thresholds for each question; and a number of footnotes to explain aspects of questions or threshold descriptions. All materials can be downloaded from &lt;a href=&quot;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&lt;/a&gt;. In addition, a dedicated Help Desk is available to provide assistance at all times. The Help Desk is accessible via email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:iwrmsdg651@un.org&quot;&gt;iwrmsdg651@un.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UNEP-DHI Centre, which manages the statistical reporting processes for UNEP on indicator 6.5.1, operates through a Business Management System that fulfils the requirements of ISO 9001 (quality management), which covers relevant areas such as consulting and capacity development and training courses. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following quality assurance guidelines are available to all individuals involved in quality assurance for 6.5.1. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Process: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nominate person responsible for QA for a country response once it is submitted for the first time. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Acknowledge receipt and inform the country of QA process. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Update QA spreadsheet, indicating date of receipt and who submitted. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upload draft survey (MS Word) to the Dropbox folder. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Undertake ALL checks described below. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If there are any discrepancies, revert to UNEP-DHI colleagues. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once action is agreed, respond to the countries. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Complete all checks on each subsequent version of the questionnaire until all quality issues are resolved and questionnaire is marked &amp;#x2018;final&amp;#x2019;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checks: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focal point:&lt;/strong&gt; Confirm the person submitting is the formal national focal point. If not, any reply should also add the national focal point in CC. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cover sheet:&lt;/strong&gt; check if cover sheet is correctly filled out. Cross-check if the person submitting is the formal national focal point. If not, any reply should include the national focal point in CC.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question scores and calculations:&lt;/strong&gt; In the spreadsheet &amp;#x2018;Quality_Assurance_651_2020.xlsx&amp;#x2019; on Dropbox, fill in the given responses in sheet &amp;#x201C;QA 2020 scores-status&amp;#x201D;. Make following checks to scores:&lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;All questions answered. The official guidance is that all questions should be answered (either with a score or n/a). &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If there is confusion about whether to score or use &amp;#x2018;n/a&amp;#x2019; for sub-national level questions, this list of administrative divisions by country may help in our understanding of the sub-national level(s) &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_administrative_divisions_by_country%20&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_administrative_divisions_by_country &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Scores are in range from 0-100, in increments of 10. If they only give &amp;#x2018;even&amp;#x2019; scores (e.g. 0, 20, 40 etc), then they may not have understood that they can also give &amp;#x2018;odd&amp;#x2019; scores (10, 30, 50 etc), if they feel their situation lies between two threshold descriptions.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Any differences between &amp;#x2018;given&amp;#x2019; and &amp;#x2018;calculated&amp;#x2019; section scores and overall score are given in columns C &amp;#x2013; G. If the difference is greater than +/- 0.5, the cells are automatically highlighted in red using conditional formatting. One also has to fill in the date of last submission in column B, otherwise the differences will not be calculated. &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Compare with baseline (2017). The QA &amp;#x2018;2017 Comparison&amp;#x2019; spreadsheet automatically calculates differences. Note any negative changes (orange), or increases of more than 20 (yellow). If there are any significant/unexpected differences, the country should have given some explanation in the free text fields. &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;In the &amp;#x2018;given&amp;#x2019; calculations (section 5 of the survey instrument), check that section averages and overall score are rounded to the nearest whole number. Rounding mistakes might occur.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Note: in the calculations, 0 scores are included, and N/A scores should be omitted. N/A scores should always have explanation (unless obvious &amp;#x2013; e.g. transboundary questions for island states).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check if the final score is calculated as average of rounded section averages.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;In the free text responses in columns (BE-BF) in the main &amp;#x201C;QA 2020-score status&amp;#x201D; tab, for assigning Low/ Medium/ High categories the following criteria should be followed: &lt;u&gt;Low:&lt;/u&gt; Less than three quarters of questions have responses and/or responses are poor quality. &lt;u&gt;Medium:&lt;/u&gt; At least three quarters of the questions have responses, and/or responses are varying quality. Each question and the points make sense and are useful. &lt;u&gt;High:&lt;/u&gt; All questions have responses and most responses are high quality. NB: Quality responses mean ones that are useful/ informative/ detailed and can contribute to stakeholder understanding/ discussions and plannings.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Free text fields: &lt;/strong&gt;Using the &amp;#x2018;text&amp;#x2019; tabs: &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check that the free text make sense in the context of the score (and vice versa) (particularly in the case of (n/a or 100 responses).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check that n/a (not applicable) is used appropriately. i.e. only if the question is not applicable to the country. In some cases, a score of zero should be given, and in others, perhaps they need more help to figure out how to answer the question. &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Guidance for assigning Low/ Medium/ High categories: Low: Blank or not useful. Medium: Some text and details. High: Useful amount of text and detail than can contribute to stakeholder understanding/consensus and planning.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANNEXES&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Annex B: Transboundary level:&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check the &amp;#x2018;transboundary basins&amp;#x2019; table. A full list of transboundary basins can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://twap-rivers.org/indicators/Report.ashx?type=IndicatorResultsSummary&quot;&gt;http://twap-rivers.org/indicators/Report.ashx?type=IndicatorResultsSummary&lt;/a&gt;. Go to the final worksheet/tab to see the countries in each basin. You can also check the maps here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://twap-rivers.org/indicators/%20&quot;&gt;http://twap-rivers.org/indicators/ &lt;/a&gt;to see if the basin is likely to be important for that country, or if there is only a small portion of the basin in their country (in which case they may not list it).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For transboundary aquifers, check: &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.geodan.nl/igrac/ggis-viewer/viewer/twap/public/default&quot;&gt;https://apps.geodan.nl/igrac/ggis-viewer/viewer/twap/public/default&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;In case any sub-basins are listed, check that the main basin name is included in brackets. &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check the transboundary questions: 1.2c; 2.2e; 3.2d; and 4.2c, and see if these make sense in the context of the country. &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Island countries should give &amp;#x2018;n/a&amp;#x2019; for all of these questions that relate to transboundary waters. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Annex C: Barriers / enablers:&lt;/strong&gt; is this filled out? Low, moderate, or high level of information? &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt; Guidance for assigning Low/ Medium/ High categories: &lt;u&gt;Low:&lt;/u&gt; Less than 1 point for each question. &lt;u&gt;Medium:&lt;/u&gt; At least one point for each question and the points make sense and are useful. &lt;u&gt;High:&lt;/u&gt; Useful analysis that would contribute to future planning.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Annex D:&lt;/strong&gt; Priorities: completed (Yes/No/Partially)? Any info in the &amp;#x2018;comments&amp;#x2019; field (low, moderate, high level of info there?)&lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Guidance for assigning Low/ Medium/ High categories: Low: Blank to few words. Medium: A few useful points. High: A longer analysis/ commentary.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Annex E: Country process:&lt;/strong&gt; level of info in the free text field, the table, and in the &amp;#x2018;additional info&amp;#x2019; field completed. &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Guidance for assigning Low/ Medium/ High categories: &lt;u&gt;Low&lt;/u&gt;: Blank to few words. &lt;u&gt;Medium&lt;/u&gt;: Minimum info to be useful to understand transparency. &lt;u&gt;High&lt;/u&gt;: More detailed description that gives good idea of robustness and transparency of the process. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All data is provided by each country and is therefore fully owned by the countries. Each country undertakes stakeholder consultation, to a level that is appropriate given resources and capacity available to them, to ensure that the data has adequate acceptance and ownership within the country. Guidance on consultation processes are provided in the monitoring guide and through the introductory powerpoint and video for focal points (all materials available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The quality management procedures in place are deemed sufficient to ensure the data submitted to the SDGs Indicator Database is of acceptable quality. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total number of countries: 185 (96% of UN Member States) (UNEP 2020) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following covers the region (UNSD regional groupings): followed by the number of countries with data / total countries in region (as of 2020); followed by the percentage of countries with data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Australia and New Zealand: 2/2; 100%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Central and Southern Asia: 14/14; 100%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eastern and South-Eastern Asia: 16/16; 100%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe and Northern America: 44/45; 98%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Latin America and the Caribbean: 32/33; 97%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Northern Africa and Western Asia: 23/23; 100%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oceania (excluding Australia and New Zealand): 9/12; 75%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sub-Saharan Africa: 46/48; 96%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World: 185/193: 96%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pre-SDGs: 2008, 2012 (UN-Water 2008, 2012). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SDG period: 2017 , 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All on IWRM Portal (&lt;a href=&quot;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strength of the indicator lies in the potential for disaggregating the country score into the four main dimensions of IWRM, and further to the questions in the survey. This provides countries with a quick assessment of which aspects of IWRM are progressing well, and which aspects require increased efforts to reach the target. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nature of the target, indicator and survey does not lend itself to disaggregation by sex, age group, income etc. However, social equality is an integral part of IWRM, and there are questions which directly address issues such as gender, vulnerable groups, geographic coverage and broad stakeholder participation in water resources development and management. These questions provide an indication of the national and sub-national situation regarding social equality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As described in the &amp;#x201C;Data Sources&amp;#x201D; section above, there are no internationally estimated data, with all data to be produced by countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URLs: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&lt;/a&gt; . This contains the latest survey instrument, monitoring guide, and all supporting documentation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gwp.org/en/sdg6support/&quot;&gt;https://www.gwp.org/en/sdg6support/&lt;/a&gt; : SDG 6 IWRM Support Programme. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- AMCOW 2018: Status Report on the Implementation of Water Resources Management in Africa: a regional report for SDG indicator 6.5.1 on IWRM implementation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- UNEP 2018: Progress on integrated water resources management. Global baseline for SDG 6 Indicator 6.5.1: degree of IWRM implementation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- United Nations Economic and Social Commission for West Asia (2019). Status Report on the Implementation of Integrated Water Resources Management in the Arab Region: Progress on SDG indicator 6.5.1. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- UN-Water initiative on integrated monitoring of SDG 6. &lt;a href=&quot;http://sdg6data.org&quot;&gt;http://sdg6data.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- UN-Water, 2016: Water and Sanitation Interlinkages across the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development. Geneva.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 6: Garantizar la disponibilidad y la gestión sostenible del agua y el saneamiento para todos&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 6.5: De aquí a 2030, implementar la gestión integrada de los recursos hídricos a todos los niveles, incluso mediante la cooperación transfronteriza, según proceda&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 6.5.1: Grado de gestión integrada de los recursos hídricos&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Última actualización: 7 de noviembre de 2019.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicadores relacionados&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Como mide el grado de aplicación de un entorno propicio para una mejor gestión de los recursos hídricos, apoya directamente las demás metas de resultados del ODS 6 (6.1, 6.6). Lo hace proporcionando más información a los países sobre el contexto y la posible explicación de los avances en otras metas, y señala los obstáculos y los facilitadores para la obtención de las otras metas. También apoya directamente las metas 6.a y 6.b de los medios de implementación, ya que la desagregación es posible para proporcionar datos sobre la financiación (6.a) y la participación de las partes interesadas (6.b). Además del ODS 6, el indicador 6.5.1 tiene vínculos con otras metas de los ODS, ya que la gestión integrada de los recursos hídricos tiene que ver con la integración de las demandas y los impactos sobre los recursos hídricos y los ecosistemas relacionados con el agua de una serie de ODS diferentes y sus metas, incluyendo: la pobreza (1.4); la agricultura (2.3); la educación (4.7); el género (5.5); la energía (7.1); el trabajo (8.5); la igualdad (10.2); las zonas urbanas (11.3); el cambio climático (13.2); los ecosistemas (15.9); la gobernanza (16.3, 16.5, 16.7) (ONU-Agua 2016).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Información institucional &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Organización (es): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Programa de las Naciones Unidas para el Medio Ambiente (PNUMA) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador 6.5.1 se asocia con el &amp;#x2018;grado de implementación de la gestión integrada de los recursos hídricos (0-100)&amp;#x2019;. Mide las etapas de desarrollo e implementación de la Gestión Integrada de los Recursos Hídricos (GIRH), en una escala de 0 a 100, en seis categorías (véase la sección de Justificación). La puntuación del indicador se calcula a partir de una encuesta por países con 33 preguntas, y cada una de ellas se puntúa en la misma escala de 0 a 100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La definición de GIRH se basa en una definición acordada internacionalmente y es de aplicación universal. La GIRH se estableció oficialmente en 1992 y se define como &amp;#x201C;un proceso que promueve el desarrollo y la gestión coordinados de los recursos hídricos, terrestres y afines con el fin de maximizar el bienestar económico y social de forma equitativa sin comprometer la sostenibilidad de los ecosistemas vitales&amp;#x201D; (GWP 2010).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El método se basa en los informes oficiales de la ONU sobre el estado de la GIRH, de 2008 y 2012, del Plan de Aplicación de Johannesburgo de la Cumbre Mundial de las Naciones Unidas para el Desarrollo Sostenible (1992).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El concepto de GIRH se mide en 4 secciones principales, cada una de las cuales representa una dimensión clave de la GIRH:.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Entorno propicio: incluye las políticas, leyes, planes y estrategias que crean el &amp;#x2018;entorno propicio&amp;#x2019; para la GIRH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Instituciones y participación: incluye la gama y los roles de las instituciones políticas, sociales, económicas y administrativas que ayudan a apoyar la implementación de la GIRH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Instrumentos de gestión: Las herramientas y actividades que permiten a los responsables de la toma de decisiones y a los usuarios hacer elecciones racionales e informadas entre acciones alternativas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. Financiación: La presupuestación y la financiación puesta a disposición y utilizada para el desarrollo y la gestión de los recursos hídricos a partir de diversas fuentes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador se basa en una encuesta nacional estructurada en torno a estas cuatro secciones principales. Cada sección se divide en dos partes: preguntas relativas al &amp;#x2018;Nivel nacional&amp;#x2019; y a &amp;#x2018;Otros niveles&amp;#x2019; respectivamente. En &amp;#x2018;Otros niveles&amp;#x2019; se incluyen el nivel sub-nacional (incluidas las provincias/estados en el caso de los países federados), el nivel de cuenca y el nivel transfronterizo, según corresponda. Estas dos partes abordan lo indicado por la Meta 6.5 respecto de &amp;#x2018;aplicar la [GIRH] a todos los niveles &amp;#x2026;&amp;#x2019;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El seguimiento de los avances en el cumplimiento del ODS 6.5 es propiedad y responsabilidad del gobierno nacional. El gobierno asignará un ministerio con la responsabilidad principal de supervisar este estudio, al que se le pedirá que asuma la responsabilidad de coordinar el proceso nacional de seguimiento e información de la GIRH. Dado que las cuestiones relativas a la gestión del agua afectan a un gran número de sectores, a menudo supervisados por diferentes ministerios y otros organismos administrativos a nivel nacional o de otro tipo, el proceso debe ser inclusivo. Las principales partes interesadas deben participar para contribuir a dar respuestas bien informadas y objetivas a la encuesta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se invita al ministerio a designar un punto focal nacional de &amp;#x201C;GIRH&amp;#x201D;, que puede ser o no un funcionario del gobierno. La ONU proporcionará apoyo cuando sea necesario y posible. Los siguientes pasos se sugieren sólo como orientación, ya que corresponde a los países decidir qué proceso o procesos se ajustan mejor a sus necesidades. También hay que tener en cuenta que los siguientes pasos representan un enfoque &amp;#x2018;en escalera&amp;#x2019;, en el sentido que completar todos los pasos generalmente conducirá a un indicador más sólido. Sin embargo, puede que no sea posible o necesario que todos los países completen todos los pasos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. El ministerio responsable o el punto focal de GIRH se pone en contacto con otros ministerios/agencias relevantes para recopilar las respuestas al cuestionario. Cada opción de respuesta posible tiene una puntuación que se utilizará para calcular la puntuación global del indicador.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. El proyecto de encuesta completado es revisado por las partes interesadas del gobierno. Estas partes interesadas podrían incluir a los implicados en los sectores relacionados con el agua, como la agricultura, la energía, el suministro de agua y el medio ambiente, así como la gestión del agua a diferentes niveles administrativos. Este proceso puede ser electrónico (por ejemplo, a través del correo electrónico) y/o mediante talleres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. El proyecto de encuesta revisado se valida en un taller con múltiples partes interesadas. Aparte de los representantes del gobierno, estas partes interesadas podrían incluir asociaciones de usuarios del agua, el sector privado, grupos de interés relacionados, por ejemplo, con el medio ambiente, la agricultura, la pobreza y el mundo académico. El proceso sugerido es a través de un taller, pero se podrían considerar medios alternativos de consulta, por ejemplo, el correo electrónico o una convocatoria pública en línea. Cabe destacar que los pasos 2 y 3 podrían combinarse si se desea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. El ministerio responsable o el punto focal de la GIRH discute con los funcionarios pertinentes y consolida los aportes en una versión final. Esta versión es la base para calcular el grado de implementación de la GIRH (0-100) para el informe global.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. El ministerio responsable presenta la puntuación final del indicador a la oficina nacional de estadística encargada de recopilar todos los datos de las metas nacionales de los ODS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sobre la base de la encuesta nacional, ONU-Agua preparará periódicamente informes de síntesis para los niveles regional y mundial con el fin de proporcionar el progreso general en el cumplimiento de la meta 6.5 de los ODS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobertura temporal: Se recomienda un ciclo de presentación de informes de tres años.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Proceso de recolección:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las contrapartes oficiales a nivel nacional supervisan el proceso de validación y consulta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La encuesta se ha diseñado para que el indicador sea comparable entre países y periodos de tiempo. No se prevén ajustes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendario&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recopilación de datos: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enero-mayo de 2020 (5 meses).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publicación de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Primer trimestre de 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se espera que la información necesaria para completar la encuesta esté en manos de los funcionarios gubernamentales responsables de la gestión de los recursos hídricos en el país, con el apoyo de la documentación oficial. Por ejemplo, el Ministerio del Agua en coordinación con el Ministerio de Medio Ambiente, el Ministerio de Finanzas, el Ministerio de Planificación, el Ministerio de Tierras y Agricultura, el Ministerio de Industria y Minería, etc. Véase también la sección &amp;#x2018;fuentes de datos&amp;#x2019; anterior. Como mínimo, un pequeño grupo de funcionarios puede completar la encuesta. Sin embargo, estos funcionarios pueden pertenecer a varias autoridades gubernamentales, por lo que será necesaria su coordinación para determinar y validar las respuestas a cada pregunta. Una mayor participación de las partes interesadas gubernamentales y no gubernamentales en la validación de las puntuaciones de las preguntas dará lugar a una puntuación más sólida del indicador y facilitará el seguimiento del progreso a lo largo del tiempo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Socios del PNUMA y de ONU-Agua, en el marco de la iniciativa ONU-Agua sobre el seguimiento integrado del ODS 6.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador proporciona una medición directa del progreso de la primera parte de la Meta 6.5 &amp;#x201C;&amp;#x2026;implementar la gestión integrada de los recursos hídricos en todos los niveles &amp;#x2026;&amp;#x201D;. La puntuación del indicador proporciona una forma fácil y comprensible de medir el progreso hacia la meta, con &amp;#x2018;0&amp;#x2019; interpretado como que no se ha implementado la GIRH, y &amp;#x2018;100&amp;#x2019; interpretado como que la GIRH se ha implementado completamente.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para facilitar la interpretación y la comparación, los resultados de los indicadores pueden clasificarse de la siguiente manera:.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Grado de implementación.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Rango de puntuación.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Interpretación general de la puntuación global de la GIRH.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Muy alta.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;91 - 100.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;La gran mayoría de los elementos de la GIRH se aplican en su totalidad, los objetivos se alcanzan sistemáticamente y los planes y programas se evalúan y revisan periódicamente.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Alta.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;71 - 90.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Los objetivos de la GIRH incluidos en los planes y programas se cumplen en general, y la cobertura geográfica y la participación de las partes interesadas son generalmente buenas.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Media-Alta.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;51 - 70.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;La capacidad para aplicar los elementos de la GIRH es, en general, adecuada, y los elementos se aplican generalmente en el marco de programas a largo plazo&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Media-Baja.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;31 - 50.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Los elementos de la GIRH están generalmente institucionalizados y su aplicación está en marcha.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Baja.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;11 - 30.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;La aplicación de los elementos de la GIRH ha comenzado en general, pero con una aceptación limitada en todo el país y una participación potencialmente escasa de los grupos interesados.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Muy baja.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;0 - 10.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;En general, el desarrollo de los elementos de la GIRH no ha comenzado o se ha estancado.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El concepto de la encuesta es que proporcione suficiente información para que sea realmente valiosa para los países a la hora de determinar su progreso hacia el objetivo, y, a través de esto, a varios aspectos de la GIRH. Se ha buscado un equilibrio entre proporcionar suficiente información para cubrir los principios básicos de la GIRH, y así proporcionar un valor de indicador sólido, y no sobrecargar a los países con requisitos de información innecesarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se anima a los países a que proporcionen información adicional sobre cada pregunta que pueda ayudar a calificar su elección de puntuación, y/o a situar esa puntuación en su contexto nacional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador 6.5.1 está respaldado por el indicador 6.5.2 &amp;#x201C;Proporción de la zona de la cuenca transfronteriza con un acuerdo operativo para la cooperación en materia de agua&amp;#x201D;, que aborda directamente la sección de la Meta 6.5 &amp;#x201C;&amp;#x2026;, incluso a través de la cooperación transfronteriza, según corresponda.&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El reto de la subjetividad en las respuestas asociado a este tipo de encuestas se aborda de varias maneras:.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Los borradores de las respuestas son revisados por una serie de partes interesadas gubernamentales y no gubernamentales en un proceso abierto, inclusivo y transparente.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Se anima a los países a que proporcionen más información para matizar sus respuestas y/o situarlas en el contexto nacional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Se proporcionan directrices para cada una de las cuatro secciones principales, cada pregunta y cada uno de los seis umbrales para cada pregunta, con el fin de garantizar que las respuestas sean lo más objetivas posibles y que sean comparables tanto entre países como entre periodos de información.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para lograr resultados sólidos en los indicadores se requiere un proceso nacional en el que participe una amplia gama de partes interesadas, lo que exigirá una cierta cantidad de tiempo y recursos. La ventaja de esto es que pone en marcha un proceso que aborda la naturaleza integrada e indivisible de las metas de los ODS, además de subrayar la importancia de &amp;#x201C;no dejar a nadie atrás&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. La encuesta contiene 33 preguntas divididas en las cuatro secciones principales descritas anteriormente.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Cada pregunta recibe una puntuación de entre 0 y 100, en incrementos de 10, guiada por descripciones de umbrales para las siguientes 6 categorías:.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Muy baja (0)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Baja (20)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Media-baja (40)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Media-alta (60)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alta (80)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Muy alta (100)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obsérvese que se proporcionan orientaciones para cada umbral de cada pregunta, a fin de garantizar resultados objetivos y comparables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. La media no ponderada de las puntuaciones de las preguntas de cada una de las cuatro secciones se calcula para obtener una puntuación de 0 &amp;#x2013; 100 para cada sección, redondeada al número entero más cercano.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. Las puntuaciones de las secciones (redondeadas al número entero más cercano), se promedian (sin ponderar), y se redondean al número entero más cercano, para obtener la puntuación del indicador, expresada como un número entre 0 y 100.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel de país:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador y la encuesta se han diseñado para que todos los países puedan presentar un valor del indicador. Entre los países que no presentaron una encuesta durante la última ronda de recopilación de datos se encontraban los Estados frágiles/países en conflicto o los pequeños Estados insulares en desarrollo. Por lo tanto, se estima que el número de respuestas de los países en el proceso de los ODS superará el 90%. Por lo tanto, no se harán estimaciones de los países que no respondan a la encuesta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel regional y mundial:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se estima que el número de respuestas de los países será superior al 90%. Esta cobertura de datos se considerará representativa de los agregados mundiales. Por lo tanto, no se harán estimaciones de los países que no respondan a la encuesta.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siguiendo el principio de la Agenda 2030 de &amp;#x201C;no dejar a nadie atrás&amp;#x201D;, los valores regionales y globales se basarán en promedios simples y no ponderados de las puntuaciones de los países. Las puntuaciones de los países se presentarán como un número entero, y las medias regionales y mundiales también se presentarán como un número entero. Las medias globales se basarán en los valores de los países, no en las medias regionales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los valores regionales pueden ser reunidos por los organismos regionales responsables de los recursos hídricos de la región, como el Consejo Ministerial Africano del Agua (AMCOW, por su sigla en inglés), la Agencia Europea del Medio Ambiente (AEMA) y la Comisión Económica y Social de las Naciones Unidas para Asia Occidental (CESPAO).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Métodos y directrices a disposición de los países para la recopilación de los datos a nivel nacional:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Puntos focales nacionales seleccionados por cada país. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La recopilación de datos se realiza mediante un sencillo cuestionario de 33 preguntas, en formato MS Word. Las respuestas a cada pregunta se dan en una escala de 0 &amp;#x2013; 100, en incrementos de 10. Se ofrecen descripciones de los umbrales para seis umbrales entre 0 y 100.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Los puntos focales nacionales son responsables de coordinar un proceso nacional para involucrar a las partes interesadas gubernamentales y no gubernamentales, según sea apropiado en el contexto de cada país, para desarrollar proyectos de respuestas y finalizar las mismas. Esto puede ser desarrollado a través del correo electrónico, de talleres y/o avisos en línea.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Los puntos focales nacionales disponen de los siguientes materiales en 7 idiomas (inglés, español, francés, árabe, ruso, chino y portugués), en &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&lt;/a&gt;: la encuesta (MS Word); una guía de seguimiento detallada; y una presentación en PowerPoint y una grabación de vídeo. Además, los puntos focales pueden acceder a los siguientes materiales: las encuestas de referencia de 2017 y los resúmenes de resultados de 2 páginas (para 172 países); y los informes de los talleres de 2017 (para 36 países).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En la guía de seguimiento y en la propia encuesta se ofrecen amplias explicaciones. La encuesta contiene: una introducción y explicación general; un glosario; una introducción y un glosario en cada una de las cuatro secciones; descripciones de umbrales para seis umbrales de cada pregunta; y varias notas a pie de página para explicar aspectos de las preguntas o descripciones de umbrales. Todo el material puede descargarse de &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&lt;/a&gt;. Además, hay un servicio de asistencia dedicado a proporcionar ayuda en todo momento. Se puede acceder al servicio de ayuda por correo electrónico en: &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;iwrmsdg651@un.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Garantía de calidad:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las siguientes directrices de garantía de calidad (GC) están a disposición de todas las personas que participan en la garantía de calidad de 6.5.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proceso:.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nombrar a la persona responsable de la garantía de calidad de la respuesta de un país una vez que se presenta por primera vez.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Acusar recibo e informar al país del proceso de GC.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Actualizar la hoja de cálculo de la GC, indicando la fecha de recepción y quién la ha presentado.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Subir el borrador de la encuesta (MS Word) a la carpeta de Dropbox.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Realizar TODAS las comprobaciones descritas a continuación.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Si hay alguna discrepancia, regresarla a los colegas del PNUMA-DHI (por su sigla en inglés).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Una vez acordada la acción, responder a los países.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Realizar todas las comprobaciones en cada una de las versiones posteriores del cuestionario hasta que se hayan resuelto todos los problemas de calidad y se marque el cuestionario como &amp;#x2018;final&amp;#x2019;.&amp;#xA0; &amp;#xA0; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comprobaciones:.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Punto focal: Confirme que la persona que lo presenta es el punto focal nacional formal. Si no es así, cualquier respuesta debe añadir también el punto focal nacional en CC.&amp;#xA0; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Respuestas a las preguntas: &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Todas las preguntas contestadas. La orientación oficial es que todas las preguntas deben ser contestadas (con una puntuación o n/a). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Puntuaciones en el rango de 0-100, en incrementos de 10. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compruebe que n/a (no aplicable) se utiliza adecuadamente. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Campos de texto libre: En los campos &amp;#x201C;&amp;#x201C;Descripción del estado&amp;#x201D; y &amp;#x201C;Camino a seguir&amp;#x201D; de cada pregunta, compruebe que el texto libre tiene sentido en el contexto de la puntuación (y viceversa). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cálculos: Comprueba que los promedios de las secciones y la puntuación final están redondeados al número entero más cercano y son correctos, utilizando la hoja de cálculo de GC en Dropbox. Rellene las respuestas dadas en las columnas M - AX, y revise que las diferencias se calculan automáticamente en las columnas C &amp;#x2013; G. Si la diferencia es superior a +/- 0,5, las celdas se resaltan automáticamente en rojo utilizando el formato condicional. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Comparar con la línea de base de 2017: Cuando esté disponible, compare con la encuesta de referencia de 2017 (para 172 países) y discuta con sus colegas si es necesario.&amp;#xA0; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cuestiones transfronterizas: &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compruebe la tabla de &amp;#x2018;cuencas transfronterizas&amp;#x2019; del Anexo B. La lista completa de cuencas transfronterizas se puede encontrar aquí: &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;http://twap-rivers.org/indicators/Report.ashx?type=IndicatorResultsSummary&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vaya a la hoja de trabajo/pestaña final para ver los países de cada cuenca. Consulta también los mapas aquí: &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;http://twap-rivers.org/indicators/&lt;/a&gt; para ver si es probable que la cuenca sea importante para ese país, o si sólo hay una pequeña porción de la cuenca en su país (en cuyo caso es posible que no la incluyan en la lista). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Compruebe las preguntas sobre transfronterizos: 1.2c, 2.2e; 3.2d; y 4.2c, y vea si tienen sentido en el contexto del país. Los países insulares deben presentar &amp;#x2018;n/a&amp;#x2019; para todas estas preguntas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todos los datos son proporcionados por cada país y, por lo tanto, son de su entera propiedad. Cada país lleva a cabo una consulta con las partes interesadas, a un nivel apropiado teniendo en cuenta los recursos y la capacidad de que disponen, para garantizar que los datos tienen la aceptación y la propiedad adecuadas dentro del país. Las orientaciones sobre los procesos de consulta figuran en la guía de seguimiento y en el powerpoint y el vídeo introductorios para los puntos focales (todos los materiales están disponibles en &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Número total de países: 172 (89% de los Estados miembros de la ONU) (PNUMA 2018).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A continuación se incluye la región (agrupaciones regionales de la División de Estadísticas de las Naciones Unidas): seguida del número de países con datos / total de países en la región (a partir de 2017); seguida del porcentaje de países con datos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Australia y Nueva Zelanda: 2/2; 100%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asia central y meridional: 10/14; 71%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asia oriental y sudoriental: 13/16; 81%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europa y América del Norte: 43/45; 96%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;América Latina y el Caribe: 29/33; 89%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;África del Norte y Asia Occidental: 22/23; 96%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oceanía (excluyendo Australia y Nueva Zelanda): 8/12; 67%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;África subsahariana: 45/48; 94%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mundo: 172/193: 89%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antes de los ODS: 2008, 2012 (ONU-Agua 2008, 2012).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Periodo de los ODS: 2017 (PNUMA 2018).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todo en el Portal de GIRH (&lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La fuerza del indicador radica en la posibilidad de desagregar la puntuación del país en las cuatro dimensiones principales de la GIRH, y además en las preguntas de la encuesta. Esto proporciona a los países una rápida evaluación de los aspectos de la GIRH que están progresando bien, y de los aspectos que requieren mayores esfuerzos para alcanzar el objetivo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La naturaleza del objetivo, del indicador y de la encuesta no se presta a una desagregación por sexo, grupo de edad, ingresos, etc. Sin embargo, la igualdad social es una parte integral de la GIRH, y hay preguntas que abordan directamente cuestiones como el género, los grupos vulnerables, la cobertura geográfica y la amplia participación de los interesados en el desarrollo y la gestión de los recursos hídricos. Estas preguntas proporcionan indicios acerca de la situación nacional y sub-nacional en materia de igualdad social.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Fuentes de discrepancias:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Como se describe en la sección &amp;#x201C;Fuentes de datos&amp;#x201D;, no habrá datos estimados a nivel internacional, ya que todos los datos serán producidos por los países.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contiene el último instrumento de encuesta, la guía de seguimiento y toda la documentación de apoyo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Referencias:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- AMCOW 2018: Informe de situación sobre la implementación de la gestión de los recursos hídricos en África: un informe regional para el indicador 6.5.1 de los ODS sobre la implementación de la GIRH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- PNUMA 2018: Progreso en la gestión integrada de los recursos hídricos. Línea de base global para el indicador 6.5.1 del ODS: grado de implementación de la GIRH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Comisión Económica y Social de las Naciones Unidas para Asia Occidental (2019). Informe de situación sobre la aplicación de la gestión integrada de los recursos hídricos en la región árabe: Avances en el indicador 6.5.1 de los ODS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Iniciativa de ONU-Agua sobre el seguimiento integrado del ODS 6. &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;http://sdg6data.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- ONU-Agua, 2016: Interrelaciones del agua y el saneamiento en la Agenda 2030 para el Desarrollo Sostenible. Ginebra.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 6: Garantir l&apos;accès de tous à des services d&apos;alimentation en eau et d&apos;assainissement gérés de façon durable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Cible 6.5: D’ici à 2030, assurer la gestion intégrée des ressources en eau à tous les niveaux, y compris au moyen de la coopération transfrontière selon qu’il convient&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 6.5.1: Degré de mise en oeuvre de la gestion intégrée des ressources en eau&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Dernière mise à jour : 7 novembre 2019&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Indicateurs connexes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Comme il mesure le degré de mise en œuvre d&apos;un environnement favorable à une meilleure gestion des ressources en eau, il soutient directement les autres objectifs de résultats de l&apos;ODD 6 (6.1 &amp;#x2013; 6.6). Pour ce faire, il fournit aux pays des informations complémentaires sur le contexte et les explications possibles des progrès réalisés sur d’autres objectifs, et souligne les obstacles et les moyens d’atteindre les autres objectifs. Il soutient également directement les objectifs de mise en œuvre 6.a et 6.b, car la désagrégation est possible de fournir des données sur le financement (6.a) et la participation des parties prenantes (6.b). Au-delà de l’ODD 6, l’indicateur 6.5.1 a des liens avec un certain nombre d’autres cibles à travers les ODD, car la gestion intégrée des ressources en eau vise à intégrer les exigences et les impacts sur les ressources en eau et les écosystèmes liés à l’eau d’un certain nombre de ODD différents et de leurs objectifs, y compris : la pauvreté (1.4); l’agriculture (2,3); l’éducation (4,7); genre (5,5); énergie (7,1); travail (8,5); égalité (10,2); zones urbaines (11,3); changement climatique (13,2); écosystèmes (15,9); gouvernance (16.3, 16.5 &amp;#x2013; 16.7) (ONU-Eau 2016). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Information institutionnelle&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Organisation(s):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Programme des Nations Unies pour l’environnement (PNUE)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Définition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L’indicateur 6.5.1 est &amp;#x2018;degré de mise en œuvre intégrée de la gestion des ressources en eau (0-100)&amp;#x2019;. Il mesure les étapes de développement et de mise en œuvre de la gestion intégrée des ressources en eau (IWRM), sur une échelle de 0 à 100, en six catégories (voir la section Justification). Le score de l’indicateur est calculé à partir d’une enquête par pays avec 33 questions, chaque question ayant été notée sur la même échelle de 0 à 100. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La définition de l’IWRM est basée sur une définition convenue au niveau international et est universellement applicable. L’IWRM a été officiellement créé en 1992 et est défini comme &amp;#x201C;, un processus qui favorise le développement et la gestion coordonnés de l’eau, des terres et des ressources connexes afin de maximiser le bien-être économique et social de manière équitable sans compromettre la durabilité des écosystèmes vitaux. &amp;#x201D; (GWP 2010). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La méthode s’appuie sur les rapports officiels de l’ONU sur l’état de l’IWRM, de 2008 et 2012, du Plan de mise en œuvre de Johannesburg du Sommet mondial des Nations Unies pour le développement durable (1992). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Le concept d’IWRM est mesuré en 4 sections principales, chacune représentant la dimension clé de l’IWRM : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 1. Environnement habilitant : cela inclut les politiques, les lois, les plans et les stratégies qui créent l’environnement habilitant &amp;#x2018;&amp;#x2019; pour l’IWRM. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 2. Institutions et participation : comprend l’éventail et les rôles des institutions politiques, sociales, économiques et administratives qui aident à soutenir la mise en œuvre de l’IWRM. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 3. Instruments de gestion : Outils et activités qui permettent aux décideurs et aux utilisateurs de faire des choix rationnels et éclairés entre des actions alternatives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 4. Financement : Budgétisation et financement mis à disposition et utilisés pour le développement et la gestion des ressources en eau à partir de diverses sources. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L’indicateur est basé sur une enquête nationale structurée autour de ces quatre sections principales. Chaque section est divisée en deux parties : les questions concernant le niveau national &amp;#x2018;&amp;#x2019; et &amp;#x2018;Autres niveaux&amp;#x2019; respectivement. &amp;#x2018; D’autres niveaux&amp;#x2019; incluent les sous-nationaux (y compris les provinces/États pour les pays fédérés), le niveau des bassins et le niveau transfrontalier, le cas échéant. Ces deux parties traitent du libellé de l’objectif 6.5 &amp;#x2018;implémenter [IWRM] à tous les niveaux &amp;#x2026;&amp;#x2019;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Sources de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le gouvernement national est responsable du suivi des progrès réalisés dans la mise en œuvre de l&apos;ODD 6.5 et en est propriétaire. Le gouvernement confiera à un ministère la responsabilité principale de superviser cette enquête, qui sera chargé de coordonner le processus national de surveillance et de production de rapports de l’IWRM. Comme les questions de gestion de l&apos;eau recoupent un grand nombre de secteurs, souvent supervisés par différents ministères et autres organes administratifs au niveau national ou autre, le processus doit être inclusif. Les principales parties prenantes devraient être impliquées afin de contribuer à des réponses bien informées et objectives à l&apos;enquête. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Le ministère est invité à désigner un point focal national &amp;#x201C;IWRM&amp;#x201D;, qui peut ou non être un fonctionnaire du gouvernement. L’ONU fournira un soutien si nécessaire et possible. Les étapes suivantes ne sont proposées qu’à titre d’orientation, car c’est aux pays de décider quel processus ou processus répondreait le mieux à leurs besoins. Il convient également de noter que les étapes suivantes représentent une approche &amp;#x2018;ladder&amp;#x2019;, en ce que l’achèvement de toutes les étapes mènera généralement à un indicateur plus robuste. Toutefois, il n’est peut-être pas possible ou nécessaire que tous les pays terminent toutes les étapes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 1. Le ministère responsable ou le point focal de l’IWRM communique avec d’autres ministères/organismes pertinents pour compiler les réponses au questionnaire. Chaque option de réponse possible a un score qui sera utilisé pour calculer le score global de l’indicateur. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 2. Le projet de sondage terminé est examiné par les intervenants gouvernementaux. Ces parties prenantes pourraient inclure les acteurs des secteurs liés à l’eau, tels que l’agriculture, l’énergie, l’approvisionnement en eau et l’environnement, ainsi que la gestion de l’eau à différents niveaux administratifs. Ce processus peut être électronique (p. ex. par courriel) et/ou par le biais d’ateliers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 3. Le projet d’enquête révisé est validé lors d’un atelier multipartite. Outre les représentants du gouvernement, ces intervenants pourraient comprendre des associations d’usagers de l’eau, du secteur privé, des groupes d’intérêt qui s’intéressent à l’environnement, à l’agriculture, à la pauvreté et au milieu universitaire. Le processus proposé se fait par le biais d’un atelier, mais d’autres moyens de consultation, par exemple le courriel ou l’appel en ligne pour les présentations publiques, pourraient être envisagés. Notez que les étapes 2 et 3 pourraient être combinées si désiré. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 4. Le ministère responsable ou le point focal de l’IWRM discute avec les fonctionnaires concernés et consolide l’entrée dans une version finale. Cette version est à la base du calcul du degré de mise en œuvre de l’IWRM (0-100) pour les rapports mondiaux. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 5. Le ministère responsable soumet le score final de l’indicateur à l’Office national des statistiques chargé de compiler toutes les données cibles nationales des ODD. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Sur la base de l’enquête nationale, ONU-Eau préparera périodiquement des rapports de synthèse aux niveaux régional et mondial afin de fournir des progrès globaux dans l’atteindre l’objectif 6.5 des ODD. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Couverture temporelle : Un cycle de déclaration de trois ans est recommandé. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Processus de collecte: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les homologues officiels au niveau national supervisent le processus de validation et de consultation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;enquête a été conçue de manière à ce que l&apos;indicateur soit comparable entre les pays et les périodes. Aucun ajustement n&apos;est prévu.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendrier&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Collecte de données : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; janvier &amp;#x2013; mai 2020 (5 mois). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publication des données : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1er trimestre 2021&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fournisseurs de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les informations requises pour répondre à l&apos;enquête doivent être détenues par les fonctionnaires responsables de la gestion des ressources en eau dans le pays, et doivent être étayées par des documents officiels. Par exemple, le ministère de l&apos;eau en coordination avec le ministère de l&apos;environnement, le ministère des finances, le ministère de la planification, le ministère des terres et de l&apos;agriculture, le ministère de l&apos;industrie et des mines, etc. Voir également la section &amp;#x2018; des sources de données &amp;#x2019; ci-dessus. Au minimum, un petit groupe de fonctionnaires peut être en mesure de remplir l&apos;enquête. Cependant, ces fonctionnaires peuvent appartenir à différentes autorités gouvernementales, et une coordination sera nécessaire pour déterminer et valider les réponses à chaque question. Une participation accrue des parties prenantes gouvernementales et non gouvernementales à la validation des scores des questions permettra d&apos;obtenir un score d&apos;indicateur plus solide et facilitera le suivi des progrès dans le temps. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compilateurs de données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le PNUE et les partenaires de l&apos;ONU-Eau, dans le cadre de l&apos;initiative de l&apos;ONU-Eau sur le suivi intégré du ODD 6. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Raison d&apos;être :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur fournit une mesure directe des progrès réalisés dans la première partie de la cible 6.5 &amp;#x201C;&amp;#x2026; mettre en œuvre une gestion intégrée des ressources en eau à tous les niveaux &amp;#x2026;&amp;#x201D;. Le score de l&apos;indicateur fournit un moyen facile et compréhensible de mesurer les progrès vers la cible, avec &amp;#x2018;0&amp;#x2019; interprété comme une absence de mise en œuvre de la GIRE, et &amp;#x2018;100&amp;#x2019; interprété comme une mise en œuvre complète de la GIRE. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour faciliter l&apos;interprétation et la comparaison, les résultats des indicateurs peuvent être classés comme suit : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Degré de mise en œuvre &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Fourchette de points &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Interprétation générale pour la note globale de la GIRE &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Très élevé &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;91 - 100&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;La grande majorité des éléments de la GIRE sont pleinement mis en œuvre,
les objectifs sont systématiquement atteints et les plans et programmes sont périodiquement évalués et révisés.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Haut &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;71 - 90&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Les objectifs de la GIRE des plans et programmes sont généralement atteints,
et la couverture géographique et l&apos;engagement des parties prenantes sont généralement bons.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Medium-high&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;51 - 70&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;La capacité de mettre en œuvre les éléments de la GIRE est généralement
adéquate, et ces éléments sont généralement mis en œuvre dans le cadre de programmes à long terme.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Medium-low&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;31 - 50&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;Les éléments de la GIRE sont généralement institutionnalisés et leur mise
en œuvre est en cours. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Faible &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;11 - 30&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;La mise en œuvre des éléments de la GIRE a généralement commencé, mais
avec une adoption limitée dans tout le pays et un engagement potentiellement faible des groupes de parties prenantes. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;Très faible &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;0 - 10&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;Le développement des éléments de la GIRE n&apos;a généralement pas commencé,
ou est au point mort.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le concept de l&apos;enquête est qu&apos;elle fournit suffisamment d&apos;informations pour être réellement utile aux pays pour déterminer leurs progrès vers l&apos;objectif, et par ce biais, les différents aspects de la GIRE. Un équilibre a été recherché entre la fourniture d&apos;informations suffisantes pour couvrir les principes de base de la GIRE, et donc fournir une valeur d&apos;indicateur solide, et ne pas surcharger les pays avec des exigences de rapport inutiles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les pays sont encouragés à fournir des informations supplémentaires sur chaque question, qui peuvent aider à qualifier leur choix de score, et/ou à replacer ce score dans leur contexte national. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur 6.5.1 est étayé par l&apos;indicateur 6.5.2 &amp;#x201C;Proportion de la zone du bassin transfrontalier faisant l&apos;objet d&apos;un arrangement opérationnel de coopération dans le domaine de l&apos;eau &amp;#x201D;, qui porte directement sur la partie de la cible 6.5 &amp;#x201C; &amp;#x2026;, y compris par le biais de la coopération transfrontalière, le cas échéant &amp;#x201D;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires et limitations : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le défi de la subjectivité dans les réponses associées à ce type d&apos;enquête est abordé de plusieurs manières : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Les projets de réponse sont examinés par un certain nombre de parties prenantes
gouvernementales et non gouvernementales dans le cadre d&apos;un processus ouvert, inclusif et transparent. &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Les pays sont encouragés à fournir des informations complémentaires pour qualifier
leurs réponses et/ou les replacer dans le contexte national. &lt;/li&gt;
  Des lignes directrices sont fournies pour chacune des quatre sections principales,
chaque question et chacun des six seuils pour chaque question, afin de garantir que les réponses soient aussi objectives que possible et comparables entre les pays et entre les périodes de déclaration. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour obtenir des indicateurs solides, il faut un processus national impliquant un large éventail de parties prenantes, ce qui demandera un certain temps et des ressources. L&apos;avantage de cette approche est qu&apos;elle met en place un processus qui tient compte de la nature intégrée et indivisible des objectifs des ODD, tout en soulignant l&apos;importance de &amp;#x201C; ne pas laisser de côté. &amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Méthodologie&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Méthode de calcul :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. L&apos;enquête contient 33 questions réparties dans les quatre grandes sections décrites ci-dessus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Chaque question reçoit une note entre 0 et 100, par tranche de 10, en fonction des descriptions des seuils pour les 6 catégories suivantes : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Très faible (0)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Faible (20)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moyen-faible (40) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moyen-élevé (60) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Haut (80)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Très élevé (100)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Il convient de noter que des orientations sont fournies pour chaque seuil de chaque question, afin de garantir des résultats objectifs et comparables. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. La moyenne non pondérée des scores des questions dans chacune des quatre sections est calculée pour donner un score de 0 &amp;#x2013; 100 pour chaque section, arrondi au nombre entier le plus proche. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. Les notes de section (arrondies au nombre entier le plus proche), sont moyennées (non pondérées), et arrondies au nombre entier le plus proche, pour donner la note de l&apos;indicateur, exprimée par un nombre entre 0 et 100. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Traitement des valeurs manquantes : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Au niveau national : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur et l&apos;enquête ont été conçus pour tous les pays afin de pouvoir soumettre une valeur d&apos;indicateur. Un certain nombre de pays n&apos;ont pas soumis d&apos;enquête lors du dernier cycle de collecte de données, notamment les États fragiles/pays en conflit ou les petits États insulaires en développement. Il est donc estimé que le nombre de réponses des pays dans le cadre du processus des ODD sera supérieur à 90 %. Les estimations pour les pays n&apos;ayant pas répondu à l&apos;enquête ne seront donc pas faites. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Au niveau régional et mondial : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On estime que le nombre de réponses des pays dépassera 90 %. Cette couverture des données sera considérée comme représentative des agrégats mondiaux. Les estimations pour les pays ne répondant pas à l&apos;enquête ne seront donc pas faites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agrégats régionaux : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conformément au principe de l&apos;Agenda 2030 &amp;#x201C; qui consiste à ne laisser personne derrière &amp;#x201D;, les valeurs régionales et mondiales seront basées sur des moyennes simples et non pondérées des scores des pays. Les scores des pays seront présentés comme un nombre entier, et les moyennes régionales et mondiales seront également présentées comme un nombre entier. Les moyennes mondiales seront basées sur les valeurs des pays, et non sur les moyennes régionales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les valeurs régionales peuvent être rassemblées par les organismes régionaux responsables des ressources en eau dans la région, tels que le Conseil ministériel africain sur l&apos;eau (AMCOW), l&apos;Agence européenne pour l&apos;environnement (AEE) et la Commission économique et sociale des Nations Unies pour l&apos;Asie occidentale (CESAO).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Méthodes et orientations mises à la disposition des pays pour la compilation des données au niveau national :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Points focaux nationaux sélectionnés par chaque pays. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La collecte des données se fait par le biais d&apos;un simple questionnaire de
33 questions, au format MS Word. Les réponses à chaque question sont données sur une échelle de 0 &amp;#x2013; 100, par incréments de 10. Les descriptions des seuils sont données pour six seuils entre 0 et 100. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les points focaux nationaux sont chargés de coordonner un processus national
visant à engager les parties prenantes gouvernementales et non gouvernementales, selon le contexte de chaque pays, à élaborer des projets de réponses et à finaliser les réponses. Cela peut se faire par courrier électronique, ateliers et avis en ligne. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les documents suivants sont disponibles pour les points focaux nationaux en
7 langues (anglais, espagnol, français, arabe, russe, chinois, portugais), sur le site &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&lt;/a&gt; : l&apos;enquête (MS Word), un guide de suivi détaillé, une présentation PowerPoint et un enregistrement vidéo. En outre, les points focaux peuvent accéder aux documents suivants : les enquêtes de référence de 2017 et les résumés des résultats de 2 pages (pour 172 pays) ; et les rapports des ateliers de 2017 (pour 36 pays). &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des explications détaillées sont fournies dans le guide de suivi et dans l&apos;enquête elle-même. L&apos;enquête contient : une introduction et une explication générales ; un glossaire ; une introduction et un glossaire dans chacune des quatre sections ; des descriptions des seuils pour six seuils pour chaque question ; et un certain nombre de notes de bas de page pour expliquer certains aspects des questions ou des descriptions des seuils. Tous les documents peuvent être téléchargés à partir du site &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&lt;/a&gt;. En outre, un service d&apos;assistance dédié est disponible à tout moment pour fournir une assistance. Le service d&apos;assistance est accessible par courrier électronique &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;iwrmsdg651@un.org&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Assurance de la qualité : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les lignes directrices suivantes sont à la disposition de toutes les personnes impliquées dans l&apos;assurance qualité pour 6.5.1. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Processus : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Désigner la personne responsable de l&apos;AQ pour une réponse d&apos;un pays une fois
qu&apos;elle est soumise pour la première fois. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accuser réception et informer le pays du processus d&apos;assurance qualité. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mettre à jour la feuille de calcul de l&apos;AQ, en indiquant la date de réception
et l&apos;auteur de la soumission. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Télécharger le projet d&apos;enquête (MS Word) dans le dossier Dropbox. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Effectuez TOUS les contrôles décrits ci-dessous. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;En cas de divergence, veuillez vous adresser à vos collègues du PNUE-DHI.
&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Une fois l&apos;action convenue, répondre aux pays. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Effectuer toutes les vérifications sur chaque version ultérieure du questionnaire
jusqu&apos;à ce que tous les problèmes de qualité soient résolus et que le questionnaire soit marqué &amp;#x2018; final &amp;#x2019;. 850] &amp;#xA0; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Vérifications : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Point focal : Confirmez que la personne qui soumet la demande est le point
focal national officiel. Si ce n&apos;est pas le cas, toute réponse doit également ajouter le point focal national dans le CC. &amp;#xA0; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Réponses aux questions : &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Réponses à toutes les questions. Selon les directives officielles, il convient
de répondre à toutes les questions (soit par une note, soit par s.o.). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les notes vont de 0 à 100, par tranches de 10. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vérifiez que s.o. (sans objet) est utilisé de manière appropriée. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Champs de texte libre : Dans les champs &amp;#x201C;&amp;#x201C;Description du statut
&amp;#x201D; et &amp;#x201C;Avancée &amp;#x201D; pour chaque question, vérifiez que le texte libre a un sens dans le contexte de la note (et vice versa). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Calculs : Vérifiez que les moyennes des sections et la note finale sont arrondies
au nombre entier le plus proche et corrigez-les, en utilisant la feuille de calcul de l&apos;assurance qualité sur Dropbox. Remplissez les réponses données dans les colonnes M - AX, et les différences sont calculées automatiquement dans les colonnes C &amp;#x2013; G. Si la différence est supérieure à +/- 0,5, les cellules sont automatiquement surlignées en rouge en utilisant un formatage conditionnel. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Comparer avec la ligne de base de 2017 : Si possible, comparer avec l&apos;enquête
de référence de 2017 (pour 172 pays) et en discuter avec des collègues si nécessaire. &amp;#xA0; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Questions transfrontalières : &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Voir le tableau &amp;#x2018;bassins transfrontaliers &amp;#x2019; de l&apos;annexe B. Une
liste complète des bassins transfrontaliers peut être trouvée ici : &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;http://twap-rivers.org/indicators/Report.ashx?type=IndicatorResultsSummary&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allez à la dernière feuille de travail/onglet pour voir les pays de chaque
bassin. Consultez également les cartes ici : &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;http://twap-rivers.org/indicators/&lt;/a&gt; pour voir si le bassin est susceptible d&apos;être important pour ce pays, ou s&apos;il n&apos;y a qu&apos;une petite partie du bassin dans leur pays (auquel cas ils peuvent ne pas l&apos;énumérer). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vérifiez les questions transfrontalières : 1.2c, 2.2e ; 3.2d ; et 4.2c, et
voyez si elles ont un sens dans le contexte du pays. Les pays insulaires doivent donner &amp;#x2018;n/a &amp;#x2019; pour toutes ces questions &lt;/li&gt;. &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toutes les données sont fournies par chaque pays et sont donc entièrement détenues par les pays. Chaque pays entreprend une consultation des parties prenantes, à un niveau approprié compte tenu des ressources et des capacités dont il dispose, afin de s&apos;assurer que les données sont acceptées et appropriées dans le pays. Des conseils sur les processus de consultation sont fournis dans le guide de suivi et par le biais du powerpoint et de la vidéo d&apos;introduction pour les points focaux (tous les documents sont disponibles sur &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilité des données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nombre total de pays : 172 (89 % des États membres des Nations unies) (PNUE 2018) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La région est couverte (groupements régionaux de la DSNU) : suivi du nombre de pays avec des données / total des pays de la région (à partir de 2017) ; suivi du pourcentage de pays avec des données.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Australie et Nouvelle-Zélande : 2/2 ; 100% &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asie centrale et du Sud : 10/14 ; 71% &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asie de l&apos;Est et du Sud-Est : 13/16 ; 81% &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe et Amérique du Nord : 43/45 ; 96% &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amérique latine et Caraïbes : 29/33 ; 89% &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afrique du Nord et Asie occidentale : 22/23 ; 96% &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Océanie (hors Australie et Nouvelle-Zélande) : 8/12 ; 67% &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afrique subsaharienne : 45/48 ; 94% &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monde : 172/193 : 89%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Séries chronologiques : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pré-SDG : 2008, 2012 (ONU-Eau 2008, 2012). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ODD période : 2017 (UNEP 2018). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tous sur le portail GIRE (&lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Désaggrégation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La force de l&apos;indicateur réside dans la possibilité de désagréger le score du pays dans les quatre dimensions principales de la GIRE, et en fonction des questions de l&apos;enquête. Cela permet aux pays d&apos;évaluer rapidement les aspects de la GIRE qui progressent bien et ceux qui nécessitent des efforts accrus pour atteindre l&apos;objectif. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La nature de la cible, de l&apos;indicateur et de l&apos;enquête ne se prête pas à une ventilation par sexe, tranche d&apos;âge, revenu, etc. Cependant, l&apos;égalité sociale fait partie intégrante de la GIRE, et certaines questions portent directement sur des aspects tels que le genre, les groupes vulnérables, la couverture géographique et la large participation des parties prenantes au développement et à la gestion des ressources en eau. Ces questions donnent une indication de la situation nationale et infranationale en matière d&apos;égalité sociale. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sources des divergences : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comme décrit dans la section &amp;#x201C; Sources de données&amp;#x201D; ci-dessous, il n&apos;y aura pas de données estimées au niveau international, toutes les données devant être produites par les pays.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Références&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il contient le dernier instrument d&apos;enquête, le guide de suivi et tous les documents d&apos;appui. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Références:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- AMCOW 2018 : Rapport sur l&apos;état de la mise en œuvre de la gestion des ressources en eau en Afrique : un rapport régional pour l&apos;indicateur 6.5.1 du ODD sur la mise en œuvre de la GIRE. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- PNUE 2018 : Progrès en matière de gestion intégrée des ressources en eau. Base de référence mondiale pour l&apos;ODD 6 Indicateur 6.5.1 : degré de mise en œuvre de la GIRE. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Commission économique et sociale des Nations Unies pour l&apos;Asie occidentale (2019). Rapport sur l&apos;état d&apos;avancement de la mise en œuvre de la gestion intégrée des ressources en eau dans la région arabe : Progrès sur l&apos;indicateur ODD 6.5.1. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Initiative de l&apos;ONU-Eau sur la surveillance intégrée du SDG 6 &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt;http://sdg6data.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- ONU-Eau, 2016 : Les liens entre l&apos;eau et l&apos;assainissement dans le cadre de l&apos;Agenda 2030 pour le développement durable. Genève. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 6: Обеспечение наличия и рационального использования водных ресурсов и санитарии для всех&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 6.5: К 2030 году обеспечить комплексное управление водными ресурсами на всех уровнях, в том числе, при необходимости, на основе трансграничного сотрудничества&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 6.5.1: Степень внедрения комплексного управления водными ресурсами (от 0 до 100)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Последнее обновление: 7 ноября 2019 года&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Связанные показатели &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Поскольку показатель отражает степень внедрения благоприятной среды для лучшего управления водными ресурсами, он напрямую поддерживает другие конечные цели в рамках ЦУР 6 (6.1 - 6.6). Это достигается путем предоставления странам дополнительной информации о контексте и возможном объяснении прогресса в достижении других целей, а также указывает на препятствия и факторы, способствующие достижению других целей. Он также напрямую поддерживает средства достижения целей 6.a и 6.b, поскольку дезагрегирование возможно для получения данных по финансированию (6.a) и участию заинтересованных сторон (6.b). Помимо ЦУР 6, показатель 6.5.1 связан с рядом других задач в рамках ЦУР, поскольку комплексное управление водными ресурсами связано с интеграцией требований и воздействий на водные ресурсы и связанные с водными ресурсами экосистемы со стороны ряда различных ЦУР и их задач, в том числе: бедность (1,4); сельское хозяйство (2,3); образование (4,7); пол (5,5); энергетика (7.1); работа (8.5); равенство (10.2); городские районы (11,3); изменение климата (13.2); экосистемы (15,9); управление (16.3, 16.5 - 16.7) (Механизм «ООН – Водные ресурсы» за 2016 год).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Институциональная информация &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Организация(и): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Программа Организации Объединенных Наций по окружающей среде (ЮНЕП) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель 6.5.1 - «степень внедрения комплексного управления водными ресурсами (0-100)». Он отражает этапы разработки и внедрения комплексного управления водными ресурсами (КУВР) по шкале от 0 до 100 баллов по шести категориям (см. раздел «Обоснование»). Значение показателя рассчитывается на основе вопросника странового обследования, состоящего из 33 вопросов, при этом каждый вопрос оценивается по одной и той же шкале от 0 до 100 баллов. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Определение КУВР основано на международно согласованном определении и использует универсальные принципы. КУВР было официально учреждено в 1992 году и определяется как &quot;процесс, который способствует скоординированному развитию и управлению водными, земельными и связанными с ними ресурсами с целью максимального повышения экономического и социального благосостояния на справедливой основе без ущерба для устойчивости жизненно важных экосистем&quot;. (Глобальное водное партнерство (ГВП) 2010 год). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Метод основан на официальных отчетах ООН о состоянии КУВР за 2008 и 2012 годы Йоханнесбургского плана выполнения решений Всемирного саммита ООН по устойчивому развитию (1992 год).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Понятие КУВР состоит из 4 основных разделов, каждый из которых представляет собой ключевой аспект КУВР: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 1. Благоприятная среда: сюда входят правила, законы, планы и стратегии, которые создают &quot;благоприятную среду&quot; для КУВР. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 2. Институты и участие: включает контингент и роли политических, социальных, экономических и административных институтов, которые помогают поддерживать внедрение КУВР. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 3. Инструменты управления: инструменты и действия, которые позволяют лицам, принимающим решения, и пользователям делать рациональный и осознанный выбор между альтернативными действиями. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 4. Финансирование: составление бюджета и финансирование из различных источников, предоставляемые и используемые для развития и управления водными ресурсами. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель основан на национальном обследовании, включающем эти четыре основных раздела. Каждый раздел разделен на две части: вопросы, касающиеся &quot;Национального уровня&quot; и &quot;Других уровней&quot; соответственно. Часть &quot;Другие уровни&quot; включает субнациональный (включая провинции / штаты для стран с федеративным устройством), бассейновый и трансграничный уровень, в зависимости от ситуации. Эти две части касаются формулировки Целевого показателя 6.5 «Реализация [комплексного управления водными ресурсами (КУВР)] на всех уровнях». &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Мониторинг прогресса в достижении ЦУР 6.5 находится в ведении правительства страны и является его обязанностью. Правительство назначает министерство, несущее основную ответственность за надзор за проведением этого обследования, которому будет предложено взять на себя ответственность за координацию национального процесса мониторинга и отчетности КУВР. Поскольку вопросы управления водными ресурсами затрагивают широкий круг секторов, которые часто контролируются различными министерствами и другими административными органами на национальном или других уровнях, то этот процесс должен быть инклюзивным, т.е. проходить с участием всех заинтересованных сторон. Необходимо привлечь основные заинтересованные стороны с тем, чтобы они внесли свой вклад в формулирование достаточно информативных и объективных ответов в рамках обследования. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Министерству предлагается назначить национального &quot;координатора по КУВР&quot;, который может быть или не быть государственным чиновником. ООН будет оказывать поддержку там, где это необходимо и возможно. Нижеследующие шаги предлагаются только в качестве руководства, поскольку страны сами решают, какой процесс или процессы лучше всего удовлетворят их потребности. Также следует отметить, что указанные шаги представляют собой &quot;лестничный&quot; подход, в котором выполнение всех шагов обычно приводит к получению более надежного показателя. Однако выполнение всех этапов может оказаться невозможным или необязательным для всех стран. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 1. Ответственное министерство или координатор КУВР связывается с другими соответствующими министерствами / ведомствами для формулирования ответов на вопросник. Для каждого возможного варианта ответа существует оценка, которая будет использоваться для расчета общей балльной оценки показателя. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 2. Заполненный проект отчета об обследовании рассматривается заинтересованными сторонами в правительстве. Эти заинтересованные стороны могут включать тех, кто вовлечен в секторы, имеющие отношение к водным ресурсам, такие как сельское хозяйство, энергетика, водоснабжение и окружающая среда, а также управление водными ресурсами на различных административных уровнях. Этот процесс может реализовываться в электронном формате (например, с использованием электронной почты) и / или посредством проведения семинаров. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 3. Проверенный проект отчета об обследовании утверждается на семинаре с участием многих заинтересованных сторон. Помимо представителей правительства, эти заинтересованные стороны могут включать ассоциации водопользователей, частный сектор, заинтересованные группы, например, связанные с окружающей средой, сельским хозяйством, вопросами бедности и представителей научных кругов. Предлагаемый процесс - семинар, но могут быть рассмотрены альтернативные способы проведения консультаций, например: посредством использования электронной почты или онлайн-звонков для публичного представления материалов. Обратите внимание, что шаги 2 и 3 при желании можно объединить. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 4. Ответственное министерство или координатор КУВР проводит обсуждение с соответствующими официальными лицами и объединяет полученные данные в окончательную версию. Эта версия является основой для расчета степени внедрения КУВР (0-100) для глобальной отчетности. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 5. Ответственное министерство представляет окончательную оценку показателя в национальное статистическое управление, отвечающее за сбор всех национальных данных по целевым показателям ЦУР. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; На основе национального обследования Механизм «ООН-Водные ресурсы» будет периодически подготавливать сводные отчеты для регионального и глобального уровней, чтобы обеспечить общий прогресс в достижении цели 6.5 ЦУР. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Временной охват: рекомендуется применять трехлетний цикл отчетности.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Официальные партнеры на страновом уровне контролируют процесс валидации и проведения консультаций. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Обследование было разработано таким образом, чтобы показатель был сопоставим по странам и временным периодам. Никаких корректировок не предвидится. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Календарь &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Сбор данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Январь - май 2020 года (5 месяцев). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Выпуск данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 1 квартал 2021 года &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Поставщики данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ожидается, что информация, необходимая для заполнения отчета об обследовании, будет подтверждаться государственными чиновниками, ответственными за управление водными ресурсами в стране, и будет подкрепляться официальной документацией. Например. Министерством водных ресурсов в сотрудничестве с Министерством окружающей среды, Министерством финансов, Министерством планирования, Министерством земель и сельского хозяйства, Министерством промышленности и горнодобывающей отрасли и т. д. См. также раздел &quot;Источники данных&quot; выше. Как минимум, небольшая группа должностных лиц может заполнить отчет об обследовании. Однако эти государственные служащие могут принадлежать к разным государственным органам и для формулирования и валидации ответов на каждый вопрос потребуется координация между ними. Более активное участие государственных и негосударственных заинтересованных сторон в валидации балльных оценок ответов на вопросы приведет к более надежной балльной оценке показателей и облегчит отслеживание прогресса в динамике по времени. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Составители данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Партнеры ЮНЕП и Механизма «ООН-водные ресурсы» в рамках инициативы «ООН-водные ресурсы» по комплексному мониторингу достижения ЦУР 6. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель обеспечивает прямую оценку хода выполнения первой части задачи 6.5 «...обеспечить комплексное управление водными ресурсами на всех уровнях...». Балльная оценка показателя обеспечивает простой и понятный способ оценки прогресса в достижении цели, которая при значении &quot;0&quot; интерпретируется как отсутствие реализации КУВР, а при значении &quot;100&quot; интерпретируется как полная реализация КУВР. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для облегчения интерпретации и сравнения результаты разработки показателя можно разделить на следующие категории: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Степень реализации &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Диапазон балльных оценок &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Общая интерпретация полной оценки КУВР &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Очень высокая &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 91 - 100 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Подавляющее большинство элементов КУВР полностью реализовано, цели последовательно достигаются, а планы и программы периодически оцениваются и пересматриваются. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Высокая &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 71–90 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Цели планов и программ КУВР в целом достигаются, а географический охват и взаимодействие с заинтересованными сторонами в основном хорошие.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Средне-высокая &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 51–70 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Потенциал для реализации элементов ИУВР в целом достаточен, и элементы в основном реализуются в рамках долгосрочных программ. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Средне-низкая &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 31–50 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Элементы КУВР в целом институционализированы, и процесс реализации продолжается.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Низкая &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 11–30 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Внедрение элементов КУВР в целом началось, но с ограниченным распространением по стране и потенциально низким вовлечением групп заинтересованных сторон. &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Очень низкая &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 0–10 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Разработка элементов КУВР вообще не началась или застопорилась.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Идея обследования заключается в том, что оно предоставляет достаточно информации, которая будет иметь реальную значимость для стран при определении прогресса в достижении цели, а, следовательно, и в различных аспектах КУВР. Был найден баланс между предоставлением информации, достаточной для охвата основных принципов КУВР и, таким образом, предоставляя надежное значение показателя, и отсутствием излишней нагрузки на страны, которая может быть обусловлена ничем не оправданными излишними требованиями к отчетности. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Странам рекомендуется предоставлять дополнительную информацию по каждому вопросу, которая может помочь уточнить их выбор балльной оценки и / или учесть этот балл в контексте своей страны. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель 6.5.1 поддерживается показателем 6.5.2 «Доля трансграничных водных бассейнов, охваченных действующими договоренностями о сотрудничестве в области водопользования», который непосредственно касается части задачи 6.5 &quot;...в том числе, при необходимости, на основе трансграничного сотрудничества&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Проблема субъективности в ответах, связанных с этим типом обследования, решается несколькими способами: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Проекты ответов рассматриваются рядом правительственных и неправительственных заинтересованных сторон в рамках открытого, инклюзивного и прозрачного процесса. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Странам рекомендуется предоставлять дополнительную информацию, чтобы уточнить свои ответы и / или изложить их в национальном контексте. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Руководящие принципы представлены для каждого из четырех основных разделов, каждого вопроса и каждого из шести пороговых значений для каждого отдельного вопроса, чтобы ответы были максимально объективными и были сопоставимы как между странами, так и между отчетными периодами. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для достижения надежных результатов по показателям требуется организовать страновой процесс с участием широкого круга заинтересованных сторон, что потребует определенного количества времени и ресурсов. Преимущество этого подхода состоит в том, что он вводит в действие процесс, который учитывает интегрированный и неделимый характер целей ЦУР, а также подчеркивает важность принципа «никто не должен быть оставлен позади.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 1. Обследование включает в себя 33 вопроса, разделенных на четыре основных раздела, описанных выше. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 2. Каждому вопросу присваивается балльная оценка от 0 до 100 баллов с шагом в 10 баллов в соответствии с описанием пороговых значений для следующих 6 категорий: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Очень низкая (0) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Низкая (20) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Средне-низкая (40) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Средне-высокая (60) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Высокая (80) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Очень высокая (100) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Обратите внимание, что руководство предоставляется для каждого порогового значения по каждому вопросу с тем, чтобы обеспечить объективные и сопоставимые результаты. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 3. Невзвешенное среднее значение баллов за ответы на вопросы в каждом из четырех разделов рассчитывается так, чтобы получить оценку 0 - 100 баллов для каждого раздела, округленную до ближайшего целого числа. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 4. Баллы по разделам (округленные до ближайшего целого числа), усредняются (невзвешенные) и округляются до ближайшего целого числа, чтобы получить балл показателя, выраженный числом от 0 до 100. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Показатель и обследование были разработаны для всех стран для того , чтобы иметь возможность рассчитать значение показателя. В число стран, которые не представили отчеты по обследованию в рамках последнего раунда сбора данных, относятся нестабильные государства / страны, находящиеся в состоянии конфликта, или малые островные развивающиеся государства. Таким образом, оценочно количество ответов стран по процессу достижения ЦУР превысит 90-процентный уровень. Поэтому оценки для стран, не представивших отчеты по обследованию, производиться не будут.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; По оценкам, количество ответов стран превысит 90-процентный уровень. Этот охват данных будет считаться репрезентативным для глобальных агрегатов. Поэтому оценки для стран, не представивших отчет по обследованию, производиться не будут.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Региональные агрегаты:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В соответствии с принципом Повестки дня на период до 2030 года &quot;никто не должен быть оставлен позади&quot;, региональные и глобальные значения будут основаны на простых невзвешенных средних балльных показателях стран. Баллы по странам будут представлены в виде целого числа и средние региональные и глобальные показатели также будут представлены в виде целого числа. Для расчета глобальных средних значений будут использоваться значения стран, а не средние региональные значения. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Региональные значения могут быть получены региональными органами, ответственными за водные ресурсы в регионе, такими как Африканский совет министров по водным ресурсам (AMCOW), Европейское агентство по окружающей среде (EEA) и Экономическая и социальная комиссия Организации Объединенных Наций для Западной Азии (ЭСКЗА). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Доступные странам методы и руководства для составления данных на национальном уровне: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Национальные координаторы выбираются каждой страной. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Сбор данных осуществляется с помощью простого вопросника, состоящего из 33 вопросов в формате MS Word. Ответы на каждый вопрос оцениваются по шкале от 0 до 100 баллов с шагом 10 баллов. Описание пороговых значений дано для шести пороговых значений от 0 до 100 баллов. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Национальные координаторы несут ответственность за согласование национального процесса по привлечению правительственных и неправительственных заинтересованных сторон, в зависимости от контекста каждой страны, в разработку проектов ответов и окончательное формулирование ответов. Это работа может быть организована с использованием электронной почты, путем организации семинаров и онлайн-уведомлений. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Следующие материалы доступны для национальных координаторов на 7 языках (английском, испанском, французском, арабском, русском, китайском, португальском) по адресу &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt; http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org &lt;/a&gt;: обследование (в формате MS Word); подробное руководство по мониторингу; презентация в формате PowerPoint и видеозапись. Кроме того, координаторы могут получить доступ к следующим материалам: базовые исследования 2017 года и двухстраничные сводки результатов (по 172 странам); и отчеты семинаров за 2017 год (по 36 странам). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Подробные пояснения приведены в руководстве по мониторингу и в материалах самого обследования. Обследование содержит: общее введение и объяснение; глоссарий; введение и глоссарий в каждом из четырех разделов; описания пороговых значений для шести пороговых значений для каждого вопроса; и ряд сносок, объясняющих аспекты вопросов или описаний пороговых значений. Все материалы можно скачать с &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt; http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org &lt;/a&gt;. Кроме того, специальная служба поддержки доступна для оказания помощи в любое время. Служба поддержки доступна по адресу электронной почты &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt; iwrmsdg651@un.org &lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обеспечение качества: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Следующие рекомендации по обеспечению качества доступны всем лицам, участвующим в обеспечении качества показателя 6.5.1. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Процесс:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Назначение человека, ответственного за обеспечение качества ответа от страны, когда ответ будет готовиться к отправке в первый раз. &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Подтверждение получения и информирование страны о процессе контроля качества. &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Обновление таблицы контроля качества с указанием даты получения и того, кто отправил материал. &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Загрузка черновика отчета по обследованию (MS Word) в папку Dropbox. &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Выполнение ВСЕХ проверок, описанных ниже. &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Если есть какие-либо расхождения, обратитесь к коллегам из UNEP-DHI (Программа ООН по окружающей среде – Датский институт гидравлики (ЮНЕП-ДИГ)). &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Направление ответа странам после согласования действий. &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Проведение всех проверок каждой последующей версии вопросника, пока все проблемы с качеством не будут решены и вопросник не будет помечен как &quot;завершен&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Проверки: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Координатор: подтверждение, что лицо, представившее отчет, является официальным национальным координатором. Если нет, то в любом ответе в копии следует также добавить адрес национального координатора.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Ответы на вопросы: &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Подготовить ответы на все вопросы. Официальное руководство гласит, что на все вопросы следует отвечать (либо баллами, либо н / п). &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Баллы в диапазоне от 0 до 100 с шагом 10 баллов. &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Убедитесь, что н / п (не применимо) используется надлежащим образом. &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Поля произвольного текста: в &quot;Описании статуса&quot; и &quot;Путь вперед&quot; поля для каждого вопроса убедитесь, что свободный текст имеет смысл в контексте оценки (и наоборот). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Вычисления. Убедитесь, что средние и окончательные оценки по разделам округлены до ближайшего целого числа и верны, используя таблицу контроля качества в Dropbox. Заполните данные ответы в столбцах M - AX, и различия будут рассчитаны автоматически в столбцах C - G. Если разница больше +/- 0,5, ячейки автоматически выделяются красным цветом с использованием условного форматирования. &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Сравните с базовым показателем 2017 года: если возможно, сравните со значением базового обследования 2017 года (имеются по 172 странам) и при необходимости обсудите с коллегами.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Трансграничные проблемы: &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Проверьте таблицу &quot;трансграничные бассейны&quot; в Приложении B. Полный список трансграничных бассейнов можно найти здесь: &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt; http://twap-rivers.org/indicators/Report.ashx?type=IndicatorResultsSummary &lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Переход на последнюю таблицу / вкладку, чтобы увидеть страны в каждом бассейне. Также проверьте карты здесь: &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt; http://twap-rivers.org/indicators/ &lt;/a&gt;, чтобы узнать, может ли бассейн иметь важное значение для этой страны или есть только небольшая часть бассейна в их стране (в этом случае они не могут ее включать). &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Проверьте трансграничные вопросы: 1.2c, 2.2e; 3.2d; и 4.2c, и посмотрите, имеют ли они смысл в контексте страны. Островные страны должны представлять &quot;н / п&quot; по всем этим вопросам. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Все данные предоставлены каждой страной и, следовательно, полностью принадлежат странам. Каждая страна проводит консультации с заинтересованными сторонами на уровне, который соответствует имеющимся у них ресурсам и возможностям, чтобы гарантировать, что данные имеют адекватное признание и право собственности в стране. Рекомендации по процессам консультаций представлены в руководстве по мониторингу, а также во вводной презентации и видео для координаторов (все материалы доступны на &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt; http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org &lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Общее количество стран: 172 (89% государств-членов ООН) (ЮНЕП 2018 года) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Следующие данные относятся к региону (региональные группы СОООН): затем следует количество стран с данными / общее количество стран в регионе (по состоянию на 2017 год); затем следует процент стран, по которым имеются данные. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Австралия и Новая Зеландия: 2/2; 100% &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Центральная и Южная Азия: 10/14; 71% &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Восточная и Юго-Восточная Азия: 13/16; 81% &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Европа и Северная Америка: 43/45; 96% &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Латинская Америка и Карибский бассейн: 29/33; 89% &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Северная Африка и Западная Азия: 22/23; 96% &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Океания (за исключением Австралии и Новой Зеландии): 8/12; 67% &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Страны Африки к югу от Сахары: 45/48; 94% &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Мир: 172/193: 89% &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Предварительные ЦУР: 2008, 2012 годы (Механизм «ООН — Водные ресурсы» 2008, 2012 годы). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Период ЦУР: 2017 год (ЮНЕП 2018 год). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Все на портале КУВР (&lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt; http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org &lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Сильной стороной показателя является возможность дезагрегировать оценку страны по четырем основным параметрам КУВР, а также по вопросам, содержащимся в обследовании. Это позволяет странам быстро оценить, какие аспекты КУВР успешно развиваются, а какие требуют дополнительных усилий для достижения цели. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Характер цели, показателя и обследования не поддается дезагрегации по полу, возрастным группам, доходам и т. д. Однако социальное равенство является неотъемлемой частью КУВР, и есть вопросы, которые напрямую касаются таких вопросов, как пол, уязвимые группы, географический охват и широкое участие заинтересованных сторон в развитии и управлении водными ресурсами. Эти вопросы дают представление о национальной и субнациональной ситуации в отношении социального равенства.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Как описано в разделе &quot;Источники данных&quot; ниже, международных оценок данных не будет, а все данные будут предоставлены странами. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt; http://iwrmdataportal.unepdhi.org &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Здесь содержится новейший инструмент обследования, руководство по мониторингу и вся сопроводительная документация. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Ссылки: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; - Африканский совет министров по водным ресурсам (AMCOW) 2018 год: Отчет о состоянии внедрения управления водными ресурсами в Африке: региональный отчет по показателю 6.5.1 ЦУР по реализации КУВР. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; - Программа ООН по окружающей среде (ЮНЕП) 2018 год: Прогресс в области комплексного управления водными ресурсами. Глобальный базовый уровень для показателя 6.5.1 ЦУР 6: степень реализации КУВР. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; - Экономическая и социальная комиссия Организации Объединенных Наций для Западной Азии (2019 год). Отчет о состоянии внедрения комплексного управления водными ресурсами в арабском регионе: прогресс в отношении показателя 6.5.1 ЦУР. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; - Инициатива &quot;ООН Водные ресурсы&quot; по комплексному мониторингу достижения ЦУР 6. &lt;a href=&quot;about:blank&quot;&gt; http://sdg6data.org &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; - Механизм «ООН — Водные ресурсы», 2016 год: Взаимосвязь водоснабжения и санитарии в Повестке дня в области устойчивого развития на период до 2030 года. Женева. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
