<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 6-b-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 6: Ensure availability and sustainable management of water and sanitation for all&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 6.b: Support and strengthen the participation of local communities in improving water and sanitation management&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 6.b.1: Proportion of local administrative units with established and operational policies and procedures for participation of local communities in water and sanitation management&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2017-07-11&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;6.5:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number of deaths, missing persons and persons affected by disaster per 100,000 people [a]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15.9:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number of deaths, missing persons and persons affected by disaster per 100,000 people [a]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.5 (implement integrated water resources management at all levels, including transboundary cooperation as appropriate) 15.9 (integrate ecosystem and biodiversity values into national and local planning, development processes, poverty reduction strategies and accounts)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;World Health Organization (WHO)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations Environment Programme (UNEP)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;World Health Organization (WHO)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations Environment Programme (UNEP)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator assesses the percentage of local administrative units (as defined by the national government) that have an established and operational mechanism by which individuals and communities can meaningfully contribute to decisions and directions about water and sanitation management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator Proportion of local administrative units with established and operational policies and procedures for participation of local communities in water and sanitation management is currently being measured by the Proportion of countries with clearly defined procedures in law or policy for participation by service users/communities in planning program in water and sanitation management, and hygiene promotion and the Proportion of countries with high level of users/communities participating in planning programs in water and sanitation management, and hygiene promotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stakeholder participation is essential to ensure the sustainability of water and sanitation management options over time, e.g. the choice of appropriate solutions for a given social and economic context, and the full understanding of the impacts of a certain development decision. Defining the procedures in policy or law for the participation of local communities is vital to ensure needs of all the community is met, including the most vulnerable and also encourages ownership of schemes which in turn contributes to their sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local administrative units refers to non-overlapping sub-districts, municipalities, communes, or other local community-level units covering both urban and rural areas to be defined by the government. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Policies and procedures for participation of local communities in water and sanitation management would define a formal mechanism to ensure participation of users in planning water and sanitation activities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A policy or procedure is considered to be established if the mechanism for participation of local communities is defined in law or has been formally approved and published. It is considered to be operational if the policy or procedure is being implemented, with appropriate funding in place and with means for verifying that participation took place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2018;Water and sanitation&amp;#x2019; includes all areas of management related to each of the targets under SDG 6, namely: water supply (6.1), sanitation and hygiene (6.2), wastewater treatment and ambient water quality (6.3), efficiency and sustainable use (6.4), integrated water resources management (6.5) and water-related ecosystems (6.6).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UN-Water Global Analysis and Assessment of Sanitation and Drinking-Water (GLAAS) provides information on governance, monitoring, human resources, and financing in the water, sanitation, and hygiene (WASH) sector. The UN-Water GLAAS survey is currently conducted on a biennial basis, led by WHO, and collected data from 94 countries (predominantly low and lower-middle income countries) in the most recent cycle in 2013-2014. The scope of the question on community and user participation has been expanded beyond WASH for the 2016-17 GLAAS cycle to address all targets in SDG 6, including water quality, water rights/allocation, water resource management, and the status of water-related ecosystems. GLAAS has completed three full cycles (2009-2010, 2011-2012, and 2013-2014), as well as a pilot conducted in 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National governments participating in the GLAAS survey fill out the questionnaire, preferably supported by a multi-stakeholder review. Although one ministry leads the process, it is often the case that many different ministries and departments must be involved in the process in order to obtain the data required to complete the questionnaire. A GLAAS national focal person supports the lead ministry to coordinate data collection, to compile the national response to the questionnaire, and to lead on the process of data validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data will be complemented by Integrated Water Resources Management (IWRM) reporting in SDG target 6.5 (for wastewater and water quality, water efficiency, water resource management, and the status of water-related ecosystems) (UNEP 2016). A key component of IWRM is community participation and management of water resources at the local level. The analysis of IWRM has been done in the past by UN-Water in 2008 (led by UN-DESA) and in 2012 (led by UNEP, UNDP, GWP and SIWI) as requested by the UN Commission for Sustainable Development (UN-Water 2008, 2012).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OECD Water Governance Initiative (WGI), a technical platform gathering 100+ members from the public, private and non-for-profit sectors, is currently developing a set of Water Governance Indicators, within the implementation strategy of the OECD Principles on Water Governance (OECD 2015a). The Water Governance Indicators are expected to be able to provide additional information on local participation on the basis of an indicators system proposed in OECD (2015b) for measuring &amp;#x201C;stakeholder engagement for inclusive water governance&amp;#x201D;. An indicator providing metrics on local participation will be developed and tested by 2017. Data will be made available through interactive platforms and databases in a format to foster policy dialogue and peer learning by 2018. A dedicated publication on &amp;#x201C;Water Governance at a Glance&amp;#x201D; will be launched at the 8th World Water Forum in Brasilia (2018).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National governments participating in the GLAAS survey fill out the questionnaire, preferably supported by a multi-stakeholder review. Although one ministry leads the process (e.g. Ministry of Water, Ministry of Environment, etc. depending on country), it is often the case that many different ministries and departments must be involved in the process in order to obtain the data required to complete the questionnaire. A GLAAS national focal person supports the lead ministry to coordinate data collection, to compile the national response to the questionnaire, and to lead on the process of data validation. For each GLAAS submission, information on the country processes are collected (number of ministries involved, whether a national meeting was held to support the filling of the questionnaire, stakeholder validation, use of documentation, etc.) Once received, the country submission undergoes a thorough data validation process, which is often an iterative process requiring communication and feedback with regional and country counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Countries are also requested to provide consent to publish individual, validated data responses as supplied to GLAAS. Thus through the data collection, validation and consultation processes, the results are expected to be comparable and no further adjustments are foreseen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The current round of UN-Water Global Analysis and Assessment of Sanitation and Drinking-Water (GLAAS) has been launched and data will be available by end-2016. (From NA to NA)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Q1 2017 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ministries with responsibilities related to water supply and sanitation, agriculture, water resources development and management, and environment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Name:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHO, OECD and UNEP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Description:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHO, with support from OECD and UNEP&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Defining the procedures in policy or law for the participation of local communities is vital to ensure the needs of all the community are met, including the most vulnerable and also encourages ownership of schemes which in turn contributes to their sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A low value of this indicator would suggest that participation of local communities in water and sanitation management is low, whereas a high value would indicate high levels of participation, indicating greater ownership and a higher likelihood of sustainable delivery and management of water and sanitation services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data on local administrative units with established and operational policies and procedures for local participation is being collected through the current cycle of GLAAS, and will be available by end-2016. Until then, the presence of policies and procedures as reported at the national level for different subsectors will be reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional data, including data measuring local participation from the OECD Water Governance Indicators and administrative data, will be progressively included in the calculation of the indicator as they become available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UN-Water Global Analysis and Assessment of Sanitation and Drinking-Water (GLAAS) questionnaire provides information on whether there are &amp;#x201C;clearly defined procedures in laws or policies for participation by service users (e.g. households) and communities in planning programs&amp;#x201D;. For countries that have data available from the local administrative unit level, they are asked to provide data on the number of local administrative units for which policies and procedures for local participation (i) exist, and (ii) are operational, as well as (iii) the number of local administrative units assessed, and (iv) the total number of units in the country. The indicator is computed as (ii) the number of local admin units with operation policies and procedures for local participation divided by (iv) the total number of local administrative units in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both numerator and denominator will be obtained through the GLAAS survey for the 2016-2017 cycle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the highly country- and context-specific nature of the indicator, no estimates are produced for countries that are missing data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operational mechanism by which individuals and communities can meaningfully contribute to water and sanitation management then the country will be excluded from the regional and global estimates for this indicator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global and regional estimates for a related indicator on the presence and use of participation policies and procedures at the national level for different water subsectors are also derived to support the target indicator. Similarly, countries with missing values are excluded from global and regional analysis for this indicator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For global and regional aggregates, the percentage of local administrative units that have a defined and operational mechanism by which individuals and communities can meaningfully contribute to decisions and directions about water and sanitation management will be averaged among countries, with each country&amp;#x2019;s percent value weighted based on total country population for the data year, as a proportion of the global population.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National governments participating in GLAAS fill out the country survey, preferably supported by a multi-stakeholder review. Although one ministry leads the process, it is often the case that many different ministries and departments must be involved in the process in order to obtain the data required to complete the questionnaire. A GLAAS national focal person supports the lead ministry to coordinate data collection, to compile the national response to the questionnaire, and to lead on the process of data validation. GLAAS survey documents for the current cycle can be found at the following link: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UN-Water Global Analysis and Assessment of Sanitation and Drinking-Water (GLAAS) provides information on governance, monitoring, human resources, and financing in the water, sanitation, and hygiene (WASH) sector. The UN-Water GLAAS survey is currently conducted on a biennial basis, led by WHO and has completed three full cycles (2009/2010, 2011/2012, and 2013/2014), as well as a pilot conducted in 2008. GLAAS survey documents for the current cycle of data collection (2016/2017) can be found at the following link: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once received, the country submission undergoes a thorough data validation process, which is often an iterative process requiring communication and feedback with regional and country counterparts. Quality of the submission is also assessed through an analysis of data collected on country processes (number of ministries involved, whether a national meeting was held to support the filling of the questionnaire, stakeholder validation, use of documentation, etc.) as well as supporting documentation provided. In addition, an external validation with key informants is conducted, in which WASH experts who have not participated in the GLAAS process respond to selected questions from the survey for a specific country within their area of expertise, and agreement with country responses is evaluated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data submitted through GLAAS are endorsed by the national government prior to submission. A form (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/entity/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-consent-form-2016.doc?ua=1&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/entity/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-consent-form-2016.doc?ua=1&lt;/a&gt;) providing consent to WHO for the release and publication of the country data is signed and submitted along with the filled survey.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asia and Pacific: Most countries (at least 50% of the countries covering 60% of the population from the region)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Africa: Some countries (approximately 50% of the countries covering 50% of the population from the region)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Latin America and the Caribbean: Most countries (at least 60% of the countries covering 80% of the population from the region)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe, North America, Australia, New Zealand and Japan: Most countries (at least 60% of the countries covering 60% of the population from the region)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that these reflect data on presence of policies and procedures for local participation at the national level. Data at the local administrative unit level is being collected through the current cycle of &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GLAAS and through administrative data that will be progressively included in the calculation of the indicator (cf. 7.1, 10.1, and 10.2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time series of parameters under the indicator are available for 2008, 2010, 2012, and 2014. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator will be generated by countries, thus no differences in global and national figures are expected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.unep.org/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.oecd.org/env/watergovernanceprogramme.htm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UN-Water Global Analysis and Assessment of Sanitation and Drinking-Water. http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OECD (2015a), OECD Principles on Water Governance, available at: https://www.oecd.org/gov/regional-policy/OECD-Principles-on-Water-Governance-brochure.pdf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OECD (2015b), Stakeholder Engagement for Inclusive Water Governance, OECD Studies on Water, OECD Publishing, Paris., http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/9789264231122-en&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UN-Water 2008 : Status Report on IWRM for CSD-16, http://www.unwater.org/publications/publications-detail/en/c/206480/UNEP-DHI &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UN-Water 2012: Status Reports on IWRM. http://www.unwater.org/publications/status-report-on-integrated-water-resources-management/en/ &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data from the 2012 Survey on the Application of Integrated Approaches to Water Resources Management. http://www.unepdhi.org/rioplus20 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNEP 2016. Degree of implementation of integrated water resources management. Draft survey to support SDG indicator 6.5.1 http://www.unepdhi.org/whatwedo/gemi &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OECD 2015. Stakeholder Engagement for Inclusive Water Governance. http://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/governance/stakeholder-engagement-for-inclusive-water-governance_9789264231122-en&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 6: Garantizar la disponibilidad y la gestión sostenible del agua y el saneamiento para todos&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 6.b: Apoyar y fortalecer la participación de las comunidades locales en la mejora de la gestión del agua y el saneamiento&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 6.b.1: Proporción de dependencias administrativas locales que han establecido políticas y procedimientos operacionales para la participación de las comunidades locales en la gestión del agua y el saneamiento&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Última actualización: 11 de julio de 2017&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicadores relacionados&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.5: Número de muertos, desaparecidos y afectados por catástrofes por cada 100.000 personas [a]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15.9: Número de muertos, desaparecidos y afectados por catástrofes por cada 100.000 personas [a]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Comentarios:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.5 (aplicar la gestión integrada de los recursos hídricos a todos los niveles, incluida la cooperación transfronteriza, según proceda) 15.9 (integrar los valores de los ecosistemas y la biodiversidad en la planificación nacional y local, los procesos de desarrollo, las estrategias de reducción de la pobreza y las cuentas)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Información institucional&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organización(es):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organización Mundial de la Salud (OMS)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programa de las Naciones Unidas para el Medio Ambiente (PNUMA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organización de Cooperación y Desarrollo Económicos (OCDE)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador evalúa el porcentaje de unidades administrativas locales (definidas por el gobierno nacional) que cuentan con un mecanismo establecido y operativo mediante el cual los individuos y las comunidades pueden contribuir de manera significativa a las decisiones y directrices sobre la gestión del agua y el saneamiento.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador Proporción de unidades administrativas locales con políticas y procedimientos establecidos y operativos para la participación de las comunidades locales en la gestión del agua y el saneamiento se mide actualmente por la Proporción de países con procedimientos claramente definidos en la ley o en la política para la participación de los usuarios/comunidades de los servicios en el programa de planificación de la gestión del agua y el saneamiento y la promoción de la higiene y la Proporción de países con un alto nivel de participación de los usuarios/comunidades en los programas de planificación de la gestión del agua y el saneamiento y la promoción de la higiene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La participación de las partes interesadas es esencial para garantizar la sostenibilidad de las opciones de gestión del agua y el saneamiento a lo largo del tiempo, por ejemplo, la elección de soluciones adecuadas para un determinado contexto social y económico, y la plena comprensión de los impactos de una determinada decisión de desarrollo. Definir los procedimientos en la política o la ley para la participación de las comunidades locales es vital para garantizar que se satisfagan las necesidades de toda la comunidad, incluidas las más vulnerables, y también fomenta la propiedad de los planes, lo que a su vez contribuye a su sostenibilidad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las unidades administrativas locales se refieren a los subdistritos, municipios, comunas u otras unidades locales a nivel de comunidad que cubren tanto las zonas urbanas como las rurales y que serán definidas por el gobierno. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las políticas y procedimientos para la participación de las comunidades locales en la gestión del agua y el saneamiento definirían un mecanismo formal para garantizar la participación de los usuarios en la planificación de las actividades de agua y saneamiento. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se considera que una política o procedimiento está establecido si el mecanismo de participación de las comunidades locales está definido en la ley o ha sido aprobado y publicado formalmente. Se considera que es operativa si la política o el procedimiento se está aplicando, con una financiación adecuada y con medios para verificar que la participación tuvo lugar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2018;Agua y saneamiento&amp;#x2019; incluye todas las áreas de gestión relacionadas con cada una de las metas del ODS 6, a saber: suministro de agua (6.1), saneamiento e higiene (6.2), tratamiento de aguas residuales y calidad del agua ambiental (6.3), eficiencia y uso sostenible (6.4), gestión integrada de los recursos hídricos (6.5) y ecosistemas relacionados con el agua (6.6).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El Análisis y Evaluación Mundial de Saneamiento y Agua Potable (GLAAS, por sus siglas en inglés) de ONU-Agua proporciona información sobre la gobernanza, el seguimiento, los recursos humanos y la financiación en el sector del agua, el saneamiento y la higiene (WASH). La encuesta GLAAS de ONU-Agua se realiza actualmente con carácter bienal, dirigida por la OMS, y recogió datos de 94 países (predominantemente países de ingresos bajos y medios-bajos) en el ciclo más reciente de 2013-2014. El alcance de la pregunta sobre la participación de la comunidad y de los usuarios se ha ampliado más allá de WASH para el ciclo GLAAS 2016-17 para abordar todas las metas del ODS 6, incluyendo la calidad del agua, los derechos/la asignación del agua, la gestión de los recursos hídricos y el estado de los ecosistemas relacionados con el agua. El GLAAS ha completado tres ciclos completos (2009-2010, 2011-2012 y 2013-2014), así como un piloto realizado en 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los gobiernos nacionales que participan en la encuesta de la GLAAS rellenan el cuestionario, preferentemente con el apoyo de una revisión de múltiples partes interesadas. Aunque un ministerio dirige el proceso, a menudo es necesario que muchos ministerios y departamentos diferentes participen en el proceso para obtener los datos necesarios para completar el cuestionario. Una persona de contacto nacional de la GLAAS apoya al ministerio principal para coordinar la recolección de datos, compilar la respuesta nacional al cuestionario y dirigir el proceso de validación de los datos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos se complementarán con los informes de la Gestión Integrada de los Recursos Hídricos (GIRH) en la meta 6.5 de los ODS (para las aguas residuales y la calidad del agua, la eficiencia del agua, la gestión de los recursos hídricos y el estado de los ecosistemas relacionados con el agua) (PNUMA 2016). Un componente clave de la GIRH es la participación comunitaria y la gestión de los recursos hídricos a nivel local. El análisis de la GIRH ha sido realizado en el pasado por ONU-Agua en 2008 (dirigido por ONU-DESA) y en 2012 (dirigido por el PNUMA, el PNUD, el GWP y el SIWI, estos dos últimos según sus siglas en inglés) a petición de la Comisión de las Naciones Unidas para el Desarrollo Sostenible (ONU-Agua 2008, 2012).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Iniciativa de Gobernanza del Agua (WGI, según sus siglas en inglés) de la OCDE, una plataforma técnica que reúne a más de 100 miembros de los sectores público, privado y sin ánimo de lucro, está desarrollando actualmente un conjunto de indicadores de gobernanza del agua, dentro de la estrategia de aplicación de los Principios de la OCDE sobre la gobernanza del agua (OCDE 2015a). Se espera que los Indicadores de Gobernanza del Agua puedan proporcionar información adicional sobre la participación local sobre la base de un sistema de indicadores propuesto en la OCDE (2015b) para medir &amp;#x201C;el compromiso de las partes interesadas para la gobernanza inclusiva del agua&amp;#x201D;. En 2017 se desarrollará y probará un indicador que proporcione métricas sobre la participación local. Los datos estarán disponibles a través de plataformas interactivas y bases de datos en un formato que fomente el diálogo político y el aprendizaje entre pares para 2018. En el 8º Foro Mundial del Agua de Brasilia (2018) se lanzará una publicación específica sobre &amp;#x201C;Panorama de la gobernanza del agua&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Proceso de recolección:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los gobiernos nacionales que participan en la encuesta GLAAS rellenan el cuestionario, preferiblemente con el apoyo de una revisión de múltiples partes interesadas. Aunque un ministerio dirige el proceso (por ejemplo, el Ministerio del Agua, el Ministerio de Medio Ambiente, etc., dependiendo del país), a menudo es necesario que muchos ministerios y departamentos diferentes participen en el proceso para obtener los datos necesarios para completar el cuestionario. Un punto focal nacional del GLAAS ayuda al ministerio principal a coordinar la recolección de datos, a compilar la respuesta nacional al cuestionario y a dirigir el proceso de validación de los datos. Para cada presentación del GLAAS, se recoge información sobre los procesos del país (número de ministerios implicados, si se celebró una reunión nacional para apoyar la cumplimentación del cuestionario, la validación de las partes interesadas, el uso de la documentación, etc.). Una vez recibida, la presentación del país se somete a un proceso exhaustivo de validación de los datos, que suele ser un proceso iterativo, que requiere comunicación y retroalimentación con los homólogos regionales y nacionales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;También se pide a los países que den su consentimiento para publicar las respuestas de datos individuales y validadas que se suministran a la GLAAS. Así, a través de los procesos de recopilación de datos, validación y consulta, se espera que los resultados sean comparables y no se prevén más ajustes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendario&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recopilación de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La actual ronda de Análisis y Evaluación Global de Saneamiento y Agua Potable (GLAAS) de ONU-Agua se ha puesto en marcha y los datos estarán disponibles a finales de 2016 (De año calendario a año calendario).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publicación de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q1 2017 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ministerios con responsabilidades relacionadas con el suministro de agua y el saneamiento, la agricultura, el desarrollo y la gestión de los recursos hídricos y el medio ambiente.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nombre:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OMS, OCDE y PNUMA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La OMS, con el apoyo de la OCDE y el PNUMA&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definir los procedimientos en la política o la ley para la participación de las comunidades locales es vital para garantizar que se satisfagan las necesidades de toda la comunidad, incluidas las más vulnerables, y también fomenta la apropiación de los planes, lo que a su vez contribuye a su sostenibilidad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Un valor bajo de este indicador sugeriría que la participación de las comunidades locales en la gestión del agua y el saneamiento es baja, mientras que un valor alto indicaría altos niveles de participación, lo que indica una mayor apropiación y una mayor probabilidad de prestación y gestión sostenible de los servicios de agua y saneamiento.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos sobre las unidades administrativas locales con políticas y procedimientos establecidos y operativos para la participación local se están recopilando a través del ciclo actual de GLAAS, y estarán disponibles a finales de 2016. Hasta entonces, se informará de la presencia de políticas y procedimientos tal y como se informa a nivel nacional para los diferentes subsectores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos adicionales, incluidos los que miden la participación local de los indicadores de gobernanza del agua de la OCDE y los datos administrativos, se incluirán progresivamente en el cálculo del indicador a medida que estén disponibles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El cuestionario de Análisis y Evaluación Mundial del Saneamiento y el Agua Potable (GLAAS) de ONU-Agua proporciona información sobre si existen &amp;#x201C;procedimientos claramente definidos en las leyes o políticas para la participación de los usuarios de los servicios (por ejemplo, los hogares) y las comunidades en la planificación de los programas&amp;#x201D;. En el caso de los países que disponen de datos a nivel de unidad administrativa local, se les pide que proporcionen datos sobre el número de unidades administrativas locales para las que las políticas y los procedimientos de participación local (i) existen, y (ii) son operativos, así como (iii) el número de unidades administrativas locales evaluadas, y (iv) el número total de unidades en el país. El indicador se calcula como (ii) el número de unidades administrativas locales con políticas y procedimientos de participación local operativos dividido por (iv) el número total de unidades administrativas locales del país.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tanto el numerador como el denominador se obtendrán a través de la encuesta GLAAS del ciclo 2016-2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel de país:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debido a la naturaleza altamente específica del país y del contexto del indicador, no se producen estimaciones para los países a los que les faltan datos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel regional y mundial:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mecanismo operativo por el cual los individuos y las comunidades pueden contribuir significativamente a la gestión del agua y el saneamiento, entonces el país será excluido de las estimaciones regionales y mundiales para este indicador. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las estimaciones globales y regionales para un indicador relacionado sobre la presencia y el uso de políticas y procedimientos de participación a nivel nacional para los diferentes subsectores del agua también se derivan para apoyar el indicador objetivo. Del mismo modo, los países con valores ausentes se excluyen del análisis global y regional para este indicador.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para los agregados globales y regionales, el porcentaje de unidades administrativas locales que cuentan con un mecanismo definido y operativo por el cual los individuos y las comunidades pueden contribuir de manera significativa a las decisiones y orientaciones sobre la gestión del agua y el saneamiento se promediarán entre los países, con el valor porcentual de cada país ponderado en base a la población total del país para el año de los datos, como proporción de la población global.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Métodos y directrices a disposición de los países para la recopilación de los datos a nivel nacional:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los gobiernos nacionales que participan en el GLAAS rellenan la encuesta del país, preferiblemente con el apoyo de una revisión de múltiples partes interesadas. Aunque un ministerio dirige el proceso, a menudo es necesario que muchos ministerios y departamentos diferentes participen en el proceso para obtener los datos necesarios para completar el cuestionario. Una persona de contacto nacional de la GLAAS ayuda al ministerio principal a coordinar la recogida de datos, a recopilar la respuesta nacional al cuestionario y a dirigir el proceso de validación de los datos. Los documentos de la encuesta GLAAS para el ciclo actual pueden encontrarse en el siguiente enlace: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El Análisis y Evaluación Global del Saneamiento y el Agua Potable (GLAAS) de ONU-Agua proporciona información sobre la gobernanza, el seguimiento, los recursos humanos y la financiación en el sector del agua, el saneamiento y la higiene (WASH). La encuesta GLAAS de ONU-Agua se realiza actualmente con carácter bienal, dirigida por la OMS, y ha completado tres ciclos completos (2009/2010, 2011/2012 y 2013/2014), así como un piloto realizado en 2008. Los documentos de la encuesta GLAAS para el actual ciclo de recolección de datos (2016/2017) se pueden encontrar en el siguiente enlace: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Aseguramiento de la calidad:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Una vez recibida, la presentación del país se somete a un exhaustivo proceso de validación de los datos, que suele ser un proceso iterativo que requiere comunicación y retroalimentación con los homólogos regionales y nacionales. La calidad de la presentación también se evalúa mediante un análisis de los datos recopilados sobre los procesos del país (número de ministerios implicados, si se celebró una reunión nacional para apoyar la cumplimentación del cuestionario, validación de las partes interesadas, uso de la documentación, etc.), así como de la documentación de apoyo proporcionada. Además, se lleva a cabo una validación externa con informantes clave, en la que expertos en WASH que no han participado en el proceso GLAAS responden a preguntas seleccionadas de la encuesta para un país específico dentro de su área de experiencia, y se evalúa la concordancia con las respuestas del país.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos presentados a través de GLAAS son aprobados por el gobierno nacional antes de su presentación. Se firma un formulario (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/entity/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-consent-form-2016.doc?ua=1&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/entity/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-consent-form-2016.doc?&lt;/a&gt; en el que se da el consentimiento a la OMS para la divulgación y publicación de los datos del país y se presenta junto con la encuesta cumplimentada.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Asia y Pacífico&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: La mayoría de los países (al menos el 50% de los países que cubren el 60% de la población de la región)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;África&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Algunos países (aproximadamente el 50% de los países que cubren el 50% de la población de la región)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;América Latina y el Caribe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: La mayoría de los países (al menos el 60% de los países que cubren el 80% de la población de la región)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Europa, América del Norte, Australia, Nueva Zelanda y Japón&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: La mayoría de los países (al menos el 60% de los países que cubren el 60% de la población de la región)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hay que tener en cuenta que estos datos reflejan la presencia de políticas y procedimientos de participación local a nivel nacional. Los datos a nivel de las unidades administrativas locales se están recopilando a través del ciclo actual de GLAAS y a través de datos administrativos que se incluirán progresivamente en el cálculo del indicador (cf. 7.1, 10.1 y 10.2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las series temporales de los parámetros del indicador están disponibles para 2008, 2010, 2012 y 2014. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fuentes de discrepancia:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Este indicador será generado por los países, por lo que no se esperan diferencias en las cifras globales y nacionales.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Referencias&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unep.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.unep.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/env/watergovernanceprogramme.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/env/watergovernanceprogramme.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Referencias:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONU-Agua Análisis y evaluación mundiales del saneamiento y el agua potable. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OCDE (2015a), OCDE Principios de la gobernanza del agua, disponible en: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oecd.org/gov/regional-policy/OECD-Principles-on-Water-Governance-brochure.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.oecd.org/gov/regional-policy/OECD-Principles-on-Water-Governance-brochure.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OCDE (2015b), Participación de las partes interesadas para la gobernanza inclusiva del agua, Estudios de la OCDE sobre el agua, Publicaciones de la OCDE, París, &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/9789264231122-en&quot;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/9789264231122-en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONU-Agua 2008 : Informe de situación de la GIRH para la CDS-16, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unwater.org/publications/publications-detail/en/c/206480/UNEP-DHI%20&quot;&gt;http://www.unwater.org/publications/publications-detail/en/c/206480/UNEP-DHI&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONU-Agua 2012: Informes de situación sobre la GIRH. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unwater.org/publications/status-report-on-integrated-water-resources-management/en/%20&quot;&gt;http://www.unwater.org/publications/status-report-on-integrated-water-resources-management/en/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Datos de la Encuesta de 2012 sobre la aplicación de enfoques integrados a la gestión de los recursos hídricos. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unepdhi.org/rioplus20%20&quot;&gt;http://www.unepdhi.org/rioplus20&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PNUMA 2016. Grado de implementación de la gestión integrada de los recursos hídricos. Proyecto de encuesta en apoyo del indicador 6.5.1 de los ODS &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unepdhi.org/whatwedo/gemi%20&quot;&gt;http://www.unepdhi.org/whatwedo/gemi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OCDE 2015. Participación de las partes interesadas para la gobernanza inclusiva del agua. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/governance/stakeholder-engagement-for-inclusive-water-governance_9789264231122-en&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/governance/stakeholder-engagement-for-inclusive-water-governance_9789264231122-en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 6: Garantir l&apos;accès de tous à des services d&apos;alimentation en eau et d&apos;assainissement gérés de façon durable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 6.b: Appuyer et renforcer la participation de la population locale à l’amélioration de la gestion de l’eau et de l’assainissement&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 6.b.1: Proportion d’administrations locales ayant mis en place des politiques et procédures opérationnelles encourageant la participation de la population locale à la gestion de l’eau et de l’assainissement&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dernière mise à jour : 11 Juillet 2017&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicateurs connexes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.5 : Nombre de morts, de personnes disparues et de personnes touchées par une catastrophe pour 100 000 personnes [a].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15.9 : Nombre de morts, de personnes disparues et de personnes touchées par une catastrophe pour 100 000 personnes [a]. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.5 (mettre en œuvre une gestion intégrée des ressources en eau à tous les niveaux, y compris la coopération transfrontalière, le cas échéant) 15.9 (intégrer les valeurs des écosystèmes et de la biodiversité dans la planification, les processus de développement, les stratégies de réduction de la pauvreté et les comptes nationaux et locaux). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Informations institutionnelles&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organization(s):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organisation mondiale de la santé (OMS)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programme des Nations unies pour l&apos;environnement (PNUE)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organisation de coopération et de développement économiques (OCDE) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Définition : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur évalue le pourcentage d&apos;unités administratives locales (telles que définies par le gouvernement national) qui disposent d&apos;un mécanisme établi et opérationnel grâce auquel les individus et les communautés peuvent contribuer de manière significative aux décisions et aux orientations concernant la gestion de l&apos;eau et de l&apos;assainissement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur Proportion d&apos;unités administratives locales ayant des politiques et procédures établies et opérationnelles pour la participation des communautés locales à la gestion de l&apos;eau et de l&apos;assainissement est actuellement mesuré par la proportion de pays ayant des procédures clairement définies dans la loi ou la politique pour la participation des utilisateurs/communautés de services à la planification des programmes de gestion de l&apos;eau et de l&apos;assainissement et de promotion de l&apos;hygiène et la proportion de pays ayant un niveau élevé d&apos;utilisateurs/communautés participant à la planification des programmes de gestion de l&apos;eau et de l&apos;assainissement et de promotion de l&apos;hygiène.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La participation des parties prenantes est essentielle pour assurer la durabilité des options de gestion de l&apos;eau et de l&apos;assainissement dans le temps, par exemple le choix de solutions appropriées pour un contexte social et économique donné, et la pleine compréhension des impacts d&apos;une certaine décision de développement. Il est essentiel de définir les procédures de participation des communautés locales dans la politique ou la législation afin de garantir la satisfaction des besoins de l&apos;ensemble de la communauté, y compris des plus vulnérables, et d&apos;encourager l&apos;appropriation des projets, ce qui contribue à leur durabilité.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Par unités administratives locales, on entend les sous-districts, municipalités, communes ou autres unités locales de niveau communautaire qui ne se chevauchent pas et qui couvrent à la fois les zones urbaines et rurales à définir par le gouvernement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les politiques et procédures de participation des communautés locales à la gestion de l&apos;eau et de l&apos;assainissement définiront un mécanisme formel pour assurer la participation des usagers à la planification des activités liées à l&apos;eau et à l&apos;assainissement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On considère qu&apos;une politique ou une procédure est établie si le mécanisme de participation des communautés locales est défini dans la loi ou a été formellement approuvé et publié. Il est considéré comme opérationnel si la politique ou la procédure est mise en œuvre, avec un financement approprié en place et avec des moyens permettant de vérifier que la participation a eu lieu. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2018; L&apos;eau et l&apos;assainissement&amp;#x2019; comprend tous les domaines de gestion liés à chacune des cibles du ODD 6, à savoir : l&apos;approvisionnement en eau (6.1), l&apos;assainissement et l&apos;hygiène (6.2), le traitement des eaux usées et la qualité de l&apos;eau ambiante (6.3), l&apos;efficacité et l&apos;utilisation durable (6.4), la gestion intégrée des ressources en eau (6.5) et les écosystèmes liés à l&apos;eau (6.6).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Sources de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;analyse et l&apos;évaluation mondiales de l&apos;assainissement et de l&apos;eau potable (GLAAS) de l&apos;ONU-Eau fournit des informations sur la gouvernance, le suivi, les ressources humaines et le financement dans le secteur de l&apos;eau, de l&apos;assainissement et de l&apos;hygiène (WASH). L&apos;enquête GLAAS d&apos;ONU-Eau est actuellement menée sur une base biennale, sous la direction de l&apos;OMS, et a recueilli des données dans 94 pays (principalement des pays à revenu faible et moyen inférieur) au cours du cycle le plus récent, en 2013-2014. La portée de la question sur la participation des communautés et des utilisateurs a été élargie au-delà de l&apos;enquête WASH pour le cycle GLAAS 2016-17 afin de couvrir tous les objectifs du ODD 6, notamment la qualité de l&apos;eau, les droits/allocations d&apos;eau, la gestion des ressources en eau et l&apos;état des écosystèmes liés à l&apos;eau. GLAAS a achevé trois cycles complets (2009-2010, 2011-2012 et 2013-2014), ainsi qu&apos;un projet pilote mené en 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les gouvernements nationaux participant à l&apos;enquête GLAAS remplissent le questionnaire, de préférence en s&apos;appuyant sur un examen multipartite. Bien qu&apos;un ministère dirige le processus, il arrive souvent que plusieurs ministères et départements différents doivent être impliqués dans le processus afin d&apos;obtenir les données requises pour remplir le questionnaire. Un responsable national du GLAAS aide le ministère responsable à coordonner la collecte des données, à compiler la réponse nationale au questionnaire et à diriger le processus de validation des données. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données seront complétées par des rapports sur la gestion intégrée des ressources en eau (GIRE) dans le cadre de l&apos;objectif 6.5 du ODD (pour les eaux usées et la qualité de l&apos;eau, l&apos;efficacité de l&apos;eau, la gestion des ressources en eau et l&apos;état des écosystèmes liés à l&apos;eau) (PNUE 2016). Un élément clé de la GIRE est la participation communautaire et la gestion des ressources en eau au niveau local. L&apos;analyse de la GIRE a été effectuée dans le passé par l&apos;ONU-Eau en 2008 (sous la direction du DAES) et en 2012 (sous la direction du PNUE, du PNUD, du GWP et du SIWI) à la demande de la Commission du développement durable des Nations unies (ONU-Eau 2008, 2012). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;Initiative de l&apos;OCDE sur la gouvernance de l&apos;eau (WGI), une plateforme technique réunissant plus de 100 membres des secteurs public, privé et à but non lucratif, élabore actuellement un ensemble d&apos;indicateurs sur la gouvernance de l&apos;eau, dans le cadre de la stratégie de mise en œuvre des Principes de l&apos;OCDE sur la gouvernance de l&apos;eau (OCDE 2015a). Les indicateurs de gouvernance de l&apos;eau devraient pouvoir fournir des informations supplémentaires sur la participation locale sur la base d&apos;un système d&apos;indicateurs proposé dans l&apos;OCDE (2015b) pour mesurer &amp;#x201C; l&apos;engagement des parties prenantes pour une gouvernance inclusive de l&apos;eau &amp;#x201D;. Un indicateur fournissant des mesures sur la participation locale sera développé et testé d&apos;ici 2017. Les données seront mises à disposition par le biais de plateformes interactives et de bases de données dans un format permettant de favoriser le dialogue politique et l&apos;apprentissage par les pairs d&apos;ici 2018. Une publication consacrée à la gouvernance de l&apos;eau &amp;#x201C; sera lancée lors du 8e Forum mondial de l&apos;eau à Brasilia (2018). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Processus de collecte : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les gouvernements nationaux participant à l&apos;enquête GLAAS remplissent le questionnaire, de préférence en s&apos;appuyant sur un examen multipartite. Bien qu&apos;un ministère dirige le processus (par exemple, le ministère de l&apos;eau, le ministère de l&apos;environnement, etc. selon le pays), il arrive souvent que de nombreux ministères et départements différents doivent être impliqués dans le processus afin d&apos;obtenir les données requises pour remplir le questionnaire. Un point focal national du GLAAS aide le ministère responsable à coordonner la collecte des données, à compiler la réponse nationale au questionnaire et à diriger le processus de validation des données. Pour chaque soumission GLAAS, des informations sur les processus nationaux sont collectées (nombre de ministères impliqués, si une réunion nationale a été organisée pour soutenir le remplissage du questionnaire, validation des parties prenantes, utilisation de la documentation, etc. Une fois reçue, la soumission du pays est soumise à un processus de validation des données approfondi, qui est souvent un processus itératif nécessitant une communication et un retour d&apos;information avec les homologues régionaux et nationaux. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Les pays sont également invités à donner leur accord pour la publication des
réponses individuelles et validées fournies au GLAAS. Ainsi, grâce aux processus de collecte, de validation et de consultation des données, les résultats devraient être comparables et aucun autre ajustement n&apos;est prévu. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendrier&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Collecte de données :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le cycle actuel d&apos;analyse et d&apos;évaluation mondiales de l&apos;assainissement et de l&apos;eau potable (GLAAS) de l&apos;ONU-Eau a été lancé et les données seront disponibles d&apos;ici la fin de l&apos;année 2016. (De NA à NA) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publication des données :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q1 2017 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fournisseurs de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ministères ayant des responsabilités liées à l&apos;approvisionnement en eau et à l&apos;assainissement, à l&apos;agriculture, au développement et à la gestion des ressources en eau et à l&apos;environnement&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compilateurs de données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nom : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OMS, OCDE et PNUE &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OMS, avec le soutien de l&apos;OCDE et du PNUE&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Raison d&apos;être :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il est essentiel de définir les procédures de participation des communautés locales dans les politiques ou les lois pour garantir la satisfaction des besoins de l&apos;ensemble de la communauté, y compris des plus vulnérables, et pour encourager l&apos;appropriation des programmes, ce qui contribue à leur durabilité.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Une valeur faible de cet indicateur suggérerait que la participation des communautés locales à la gestion de l&apos;eau et de l&apos;assainissement est faible, tandis qu&apos;une valeur élevée indiquerait des niveaux élevés de participation, ce qui indique une plus grande appropriation et une plus grande probabilité de fourniture et de gestion durables des services d&apos;eau et d&apos;assainissement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires et limitations : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des données sur les unités administratives locales ayant des politiques et des procédures établies et opérationnelles pour la participation locale sont collectées dans le cadre du cycle actuel du GLAAS et seront disponibles d&apos;ici la fin de l&apos;année 2016. D&apos;ici là, la présence de politiques et de procédures telles que rapportées au niveau national pour différents sous-secteurs sera signalée.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des données supplémentaires, notamment des données mesurant la participation locale provenant des indicateurs de l&apos;OCDE sur la gouvernance de l&apos;eau et des données administratives, seront progressivement incluses dans le calcul de l&apos;indicateur au fur et à mesure qu&apos;elles seront disponibles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Méthodologie&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Méthode de calcul :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le questionnaire d&apos;analyse et d&apos;évaluation mondiales de l&apos;assainissement et de l&apos;eau potable (GLAAS) de l&apos;ONU-Eau fournit des informations sur l&apos;existence de &amp;#x201C; procédures clairement définies dans les lois ou les politiques pour la participation des utilisateurs de services (par exemple les ménages) et des communautés aux programmes de planification &amp;#x201D;. Pour les pays qui disposent de données au niveau des unités administratives locales, il leur est demandé de fournir des données sur le nombre d&apos;unités administratives locales pour lesquelles des politiques et des procédures de participation locale (i) existent, et (ii) sont opérationnelles, ainsi que (iii) le nombre d&apos;unités administratives locales évaluées, et (iv) le nombre total d&apos;unités dans le pays. L&apos;indicateur est calculé comme suit : (ii) le nombre d&apos;unités administratives locales ayant des politiques et procédures opérationnelles pour la participation locale, divisé par (iv) le nombre total d&apos;unités administratives locales dans le pays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le numérateur et le dénominateur seront obtenus par l&apos;enquête GLAAS pour le cycle 2016-2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Traitement des valeurs manquantes : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Au niveau national : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En raison de la nature très spécifique de l&apos;indicateur en fonction du pays et du contexte, aucune estimation n&apos;est produite pour les pays dont les données sont manquantes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Au niveau régional et mondial : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mécanisme opérationnel par lequel les individus et les communautés peuvent contribuer de manière significative à la gestion de l&apos;eau et de l&apos;assainissement ; le pays sera alors exclu des estimations régionales et mondiales pour cet indicateur. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des estimations mondiales et régionales pour un indicateur connexe sur la présence et l&apos;utilisation de politiques et de procédures de participation au niveau national pour différents sous-secteurs de l&apos;eau sont également dérivées pour soutenir l&apos;indicateur cible. De même, les pays pour lesquels des valeurs sont manquantes sont exclus de l&apos;analyse mondiale et régionale pour cet indicateur. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agrégats régionaux : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour les agrégats mondiaux et régionaux, le pourcentage d&apos;unités administratives locales qui disposent d&apos;un mécanisme défini et opérationnel permettant aux individus et aux communautés de contribuer de manière significative aux décisions et aux orientations concernant la gestion de l&apos;eau et de l&apos;assainissement sera calculé en moyenne par pays, la valeur du pourcentage de chaque pays&amp;#x2019; étant pondérée en fonction de la population totale du pays pour l&apos;année considérée, en proportion de la population mondiale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Méthodes et orientations mises à la disposition des pays pour la compilation des données au niveau national :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les gouvernements nationaux participant au GLAAS remplissent l&apos;enquête par pays, de préférence en s&apos;appuyant sur un examen multipartite. Bien qu&apos;un ministère dirige le processus, il arrive souvent que plusieurs ministères et départements différents doivent être impliqués dans le processus afin d&apos;obtenir les données requises pour remplir le questionnaire. Un responsable national du GLAAS aide le ministère responsable à coordonner la collecte des données, à compiler la réponse nationale au questionnaire et à diriger le processus de validation des données. Les documents de l&apos;enquête GLAAS pour le cycle actuel peuvent être trouvés sur le lien suivant : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;analyse et l&apos;évaluation mondiales de l&apos;assainissement et de l&apos;eau potable (GLAAS) de l&apos;ONU-Eau fournit des informations sur la gouvernance, le suivi, les ressources humaines et le financement dans le secteur de l&apos;eau, de l&apos;assainissement et de l&apos;hygiène (WASH). L&apos;enquête GLAAS d&apos;ONU-Eau est actuellement menée sur une base biennale, sous la direction de l&apos;OMS et a achevé trois cycles complets (2009/2010, 2011/2012 et 2013/2014), ainsi qu&apos;un projet pilote mené en 2008. Les documents de l&apos;enquête GLAAS pour le cycle actuel de collecte de données (2016/2017) peuvent être consultés sur le lien suivant : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Assurance de la qualité : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Une fois reçue, la soumission du pays est soumise à un processus de validation des données approfondi, qui est souvent un processus itératif nécessitant une communication et un retour d&apos;information avec les homologues régionaux et nationaux. La qualité de la soumission est également évaluée par une analyse des données collectées sur les processus nationaux (nombre de ministères impliqués, si une réunion nationale a été organisée pour aider à remplir le questionnaire, validation des parties prenantes, utilisation de la documentation, etc. En outre, une validation externe avec des informateurs clés est effectuée, dans laquelle les experts en WASH qui n&apos;ont pas participé au processus GLAAS répondent à des questions sélectionnées de l&apos;enquête pour un pays spécifique dans leur domaine d&apos;expertise, et l&apos;accord avec les réponses des pays est évalué. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données soumises par le biais de GLAAS sont approuvées par le gouvernement national avant d&apos;être soumises. Un formulaire (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/entity/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-consent-form-2016.doc?ua=1&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/entity/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-consent-form-2016.doc?ua=1&lt;/a&gt;) de consentement à la diffusion et à la publication des données nationales par l&apos;OMS est signé et soumis avec l&apos;enquête remplie.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilité des données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Asie et Pacifique &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; : La plupart des pays (au moins 50% des pays couvrant 60% de la population de la région) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Afrique&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Certains pays (environ 50 % des pays couvrant 50 % de la population de la région) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Amérique latine et Caraïbes &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; : La plupart des pays (au moins 60% des pays couvrant 80% de la population de la région) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Europe, Amérique du Nord, Australie, Nouvelle-Zélande et Japon &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; : La plupart des pays (au moins 60% des pays couvrant 60% de la population de la région) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Veuillez noter que ces données reflètent la présence de politiques et de procédures de participation locale au niveau national. Les données au niveau des unités administratives locales sont collectées dans le cadre du cycle actuel de GLAAS et par le biais de données administratives qui seront progressivement incluses dans le calcul de l&apos;indicateur (cf. 7.1, 10.1 et 10.2) &lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;h2&gt;Série chronologique : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les séries chronologiques des paramètres de l&apos;indicateur sont disponibles pour 2008, 2010, 2012 et 2014. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sources des divergences : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur sera généré par les pays, donc aucune différence n&apos;est prévue entre les chiffres mondiaux et nationaux.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Références&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unep.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.unep.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/env/watergovernanceprogramme.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/env/watergovernanceprogramme.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Références:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analyse et évaluation mondiales de l&apos;&apos;assainissement et de l&apos;eau potable par l&apos;ONU-Eau. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OCDE (2015a), Principes de l&apos;OCDE sur la gouvernance de l&apos;eau, disponible à l&apos;adresse suivante &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oecd.org/gov/regional-policy/OECD-Principles-on-Water-Governance-brochure.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.oecd.org/gov/regional-policy/OECD-Principles-on-Water-Governance-brochure.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OCDE (2015b), Engagement des parties prenantes pour une gouvernance inclusive de l&apos;eau, Études de l&apos;OCDE sur l&apos;eau, Éditions de l&apos;OCDE, Paris, &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/9789264231122-en&quot;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/9789264231122-en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONU-Eau 2008 : Rapport d&apos;étape sur la GIRE pour la CDD-16, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unwater.org/publications/publications-detail/en/c/206480/UNEP-DHI%20&quot;&gt;http://www.unwater.org/publications/publications-detail/en/c/206480/UNEP-DHI&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONU-Eau 2012 : Rapports sur l&apos;état d&apos;avancement de la gestion intégrée des ressources en eau. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unwater.org/publications/status-report-on-integrated-water-resources-management/en/%20&quot;&gt;http://www.unwater.org/publications/status-report-on-integrated-water-resources-management/en/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
1544]Données de l&apos;enquête 2012 sur l&apos;application des approches intégrées de la gestion des ressources en eau. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unepdhi.org/rioplus20%20&quot;&gt;http://www.unepdhi.org/rioplus20&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNEP 2016. Degré de mise en œuvre de la gestion intégrée des ressources en eau. Projet d&apos;enquête à l&apos;appui de l&apos;indicateur 6.5.1 du ODD &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unepdhi.org/whatwedo/gemi%20&quot;&gt;http://www.unepdhi.org/whatwedo/gemi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OCDE 2015. Engagement des parties prenantes pour une gouvernance inclusive de l&apos;eau. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/governance/stakeholder-engagement-for-inclusive-water-governance_9789264231122-en&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/governance/stakeholder-engagement-for-inclusive-water-governance_9789264231122-en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 6: Обеспечение наличия и рационального использования водных ресурсов и санитарии для всех&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 6.b: Поддерживать и укреплять участие местных общин в улучшении водного хозяйства и санитарии&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 6.b.1: Доля  местных административных единиц, в которых установлены и действуют правила и процедуры участия местных общин в улучшении водного хозяйства и санитарии&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Последнее обновление: 11 июля 2017 года&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Связанные показатели &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 6.5: Число погибших, пропавших без вести и пострадавших в результате стихийного бедствия на 100 000 человек [a] &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 15.9: Число погибших, пропавших без вести и пострадавших от стихийных бедствий на 100 000 человек [a] &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 6.5 (обеспечить комплексное управление водными ресурсами на всех уровнях, в том числе, при необходимости, на основе трансграничного сотрудничества) 15.9 (обеспечить учет ценности экосистем и биологического разнообразия в ходе общенационального и местного планирования и процессов развития, а также при разработке стратегий и планов сокращения масштабов бедности) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Институциональная информация &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Организация (и): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Всемирная организация здравоохранения (ВОЗ) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Программа Организации Объединенных Наций по окружающей среде (ЮНЕП) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Организация экономического сотрудничества и развития (ОЭСР) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель отражает долю местных административных единиц (как это определено национальным правительством), у которых есть установленный и действующий механизм, с помощью которого отдельные лица и сообщества могут вносить весомый вклад в решения и указания по управлению водными ресурсами и санитарией. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель Доля местных административных единиц, в которых установлены и действуют правила и процедуры участия местных общин в улучшении водного хозяйства и санитарии в настоящее время отображает долю стран с четко определенными в законе процедурами или политикой участия пользователей услуг / сообществ в программе планирования в области управления водными ресурсами и санитарией, и пропаганды гигиены, а также долю стран с высоким уровнем участия пользователей / сообществ в программах планирования в области управления водными ресурсами и санитарией и пропаганды гигиены. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Участие заинтересованных сторон необходимо для обеспечения устойчивости вариантов управления водными ресурсами и санитарией с течением времени, например: выбор подходящих решений для данного социального и экономического контекста и полное понимание последствий определенного решения в области развития. Определение процедур в правилах или законе по участию местных сообществ имеет жизненно важное значение для удовлетворения потребностей всего сообщества, включая наиболее уязвимые, а также поощряет владение схемами, что, в свою очередь, способствует их устойчивости. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Под местными административными единицами понимаются неперекрывающиеся суб-районы, муниципалитеты, коммуны или другие единицы местного сообщества, охватывающие как городские, так и сельские районы, которые определяются правительством. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Правила и процедуры участия местных сообществ в управлении водными ресурсами и санитарией будут определять формальный механизм для обеспечения участия пользователей в планировании деятельности в области водоснабжения и санитарии. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Правило или процедура считается установленной, если механизм участия местных сообществ определен законом или официально утвержден и опубликован. Механизм считается действующим, если правило или процедура внедряются при наличии соответствующего финансирования и средств для проверки того, что участие имело место. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &amp;#x2018; Водоснабжение и канализация &amp;#x2019; включает все области управления, связанные с каждой из задач в рамках ЦУР 6, а именно: водоснабжение (6.1), санитария и гигиена (6.2), очистка сточных вод и качество окружающей воды (6.3), повышение эффективности и устойчивое использование (6.4), комплексное управление водными ресурсами (6.5) и связанные с водой экосистемы (6.6). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Глобальный анализ и оценка состояния санитарии и питьевого водоснабжения в рамках Механизма «ООН – Водные ресурсы» (ГЛAAС) предоставляет информацию об управлении, мониторинге, людских ресурсах и финансировании в секторе водоснабжения, санитарии и гигиены (ВСГ). Обследование «ООН – Водные ресурсы» ГЛААС в настоящее время проводится раз в два года под руководством ВОЗ и собирает данные из 94 стран (преимущественно стран с низким уровнем дохода и уровнем дохода ниже среднего) за недавно проведенный цикл 2013–2014 годов. Охват вопроса об участии сообщества и пользователей был расширен за пределы ВСГ для цикла ГЛААС 2016-17 годов, чтобы охватить все задачи ЦУР 6, включая качество воды, права / распределение воды, управление водными ресурсами и статус связанных с водой экосистем. Процесс ГЛААС завершил три полных цикла (2009-2010, 2011-2012 и 2013-2014 годы), а также пилотный проект, проведенный в 2008 году. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Национальные правительства, участвующие в обследовании ГЛААС, заполняют вопросник, желательно при поддержке широкого круга заинтересованных сторон. Хотя процесс возглавляет одно министерство, часто бывает, что в процесс необходимо вовлекать множество различных министерств и ведомств, чтобы получить данные, необходимые для заполнения вопросника. Национальный координатор ГЛААС оказывает помощь ведущему министерству в координации сбора данных, в заполнении вопросника национальными данными и в руководстве процессом валидации данных.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные будут дополнены отчетностью по Комплексному управлению водными ресурсами (КУВР) в рамках задачи 6.5 ЦУР (для сточных вод и качества воды, повышения эффективности водопользования, управления водными ресурсами и состояния связанных с водой экосистем) (ЮНЕП, 2016 год). Ключевым компонентом КУВР является участие сообщества и управление водными ресурсами на местном уровне. Анализ КУВР был осуществлен в прошлом раунде обследования «ООН-Водные ресурсы» в 2008 году (проводился под руководством ООН-ДЭСВ) и в 2012 году (проводился под руководством ЮНЕП, ПРООН, ГВП и Стокгольмского международного института водных ресурсов (SIWI)) по запросу Комиссии ООН по устойчивому развитию (ООН-Водные ресурсы за 2008, 2012 годы). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Инициатива ОЭСР по руководству водными ресурсами (ИРВР), техническая платформа, объединяющая более 100 членов из государственного, частного и некоммерческого секторов, в настоящее время разрабатывает набор показателей руководства водными ресурсами в рамках стратегии реализации Принципов ОЭСР по руководству водными ресурсами (ОЭСР 2015a). Ожидается, что показатели руководства водными ресурсами смогут предоставить дополнительную информацию об участии местного населения на основе системы показателей, предложенной в ОЭСР (2015b) для оценки «взаимодействия заинтересованных сторон для инклюзивного руководства водными ресурсами». К 2017 году будет разработан и апробирован показатель, обеспечивающий критерии участия на местном уровне. К 2018 году данные будут доступны с помощью интерактивных платформ и баз данных в формате, способствующем развитию стратегического диалога и взаимного обучения. На 8-м Всемирном форуме по водным ресурсам в Бразилиа (2018 год) будет дан старт выпуску специальной публикации &quot;Краткий обзор вопросов руководства водными ресурсами&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Национальные правительства, участвующие в обследовании ГЛААС, проводят заполнение вопросника, которое желательно совмещать с проверкой при участии многих заинтересованных сторон. Хотя процесс возглавляет одно министерство (например, министерство водных ресурсов, министерство окружающей среды и т. д., в зависимости от страны), часто бывает так, что в процесс должны быть вовлечены многие другие министерства и ведомства, чтобы получить данные, необходимые для заполнения вопросника. Национальный координатор ГЛААС оказывает помощь ведущему министерству в координации сбора данных, в составлении национального ответа на вопросник и в руководстве процессом валидации данных. Для каждого представления данных для ГЛААС собирается информация о процессах в стране (количество задействованных министерств, проводилось ли национальное совещание для помощи в заполнении вопросника, валидация заинтересованными сторонами, использование документации и т. д.). После получения ответа от страны осуществляется тщательный процесс валидации данных, который часто является повторяющимся процессом, требующим взаимодействия и обратной связи с региональными и страновыми партнерами. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Странам также предлагается дать согласие на публикацию отдельных подтвержденных данных, представленных в ГЛААС. Таким образом, ожидается, что благодаря процессам сбора, валидации и консультаций результаты будут сопоставимы и никаких дальнейших корректировок не предвидится.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Календарь &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Сбор данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Текущий раунд проведения Глобального анализа и оценки состояния санитарии и питьевого водоснабжения в рамках Механизма «ООН – Водные ресурсы» ГЛAAС начат и данные будут доступны к концу 2016 года. (От NA до NA) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Выпуск данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Первый квартал 2017 года &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Поставщики данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Министерства, отвечающие за вопросы водоснабжения и санитарии, сельского хозяйства, развития и управления водными ресурсами, а также окружающей среды &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Составители данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Название: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ВОЗ, ОЭСР и ЮНЕП &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ВОЗ при поддержке ОЭСР и ЮНЕП &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Определение процедур участия местных сообществ в осуществлении политических или законодательных мер имеет жизненно важное значение для удовлетворения потребностей всех сообществ, в том числе наиболее уязвимых, а также поощряет владение программами, что, в свою очередь, способствует их устойчивости. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Небольшое значение этого показателя указывает на низкий уровень участия местных сообществ в управлении водными ресурсами и санитарией, тогда как большое значение указывает на высокий уровень участия, что указывает на большую ответственность и более высокую вероятность устойчивого предоставления и управления водными ресурсами и услугами санитарии. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные по местным административным единицам с установленными и действующими правилами и процедурами, обеспечивающими участие местного населения, собираются в рамках текущего цикла процесса ГЛААС и будут доступны к концу 2016 года. До тех пор будет представляться информация о наличии правил и процедур, принятых на национальном уровне для различных подсекторов. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Дополнительные данные, в том числе данные по участию местного населения, содержащиеся в Инициативе ОЭСР по руководству водными ресурсами и в административных данных, будут постепенно включаться в расчет показателя по мере их появления. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Вопросник по Глобальному анализу и оценке состояния санитарии и питьевого водоснабжения в рамках Механизма «ООН – Водные ресурсы» ГЛAAС предоставляет информацию о том, существуют ли в законах &quot;четко определенные процедуры или правила для участия пользователей услуг (например, домашних хозяйств) и сообществ в программах планирования&quot;. Для стран, у которых есть данные на уровне местных административных единиц, их просят предоставить данные по количеству местных административных единиц, для которых правила и процедуры местного участия (i) существуют и (ii) действуют, а также (iii) количество оцениваемых местных административных единиц и (iv) общее количество административных единиц в стране. Показатель рассчитывается как (ii) количество местных административных единиц с действующими правилами и процедурами для участия местных единиц, деленное на (iv) общее количество местных административных единиц в стране. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Числитель и знаменатель будут получены в результате проведения обследования ГЛААС для цикла 2016-2017 годов. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На страновом уровне: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Вследствие того, что показатель сильно зависит от страны и контекста, оценки по странам, по которым отсутствуют данные, не производятся. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; На региональном и глобальном уровнях: &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Действующий механизм, с помощью которого отдельные лица и сообщества могут вносить значительный вклад в управление водными ресурсами и санитарией; затем страна будет исключена из региональных и глобальных оценок этого показателя. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Глобальные и региональные оценки для соответствующего показателя наличия и использования правил и процедур участия на национальном уровне для различных подсекторов водных ресурсов также получены для поддержки целевого показателя. Точно так же страны с отсутствующими значениями исключаются из глобального и регионального анализа по этому показателю.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Региональные агрегаты: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для глобальных и региональных агрегатов доля местных административных единиц, которые имеют определенный и действующий механизм, с помощью которого отдельные лица и сообщества могут вносить значимый вклад в решения и направления по управлению водными ресурсами и санитарией, будет рассчитана как средняя величина по странам с учетом каждой страновой доли, выраженной в процентах и взвешенной на общую численность населения страны за отчетный год, принятой в качестве доли от численности населения мира.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Доступные странам методы и руководства для составления данных на национальном уровне: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Национальные правительства, участвующие в процессе ГЛААС, заполняют вопросник данными по стране, полученными на основе обследования, желательно в рамках обсуждения с участием многих заинтересованных сторон. Хотя процесс возглавляет одно министерство, часто бывает, что в процесс должны быть вовлечены многие различные министерства и ведомства с тем, чтобы получить данные, необходимые для заполнения вопросника. Национальный координатор процесса ГЛААС оказывает помощь ведущему министерству в координации сбора данных, в составлении национального ответа на вопросник и в руководстве процессом валидации данных. Документы обследования ГЛААС для текущего цикла можно найти по следующей ссылке: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&quot;&gt; http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Глобальный анализ и оценка состояния санитарии и питьевого водоснабжения в рамках Механизма «ООН – Водные ресурсы» ГЛAAС предоставляет информацию об управлении, мониторинге, людских ресурсах и финансировании в секторе водоснабжения, санитарии и гигиены (ВСГ). Обследование ООН-Водные ресурсы ГЛААС в настоящее время проводится раз в два года под руководством ВОЗ и уже завершены три полных цикла (2009/2010, 2011/2012 и 2013/2014 годы), а также пилотный проект, проведенный в 2008 году. Документы обследования ГЛААС для текущего цикла сбора данных (2016/2017 годы) можно найти по следующей ссылке: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&quot;&gt; http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обеспечение качества: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Страновая документация, после ее получения, проходит тщательный процесс валидации, который часто является повторяющимся процессом, требующим взаимодействия и обратной связи с региональными и страновыми партнерами. Качество документации также оценивается посредством анализа данных, собранных о процессах в стране (количество задействованных министерств, проводилось ли национальное совещание для помощи в заполнении вопросника, а также процесс валидации заинтересованными сторонами, использование документации и т. д.), а также дополнительно предоставленной документации. Кроме того, проводится внешняя валидация с ключевыми лицами, предоставившими сведения, в ходе которой эксперты ВСГ, которые не участвовали в процессе ГЛААС, отвечают на выбранные вопросы из обследования для конкретной страны в своей области знаний, и оценивается согласованность с ответами страны. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные, представленные посредством ГЛААС, перед отправкой утверждаются национальным правительством. Форма, (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/entity/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-consent-form-2016.doc?ua=1&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int /entity/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-consent-form-2016.doc?ua=1&lt;/a&gt;) дающая согласие Всемирной организации здравоохранения на распространение и публикацию данных по стране, подписывается и отправляется вместе с заполненным вопросником. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Азиатско-Тихоокеанский регион &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: Большинство стран (не менее 50% стран, охватывающих 60% населения региона) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Африка &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: Некоторые страны (примерно 50% стран, охватывающих 50% населения региона) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Латинская Америка и Карибский бассейн &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: большинство стран (не менее 60% стран, охватывающих 80% населения региона) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Европа, Северная Америка, Австралия, Новая Зеландия и Япония &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;: большинство стран (не менее 60% стран, охватывающих 60% населения региона) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Обратите внимание, что они отражают данные по наличию практики и процедур для местного участия на национальном уровне. Данные на уровне местных административных единиц собираются в рамках текущего цикла ГЛААС и посредством административных данных, которые будут постепенно включаться в расчет показателя (см. 7.1, 10.1 и 10.2). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Временные ряды параметров по показателю доступны для данных за 2008, 2010, 2012 и 2014 годы. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Этот показатель будет формироваться странами, поэтому никаких различий в глобальных и национальных значениях не ожидается. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/&quot;&gt; http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unep.org/&quot;&gt; http://www.unep.org/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/env/watergovernanceprogramme.htm&quot;&gt; http://www.oecd.org/env/watergovernanceprogramme.htm &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Ссылки: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Глобальный анализ и оценка системы водоснабжения и санитарии и питьевой воды ООН. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/&quot;&gt; http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ОЭСР (2015a), Принципы ОЭСР по управлению водными ресурсами, публикация доступна по адресу: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oecd.org/gov/regional-policy/OECD-Principles-on-Water-Governance-brochure.pdf&quot;&gt; https://www.oecd.org/gov/regional-policy/OECD-Principles-on-Water-Governance-brochure.pdf &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ОЭСР (2015b), Взаимодействие с заинтересованными сторонами для всеохватного управления водными ресурсами, Исследования ОЭСР по водным ресурсам, Издательство ОЭСР, Париж., &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/9789264231122-en&quot;&gt; http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/9789264231122-en &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ООН – Водные ресурсы за 2008 год: Отчет о состоянии КУВР для КУР -16, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unwater.org/publications/publications-detail/en/c/206480/UNEP-DHI%20&quot;&gt; http://www.unwater.org/publications/publications-detail/en/c/206480/UNEP-DHI &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ООН – Водные ресурсы за 2012 год: Отчеты о состоянии КУВР. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unwater.org/publications/status-report-on-integrated-water-resources-management/en/%20&quot;&gt; http://www.unwater.org/publications/status-report-on-integrated-water-resources-management/en/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные исследования за 2012 год по применению комплексных подходов к управлению водными ресурсами. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unepdhi.org/rioplus20%20&quot;&gt; http://www.unepdhi.org/rioplus20 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ЮНЕП за 2016 год. Степень внедрения комплексного управления водными ресурсами. Проект обследования в поддержку показателя 6.5.1 ЦУР &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unepdhi.org/whatwedo/gemi%20&quot;&gt; http://www.unepdhi.org/whatwedo/gemi &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; OECD за 2015 год. Взаимодействие с заинтересованными сторонами для всеохватного управления водными ресурсами. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/governance/stakeholder-engagement-for-inclusive-water-governance_9789264231122-en&quot;&gt; http://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/governance/stakeholder-engagement-for-inclusive-water-governance_9789264231122-en &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
