<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 6-b-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 6: Ensure availability and sustainable management of water and sanitation for all&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 6.b: Support and strengthen the participation of local communities in improving water and sanitation management&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 6.b.1: Proportion of local administrative units with established and operational policies and procedures for participation of local communities in water and sanitation management&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last updated: 11 July 2017&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Related indicators&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.5: Number of deaths, missing persons and persons affected by disaster per 100,000 people [a]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15.9: Number of deaths, missing persons and persons affected by disaster per 100,000 people [a]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Comments:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.5 (implement integrated water resources management at all levels, including transboundary cooperation as appropriate) 15.9 (integrate ecosystem and biodiversity values into national and local planning, development processes, poverty reduction strategies and accounts)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Institutional information&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organization(s):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World Health Organization (WHO)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations Environment Programme (UNEP)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator assesses the percentage of local administrative units (as defined by the national government) that have an established and operational mechanism by which individuals and communities can meaningfully contribute to decisions and directions about water and sanitation management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator Proportion of local administrative units with established and operational policies and procedures for participation of local communities in water and sanitation management is currently being measured by the Proportion of countries with clearly defined procedures in law or policy for participation by service users/communities in planning program in water and sanitation management, and hygiene promotion and the Proportion of countries with high level of users/communities participating in planning programs in water and sanitation management, and hygiene promotion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stakeholder participation is essential to ensure the sustainability of water and sanitation management options over time, e.g. the choice of appropriate solutions for a given social and economic context, and the full understanding of the impacts of a certain development decision. Defining the procedures in policy or law for the participation of local communities is vital to ensure needs of all the community is met, including the most vulnerable and also encourages ownership of schemes which in turn contributes to their sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local administrative units refers to non-overlapping sub-districts, municipalities, communes, or other local community-level units covering both urban and rural areas to be defined by the government. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Policies and procedures for participation of local communities in water and sanitation management would define a formal mechanism to ensure participation of users in planning water and sanitation activities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A policy or procedure is considered to be established if the mechanism for participation of local communities is defined in law or has been formally approved and published. It is considered to be operational if the policy or procedure is being implemented, with appropriate funding in place and with means for verifying that participation took place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2018;Water and sanitation&amp;#x2019; includes all areas of management related to each of the targets under SDG 6, namely: water supply (6.1), sanitation and hygiene (6.2), wastewater treatment and ambient water quality (6.3), efficiency and sustainable use (6.4), integrated water resources management (6.5) and water-related ecosystems (6.6).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UN-Water Global Analysis and Assessment of Sanitation and Drinking-Water (GLAAS) provides information on governance, monitoring, human resources, and financing in the water, sanitation, and hygiene (WASH) sector. The UN-Water GLAAS survey is currently conducted on a biennial basis, led by WHO, and collected data from 94 countries (predominantly low and lower-middle income countries) in the most recent cycle in 2013-2014. The scope of the question on community and user participation has been expanded beyond WASH for the 2016-17 GLAAS cycle to address all targets in SDG 6, including water quality, water rights/allocation, water resource management, and the status of water-related ecosystems. GLAAS has completed three full cycles (2009-2010, 2011-2012, and 2013-2014), as well as a pilot conducted in 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National governments participating in the GLAAS survey fill out the questionnaire, preferably supported by a multi-stakeholder review. Although one ministry leads the process, it is often the case that many different ministries and departments must be involved in the process in order to obtain the data required to complete the questionnaire. A GLAAS national focal person supports the lead ministry to coordinate data collection, to compile the national response to the questionnaire, and to lead on the process of data validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data will be complemented by Integrated Water Resources Management (IWRM) reporting in SDG target 6.5 (for wastewater and water quality, water efficiency, water resource management, and the status of water-related ecosystems) (UNEP 2016). A key component of IWRM is community participation and management of water resources at the local level. The analysis of IWRM has been done in the past by UN-Water in 2008 (led by UN-DESA) and in 2012 (led by UNEP, UNDP, GWP and SIWI) as requested by the UN Commission for Sustainable Development (UN-Water 2008, 2012).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The OECD Water Governance Initiative (WGI), a technical platform gathering 100+ members from the public, private and non-for-profit sectors, is currently developing a set of Water Governance Indicators, within the implementation strategy of the OECD Principles on Water Governance (OECD 2015a). The Water Governance Indicators are expected to be able to provide additional information on local participation on the basis of an indicators system proposed in OECD (2015b) for measuring &amp;#x201C;stakeholder engagement for inclusive water governance&amp;#x201D;. An indicator providing metrics on local participation will be developed and tested by 2017. Data will be made available through interactive platforms and databases in a format to foster policy dialogue and peer learning by 2018. A dedicated publication on &amp;#x201C;Water Governance at a Glance&amp;#x201D; will be launched at the 8th World Water Forum in Brasilia (2018).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Collection process:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National governments participating in the GLAAS survey fill out the questionnaire, preferably supported by a multi-stakeholder review. Although one ministry leads the process (e.g. Ministry of Water, Ministry of Environment, etc. depending on country), it is often the case that many different ministries and departments must be involved in the process in order to obtain the data required to complete the questionnaire. A GLAAS national focal person supports the lead ministry to coordinate data collection, to compile the national response to the questionnaire, and to lead on the process of data validation. For each GLAAS submission, information on the country processes are collected (number of ministries involved, whether a national meeting was held to support the filling of the questionnaire, stakeholder validation, use of documentation, etc.) Once received, the country submission undergoes a thorough data validation process, which is often an iterative process requiring communication and feedback with regional and country counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Countries are also requested to provide consent to publish individual, validated data responses as supplied to GLAAS. Thus through the data collection, validation and consultation processes, the results are expected to be comparable and no further adjustments are foreseen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendar&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Data collection:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current round of UN-Water Global Analysis and Assessment of Sanitation and Drinking-Water (GLAAS) has been launched and data will be available by end-2016. (From NA to NA)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Data release:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q1 2017 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data providers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ministries with responsibilities related to water supply and sanitation, agriculture, water resources development and management, and environment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data compilers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Name:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHO, OECD and UNEP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHO, with support from OECD and UNEP&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Rationale:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defining the procedures in policy or law for the participation of local communities is vital to ensure the needs of all the community are met, including the most vulnerable and also encourages ownership of schemes which in turn contributes to their sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A low value of this indicator would suggest that participation of local communities in water and sanitation management is low, whereas a high value would indicate high levels of participation, indicating greater ownership and a higher likelihood of sustainable delivery and management of water and sanitation services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comments and limitations:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data on local administrative units with established and operational policies and procedures for local participation is being collected through the current cycle of GLAAS, and will be available by end-2016. Until then, the presence of policies and procedures as reported at the national level for different subsectors will be reported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional data, including data measuring local participation from the OECD Water Governance Indicators and administrative data, will be progressively included in the calculation of the indicator as they become available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computation method:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UN-Water Global Analysis and Assessment of Sanitation and Drinking-Water (GLAAS) questionnaire provides information on whether there are &amp;#x201C;clearly defined procedures in laws or policies for participation by service users (e.g. households) and communities in planning programs&amp;#x201D;. For countries that have data available from the local administrative unit level, they are asked to provide data on the number of local administrative units for which policies and procedures for local participation (i) exist, and (ii) are operational, as well as (iii) the number of local administrative units assessed, and (iv) the total number of units in the country. The indicator is computed as (ii) the number of local admin units with operation policies and procedures for local participation divided by (iv) the total number of local administrative units in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both numerator and denominator will be obtained through the GLAAS survey for the 2016-2017 cycle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Treatment of missing values:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At country level:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the highly country- and context-specific nature of the indicator, no estimates are produced for countries that are missing data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At regional and global levels:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operational mechanism by which individuals and communities can meaningfully contribute to water and sanitation management then the country will be excluded from the regional and global estimates for this indicator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global and regional estimates for a related indicator on the presence and use of participation policies and procedures at the national level for different water subsectors are also derived to support the target indicator. Similarly, countries with missing values are excluded from global and regional analysis for this indicator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Regional aggregates:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For global and regional aggregates, the percentage of local administrative units that have a defined and operational mechanism by which individuals and communities can meaningfully contribute to decisions and directions about water and sanitation management will be averaged among countries, with each country&amp;#x2019;s percent value weighted based on total country population for the data year, as a proportion of the global population.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Methods and guidance available to countries for the compilation of the data at the national level:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National governments participating in GLAAS fill out the country survey, preferably supported by a multi-stakeholder review. Although one ministry leads the process, it is often the case that many different ministries and departments must be involved in the process in order to obtain the data required to complete the questionnaire. A GLAAS national focal person supports the lead ministry to coordinate data collection, to compile the national response to the questionnaire, and to lead on the process of data validation. GLAAS survey documents for the current cycle can be found at the following link: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UN-Water Global Analysis and Assessment of Sanitation and Drinking-Water (GLAAS) provides information on governance, monitoring, human resources, and financing in the water, sanitation, and hygiene (WASH) sector. The UN-Water GLAAS survey is currently conducted on a biennial basis, led by WHO and has completed three full cycles (2009/2010, 2011/2012, and 2013/2014), as well as a pilot conducted in 2008. GLAAS survey documents for the current cycle of data collection (2016/2017) can be found at the following link: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Quality assurance:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once received, the country submission undergoes a thorough data validation process, which is often an iterative process requiring communication and feedback with regional and country counterparts. Quality of the submission is also assessed through an analysis of data collected on country processes (number of ministries involved, whether a national meeting was held to support the filling of the questionnaire, stakeholder validation, use of documentation, etc.) as well as supporting documentation provided. In addition, an external validation with key informants is conducted, in which WASH experts who have not participated in the GLAAS process respond to selected questions from the survey for a specific country within their area of expertise, and agreement with country responses is evaluated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data submitted through GLAAS are endorsed by the national government prior to submission. A form (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/entity/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-consent-form-2016.doc?ua=1&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/entity/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-consent-form-2016.doc?ua=1&lt;/a&gt;) providing consent to WHO for the release and publication of the country data is signed and submitted along with the filled survey.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data availability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Asia and Pacific&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Most countries (at least 50% of the countries covering 60% of the population from the region)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Africa&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Some countries (approximately 50% of the countries covering 50% of the population from the region)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Latin America and the Caribbean&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Most countries (at least 60% of the countries covering 80% of the population from the region)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Europe, North America, Australia, New Zealand and Japan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Most countries (at least 60% of the countries covering 60% of the population from the region)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that these reflect data on presence of policies and procedures for local participation at the national level. Data at the local administrative unit level is being collected through the current cycle of GLAAS and through administrative data that will be progressively included in the calculation of the indicator (cf. 7.1, 10.1, and 10.2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Time series:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time series of parameters under the indicator are available for 2008, 2010, 2012, and 2014. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator will be generated by countries, thus no differences in global and national figures are expected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;References&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unep.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.unep.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/env/watergovernanceprogramme.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/env/watergovernanceprogramme.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UN-Water Global Analysis and Assessment of Sanitation and Drinking-Water. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OECD (2015a), OECD Principles on Water Governance, available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oecd.org/gov/regional-policy/OECD-Principles-on-Water-Governance-brochure.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.oecd.org/gov/regional-policy/OECD-Principles-on-Water-Governance-brochure.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OECD (2015b), Stakeholder Engagement for Inclusive Water Governance, OECD Studies on Water, OECD Publishing, Paris., &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/9789264231122-en&quot;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/9789264231122-en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UN-Water 2008 : Status Report on IWRM for CSD-16, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unwater.org/publications/publications-detail/en/c/206480/UNEP-DHI%20&quot;&gt;http://www.unwater.org/publications/publications-detail/en/c/206480/UNEP-DHI&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UN-Water 2012: Status Reports on IWRM. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unwater.org/publications/status-report-on-integrated-water-resources-management/en/%20&quot;&gt;http://www.unwater.org/publications/status-report-on-integrated-water-resources-management/en/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data from the 2012 Survey on the Application of Integrated Approaches to Water Resources Management. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unepdhi.org/rioplus20%20&quot;&gt;http://www.unepdhi.org/rioplus20&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNEP 2016. Degree of implementation of integrated water resources management. Draft survey to support SDG indicator 6.5.1 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unepdhi.org/whatwedo/gemi%20&quot;&gt;http://www.unepdhi.org/whatwedo/gemi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OECD 2015. Stakeholder Engagement for Inclusive Water Governance. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/governance/stakeholder-engagement-for-inclusive-water-governance_9789264231122-en&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/governance/stakeholder-engagement-for-inclusive-water-governance_9789264231122-en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Meta 6: Garantizar la disponibilidad y la gestión sostenible del agua y el saneamiento para todos&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 6.b: Apoyar y fortalecer la participación de las comunidades locales en la mejora de la gestión del agua y el saneamiento&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 6.b.1: Proporción de dependencias administrativas locales que han establecido políticas y procedimientos operacionales para la participación de las comunidades locales en la gestión del agua y el saneamiento&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Última actualización: 11 de julio de 2017&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 6: Garantir l&apos;accès de tous à des services d&apos;alimentation en eau et d&apos;assainissement gérés de façon durable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 6.b: Appuyer et renforcer la participation de la population locale à l’amélioration de la gestion de l’eau et de l’assainissement&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 6.b.1: Proportion d’administrations locales ayant mis en place des politiques et procédures opérationnelles encourageant la participation de la population locale à la gestion de l’eau et de l’assainissement&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dernière mise à jour : 11 Juillet 2017&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicateurs connexes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.5 : Nombre de morts, de personnes disparues et de personnes touchées par une catastrophe pour 100 000 personnes [a].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15.9 : Nombre de morts, de personnes disparues et de personnes touchées par une catastrophe pour 100 000 personnes [a]. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.5 (mettre en œuvre une gestion intégrée des ressources en eau à tous les niveaux, y compris la coopération transfrontalière, le cas échéant) 15.9 (intégrer les valeurs des écosystèmes et de la biodiversité dans la planification, les processus de développement, les stratégies de réduction de la pauvreté et les comptes nationaux et locaux). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Informations institutionnelles&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organization(s):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organisation mondiale de la santé (OMS)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programme des Nations unies pour l&apos;environnement (PNUE)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organisation de coopération et de développement économiques (OCDE) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Définition : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur évalue le pourcentage d&apos;unités administratives locales (telles que définies par le gouvernement national) qui disposent d&apos;un mécanisme établi et opérationnel grâce auquel les individus et les communautés peuvent contribuer de manière significative aux décisions et aux orientations concernant la gestion de l&apos;eau et de l&apos;assainissement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur Proportion d&apos;unités administratives locales ayant des politiques et procédures établies et opérationnelles pour la participation des communautés locales à la gestion de l&apos;eau et de l&apos;assainissement est actuellement mesuré par la proportion de pays ayant des procédures clairement définies dans la loi ou la politique pour la participation des utilisateurs/communautés de services à la planification des programmes de gestion de l&apos;eau et de l&apos;assainissement et de promotion de l&apos;hygiène et la proportion de pays ayant un niveau élevé d&apos;utilisateurs/communautés participant à la planification des programmes de gestion de l&apos;eau et de l&apos;assainissement et de promotion de l&apos;hygiène.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La participation des parties prenantes est essentielle pour assurer la durabilité des options de gestion de l&apos;eau et de l&apos;assainissement dans le temps, par exemple le choix de solutions appropriées pour un contexte social et économique donné, et la pleine compréhension des impacts d&apos;une certaine décision de développement. Il est essentiel de définir les procédures de participation des communautés locales dans la politique ou la législation afin de garantir la satisfaction des besoins de l&apos;ensemble de la communauté, y compris des plus vulnérables, et d&apos;encourager l&apos;appropriation des projets, ce qui contribue à leur durabilité.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Par unités administratives locales, on entend les sous-districts, municipalités, communes ou autres unités locales de niveau communautaire qui ne se chevauchent pas et qui couvrent à la fois les zones urbaines et rurales à définir par le gouvernement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les politiques et procédures de participation des communautés locales à la gestion de l&apos;eau et de l&apos;assainissement définiront un mécanisme formel pour assurer la participation des usagers à la planification des activités liées à l&apos;eau et à l&apos;assainissement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On considère qu&apos;une politique ou une procédure est établie si le mécanisme de participation des communautés locales est défini dans la loi ou a été formellement approuvé et publié. Il est considéré comme opérationnel si la politique ou la procédure est mise en œuvre, avec un financement approprié en place et avec des moyens permettant de vérifier que la participation a eu lieu. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x2018; L&apos;eau et l&apos;assainissement&amp;#x2019; comprend tous les domaines de gestion liés à chacune des cibles du ODD 6, à savoir : l&apos;approvisionnement en eau (6.1), l&apos;assainissement et l&apos;hygiène (6.2), le traitement des eaux usées et la qualité de l&apos;eau ambiante (6.3), l&apos;efficacité et l&apos;utilisation durable (6.4), la gestion intégrée des ressources en eau (6.5) et les écosystèmes liés à l&apos;eau (6.6).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Sources de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;analyse et l&apos;évaluation mondiales de l&apos;assainissement et de l&apos;eau potable (GLAAS) de l&apos;ONU-Eau fournit des informations sur la gouvernance, le suivi, les ressources humaines et le financement dans le secteur de l&apos;eau, de l&apos;assainissement et de l&apos;hygiène (WASH). L&apos;enquête GLAAS d&apos;ONU-Eau est actuellement menée sur une base biennale, sous la direction de l&apos;OMS, et a recueilli des données dans 94 pays (principalement des pays à revenu faible et moyen inférieur) au cours du cycle le plus récent, en 2013-2014. La portée de la question sur la participation des communautés et des utilisateurs a été élargie au-delà de l&apos;enquête WASH pour le cycle GLAAS 2016-17 afin de couvrir tous les objectifs du ODD 6, notamment la qualité de l&apos;eau, les droits/allocations d&apos;eau, la gestion des ressources en eau et l&apos;état des écosystèmes liés à l&apos;eau. GLAAS a achevé trois cycles complets (2009-2010, 2011-2012 et 2013-2014), ainsi qu&apos;un projet pilote mené en 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les gouvernements nationaux participant à l&apos;enquête GLAAS remplissent le questionnaire, de préférence en s&apos;appuyant sur un examen multipartite. Bien qu&apos;un ministère dirige le processus, il arrive souvent que plusieurs ministères et départements différents doivent être impliqués dans le processus afin d&apos;obtenir les données requises pour remplir le questionnaire. Un responsable national du GLAAS aide le ministère responsable à coordonner la collecte des données, à compiler la réponse nationale au questionnaire et à diriger le processus de validation des données. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données seront complétées par des rapports sur la gestion intégrée des ressources en eau (GIRE) dans le cadre de l&apos;objectif 6.5 du ODD (pour les eaux usées et la qualité de l&apos;eau, l&apos;efficacité de l&apos;eau, la gestion des ressources en eau et l&apos;état des écosystèmes liés à l&apos;eau) (PNUE 2016). Un élément clé de la GIRE est la participation communautaire et la gestion des ressources en eau au niveau local. L&apos;analyse de la GIRE a été effectuée dans le passé par l&apos;ONU-Eau en 2008 (sous la direction du DAES) et en 2012 (sous la direction du PNUE, du PNUD, du GWP et du SIWI) à la demande de la Commission du développement durable des Nations unies (ONU-Eau 2008, 2012). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;Initiative de l&apos;OCDE sur la gouvernance de l&apos;eau (WGI), une plateforme technique réunissant plus de 100 membres des secteurs public, privé et à but non lucratif, élabore actuellement un ensemble d&apos;indicateurs sur la gouvernance de l&apos;eau, dans le cadre de la stratégie de mise en œuvre des Principes de l&apos;OCDE sur la gouvernance de l&apos;eau (OCDE 2015a). Les indicateurs de gouvernance de l&apos;eau devraient pouvoir fournir des informations supplémentaires sur la participation locale sur la base d&apos;un système d&apos;indicateurs proposé dans l&apos;OCDE (2015b) pour mesurer &amp;#x201C; l&apos;engagement des parties prenantes pour une gouvernance inclusive de l&apos;eau &amp;#x201D;. Un indicateur fournissant des mesures sur la participation locale sera développé et testé d&apos;ici 2017. Les données seront mises à disposition par le biais de plateformes interactives et de bases de données dans un format permettant de favoriser le dialogue politique et l&apos;apprentissage par les pairs d&apos;ici 2018. Une publication consacrée à la gouvernance de l&apos;eau &amp;#x201C; sera lancée lors du 8e Forum mondial de l&apos;eau à Brasilia (2018). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Processus de collecte : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les gouvernements nationaux participant à l&apos;enquête GLAAS remplissent le questionnaire, de préférence en s&apos;appuyant sur un examen multipartite. Bien qu&apos;un ministère dirige le processus (par exemple, le ministère de l&apos;eau, le ministère de l&apos;environnement, etc. selon le pays), il arrive souvent que de nombreux ministères et départements différents doivent être impliqués dans le processus afin d&apos;obtenir les données requises pour remplir le questionnaire. Un point focal national du GLAAS aide le ministère responsable à coordonner la collecte des données, à compiler la réponse nationale au questionnaire et à diriger le processus de validation des données. Pour chaque soumission GLAAS, des informations sur les processus nationaux sont collectées (nombre de ministères impliqués, si une réunion nationale a été organisée pour soutenir le remplissage du questionnaire, validation des parties prenantes, utilisation de la documentation, etc. Une fois reçue, la soumission du pays est soumise à un processus de validation des données approfondi, qui est souvent un processus itératif nécessitant une communication et un retour d&apos;information avec les homologues régionaux et nationaux. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Les pays sont également invités à donner leur accord pour la publication des réponses individuelles et validées fournies au GLAAS. Ainsi, grâce aux processus de collecte, de validation et de consultation des données, les résultats devraient être comparables et aucun autre ajustement n&apos;est prévu. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendrier&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Collecte de données :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le cycle actuel d&apos;analyse et d&apos;évaluation mondiales de l&apos;assainissement et de l&apos;eau potable (GLAAS) de l&apos;ONU-Eau a été lancé et les données seront disponibles d&apos;ici la fin de l&apos;année 2016. (De NA à NA) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publication des données :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q1 2017 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fournisseurs de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ministères ayant des responsabilités liées à l&apos;approvisionnement en eau et à l&apos;assainissement, à l&apos;agriculture, au développement et à la gestion des ressources en eau et à l&apos;environnement&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compilateurs de données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nom : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OMS, OCDE et PNUE &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OMS, avec le soutien de l&apos;OCDE et du PNUE&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Raison d&apos;être :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il est essentiel de définir les procédures de participation des communautés locales dans les politiques ou les lois pour garantir la satisfaction des besoins de l&apos;ensemble de la communauté, y compris des plus vulnérables, et pour encourager l&apos;appropriation des programmes, ce qui contribue à leur durabilité.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Une valeur faible de cet indicateur suggérerait que la participation des communautés locales à la gestion de l&apos;eau et de l&apos;assainissement est faible, tandis qu&apos;une valeur élevée indiquerait des niveaux élevés de participation, ce qui indique une plus grande appropriation et une plus grande probabilité de fourniture et de gestion durables des services d&apos;eau et d&apos;assainissement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires et limitations : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des données sur les unités administratives locales ayant des politiques et des procédures établies et opérationnelles pour la participation locale sont collectées dans le cadre du cycle actuel du GLAAS et seront disponibles d&apos;ici la fin de l&apos;année 2016. D&apos;ici là, la présence de politiques et de procédures telles que rapportées au niveau national pour différents sous-secteurs sera signalée.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des données supplémentaires, notamment des données mesurant la participation locale provenant des indicateurs de l&apos;OCDE sur la gouvernance de l&apos;eau et des données administratives, seront progressivement incluses dans le calcul de l&apos;indicateur au fur et à mesure qu&apos;elles seront disponibles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Méthodologie&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Méthode de calcul :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le questionnaire d&apos;analyse et d&apos;évaluation mondiales de l&apos;assainissement et de l&apos;eau potable (GLAAS) de l&apos;ONU-Eau fournit des informations sur l&apos;existence de &amp;#x201C; procédures clairement définies dans les lois ou les politiques pour la participation des utilisateurs de services (par exemple les ménages) et des communautés aux programmes de planification &amp;#x201D;. Pour les pays qui disposent de données au niveau des unités administratives locales, il leur est demandé de fournir des données sur le nombre d&apos;unités administratives locales pour lesquelles des politiques et des procédures de participation locale (i) existent, et (ii) sont opérationnelles, ainsi que (iii) le nombre d&apos;unités administratives locales évaluées, et (iv) le nombre total d&apos;unités dans le pays. L&apos;indicateur est calculé comme suit : (ii) le nombre d&apos;unités administratives locales ayant des politiques et procédures opérationnelles pour la participation locale, divisé par (iv) le nombre total d&apos;unités administratives locales dans le pays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le numérateur et le dénominateur seront obtenus par l&apos;enquête GLAAS pour le cycle 2016-2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Traitement des valeurs manquantes : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Au niveau national : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En raison de la nature très spécifique de l&apos;indicateur en fonction du pays et du contexte, aucune estimation n&apos;est produite pour les pays dont les données sont manquantes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Au niveau régional et mondial : &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mécanisme opérationnel par lequel les individus et les communautés peuvent contribuer de manière significative à la gestion de l&apos;eau et de l&apos;assainissement ; le pays sera alors exclu des estimations régionales et mondiales pour cet indicateur. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des estimations mondiales et régionales pour un indicateur connexe sur la présence et l&apos;utilisation de politiques et de procédures de participation au niveau national pour différents sous-secteurs de l&apos;eau sont également dérivées pour soutenir l&apos;indicateur cible. De même, les pays pour lesquels des valeurs sont manquantes sont exclus de l&apos;analyse mondiale et régionale pour cet indicateur. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agrégats régionaux : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour les agrégats mondiaux et régionaux, le pourcentage d&apos;unités administratives locales qui disposent d&apos;un mécanisme défini et opérationnel permettant aux individus et aux communautés de contribuer de manière significative aux décisions et aux orientations concernant la gestion de l&apos;eau et de l&apos;assainissement sera calculé en moyenne par pays, la valeur du pourcentage de chaque pays&amp;#x2019; étant pondérée en fonction de la population totale du pays pour l&apos;année considérée, en proportion de la population mondiale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Méthodes et orientations mises à la disposition des pays pour la compilation des données au niveau national :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les gouvernements nationaux participant au GLAAS remplissent l&apos;enquête par pays, de préférence en s&apos;appuyant sur un examen multipartite. Bien qu&apos;un ministère dirige le processus, il arrive souvent que plusieurs ministères et départements différents doivent être impliqués dans le processus afin d&apos;obtenir les données requises pour remplir le questionnaire. Un responsable national du GLAAS aide le ministère responsable à coordonner la collecte des données, à compiler la réponse nationale au questionnaire et à diriger le processus de validation des données. Les documents de l&apos;enquête GLAAS pour le cycle actuel peuvent être trouvés sur le lien suivant : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;analyse et l&apos;évaluation mondiales de l&apos;assainissement et de l&apos;eau potable (GLAAS) de l&apos;ONU-Eau fournit des informations sur la gouvernance, le suivi, les ressources humaines et le financement dans le secteur de l&apos;eau, de l&apos;assainissement et de l&apos;hygiène (WASH). L&apos;enquête GLAAS d&apos;ONU-Eau est actuellement menée sur une base biennale, sous la direction de l&apos;OMS et a achevé trois cycles complets (2009/2010, 2011/2012 et 2013/2014), ainsi qu&apos;un projet pilote mené en 2008. Les documents de l&apos;enquête GLAAS pour le cycle actuel de collecte de données (2016/2017) peuvent être consultés sur le lien suivant : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-2017-survey/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Assurance de la qualité : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Une fois reçue, la soumission du pays est soumise à un processus de validation des données approfondi, qui est souvent un processus itératif nécessitant une communication et un retour d&apos;information avec les homologues régionaux et nationaux. La qualité de la soumission est également évaluée par une analyse des données collectées sur les processus nationaux (nombre de ministères impliqués, si une réunion nationale a été organisée pour aider à remplir le questionnaire, validation des parties prenantes, utilisation de la documentation, etc. En outre, une validation externe avec des informateurs clés est effectuée, dans laquelle les experts en WASH qui n&apos;ont pas participé au processus GLAAS répondent à des questions sélectionnées de l&apos;enquête pour un pays spécifique dans leur domaine d&apos;expertise, et l&apos;accord avec les réponses des pays est évalué. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données soumises par le biais de GLAAS sont approuvées par le gouvernement national avant d&apos;être soumises. Un formulaire (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/entity/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-consent-form-2016.doc?ua=1&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/entity/water_sanitation_health/monitoring/investments/glaas-consent-form-2016.doc?ua=1&lt;/a&gt;) de consentement à la diffusion et à la publication des données nationales par l&apos;OMS est signé et soumis avec l&apos;enquête remplie.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilité des données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Asie et Pacifique &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; : La plupart des pays (au moins 50% des pays couvrant 60% de la population de la région) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Afrique&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Certains pays (environ 50 % des pays couvrant 50 % de la population de la région) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt; Amérique latine et Caraïbes &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; : La plupart des pays (au moins 60% des pays couvrant 80% de la population de la région) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Europe, Amérique du Nord, Australie, Nouvelle-Zélande et Japon &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; : La plupart des pays (au moins 60% des pays couvrant 60% de la population de la région) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Veuillez noter que ces données reflètent la présence de politiques et de procédures de participation locale au niveau national. Les données au niveau des unités administratives locales sont collectées dans le cadre du cycle actuel de GLAAS et par le biais de données administratives qui seront progressivement incluses dans le calcul de l&apos;indicateur (cf. 7.1, 10.1 et 10.2) &lt;/p&gt;.
&lt;h2&gt;Série chronologique : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les séries chronologiques des paramètres de l&apos;indicateur sont disponibles pour 2008, 2010, 2012 et 2014. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sources des divergences : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur sera généré par les pays, donc aucune différence n&apos;est prévue entre les chiffres mondiaux et nationaux.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Références&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unep.org/&quot;&gt;http://www.unep.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/env/watergovernanceprogramme.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd.org/env/watergovernanceprogramme.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Références:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analyse et évaluation mondiales de l&apos;&apos;assainissement et de l&apos;eau potable par l&apos;ONU-Eau. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/water_sanitation_health/glaas/en/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OCDE (2015a), Principes de l&apos;OCDE sur la gouvernance de l&apos;eau, disponible à l&apos;adresse suivante &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oecd.org/gov/regional-policy/OECD-Principles-on-Water-Governance-brochure.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.oecd.org/gov/regional-policy/OECD-Principles-on-Water-Governance-brochure.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OCDE (2015b), Engagement des parties prenantes pour une gouvernance inclusive de l&apos;eau, Études de l&apos;OCDE sur l&apos;eau, Éditions de l&apos;OCDE, Paris, &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/9789264231122-en&quot;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/9789264231122-en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONU-Eau 2008 : Rapport d&apos;étape sur la GIRE pour la CDD-16, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unwater.org/publications/publications-detail/en/c/206480/UNEP-DHI%20&quot;&gt;http://www.unwater.org/publications/publications-detail/en/c/206480/UNEP-DHI&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ONU-Eau 2012 : Rapports sur l&apos;état d&apos;avancement de la gestion intégrée des ressources en eau. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unwater.org/publications/status-report-on-integrated-water-resources-management/en/%20&quot;&gt;http://www.unwater.org/publications/status-report-on-integrated-water-resources-management/en/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
1544]Données de l&apos;enquête 2012 sur l&apos;application des approches intégrées de la gestion des ressources en eau. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unepdhi.org/rioplus20%20&quot;&gt;http://www.unepdhi.org/rioplus20&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNEP 2016. Degré de mise en œuvre de la gestion intégrée des ressources en eau. Projet d&apos;enquête à l&apos;appui de l&apos;indicateur 6.5.1 du ODD &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unepdhi.org/whatwedo/gemi%20&quot;&gt;http://www.unepdhi.org/whatwedo/gemi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OCDE 2015. Engagement des parties prenantes pour une gouvernance inclusive de l&apos;eau. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/governance/stakeholder-engagement-for-inclusive-water-governance_9789264231122-en&quot;&gt;http://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/governance/stakeholder-engagement-for-inclusive-water-governance_9789264231122-en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 6: Обеспечение наличия и рационального использования водных ресурсов и санитарии для всех&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 6.b: Поддерживать и укреплять участие местных общин в улучшении водного хозяйства и санитарии&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 6.b.1: Доля  местных административных единиц, в которых установлены и действуют правила и процедуры участия местных общин в улучшении водного хозяйства и санитарии&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Последнее обновление: 11 июля 2017 года&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
