<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 7-2-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 7: Ensure access to affordable, reliable, sustainable and modern energy for all&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 7.2: By 2030, increase substantially the share of renewable energy in the global energy mix&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 7.2.1: Renewable energy share in the total final energy consumption&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2021-02-15&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;International Energy Agency (IEA) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations Statistics Division (UNSD) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International Renewable Energy Agency (IRENA)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;International Energy Agency (IEA) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations Statistics Division (UNSD) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International Renewable Energy Agency (IRENA)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The renewable energy share in total final consumption is the percentage of final consumption of energy that is derived from renewable resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renewable energy consumption includes consumption of energy derived from: hydro, wind, solar, solid biofuels, liquid biofuels, biogas, geothermal, marine and renewable waste. Total final energy consumption is calculated from balances as total final consumption minus non-energy use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments with regard to specific renewable energy sources: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solar energy includes solar PV and solar thermal. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Liquid biofuels include biogasoline, biodiesels and other liquid biofuels. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solid biofuels include fuelwood, animal waste, vegetable waste, black liquor, bagasse and charcoal. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Renewable waste energy covers energy from renewable municipal waste.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The renewable energy share in the total final energy consumption is expressed as a percentage and has no unit of measurement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;#x201C;International Recommendations for Energy Statistics&amp;#x201D; (IRES), adopted by the UN Statistical Commission, is the globally recognized standard used to develop the energy statistics underlying the calculation of the indicator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This standard is available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/methodology/ires&quot;&gt;unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/methodology/ires&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data on renewable energy consumption are available through national energy balances compiled based on data collected by the International Energy Agency (for around 150 countries) and the United Nations Statistics Division (UNSD) for all countries. The energy balances make it possible to trace all the different sources and uses of energy at the national level. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some technical assistance may be needed to improve these statistics, particularly in the case of renewable energy sources. Specialized industry surveys (e.g. on bioenergy use) or household surveys (in combination with the measurement of other indicators) would be feasible approaches to filling in data gaps (e.g. for use of firewood, off-grid solar energy).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The IEA collects energy data at the national level according to harmonised international definitions and questionnaires, as described in the UN International Recommendations for Energy Statistics (unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/methodology/ires/).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNSD also collects energy statistics from countries according to the same harmonised methodology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data are collected on an annual basis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The IEA World Energy Balances are published in February, April and July with progressively broader geographical coverage (publishing full information for two calendar years prior and selected information for one year prior). The UN Energy Statistics Database is made available towards the end of the calendar year with full geographical coverage (publishing information for two calendar years prior).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;National administrations, as described in documentation on sources for IEA and UNSD:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wds.iea.org/wds/pdf/WORLDBAL_Documentation.pdf&quot;&gt;http://wds.iea.org/wds/pdf/WORLDBAL_Documentation.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/data&quot;&gt;unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The International Energy Agency (IEA) and the United Nations Statistics Division (UNSD) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IEA and UNSD are the primary compilers of energy statistics across countries and develop internationally comparable energy balances based on internationally agreed methodologies. Aggregates are based on analysis merging of IEA and UNSD data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;IEA as one of the custodian agencies responsible for monitoring progress towards the SDG 7.2 target, leverage on their national data efforts and add value by promoting coherent standards, definitions and methodologies for both raw data and the derived indicators with the ultimate goal of producing international comparable datasets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UNSD mission in the area of energy statistics is to strengthen national statistical systems in order to assist them in producing high quality energy statistics and balances. The mission is realized through four workstreams: Data collection (since 1950); Development of methodological guidelines and standards in energy statistics (e.g., IRES, ESCM); Capacity building (to disseminate such methodology and to assist countries to strengthen their energy statistical systems); and International cooperation and coordination. UNSD was selected as one of the custodians of indicator 7.2.1 because it collects for all countries the underlying data necessary to calculate the indicator. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The target &amp;#x201C;By 2030, increase substantially the share of renewable energy in the global energy mix&amp;#x201D; impacts all three dimensions of sustainable development. Renewable energy technologies represent a major element in strategies for greening economies everywhere in the world and for tackling the critical global problem of climate change. A number of definitions of renewable energy exist; what they have in common is highlighting as renewable all forms of energy that their consumption does not deplete their availability in the future. These include solar, wind, ocean, hydropower, geothermal sources, and bioenergy (in the case of bioenergy, which can be depleted, sources of bioenergy can be replaced within a short to medium-term frame). Importantly, this indicator focuses on the amount of renewable energy actually consumed rather than the capacity for renewable energy production, which cannot always be fully utilized. By focusing on consumption by the end user, it avoids the distortions caused by the fact that conventional energy sources are subject to significant energy losses along the production chain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A limitation with existing renewable energy statistics is that they are not able to distinguish whether renewable energy is being sustainably produced. For example, a substantial share of today&amp;#x2019;s renewable energy consumption comes from the use of wood and charcoal by households in the developing world, which sometimes may be associated with unsustainable forestry practices. There are efforts underway to improve the ability to measure the sustainability of bio-energy, although this remains a significant challenge. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Off-grid renewables data are limited and not sufficiently captured in national and international energy statistics. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The method of allocation of renewable energy consumption from electricity and heat output assumes that the share of transmission and distribution losses are the same among all technologies. However, this is not always true; for example when renewables are usually located in more remote areas and may incur larger losses. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Likewise, imports and exports of electricity and heat are assumed to follow the renewable share of electricity and heat generation, respectively. This is a simplification that in many cases will not affect the indicator too much, but that might do so in some cases, for example, when a country only generates electricity from fossil fuels but imports a great share of the electricity it uses from a neighboring country&amp;#x2019;s hydroelectric power plant. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Methodological challenges associated with defining and measuring renewable energy are more fully described in the Global Tracking Framework (IEA and World Bank, 2013) Chapter 4, Section 1, pages 194-200. Data for traditional use of solid biofuels are generally scarce globally, and developing capacity in tracking such energy use, including developing national-level surveys, is essential for sound global energy tracking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This indicator is based on the development of comprehensive energy statistics across supply and demand for all energy sources &amp;#x2013; statistics used to produce the energy balance. Internationally agreed methodologies for energy statistics are described in the &amp;#x201C;International Recommendations for Energy Statistics&amp;#x201D; (IRES), adopted by the UN Statistical Commission, available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/methodology/ires&quot;&gt;unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/methodology/ires&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once an energy balance is developed, the indicator can be calculated by dividing final energy consumption from all renewable sources by total final energy consumption. Renewable energy consumption is derived as the sum of direct final consumption of renewable sources plus the components of electricity and heat consumption estimated to be derived from renewable sources based on generation shares. For instance, if total final consumption is 150 TJ for biogas energy, while total final consumption of electricity is 400 TJ and heat 100 TJ, and the share of biogas is 10 percent in electricity output and 5 percent in heat output, the total reported number for biogas consumption will be 195 TJ (150 TJ+400TJ*10%+100TJ*5%). The Global Tracking Framework Report (IEA and World Bank, 2013) provides more details on the suggested methodology for defining and measuring renewable energy (Chapter 4, Section 1, page 201-202). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The IEA has several internal procedures in place for energy data validation. This includes energy balance checks, time series analysis and reconciling differences in statistical classifications and definitions. UNSD also has a number of internal validation procedures to ensure internal data consistency, for instance through energy balance checks, and trend consistency, e.g. by way of time series analysis. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The country specific commodity balances underlying the IEA energy data are based on national energy data of heterogeneous nature converted and adapted to fit the IEA format and methodology. Considerable effort has been made to ensure that the data adhere to the IEA definitions based on the guidelines provided by IRES. Nevertheless, energy statistics at the national level are often collected using criteria and definitions which differ, sometimes considerably, from those of international organisations. This is especially true for non-OECD countries, which are submitting data to the IEA on a voluntary basis. The IEA has identified most of these differences and, where possible, adjusted the data to meet international definitions. For details on recognized country specific anomalies and the corresponding adjustments, please refer to country specific notes included in the IEA World energy balances documentation file available at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://wds.iea.org/wds/pdf/WORLDBAL_Documentation.pdf&quot;&gt;wds.iea.org/wds/pdf/WORLDBAL_Documentation.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, UNSD also needs to adjust certain data to fit the international methodology set by IRES, thus ensuring data comparability across countries. Data from all countries are submitted voluntarily to UNSD, sometimes via non-standard formats or through sharing of national publications. The identification of such deviations from the standard is an ongoing task, and UNSD has started publishing some of this information in a supplement to the Energy Statistics Database named &amp;#x201C;Notes on sources&amp;#x201D;, available at: unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/pubs/yearbook/ , with the goal of increasing transparency and providing more and more information with time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IEA has attempted to provide all the elements of energy balances down to the level of final consumption, for over 150 countries. Providing all the elements of supply, as well as all inputs and outputs of the main transformation activities and final consumption has often required estimations. Estimations have been generally made after consultation with national statistical offices, energy companies, utilities and national energy experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, UNSD attempts to provide full energy balances for the 225 countries and areas it covers, including the 75 or so it covers for SDG reporting. This may require searching for national official publications, data from other international organizations and expert estimation based on reputable sources and other publicly available information. Generally speaking, data on the supply side is more widely available than transformation activities and final consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022; At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to estimates at a country level, adjustments addressing differences in definitions alongside estimations for informal and/or confidential trade, production or consumption of energy products are sometimes required to complete major aggregates, when key statistics are missing. Such estimations and adjustments implemented by IEA have been generally made after consultation with national statistical offices, energy companies, utilities and national energy experts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aggregates are calculated, whether by region or global, using final energy consumption as weights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The IEA data corresponding to OECD countries are derived based on information provided in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the five fuel specific annual IEA/Eurostat joint questionnaires completed by the national administrations. These questionnaires are available online at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iea.org/areas-of-work/data-and-statistics/questionnaires&quot;&gt;iea.org/areas-of-work/data-and-statistics/questionnaires&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IEA commodity balances for all other countries are based on national energy data of heterogeneous nature, converted and adapted to fit the IEA format and methodology based on IRES recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to IRES, UNSD has published the &lt;em&gt;Energy Statistics Compilers Manual&lt;/em&gt; (ESCM - &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/methodology/escm/&quot;&gt;unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/methodology/escm/&lt;/a&gt;) as a practical companion to assist countries in the compilation of data according to the international methodology. UNSD sends countries its own questionnaire (&lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\leonardo.souza\Documents\Leo\Energy\Sustainable%20Development\SDG%20Indicators\IEA%20coordination\unstats.un.org\unsd\energystats\questionnaire\&quot;&gt;unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/questionnaire/&lt;/a&gt;), except to the countries which are mandated to submit the IEA/Eurostat joint questionnaires. In the latter case, UNSD obtains data from the IEA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The IEA, in co-operation with the Statistical Office of the European Communities (Eurostat), has published an Energy Statistics Manual. This Manual helps the energy statisticians have a better grasp of definitions, units and methodologies. Moreover, IEA has established a quality management framework based on the internationally recognized guidelines recommended by IRES to ensure quality of statistical products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ESCM contains a full chapter on the Generic Statistical Business Process Model applied to energy statistics, helping countries manage energy data quality. Inside UNSD, processes are established to ensure the quality of its products, and such processes are reviewed periodically.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The IEA follows the guidelines recommended by the IRES to ensure relevance, accuracy and reliability, timeliness and punctuality, accessibility and clarity as well as coherence and comparability of the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNSD coordinated input from international organizations and countries to publish IRES and its practical companion the ESCM. Each of both contains a chapter on quality assurance and metadata to help guide all countries ensure good energy data quality. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between the various existing data sources, primarily the IEA World Energy Balances and the UN Energy Statistics Database, annual total and renewable energy consumption for every country and area can be collected. The Tracking SDG7: The Energy Progress Report (formerly &lt;em&gt;Sustainable Energy for All Global Tracking Framework&lt;/em&gt;) is reporting this indicator at a global level between 1990 and 2030. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2000 &amp;#x2013; present&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disaggregation of the data on consumption of renewable energy, e.g. by resource and end-use sector, could provide insights into other dimensions of the goal, such as affordability and reliability. For solar energy, it may also be of interest to disaggregate between on grid and off-grid capacity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IEA World energy balances and the UN Energy Statistics Database, which provide the underlying data for calculating this indicator, are global databases obtained following harmonised definitions and comparable methodologies across countries. However, they do not represent an official source for national submissions of the indicator 7.2.1 on renewable energy. Due to possible deviations from IRES in national methodologies, national indicators may differ from the internationally comparable ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Difference may arise due to different sources of official energy data, dissimilarities in the underlying methodologies, adjustments and estimations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iea.org; &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/&quot;&gt;unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IEA Energy Balances and Statistics &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iea.org/statistics/&quot;&gt;http://www.iea.org/statistics/ &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UN Energy Statistics Database &lt;a id=&quot;OLE_LINK2&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;OLE_LINK1&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/data/&quot;&gt;unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/data&lt;/a&gt; (description) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://data.un.org/Explorer.aspx?d=EDATA&quot;&gt;data.un.org/Explorer.aspx?d=EDATA&lt;/a&gt; (data)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IEA SDG 7 webpage: &lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\leonardo.souza\Documents\Leo\Energy\Sustainable%20Development\SDG%20Indicators\IEA%20coordination\iea.org\reports\sdg7-data-and-projections&quot;&gt;iea.org/reports/sdg7-data-and-projections&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations. 2018. &amp;#x201C;International Recommendations for Energy Statistics&amp;#x201D;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/methodology/ires&quot;&gt;unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/methodology/ires&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International Energy Agency (IEA), International Renewable Energy Agency (IRENA), United Nations Statistics Division (UNSD), the World Bank, World Health Organization (WHO). 2019. &amp;#x201C;Tracking SDG7: The Energy Progress Report 2019&amp;#x201D;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://trackingsdg7.esmap.org/&quot;&gt;trackingsdg7.esmap.org/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International Energy Agency (IEA), International Renewable Energy Agency (IRENA), United Nations Statistics Division (UNSD), the World Bank, World Health Organization (WHO). 2018. &amp;#x201C;Tracking SDG7: The Energy Progress Report 2018&amp;#x201D;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://trackingsdg7.esmap.org/&quot;&gt;trackingsdg7.esmap.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International Energy Agency (IEA) and the World Bank. 2017. &amp;#x201C;Global Tracking Framework 2017&amp;#x2014;Progress toward Sustainable Energy&amp;#x201D;. World Bank, Washington, DC. License: Creative Commons Attribution CC BY 3.0 IGO. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seforall.org/sites/default/files/eegp17-01_gtf_full_report_final_for_web_posting_0402.pdf&quot;&gt;seforall.org/sites/default/files/eegp17-01_gtf_full_report_final_for_web_posting_0402.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International Energy Agency (IEA) and the World Bank. 2015. &amp;#x201C;Global Tracking Framework 2015&amp;#x2014;Progress Toward Sustainable Energy&amp;#x201D;, World Bank, Washington, DC. Doi: 10.1596/978-1-4648 -0690-2 License: Creative Commons Attribution CC BY 3.0 IGO. &lt;a href=&quot;http://seforall.org/sites/default/files/GTF-2105-Full-Report.pdf&quot;&gt;seforall.org/sites/default/files/GTF-2105-Full-Report.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International Energy Agency (IEA) and the World Bank. 2013. &amp;#x201C;Global Tracking Framework 2013&amp;#x201D;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://webstore.iea.org/global-tracking-framework-2013&quot;&gt;webstore.iea.org/global-tracking-framework-2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IRENA Renewable Energy Database &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irena.org/statistics&quot;&gt;https://www.irena.org/statistics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations. 2016. &amp;#x201C;Energy Statistics Compilers Manual&amp;#x201D; (whitecover)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/methodology/escm/&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 7: Garantizar el acceso a una energía asequible, fiable, sostenible y moderna para todos&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 7.2: De aquí a 2030, aumentar considerablemente la proporción de energía renovable en el conjunto de fuentes energéticas&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 7.2.1: Proporción de energía renovable en el consumo final total de energía&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Última actualización: 7 de febrero de 2020&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Información institucional&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Organización(es):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Agencia Internacional de la Energía (AIE) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; División de Estadística de las Naciones Unidas &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Agencia Internacional de Energías Renovables (IRENA)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La cuota de energía renovable en el consumo final total es el porcentaje del consumo final de energía que procede de recursos renovables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El consumo de energía renovable incluye el consumo de energía derivada de: biocombustibles sólidos, hidroeléctrica, eólica, solar, biocombustibles líquidos, biogás, geotérmica, marina y residuos. El consumo total de energía final se calcula a partir de los balances y estadísticas nacionales como el consumo final total menos el uso no energético. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comentarios sobre recursos energéticos renovables específicos: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;El consumo de energía solar incluye la energía solar fotovoltaica y la energía solar térmica. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;El consumo de energía de los biocombustibles líquidos incluye la biogasolina, los biodiésel y otros biocombustibles líquidos. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;El consumo de biocombustibles sólidos incluye la leña, los residuos animales, los residuos vegetales, el licor negro, el bagazo y el carbón vegetal.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La energía de los residuos abarca la energía procedente de los residuos municipales renovables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos sobre el consumo de energías renovables están disponibles a través de los balances energéticos nacionales elaborados a partir de los datos recogidos por la Agencia Internacional de la Energía (para unos 150 países) y la División de Estadística de las Naciones Unidas (UNSD) para todos los países. Los balances energéticos permiten rastrear todas las diferentes fuentes y usos de la energía a nivel nacional. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puede ser necesaria cierta asistencia técnica para mejorar estas estadísticas, sobre todo en el caso de las fuentes de energía renovables. Las encuestas industriales especializadas (por ejemplo, sobre el uso de la bioenergía) o las encuestas de hogares (en combinación con la medición de otros indicadores) serían enfoques factibles para llenar las brechas de datos (por ejemplo, para el uso de la leña, la energía solar fuera de la red). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendario&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recopilación de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos se recopilan anualmente.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publicación de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los Balances Energéticos de la AIE se publican en verano (publicando información de dos años calendario anteriores). La base de datos de estadísticas energéticas de la ONU se publica a finales del año calendario (publicando información de dos años calendario anteriores).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Administraciones nacionales, tal y como se describe en la documentación sobre las fuentes de la AIE y la UNSD:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\leonardo.souza\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\INetCache\Content.Outlook\6GFD9MJP\wds.iea.org\wds\pdf\WORLDBAL_Documentation.pdf&quot;&gt;http://wds.iea.org/wds/pdf/WORLDBAL_Documentation.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/data&quot;&gt;unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nombre:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Agencia Internacional de la Energía (AIE) y la División de Estadística de las Naciones Unidas (UNSD) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La AIE y la UNSD son los principales recopiladores de estadísticas energéticas nacionales y desarrollan balances energéticos comparables internacionalmente basados en metodologías acordadas internacionalmente. Los agregados se basan en la fusión de análisis de los datos de la AIE y la UNSD. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La meta &amp;#x201C;Para 2030, aumentar sustancialmente la cuota de energía renovable en la combinación energética mundial&amp;#x201D; afecta a las tres dimensiones del desarrollo sostenible. Las tecnologías de energía renovable representan un elemento importante de las estrategias para hacer más ecológicas las economías de todo el mundo y para abordar el problema mundial crítico del cambio climático. Existen varias definiciones de energía renovable; lo que tienen en común es destacar como renovables todas las formas de energía que su consumo no agote su disponibilidad en el futuro. Estos incluyen energía solar, eólica, oceánica, hidroeléctrica, recursos geotérmicos y bioenergía (en el caso de la bioenergía, que puede agotarse, las fuentes de bioenergía se pueden reemplazar en un marco de corto a mediano plazo). Es importante destacar que este indicador se centra en la cantidad de energía renovable realmente consumida en lugar de la capacidad de producción de energía renovable, que no siempre se puede utilizar plenamente. Al centrarse en el consumo del usuario final, evita las distorsiones causadas por el hecho de que las fuentes de energía convencionales están sujetas a pérdidas de energía significativas a lo largo de la cadena de producción. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Una de las limitaciones de las estadísticas existentes sobre energías renovables es que no pueden distinguir si la energía renovable se produce de forma sostenible. Por ejemplo, una parte importante del consumo actual de energía renovable procede del uso de madera y carbón vegetal por parte de los hogares del mundo en desarrollo, lo que a veces puede estar asociado a prácticas forestales insostenibles. Se están realizando esfuerzos para mejorar la capacidad de medir la sostenibilidad de la bioenergía, aunque esto sigue siendo un reto importante. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Los datos sobre las energías renovables fuera de la red son limitados y no se recogen suficientemente en las estadísticas energéticas. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;El método de asignación del consumo de energía renovable a partir de la producción de electricidad y calor supone que la parte de las pérdidas de transmisión y distribución es la misma entre todas las tecnologías. Sin embargo, esto no siempre es cierto porque las renovables suelen estar situadas en zonas más alejadas de los centros de consumo y pueden incurrir en mayores pérdidas. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Asimismo, se supone que las importaciones y exportaciones de electricidad y calor siguen la cuota de renovabilidad de la generación de electricidad y calor, respectivamente. Se trata de una simplificación que en muchos casos no afectará demasiado al indicador, pero que podría hacerlo en algunos casos, por ejemplo, cuando un país sólo genera electricidad a partir de combustibles fósiles pero importa una gran parte de la electricidad que utiliza de una central hidroeléctrica de un país vecino. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Los retos metodológicos asociados a la definición y medición de las energías renovables se describen con más detalle en el Marco de Seguimiento Global (AIE y Banco Mundial, 2013) Capítulo 4, Sección 1, páginas 194-200. Los datos sobre el uso tradicional de los biocombustibles sólidos son generalmente escasos a nivel mundial, y el desarrollo de la capacidad de seguimiento de dicho uso de la energía, incluido el desarrollo de encuestas a nivel nacional, es esencial para un sólido seguimiento de la energía mundial.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Este indicador se basa en la elaboración de estadísticas energéticas completas sobre la oferta y la demanda de todas las fuentes de energía &amp;#x2013; estadísticas utilizadas para elaborar un balance energético nacional. Las metodologías acordadas internacionalmente para las estadísticas energéticas se describen en las &amp;#x201C;Recomendaciones Internacionales para las Estadísticas Energéticas&amp;#x201D; (IRES, por sus siglas en inglés), adoptadas por la Comisión de Estadística de la ONU, disponibles en: &lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\leonardo.souza\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\INetCache\Content.Outlook\6GFD9MJP\unstats.un.org\unsd\energystats\methodology\ires&quot;&gt;unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/methodology/ires&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Una vez que se ha elaborado un balance energético nacional, el indicador puede calcularse dividiendo el consumo de energía final procedente de todas las fuentes renovables por el consumo total de energía final. El consumo de energía renovable se obtiene de tres tablas de las estadísticas y balances energéticos mundiales de la AIE: consumo final total, producción de electricidad y producción de calor. Todos los volúmenes indicados en la tabla de consumo final total se toman tal y como se indican. Dado que los volúmenes de electricidad y calor de la tabla de consumo final no se desglosan por tecnología, se utilizan las tablas de producción de electricidad y calor para desglosar el consumo final de electricidad y calor por tecnología. La asignación por tecnología se realiza derivando la cuota de tecnología en las tablas de producción de electricidad y calor y multiplicando dicha cuota por el consumo energético final de electricidad y calor, respectivamente. Por ejemplo, si la tabla de consumo final total informa de 150 TJ para la energía del biogás, mientras que el consumo final total de electricidad es de 400 TJ y el de calor de 100 TJ, y la cuota del biogás en la producción total de electricidad es del 10% y del 5% en la de calor, la cifra total informada para el consumo de biogás será de 195 TJ (150 TJ+400TJ*10%+100TJ*5%). El Informe del Marco de Seguimiento Global (AIE y Banco Mundial, 2013) proporciona más detalles sobre la metodología sugerida para definir y medir la energía renovable (Capítulo 4, Sección 1, página 201-202). La División de Estadística de las Naciones Unidas sigue la misma metodología para calcular los indicadores, aunque la información puede proceder de tablas diferentes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los agregados se calculan, ya sea por regiones o globalmente, utilizando como ponderación el consumo de energía final. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entre las diversas fuentes de datos existentes, principalmente los Balances Energéticos de la AIE y la Base de Datos de Estadísticas Energéticas de la ONU, se puede recopilar el consumo anual de energía total y renovable para cada país y zona. El informe &lt;em&gt; Seguimiento del ODS 7: Reporte sobre el progreso energético&lt;/em&gt; (anteriormente &lt;em&gt;Marco de seguimiento mundial de la energía sostenible para todos&lt;/em&gt;) informa sobre este indicador a nivel mundial entre 2010 y 2030.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2000 &amp;#x2013; actual &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La desagregación de los datos sobre el consumo de energía renovable, por ejemplo, por recurso y sector de uso final, podría proporcionar información sobre otras dimensiones del objetivo, como la asequibilidad y la fiabilidad. En el caso de la energía solar, también puede ser interesante desglosar la capacidad en la red y fuera de la red. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iea.org&quot;&gt;www.iea.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/&quot;&gt;unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Referencias: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Balances y estadísticas energéticas de la AIE &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\leonardo.souza\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\INetCache\Content.Outlook\6GFD9MJP\www.iea.org\statistics\&quot;&gt;http://www.iea.org/statistics/ &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Base de datos de estadísticas energéticas de la ONU &lt;a id=&quot;OLE_LINK1&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;OLE_LINK2&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/data/&quot;&gt;unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/data&lt;/a&gt; (descripción) y &lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\leonardo.souza\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\INetCache\Content.Outlook\6GFD9MJP\data.un.org\Explorer.aspx%3fd=EDATA&quot;&gt;data.un.org/Explorer.aspx?d=EDATA&lt;/a&gt; (datos)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Página web del ODS 7 de la AIE: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iea.org/sdg&quot;&gt;http://www.iea.org/sdg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recomendaciones internacionales para las estadísticas de energía (IRES) &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/methodology/ires&quot;&gt;unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/methodology/ires&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agencia Internacional de la Energía (AIE), Agencia Internacional de Energías Renovables (IRENA), División de Estadística de las Naciones Unidas (UNSD), Banco Mundial, Organización Mundial de la Salud (OMS). 2019. &amp;#x201C;Seguimiento del ODS7: Reporte sobre el progreso energético 2019&amp;#x201D;. &lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\leonardo.souza\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\INetCache\Content.Outlook\6GFD9MJP\trackingsdg7.esmap.org\&quot;&gt;trackingsdg7.esmap.org/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agencia Internacional de la Energía (AIE), Agencia Internacional de Energías Renovables (IRENA), División de Estadística de las Naciones Unidas (UNSD), Banco Mundial, Organización Mundial de la Salud (OMS). 2018. &amp;#x201C;Seguimiento del ODS7: Reporte sobre el progreso energético 2018&amp;#x201D;. &lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\leonardo.souza\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\INetCache\Content.Outlook\6GFD9MJP\trackingsdg7.esmap.org\&quot;&gt;trackingsdg7.esmap.org/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agencia Internacional de la Energía (AIE) y el Banco Mundial. 2017. &amp;#x201C;Marco de seguimiento mundial 2017&amp;#x2014;Progreso hacia la energía sostenible&amp;#x201D;. Banco Mundial, Washington, DC. Licencia: Creative Commons Attribution CC BY 3.0 IGO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agencia Internacional de la Energía (AIE) y Banco Mundial. 2015. &amp;#x201C;Marco de seguimiento mundial 2015&amp;#x2014;Progreso hacia la energía sostenible&amp;#x201D;, Banco Mundial, Washington, DC. Doi: 10.1596/978-1-4648 -0690-2 Licencia: Creative Commons Attribution CC BY 3.0 IGO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agencia Internacional de la Energía (AIE) y Banco Mundial. 2013. &amp;#x201C;Marco de seguimiento global 2013&amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Base de datos de energías renovables de IRENA &lt;a href=&quot;http://resourceirena.irena.org/gateway/dashboard&quot;&gt;http://resourceirena.irena.org/gateway/dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 7 : Garantir l’accès de tous à des services énergétiques fiables, durables et modernes, à un coût abordable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 7.2: D’ici à 2030, accroître nettement la part de l’énergie renouvelable dans le bouquet énergétique mondial&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 7.2.1: Part de l’énergie renouvelable dans la consommation finale d’énergie&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;15 février 2021&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Informations institutionnelles&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organization(s):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agence internationale de l&apos;énergie (AIE) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Division des statistiques des Nations unies (DSNU) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agence internationale pour les énergies renouvelables (IRENA) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Définition : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La part des énergies renouvelables dans la consommation finale totale est le pourcentage de la consommation finale d&apos;énergie qui provient de ressources renouvelables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La consommation d&apos;énergie renouvelable comprend la consommation d&apos;énergie dérivée de : l&apos;hydroélectricité, les biocarburants solides, le vent, le soleil, les biocarburants liquides, le biogaz, la géothermie, la mer et les déchets. La consommation totale d&apos;énergie finale est calculée à partir des bilans et des statistiques nationales comme la consommation finale totale moins l&apos;utilisation non énergétique. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Observations concernant les ressources énergétiques renouvelables spécifiques : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La consommation d&apos;énergie solaire comprend le solaire photovoltaïque et le
solaire thermique. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La consommation énergétique des biocarburants liquides comprend le biogazoline,
les biodiesels et autres biocarburants liquides. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La consommation de biocarburants solides comprend le bois de chauffage, les
déchets animaux, les déchets végétaux, la liqueur noire, la bagasse et le charbon de bois. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;L&apos;énergie des déchets couvre l&apos;énergie provenant des déchets municipaux renouvelables.
&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Sources de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sur la consommation d&apos;énergie renouvelable sont disponibles par le biais des bilans énergétiques nationaux établis sur la base des données collectées par l&apos;Agence internationale de l&apos;énergie (pour environ 150 pays) et la Division des statistiques des Nations unies (DSNU) pour tous les pays. Les bilans énergétiques permettent de retracer toutes les différentes sources et utilisations de l&apos;énergie au niveau national. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Une assistance technique peut être nécessaire pour améliorer ces statistiques, en particulier dans le cas des sources d&apos;énergie renouvelables. Des enquêtes spécialisées sur l&apos;industrie (par exemple sur l&apos;utilisation de la bioénergie) ou des enquêtes auprès des ménages (en combinaison avec la mesure d&apos;autres indicateurs) seraient des approches possibles pour combler les lacunes dans les données (par exemple pour l&apos;utilisation du bois de chauffage, de l&apos;énergie solaire hors réseau). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendrier&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Collecte de données :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont collectées sur une base annuelle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publication des données :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les bilans énergétiques de l&apos;AIE sont publiés en été (en publiant les informations relatives aux deux années civiles précédentes). La base de données des statistiques énergétiques des Nations unies est mise à disposition vers la fin de l&apos;année civile (en publiant les informations relatives aux deux années civiles précédentes).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fournisseurs de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les administrations nationales, telles que décrites dans la documentation sur les sources de l&apos;AIE et de la DSNU :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\leonardo.souza\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\INetCache\Content.Outlook\6GFD9MJP\wds.iea.org\wds\pdf\WORLDBAL_Documentation.pdf&quot;&gt;http://wds.iea.org/wds/pdf/WORLDBAL_Documentation.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/data&quot;&gt;unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compilateurs de données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nom : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;Agence internationale de l&apos;énergie (AIE) et la Division des statistiques des Nations unies (DSNU) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;AIE et la DSNU sont les principaux compilateurs de statistiques nationales sur l&apos;énergie et élaborent des bilans énergétiques comparables au niveau international sur la base de méthodologies convenues au niveau international. Les agrégats sont basés sur une analyse fusionnant les données de l&apos;AIE et de l&apos;UNSD. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Raison d&apos;être :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;objectif &amp;#x201C; d&apos;ici 2030, augmenter sensiblement la part des énergies renouvelables dans le bouquet énergétique mondial&amp;#x201D; a des répercussions sur les trois dimensions du développement durable. Les technologies des énergies renouvelables représentent un élément majeur des stratégies d&apos;écologisation des économies partout dans le monde et de lutte contre le grave problème mondial du changement climatique. Il existe un certain nombre de définitions des énergies renouvelables ; leur point commun est de mettre en évidence comme renouvelables toutes les formes d&apos;énergie dont la consommation n&apos;épuise pas leur disponibilité à l&apos;avenir. Il s&apos;agit notamment de l&apos;énergie solaire, éolienne, océanique, hydroélectrique, géothermique et bioénergétique (dans le cas de la bioénergie, qui peut être épuisée, les sources de bioénergie peuvent être remplacées à court ou moyen terme). Il est important de noter que cet indicateur se concentre sur la quantité d&apos;énergie renouvelable réellement consommée plutôt que sur la capacité de production d&apos;énergie renouvelable, qui ne peut pas toujours être pleinement utilisée. En se concentrant sur la consommation par l&apos;utilisateur final, il évite les distorsions causées par le fait que les sources d&apos;énergie conventionnelles sont sujettes à d&apos;importantes pertes d&apos;énergie tout au long de la chaîne de production. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires et limitations : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Une des limites des statistiques existantes sur les énergies renouvelables est qu&apos;elles ne permettent pas de distinguer si les énergies renouvelables sont produites de manière durable. Par exemple, une part importante de la consommation actuelle d&apos;énergie renouvelable&amp;#x2019; provient de l&apos;utilisation de bois et de charbon de bois par les ménages du monde en développement, qui peut parfois être associée à des pratiques forestières non durables. Des efforts sont en cours pour améliorer la capacité à mesurer la durabilité de la bioénergie, bien que cela reste un défi important. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les données sur les énergies renouvelables hors réseau sont limitées et ne sont pas suffisamment prises en compte dans les statistiques énergétiques. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;La méthode de répartition de la consommation d&apos;énergie renouvelable provenant de la production d&apos;électricité et de chaleur suppose que la part des pertes de transmission et de distribution est la même pour toutes les technologies. Cependant, cela n&apos;est pas toujours vrai car les énergies renouvelables sont généralement situées dans des zones plus éloignées des centres de consommation et peuvent subir des pertes plus importantes. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;De même, les importations et les exportations d&apos;électricité et de chaleur sont supposées suivre la part de la production d&apos;électricité et de chaleur renouvelable, respectivement. Il s&apos;agit d&apos;une simplification qui, dans de nombreux cas, n&apos;affectera pas trop l&apos;indicateur, mais qui pourrait le faire dans certains cas, par exemple lorsqu&apos;un pays ne produit de l&apos;électricité qu&apos;à partir de combustibles fossiles mais importe une grande partie de l&apos;électricité qu&apos;il utilise de la centrale hydroélectrique d&apos;un pays voisin &amp;#x2019;. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Les défis méthodologiques associés à la définition et à la mesure des énergies renouvelables sont décrits plus en détail dans le Cadre mondial de suivi (AIE et Banque mondiale, 2013), chapitre 4, section 1, pages 194-200. Les données relatives à l&apos;utilisation traditionnelle des biocarburants solides sont généralement rares au niveau mondial, et il est essentiel de développer les capacités de suivi de cette utilisation de l&apos;énergie, notamment en élaborant des enquêtes au niveau national, pour assurer un bon suivi énergétique mondial. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Méthodologie&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Méthode de calcul :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur est basé sur le développement de statistiques énergétiques complètes sur l&apos;offre et la demande pour toutes les sources d&apos;énergie&amp;#x2013;, statistiques utilisées pour produire un bilan énergétique national. Les méthodologies internationalement reconnues pour les statistiques énergétiques sont décrites dans les &amp;#x201C; Recommandations internationales pour les statistiques de l&apos;énergie&amp;#x201D; (IRES), adoptées par la Commission statistique des Nations unies, disponibles à l&apos;adresse suivante &lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\leonardo.souza\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\INetCache\Content.Outlook\6GFD9MJP\unstats.un.org\unsd\energystats\methodology\ires&quot;&gt;unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/methodology/ires &lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Une fois qu&apos;un bilan énergétique national est établi, l&apos;indicateur peut être calculé en divisant la consommation finale d&apos;énergie provenant de toutes les sources renouvelables par la consommation finale totale d&apos;énergie. La consommation d&apos;énergie renouvelable est dérivée de trois tableaux des statistiques et bilans énergétiques mondiaux de l&apos;AIE : consommation finale totale, production d&apos;électricité et production de chaleur. Tous les volumes indiqués dans le tableau de la consommation finale totale sont pris tels quels. Étant donné que les volumes d&apos;électricité et de chaleur du tableau de la consommation finale ne sont pas ventilés par technologie, les tableaux de la production d&apos;électricité et de chaleur sont utilisés à la place pour ventiler la consommation finale d&apos;électricité et de chaleur par technologie. La répartition par technologie est effectuée en calculant la part de la technologie dans les tableaux de production d&apos;électricité et de chaleur et en multipliant cette part par la consommation finale d&apos;énergie d&apos;électricité et de chaleur, respectivement. Par exemple, si le tableau de la consommation finale totale indique 150 TJ pour l&apos;énergie du biogaz, alors que la consommation finale totale d&apos;électricité est de 400 TJ et de chaleur de 100 TJ, et que la part du biogaz dans la production totale d&apos;électricité est de 10 % et de 5 % pour la chaleur, le nombre total indiqué pour la consommation de biogaz sera de 195 TJ (150 TJ+400TJ*10 %+100TJ*5 %). Le rapport sur le cadre mondial de suivi (AIE et Banque mondiale, 2013) fournit plus de détails sur la méthodologie suggérée pour définir et mesurer les énergies renouvelables (chapitre 4, section 1, page 201-202). La DSNU suit la même méthodologie pour calculer les indicateurs, bien que les informations puissent provenir de différents tableaux. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Agrégats régionaux:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les agrégats sont calculés, que ce soit par région ou à l’échelle mondiale, en utilisant la consommation finale d’énergie comme poids. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilité des données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entre les différentes sources de données existantes, principalement les bilans énergétiques de l&apos;AIE et la base de données des statistiques énergétiques des Nations unies, la consommation annuelle totale et la consommation d&apos;énergie renouvelable pour chaque pays et chaque région peuvent être collectées. Le &lt;em&gt;Tracking SDG7 : The Energy Progress Report&lt;/em&gt; (anciennement &lt;em&gt;Cadre mondial de suivi de l&apos;énergie durable pour tous&lt;/em&gt;) présente cet indicateur au niveau mondial entre 2010 et 2030. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Série chronologique : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2000 &amp;#x2013; présent &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Désagrégation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La ventilation des données sur la consommation d&apos;énergie renouvelable, par exemple par ressource et par secteur d&apos;utilisation finale, pourrait donner un aperçu d&apos;autres dimensions de l&apos;objectif, telles que le caractère abordable et la fiabilité. Pour l&apos;énergie solaire, il peut également être intéressant de ventiler les données entre les capacités en réseau et hors réseau. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Références&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iea.org&quot;&gt;www.iea.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/&quot;&gt;unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Références : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bilans et statistiques énergétiques de l&apos;AIE. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\leonardo.souza\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\INetCache\Content.Outlook\6GFD9MJP\www.iea.org\statistics\&quot;&gt;http://www.iea.org/statistics/ &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Base de données des statistiques énergétiques des Nations Unies &lt;a id=&quot;OLE_LINK1&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;OLE_LINK2&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/data/&quot;&gt;unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/data &lt;/a&gt; (description) et &lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\leonardo.souza\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\INetCache\Content.Outlook\6GFD9MJP\data.un.org\Explorer.aspx%3fd=EDATA&quot;&gt;data.un.org/Explorer.aspx?d=EDATA &lt;/a&gt; (données) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IEA ODD 7 page web : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iea.org/sdg&quot;&gt;http://www.iea.org/sdg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommandations internationales pour les statistiques de l&apos;énergie (IRES) &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/methodology/ires&quot;&gt;unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/methodology/ires &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agence internationale de l&apos;énergie (AIE), Agence internationale pour les énergies renouvelables (IRENA), Division des statistiques des Nations Unies (DSNU), Banque Mondiale, Organisation mondiale de la santé (OMS). 2019. &amp;#x201C;Suivi du ODD7 : Rapport sur l&apos;état d&apos;avancement de l&apos;énergie 2019 &amp;#x201D;. &lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\leonardo.souza\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\INetCache\Content.Outlook\6GFD9MJP\trackingsdg7.esmap.org\&quot;&gt;trackingsdg7.esmap.org/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agence internationale de l&apos;énergie (AIE), Agence internationale pour les énergies renouvelables (IRENA), Division des statistiques des Nations unies (DSNU), Banque Mondiale, Organisation mondiale de la santé (OMS). 2018. &amp;#x201C;Suivi du ODD7 : Rapport sur l&apos;état d&apos;avancement de l&apos;énergie 2018 &amp;#x201D;. &lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\leonardo.souza\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\INetCache\Content.Outlook\6GFD9MJP\trackingsdg7.esmap.org\&quot;&gt;trackingsdg7.esmap.org/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agence internationale de l&apos;énergie (AIE) et Banque mondiale. 2017. &amp;#x201C;Cadre mondial de suivi 2017 &amp;#x2014;Progrès vers l&apos;énergie durable &amp;#x201D;. Banque mondiale, Washington, DC. Licence : Paternité Creative Commons CC BY 3.0 IGO &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agence internationale de l&apos;énergie (AIE) et Banque mondiale. 2015. &amp;#x201C;Cadre mondial de suivi 2015 &amp;#x2014;Progrès vers l&apos;énergie durable &amp;#x201D;, Banque mondiale, Washington, DC. Doi : 10.1596/978-1-4648 -0690-2 Licence : Paternité Creative Commons CC BY 3.0 IGO &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agence internationale de l&apos;énergie (AIE) et Banque Mondiale. 2013. &amp;#x201C;Cadre mondial de suivi 2013 &amp;#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IRENA Renewable Energy Database &lt;a href=&quot;http://resourceirena.irena.org/gateway/dashboard&quot;&gt;http://resourceirena.irena.org/gateway/dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 7: Обеспечение доступа к недорогим, надежным, устойчивым и современным источникам энергии для всех&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 7.2: К 2030 году значительно увеличить долю энергии из возобновляемых источников в мировом энергетическом балансе&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 7.2.1: Доля возобновляемых источников энергии в общем объеме конечного энергопотребления&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Последнее обновление: 7 февраля 2020 года &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Институциональная информация &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Организация (и): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Международное энергетическое агентство (МЭА) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Статистический отдел Организации Объединенных Наций (СОООН) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Международное агентство по возобновляемым источникам энергии (IRENA) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Доля возобновляемых источников энергии в общем объеме конечного энергопотребления - это процент конечного потребления энергии, полученной из возобновляемых ресурсов. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Потребление возобновляемой энергии включает потребление энергии, полученной из: энергии падающей воды, твердого биотоплива, энергии ветра, солнца, жидкого биотоплива, биогаза, геотермальной, морской энергии и отходов. Общее конечное потребление энергии рассчитывается на основе национальных балансов и статистических данных как общее конечное потребление за вычетом неэнергетического использования. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Комментарии относительно конкретных возобновляемых источников энергии: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Потребление солнечной энергии включает фотоэлектрическую солнечную энергию и гелиотермальную энергию. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Потребление энергии жидкого биотоплива включает биогазолин, биодизельное топливо и другие виды жидкого биотоплива. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Потребление твердого биотоплива включает топливную древесину, отходы животноводства, растительные отходы, черный щелок, жмых и древесный уголь. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Энергия отходов включают энергию из возобновляемых бытовых отходов. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные по потреблению возобновляемой энергии доступны путем использования национальных энергетических балансов, составленных на основе данных, собранных Международным энергетическим агентством (примерно по 150 странам) и Статистическим отделом Организации Объединенных Наций (СОООН) по всем стран. Энергетические балансы позволяют отслеживать все различные источники и способы использования энергии на национальном уровне. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Для улучшения этих статистических данных может потребоваться некоторая техническая помощь, особенно в случае возобновляемых источников энергии. Специализированные отраслевые обследования (например, по использованию биоэнергетики) или обследования домашних хозяйств (в сочетании с определением параметров других показателей) стали бы целесообразными подходами к заполнению пробелов в данных (например, по использованию дров, солнечной энергии, не входящей в энергосистему). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Календарь &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Сбор данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные собираются ежегодно. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Выпуск данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Энергетические балансы МЭА публикуются летом (публикация информации с задержкой в два календарных года). База данных энергетической статистики ООН становится доступной ближе к концу календарного года (публикация информации с задержкой в два календарных года). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Поставщики данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Национальные администрации, как описано в документации по источникам для МЭА и СОООН: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\leonardo.souza\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\INetCache\Content.Outlook\6GFD9MJP\wds.iea.org\wds\pdf\WORLDBAL_Documentation.pdf&quot;&gt; http://wds.iea.org/wds/pdf/WORLDBAL_Documentation.pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/data&quot;&gt; unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/data &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Составители данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Название: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Международное энергетическое агентство (МЭА) и Статистический отдел Организации Объединенных Наций (СОООН) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; МЭА и СОООН являются основными составителями национальной энергетической статистики и разрабатывают сопоставимые на международном уровне энергетические балансы на основе международно согласованных методологий. Агрегаты основаны на анализе, объединяющем данные МЭА и СОООН. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Задача &quot;К 2030 году значительно увеличить долю энергии из возобновляемых источников в мировом энергетическом балансе&quot; влияет на все три аспекта устойчивого развития. Технологии возобновляемых источников энергии представляют собой важный элемент в стратегиях экологизации экономики во всем мире и решения важнейшей глобальной проблемы, связанной с изменением климата. Существует ряд определений возобновляемой энергии; их объединяет то, что они считают возобновляемыми все виды энергии, потребление которых не влияет негативно на их наличие в будущем. К ним относятся солнечная энергия, энергия ветра, океанских приливов, гидроэнергетика, геотермальные ресурсы и биоэнергетика (что касается биоэнергии, которая может быть исчерпана, источники биоэнергии могут быть восстановлены в краткосрочной или среднесрочной перспективе). Важно отметить, что этот показатель фокусируется на количестве фактически потребляемой возобновляемой энергии, а не на мощностях для производства возобновляемой энергии, которые не всегда можно использовать в полной мере. Сосредоточившись на потреблении энергии конечным пользователем, показатель позволяет избежать искажений, вызванных тем фактом, что в традиционных источниках энергии происходят значительные потери энергии в производственной цепочке.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt; Ограничение существующей статистики возобновляемых источников энергии состоит в том, что эти данные не могут распознать, является ли производство возобновляемой энергии устойчивым процессом. Например, значительная доля сегодняшнего потребления возобновляемой энергии приходится на использование древесины и древесного угля домашними хозяйствами в развивающихся странах, что иногда может быть связано с нерациональными методами ведения лесного хозяйства. В настоящее время предпринимаются попытки улучшить способность оценки устойчивости биоэнергетики, хотя это остается серьезной проблемой. &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt; Объем данных по автономным возобновляемым источникам энергии ограничен и они недостаточно отражены в энергетической статистике. &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt; Метод отделения потребления возобновляемой энергии от выработки электроэнергии и тепла предполагает, что доля потерь при передаче и распределении одинакова для всех технологий. Однако это не всегда верно, поскольку возобновляемые источники энергии обычно расположены в более удаленных от мест потребления районах и это может приводить к гораздо большим потерям. &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt; Аналогичным образом предполагается, что импорт и экспорт электроэнергии и тепла будут соответствовать доле возобновляемости ресурсов производства электроэнергии и тепла, соответственно. Это упрощение, которое во многих случаях не слишком сильно будет влиять на показатель, но может сказаться в некоторых случаях, например, когда страна вырабатывает электроэнергию только из ископаемого топлива, но импортирует значительную часть потребляемой электроэнергии, производимой гидроэлектростанцией соседней страны. &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt; Методологические проблемы, связанные с определением и оценкой возобновляемых источников энергии, более полно описаны в Структуре глобального отслеживания (МЭА и Всемирный банк, 2013 год), глава 4, раздел 1, страницы 194–200. Данных по традиционному использованию твердого биотоплива в глобальном масштабе, как правило, мало, и развитие потенциала для отслеживания такого использования энергии, включая разработку обследований на национальном уровне, имеет важное значение для надежного глобального отслеживания использования энергии.&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Этот показатель основан на разработке комплексной энергетической статистики по спросу и предложению для всех источников энергии - статистических данных, используемых для составления энергетического баланса. Согласованные на международном уровне методологии для статистики энергетики описаны в «Международных рекомендациях по энергетической статистике&quot; (МРЭС), принятых Статистической комиссией ООН, доступных по адресу: &lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\leonardo.souza\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\INetCache\Content.Outlook\6GFD9MJP\unstats.un.org\unsd\energystats\methodology\ires&quot;&gt; unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/methodology/ires &lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; После разработки национального энергетического баланса этот показатель можно рассчитать путем деления конечного потребления энергии из всех возобновляемых источников на общее конечное потребление энергии. Потребление возобновляемой энергии получается из трех таблиц мировой энергетической статистики и балансов МЭА: общее конечное потребление, выработка электроэнергии и выработка тепла. Все объемы, указанные в таблице общего конечного потребления, считаются отчетными. Поскольку объемы электроэнергии и тепла в таблице конечного потребления не разбиты по технологиям, вместо этого используются таблицы объемов производства электроэнергии и тепла для разбивки конечного потребления электроэнергии и тепла по технологиям. Распределение по технологиям осуществляется путем получения доли технологий в таблицах выработки электроэнергии и тепла и умножения этой доли на конечное энергопотребление электроэнергии и тепла, соответственно. Например, если в таблице общего конечного потребления указано 150 ТДж для энергии биогаза, в то время как общее конечное потребление электроэнергии составляет 400 ТДж, а тепла - 100 ТДж, а доля биогаза в общем объеме выработки электроэнергии составляет 10 процентов и 5 процентов по теплу, то итоговое отчетное значение количества потребляемого биогаза составит 195 ТДж (150 ТДж + 400 ТДж * 10% + 100 ТДж * 5%). Отчет по структуре глобального отслеживания (МЭА и Всемирный банк, 2013 год) содержит более подробную информацию о предлагаемой методологии определения и оценки возобновляемой энергии (глава 4, раздел 1, стр. 201-202). СОООН использует ту же методологию для расчета показателей, хотя информация может поступать из разных таблиц. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Региональные агрегаты: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Агрегированные показатели рассчитываются как по регионам, так и по всему миру, с использованием конечного потребления энергии в качестве весов. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Среди различных существующих источников данных, в первую очередь Энергетического баланса МЭА и Статистической базы данных ООН по энергетике, можно собирать данные по общему годовому потреблению энергии из возобновляемых источников для каждой страны и региона. &lt;em&gt; Отслеживание ЦУР 7: Отчет о прогрессе в энергетике &lt;/em&gt; (ранее &lt;em&gt; Глобальная структура отслеживания устойчивой энергетики для всех&lt;/em&gt;) представляет этот показатель на глобальном уровне в период с 2010 по 2030 год. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 2000 - настоящее время &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Дезагрегирование данных по потреблению возобновляемой энергии, например, по ресурсам и сектору конечного использования, может дать представление о других аспектах цели, таких как ценовая доступность и надежность. Что касается солнечной энергии, то в ней также может заинтересовать разделение мощности на сетевую и не входящую в энергосистему. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iea.org&quot;&gt; www.iea.org &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/&quot;&gt; unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Ссылки: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Энергетические балансы и статистика МЭА &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\leonardo.souza\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\INetCache\Content.Outlook\6GFD9MJP\www.iea.org\statistics\&quot;&gt; http://www.iea.org/statistics/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; База данных статистики энергетики ООН &lt;a id=&quot;OLE_LINK1&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a id=&quot;OLE_LINK2&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/data/&quot;&gt; unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/data &lt;/a&gt; (описание) и &lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\leonardo.souza\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\INetCache\Content.Outlook\6GFD9MJP\data.un.org\Explorer.aspx%3fd=EDATA&quot;&gt; data.un.org/Explorer.aspx?d=EDATA &lt;/a&gt; (данные) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Веб-страница МЭА по ЦУР 7: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iea.org/sdg&quot;&gt; http://www.iea.org/sdg &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Международные рекомендации по энергетической статистике (МРЭС) &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/methodology/ires&quot;&gt; unstats.un.org/unsd/energystats/methodology/ires &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Международное энергетическое агентство (МЭА), Международное агентство по возобновляемым источникам энергии (IRENA), Статистический отдел ООН (СОООН), Всемирный банк, Всемирная организация здравоохранения (ВОЗ). 2019 год. &amp;#x201C;Отслеживание ЦУР 7: Отчет о прогрессе в области энергетики за 2019 год&amp;#x201D;. &lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\leonardo.souza\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\INetCache\Content.Outlook\6GFD9MJP\trackingsdg7.esmap.org\&quot;&gt; trackingsdg7.esmap.org/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Международное энергетическое агентство (МЭА), Международное агентство по возобновляемым источникам энергии (IRENA), Статистический отдел ООН (СОООН), Всемирный банк, Всемирная организация здравоохранения (ВОЗ). 2018. &amp;#x201C;Отслеживание ЦУР 7: Отчет о прогрессе в области энергетики за 2018 год&amp;#x201D;. &lt;a href=&quot;file:///C:\Users\leonardo.souza\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\INetCache\Content.Outlook\6GFD9MJP\trackingsdg7.esmap.org\&quot;&gt; trackingsdg7.esmap.org/ &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Международное энергетическое агентство (МЭА) и Всемирный банк. 2017 год. &amp;#x201C;Глобальная структура отслеживания 2017 год &amp;#x2014; Прогресс на пути к устойчивой энергетике&amp;#x201D;. Всемирный банк, Вашингтон, округ Колумбия. Лицензия: Creative Commons Attribution CC BY 3.0 IGO &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Международное энергетическое агентство (МЭА) и Всемирный банк. 2015 год. &amp;#x201C;Глобальная структура отслеживания 2015 год. &amp;#x2014; Прогресс на пути к устойчивой энергетике&amp;#x201D;. Всемирный банк, Вашингтон, округ Колумбия. Doi: 10.1596 / 978-1-4648 -0690-2 Лицензия: Creative Commons Attribution CC BY 3.0 IGO &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Международное энергетическое агентство (МЭА) и Всемирный банк. 2013. &amp;#x201C;Глобальная структура отслеживания 2013 год&amp;#x201D;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; База данных IRENA по возобновляемым источникам энергии &lt;a href=&quot;http://resourceirena.irena.org/gateway/dashboard&quot;&gt; http://resourceirena.irena.org/gateway/dashboard &lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
