<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 8-10-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 8: Promote sustained, inclusive and sustainable economic growth, full and productive employment and decent work for all&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 8.10: Strengthen the capacity of domestic financial institutions to encourage and expand access to banking, insurance and financial services for all&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 8.10.2: Proportion of adults (15 years and older) with an account at a bank or other financial institution or with a mobile-money-service provider &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Applies to all series. &lt;/p&gt;2023-03-31&lt;p&gt;Not applicable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;World Bank &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;World Bank&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The percentage of adults (ages 15+) who report having an account (by themselves or together with someone else) at a bank or another type of financial institution or personally using a mobile money service in the past 12 months. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial institution accounts (excluding mobile money) denote the percentage of respondents who report having an account (by themselves or together with someone else) at a bank, credit union, microfinance institution, or post office that falls under prudential regulation by a government body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data on adults with a financial institution account include respondents who reported having an account at a bank or at another type of financial institution, such as a credit union, a microfinance institution, a cooperative, or the post office (if applicable). The data also include an additional 3 percent of respondents in 2021 who reported receiving wages, government transfers, a public sector pension, or payments for agricultural products into a financial institution account in the past year; paying utility bills or school fees from a financial institution account in the past year; or receiving wages, government transfers, or agricultural payments into a card in the past year. The definition does not include non-bank financial institutions such as pension funds, retirement accounts, insurance companies, or equity holdings such as stocks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mobile money accounts denote the percentage of respondents who report personally using a mobile money service to make payments, buy things, or to send or receive money in the past year. Data on adults with a mobile money account include respondents who reported personally using services included in the GSM Association&amp;#x2019;s Mobile Money for the Unbanked (GSMA MMU) database to pay bills or to send or receive money in the past year. The data also include an additional 2 percent of respondents in 2021 who reported receiving wages, government transfers, a public sector pension, or payments for agricultural products through a mobile phone in the past year. Unlike the definition of account at a financial institution, the definition of mobile money account does not include the payment of utility bills or school fees through a mobile phone. The reason is that the phrasing of the possible answers leaves it open as to whether those payments were made using a mobile money account or an over-the-counter service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Percent (%)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data is also aggregated using the World Bank classifications for World, low- and middle-income economies, income groups (low-income, lower-middle-income, and upper-middle-income economies), and developing regions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The indicators in the &lt;s&gt;2021 &lt;/s&gt;Global&lt;u&gt; Findex Database 2021&lt;/u&gt;&lt;s&gt; Financial Inclusion (Global Findex) database&lt;/s&gt; are drawn from survey data covering almost 128,000 people in 123 economies&amp;#x2014;representing 91 percent of the world&amp;#x2019;s population. The survey was carried out over the 2021 calendar year&lt;u&gt;, and now marks the fourth round of Global Findex data since 2011. Typically, the survey captures data from more than 140 economies, but surveying was postponed in a handful of countries in 2021 due to COVID-19. These countries were surveyed in 2022, and data on these additional 17 countries will be available in 2023. &lt;/u&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;The surveying is undertaken&lt;/u&gt; by Gallup, Inc. as part of its Gallup World Poll&lt;u&gt;, &lt;/u&gt;&lt;s&gt;,&lt;/s&gt; which since 2005 has continually conducted surveys of approximately 1,000 people in each of more than 160 economies and in over 150 languages, using randomly selected, nationally representative samples. The target population is the entire civilian, noninstitutionalized population age 15 and above. &lt;s&gt;Data on additional 17 countries will be available in 2023. &lt;/s&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full report, including methodology and interview procedures, data preparation, margin of error and notes by country are all available under Methodology Table A.1 here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldbank.org/en/publication/globalfindex/Report&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://www.worldbank.org/en/publication/globalfindex/Report&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;u&gt; &lt;/u&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In most developing economies, Global Findex data have traditionally been collected through face-to-face&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;interviews. Surveys are conducted face-to-face in economies where telephone coverage represents less than 80 percent of the population or where in-person surveying is the customary methodology. However, during 2021, due to ongoing COVID-19&amp;#x2013;related mobility restrictions, face-to-face interviewing was not possible in some of these economies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Phone-based surveys were therefore conducted in 67 economies that had been surveyed face-to-face in 2017. These 67 economies were selected for inclusion based on population size, phone penetration rate, COVID-19 infection rates, and the feasibility of executing phone-based methods where Gallup would otherwise conduct face-to-face data collection, while complying with all government-issued guidance throughout the interviewing process. Gallup takes both mobile phone and landline ownership into consideration. According to Gallup World Poll 2019 data, when face-to-face surveys were last carried out in these economies, at least 80 percent of adults in almost all of them reported mobile phone ownership. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All samples are probability-based and nationally representative of the resident adult population. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Four rounds of data collection are completed, for years: 2011, 2014, 2017, and 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surveying for 2020 was delayed to 2021 due to COVID-19 restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data are collected every three years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collected by Gallup, Inc. through the Gallup World Poll and compiled by the World Bank&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;World Bank &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Development Research Group (DECRG) is the World Bank&amp;apos;s principal research department under the Development Economics Vice Presidency. Under the guidance of the World Bank&amp;#x2019;s Chief Economist, DECRG provides high quality economic information, data, analysis, research, and training to the Bank Group and its partners. DECRG&amp;apos;s research programs generate and disseminate knowledge about development policies essential for the achievement of the World Bank&amp;apos;s ultimate mandate of poverty reduction and shared prosperity. Within DECRG, the &amp;#x201C;Findex team&amp;#x201D; manages the extensive Global Findex Database that provides in-depth data on how people, especially women and the poor, save, borrow, make payments and manage risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Global Findex Database is collected in partnership with Gallup, Inc., as a part of its Gallup World Poll. For more information on their mandate and methodology , please see here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gallup.com/178667/gallup-world-poll-work.aspx&quot;&gt;https://www.gallup.com/178667/gallup-world-poll-work.aspx&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Financial inclusion means that households have access to and can effectively use appropriate financial services that are provided responsibly and sustainably in a well-regulated environment. Studies show that when people participate in the financial system, they are better able to start and expand businesses, invest in education, manage risk and absorb financial shocks. Measurement is key to understanding financial inclusion and identifying opportunities to remove barriers that may be preventing people from using financial services. The Global Findex Database 2021 is the first global, comparable database of demand-side financial inclusion indicators, capturing insights into how adults around the world save, borrow, make payments and manage risk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Global Findex Database&amp;#x2014;only measures the &amp;#x2018;perception&amp;#x2019; people have about their account ownership and usage by providing individual-level survey data on the demographic characteristics of users of financial services. This demand-side data collects information on the percent of adults who think of themselves as &amp;#x2018;banked&amp;#x2019; and having access to an account. The database complements but does replace existing supply-side data and other household surveys.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The indicator is based on data collected through individual level surveys in each country with representative samples. Data weighting is used to ensure a nationally representative sample for each economy. Final weights consist of the base sampling weight, which corrects for unequal probability of selection based on household size, and the poststratification weight, which corrects for sampling and nonresponse error. Poststratification weights use economy-level population statistics on gender and age and, where reliable data are available, education or socioeconomic status. Regional population weights are used to calculate regional aggregates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full report, including methodology and interview procedures, data preparation, margin of error and notes by country are all available under Methodology Table A.1 here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldbank.org/en/publication/globalfindex/Report&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.worldbank.org/en/publication/globalfindex/Report&quot;&gt;https://www.worldbank.org/en/publication/globalfindex/Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a thorough review process of the Global Findex surveys to ensure its quality and integrity. Gallup, Inc, the survey vendor for the Global Findex database, follows the highest standards for sampling and collecting the data and thoroughly vets the data before sharing it with the Global Findex team. Once the data is received by the Findex team, the team vets the data by comparing headline indicators from the database against data from previous rounds of the database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gallup.com/178667/gallup-world-poll-work.aspxNot&quot;&gt;Not&lt;/a&gt; applicable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At country level &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Data for &amp;#x201C;don&amp;#x2019;t know&amp;#x201D; and &amp;#x201C;refused to answer&amp;#x201D; form 0-1% of the total responses and are counted as &amp;#x201C;no&amp;#x201D; instead of missing. Any estimates based on fewer than 10% of survey sample observations are considered economically insignificant and therefore suppressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At regional and global levels &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Not applicable &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regional estimates are calculated by aggregating individual level surveys for each country in the developing regions. Appropriate regional population-based weights are applied. Information on developing regional classification(s) is taken from the World Bank and the population data is taken from the World Development Indicators (WDI). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Findex team oversees the quality management of the Global Findex Database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For quality assurance, the Findex team has additional processes in place after it receives the data from Gallup Inc. The Findex team compares the data against (the limited number of) demand-side survey data from external sources for countries whenever available such as from the Financial Inclusion Insights Survey, FinScope, or from Central Banks. The team also consults with key practitioners both within the World Bank and at other key organizations to confirm the credibility of headline numbers on account ownership. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All the source code for the headline indicator is reviewed by an independent and external statistics department within the World Bank. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 162 countries with regional and World aggregates that have at least 1 data point after 2011 for this indicator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Triennial (2011,2014, 2017 and 2021)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disaggregation are available by: Income (Adults in the poorest 40 percent of households vs. Adults in the richest 60 percent of households); Participation in labour force (In labor force vs. Out of labor force); Age (Ages 15-25 vs. Age 25+); Education level (Primary and below vs. Primary and above); Urbanicity of residence (Rural vs. Urban ); Gender (Female vs. Male)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global Findex Database is an individual level survey, measuring an individual&amp;#x2019;s perception of ownership of accounts. It assumes financial inclusion is an individual-level concept which may create two potential discrepancies. First, the data may deviate from supply side data which counts the number of accounts and may overstate the level of financial inclusion in a country if a significant number of adults have an account they do not use and did not formally close. Second, not all demand-side data is the same and that the data from different demand-side surveys cannot necessarily be compared if the survey method is different. In particular, surveys of individuals cannot be compared directly with surveys of household heads, since the use of financial services can differ considerably between different household members.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.worldbank.org/en/publication/globalfindex &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demirg&amp;#xFC;&amp;#xE7;-Kunt, Asli, Leora Klapper, Dorothe Singer, and Saniya Ansar. 2022. The Global Findex Database 2021: Financial Inclusion, Digital Payments, and Resilience in the Age of COVID-19. Washington, DC: World Bank. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 8: Promover el crecimiento económico sostenido, inclusivo y sostenible, el empleo pleno y productivo y el trabajo decente para todos&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 8.10: Fortalecer la capacidad de las instituciones financieras nacionales para fomentar y ampliar el acceso a los servicios bancarios, financieros y de seguros para todos&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 8.10.2: Proporción de adultos (a partir de 15 años de edad) que tienen una cuenta en un banco u otra institución financiera o un proveedor de servicios de dinero móvil&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Última actualización: 19 de julio de 2016&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicadores relacionados&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.4, 5.a, 2.3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Información institucional &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Organización (es): &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Banco Mundial (BM) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definición:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Porcentaje de adultos (mayores de 15 años) que declaran tener una cuenta (por sí mismos o junto con otra persona) en un banco u otro tipo de institución financiera o utilizar personalmente un servicio de dinero móvil en los últimos 12 meses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cuenta en una institución financiera incluye a los encuestados que declaran tener una cuenta en un banco o en otro tipo de institución financiera, como una cooperativa de crédito, una institución de microfinanzas, una cooperativa o la oficina de correos (si aplica), o tener una tarjeta de débito a su nombre. Además, incluye a los encuestados que declaran haber recibido salarios, transferencias del gobierno o pagos por productos agrícolas en una cuenta de una institución financiera en los últimos 12 meses; haber pagado facturas de servicios públicos o cuotas escolares desde una cuenta de una institución financiera en los últimos 12 meses; o haber recibido salarios o transferencias del gobierno en una tarjeta en los últimos 12 meses. La cuenta de dinero móvil incluye a los encuestados que declaran haber utilizado personalmente los servicios de dinero móvil de la Asociación GSM para servicios no bancarizados (MMU) en los últimos 12 meses para pagar facturas o enviar o recibir dinero. Además, incluye a los encuestados que declaran haber recibido salarios, transferencias gubernamentales o pagos por productos agrícolas a través de un teléfono móvil en los últimos 12 meses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Descripción:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los indicadores de la base de datos de Inclusión Financiera Global 2014 (Global Findex) se han extraído de los datos de una encuesta que abarca a casi 150.000 personas en más de 140 economías&amp;#x2014;que representan más del 97% de la población mundial&amp;#x2019;. La encuesta fue realizada durante el año 2014 por Gallup, Inc. como parte de su Gallup World Poll, que desde 2005 ha realizado continuamente encuestas a aproximadamente 1000 personas en cada una de las más de 160 economías y en más de 140 idiomas, utilizando muestras representativas a nivel nacional seleccionadas al azar. La población objetivo es toda la población civil no institucionalizada de 15 años o más. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La metodología, incluidos los procedimientos de entrevista, la preparación de los datos, el margen de error y las notas por país están disponibles en &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldbank.org/content/dam/Worldbank/Research/GlobalFindex/PDF/Methodology.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.worldbank.org/content/dam/Worldbank/Research/GlobalFindex/PDF/Methodology.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Proceso de recolección:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Los datos son comparables entre países por diseño. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendario&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recolección de datos:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Próxima ronda de recolección: 2017. Los datos se recogen cada tres años.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Publicación de datos: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 2017 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;n/a&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banco Mundial&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Justificación:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El acceso a servicios financieros formales como el ahorro, los seguros, los pagos, el crédito y las remesas es esencial para que las personas&amp;#x2014;independientemente de su nivel de ingresos, género, edad, educación o lugar de residencia&amp;#x2014;puedan gestionar sus vidas, construir su futuro y hacer crecer sus negocios. Tener acceso a una cuenta es un punto de partida importante para que las personas puedan acceder a una serie de servicios financieros.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La base de datos Global Findex del Banco Mundial&amp;#x2019;se basa en encuestas a nivel individual en todo el mundo, realizadas cada tres años. La primera ronda de la encuesta se realizó en 2011, y la segunda en 2014. La tercera ronda se realizará en 2017. La base de datos abarca unos 140 países.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador se basa en datos recogidos mediante encuestas a nivel individual en cada país con muestras representativas. Para calcular los agregados a nivel de país se utilizan ponderaciones de muestreo adecuadas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A nivel de país:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;n/a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A nivel regional y mundial:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;n/a&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A nivel de país; el porcentaje de adultos que poseen cuentas se multiplica por el número de adultos del país. A continuación, para los valores regionales, se toma la suma de todos los países de la región y se divide por el total de adultos que viven en ella. Del mismo modo, para las cifras globales, se repite el mismo cálculo para todos los países.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Descripción:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Países que tienen al menos 1 punto de datos después de 2010 para este indicador:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Asia y Pacífico: 35&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;África: 38 &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;América Latina y el Caribe: 21&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Europa, América del Norte, Australia, Nueva Zelanda y Japón: 47&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2011 y 2014. Se recogerá cada 3 años.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desagregación por ingresos; edad; nivel de educación; urbano/rural; género&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fuentes de discrepancias:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global Findex es una encuesta a nivel individual que mide la titularidad de cuentas por parte de los individuos&amp;#x2019;. Dado que la inclusión financiera es un concepto a nivel individual, ésta es la medida adecuada. Otras encuestas que se realizan a nivel de hogar pueden medir el acceso a la financiación a través de otro miembro del hogar, lo que puede sobreestimar la inclusión financiera.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;&lt;u&gt; &lt;/u&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;www.worldbank.org&quot;&gt;www.worldbank.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Referencias:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldbank.org/globalfindex&quot;&gt;http://www.worldbank.org/globalfindex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 8 : Promouvoir une croissance économique soutenue, inclusive et durable, le plein emploi productif et un travail décent pour tous&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 8.10 : Renforcer la capacité des institutions financières nationales de favoriser et généraliser l’accès de tous aux services bancaires et financiers et aux services d’assurance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 8.10.2: Proportion d’adultes (15 ans ou plus) possédant un compte dans une banque ou dans une autre institution financière ou faisant appel à des services monétaires mobiles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2016-07-19&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicateurs connexes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.4, 5.a et 2.3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Information institutionnelle&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organisation :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banque mondiale&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Définition : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pourcentage d&apos;adultes (15 ans et plus) qui déclarent avoir ouvert un compte (seul ou avec quelqu&apos;un d&apos;autre) dans une banque ou un autre type d&apos;institution financière ou avoir utilisé personnellement un service d&apos;argent mobile au cours des 12 derniers mois. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le concept de compte dans une institution financière comprend les répondants qui déclarent avoir un compte dans une banque ou dans un autre type d&apos;institution financière, comme une coopérative de crédit, une institution de microfinance, une coopérative ou la poste (le cas échéant), ou avoir une carte de débit à leur propre nom. Le tout inclut les répondants qui déclarent avoir reçu des salaires, des transferts gouvernementaux ou des paiements pour des produits agricoles dans un compte d&apos;une institution financière au cours des 12 derniers mois ; avoir payé des factures de services publics ou des frais de scolarité à partir d&apos;un compte dans une institution financière au cours des 12 derniers mois ; ou avoir reçu des salaires ou des transferts gouvernementaux sur une carte au cours des 12 derniers mois. Le concept de compte d&apos;argent mobile comprend les répondants qui déclarent avoir utilisé personnellement les services de Mobile Money for the Unbanked (MMU) de la GSM Association (GSMA) au cours des 12 derniers mois pour payer des factures ou pour envoyer ou recevoir de l&apos;argent. Le tout inclut les répondants qui déclarent avoir reçu des salaires, des transferts gouvernementaux ou des paiements pour des produits agricoles par l&apos;intermédiaire d&apos;un téléphone portable au cours des 12 derniers mois. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Sources de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les indicateurs de la base de données de 2014 de Global Findex sont tirés de données d&apos;enquête couvrant près de 150 000 personnes dans plus de 140 économies&amp;#x2014;représentant plus de 97 % de la population mondiale. L&apos;enquête a été réalisée au cours de l&apos;année civile 2014 par Gallup, Inc. Dans le cadre de son Gallup World Poll, l&apos;entreprise mène continuellement des enquêtes, et ce depuis 2005, auprès d&apos;environ 1 000 personnes chacune dans plus de 160 économies et dans plus de 140 langues, en utilisant des échantillons nationaux représentatifs sélectionnés au hasard. La population cible est l&apos;ensemble de la population civile, non institutionnalisée, âgée de 15 ans et plus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La méthodologie, y compris les procédures d&apos;entretien, la préparation des données, la marge d&apos;erreur et les notes par pays sont toutes disponibles à &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldbank.org/content/dam/Worldbank/Research/GlobalFindex/PDF/Methodology.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.worldbank.org/content/dam/Worldbank/Research/GlobalFindex/PDF/Methodology.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Processus de collecte :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données sont comparables entre les pays.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendrier&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collecte de données : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prochain cycle de collecte : 2017. Les données sont recueillies tous les trois ans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Diffusion des données :&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;2017&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fournisseur de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;s. o.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compilateur des données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banque mondiale&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Justification : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;accès aux services financiers formels tels que l&apos;épargne, l&apos;assurance, les paiements, le crédit et les transferts de fonds est essentiel à la capacité des personnes&amp;#x2014;quels que soient leur niveau de revenu, leur sexe, leur âge, leur niveau d&apos;éducation ou leur lieu de résidence&amp;#x2014;à gérer leur vie, à construire leur avenir et à développer leurs entreprises. L&apos;accès à un compte est un point de départ important pour accéder à toute une gamme de services financiers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commentaires et limites : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La base de données Global Findex de la Banque mondiale est basée sur des enquêtes individuelles menées tous les trois ans dans le monde entier. Le premier cycle de l&apos;enquête a été réalisé en 2011, le second en 2014, et le troisième en 2017. La base de données couvre environ 140 pays.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Méthodologie&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Méthode de calcul : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur est basé sur des données recueillies par des enquêtes individuelles dans chaque pays ayant des échantillons représentatifs. Des poids d&apos;échantillonnage appropriés sont utilisés pour calculer les agrégats au niveau des pays.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traitement des valeurs manquantes : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Au niveau national : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;s. o.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aux niveaux régional et mondial : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;s. o.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agrégats régionaux : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Au niveau national, le pourcentage d&apos;adultes possédant un compte est multiplié par le nombre d&apos;adultes dans le pays. Ensuite, pour les valeurs régionales, la somme de tous les pays de la région est prise et divisée par le nombre total d&apos;adultes vivant dans la région. De façon similaire, pour les chiffres mondiaux, le même calcul est répété pour tous les pays.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilité des données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Description : &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Pays disposant d&apos;au moins une observation après 2010 pour cet indicateur : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Asie et Pacifique : 35 &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Afrique : 38 &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Amérique latine et Caraïbes : 21 &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Europe, Amérique du Nord, Australie, Nouvelle-Zélande et Japon : 47 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Séries chronologiques : &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 2011 et 2014. Données recueillies tous les 3 ans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Désagrégation : &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Désagrégation par revenu; âge; niveau d&apos;éducation; urbain / rural; et sexe. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources des divergences : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global Findex est une enquête au niveau individuel qui mesure le nombre d&apos;individus possédant un compte. Comme l&apos;inclusion financière est un concept individuel, il s&apos;agit de la mesure appropriée. D&apos;autres enquêtes réalisées au niveau des ménages peuvent mesurer l&apos;accès au financement par un autre membre du ménage, ce qui peut surestimer l&apos;inclusion financière.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Référence &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;www.banquemondiale.org&quot;&gt;www.banquemondiale.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Références : &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldbank.org/globalfindex&quot;&gt;http://www.worldbank.org/globalfindex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 8: Содействие поступательному, всеохватному и устойчивому экономическому росту, полной и производительной занятости и достойной работе для всех&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 8.10: Укреплять способность национальных финансовых учреждений поощрять и расширять доступ к банковским, страховым и финансовым услугам для всех&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 8.10.2: Доля  взрослых (15 лет и старше), имеющих счет в банке или ином финансовом учреждении или пользующихся услугами операторов мобильных финансовых услуг&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Последнее обновление: 19 июля 2016 года&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Связанные показатели &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 1.4, 5.а, 2.3 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Институциональная информация&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Организация(и):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Всемирный банк (ВБ)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Определение: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Доля взрослых (в возрасте 15 лет и старше), которые сообщают о наличии счета (самостоятельного или совместно с кем-либо) в банке или ином финансовом учреждении или лично пользовавшихся услугами операторов мобильных финансовых услуг в течение последних 12 месяцев. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Понятия: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель наличия счета в финансовом учреждении включает респондентов, которые сообщили, что у них есть счет в банке или ином финансовом учреждении, таком как кредитный союз, микрофинансирующая организация, кооператив или почтовое отделение (если применимо), или у них есть дебетовая карта на свое имя. Кроме того, сюда входят респонденты, сообщившие о получении заработной платы, государственных трансфертов или платежей за сельскохозяйственную продукцию на счет в финансовом учреждении за последние 12 месяцев; совершавшие оплату счетов за коммунальные услуги или плату за обучение со счета в финансовом учреждении за последние 12 месяцев; или получавшие заработную плату или государственные переводы на карту в течение последних 12 месяцев. Показатель наличия счета мобильного банка включает респондентов, которые сообщили, что они сами использовали мобильный банк Ассоциации GSM (GSMA) для небанковских услуг (MMU) в течение последних 12 месяцев для оплаты счетов или для отправки или получения денег. Кроме того, сюда входят респонденты, сообщившие о получении заработной платы, государственных трансфертов или платежей за сельскохозяйственную продукцию через мобильный телефон за последние 12 месяцев.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Описание:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Показатели в Глобальной базе данных по охвату населения финансовыми услугами (ФИНДЕКС) 2014 года рассчитаны на основе данных обследования, охватывающего почти 150 000 человек в более чем 140 странах, представляющих более 97 процентов населения мира. Обследование проводилось в течение 2014 календарного года компанией Gallup, Inc. в рамках опроса Gallup World Poll, в котором, начиная с 2005 года, постоянно опрашиваются примерно 1000 человек в каждой из более чем 160 стран и на более чем 140 языках с использованием национальных репрезентативных случайных выборок. Целевой группой является все гражданское неинституциональное население в возрасте 15 лет и старше.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Методология, включающая процедуры проведения интервью, подготовку данных, определение погрешности и примечания в разбивке по странам, размещена по адресу &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldbank.org/content/dam/Worldbank/Research/GlobalFindex/PDF/Methodology.pdf&quot;&gt; http://www.worldbank.org/content/dam/Worldbank/Research/GlobalFindex/PDF/Methodology.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Процесс сбора:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные по странам сопоставимы по структуре&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Календарь &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Сбор данных: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Следующий раунд сбора: 2017 год. Данные собираются каждые три года. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Выпуск данных: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2017 год&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Поставщики данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Не применимо&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Составители данных&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Всемирный банк&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Обоснование:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Доступ к официальным финансовым услугам, таким как сбережения, страхование, платежи, кредиты и денежные переводы, необходим для того, чтобы люди, независимо от уровня дохода, пола, возраста, образования или места проживания, могли организовывать свою жизнь, строить свое будущее и развивать свой бизнес. Наличие доступа к счету является важной отправной точкой для доступа людей к целому ряду финансовых услуг.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Глобальная база данных по охвату населения финансовыми услугами (ФИНДЕКС) основана на информации, получаемой из индивидуальных опросов, проводимых во всех странах мира каждые три года. Первый раунд опросов был проведен в 2011 году, а второй в 2014 году. Третий раунд будет проведен в 2017 году. База данных охватывает около 140 стран.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель основан на данных, собираемых в ходе индивидуальных опросов в каждой стране с репрезентативными выборками. При расчете агрегированных показателей на страновом уровне используются соответствующие веса выборки. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Обработка отсутствующих значений:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;На страновом уровне:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Не применимо&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;На региональном и глобальном уровнях:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Не применимо &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Региональные агрегаты:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;На страновом уровне; доля взрослых, владеющих счетами, умножается на численность взрослого населения страны. Затем для региональных значений вычисляется сумма по всем странам региона и делится на общую численность взрослого населения, проживающего в этом регионе. Аналогичным образом для глобальных значений один и тот же расчет повторяется для всех стран.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Наличие данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Описание:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Страны, имеющие по крайней мере 1 элемент данных после 2010 года по этому показателю: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Азиатско-Тихоокеанский регион: 35 &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Африка: 38 &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Латинская Америка и Карибский бассейн: 21 &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Европа, Северная Америка, Австралия, Новая Зеландия и Япония: 47&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные за 2011 и 2014 годы. Подлежат сбору каждые 3 года.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Дезагрегирование по доходам; возрасту; уровню образования; городской/сельской местности; полу&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Источники расхождений: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Охват населения финансовыми услугами ФИНДЕКС- это опрос на уровне отдельных лиц, служащий для оценки индивидуального владения счетами. Поскольку доступ к финансовым услугам является понятием индивидуального уровня, эта процедура является подходящим инструментом оценки. Иные обследования, проводимые на уровне домохозяйств, могут включать оценку доступа к финансовым услугам при посредничестве другого члена домохозяйства, что может завысить уровень охвата финансовыми услугами.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; URL: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;www.worldbank.org&quot;&gt;www.worldbank.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Ссылки: &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldbank.org/globalfindex&quot;&gt; http://www.worldbank.org/globalfindex &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
