<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 8-4-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 8: Promote sustained, inclusive and sustainable economic growth, full and productive employment and decent work for all&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 8.4: Improve progressively, through 2030, global resource efficiency in consumption and production and endeavour to decouple economic growth from environmental degradation, in accordance with the 10-Year Framework of Programmes on Sustainable Consumption and Production, with developed countries taking the lead&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 8.4.2: Domestic material consumption, domestic material consumption per capita, and domestic material consumption per GDP&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last updated: 12 February 2018&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Related indicators&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicator 12.2.2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Institutional information&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organization(s):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations Environment Programme (UNEP)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Domestic Material Consumption (DMC) is a standard material flow accounting (MFA) indicator and reports the apparent consumption of materials in a national economy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Domestic Material Consumption (DMC) and MF need to be looked at in combination as they cover the two aspects of the economy, production and consumption. The DMC reports the actual amount of material in an economy, MF the virtual amount required across the whole supply chain to service final demand. A country can, for instance have a very high DMC because it has a large primary production sector for export or a very low DMC because it has outsourced most of the material intensive industrial process to other countries. The material footprint corrects for both phenomena. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The global material flows database is based on country material flow accounts from the European Union and Japan and estimated data for the rest of the world. Estimated data is produced on the bases of data available from different national or international datasets in the domain of agriculture, forestry, fisheries, mining and energy statistics. International statistical sources for DMC and MF include the IEA, USGS, FAO and COMTRADE databases. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Collection process:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IRP Global Material Flows and Resource Productivity working group compiles the data from countries and from other sources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendar&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Data collection:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under discussion&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Data release:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11 September 2017&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data providers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National Statistical Offices &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data compilers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNEP, OECD and EUROSTAT&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Rationale:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DMC reports the amount of materials that are used in a national economy. DMC is a territorial (production side) indicator. DMC also presents the amount of material that needs to be handled within an economy, which is either added to material stocks of buildings and transport infrastructure or used to fuel the economy as material throughput. DMC describes the physical dimension of economic processes and interactions. It can also be interpreted as long-term waste equivalent. Per-capita DMC describes the average level of material use in an economy &amp;#x2013; an environmental pressure indicator &amp;#x2013; and is also referred to as metabolic profile. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comments and limitations:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DMC cannot be disaggregated to economic sectors which limits its potential to become a satellite account to the System of National Accounts (SNA). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computation method:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is calculated as direct imports (IM) of material plus domestic extraction (DE) of materials minus direct exports (EX) of materials measured in metric tonnes. DMC measure the amount of materials that are used in economic processes. It does not include materials that are mobilized the process of domestic extraction but do not enter the economic process. DMC is based on official economic statistics and it requires some modelling to adapt the source data to the methodological requirements of the MFA. The accounting standard and accounting methods are set out in the EUROSTAT guidebooks for MFA accounts in the latest edition of 2013. MFA accounting is also part of the central framework of the System of integrated Environmental-Economic Accounts (SEEA). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Treatment of missing values:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At country level:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A zero is imputed when no positive real value was officially recorded, in the base data sets used, for any of the underlying components which make up this aggregated total. Thus &amp;#x201C;0.0&amp;#x201D; can represent either NA, or a genuine 0.0, or (crucially) a combination of both, which is a common situation. This allows for values to be easily aggregated into further aggregations; however, it should be thus noted that due to imputing missing values as &amp;#x2018;0.0&amp;#x2019;, the aggregations may represent a lower value than actual situation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At regional and global levels:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, missing values are imputed as zero in the regional and global aggregations. However, in the case where no data is available at all for a particular country then the per capita and per GDP estimates are weighted averages of the available data. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Regional aggregates:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See: &lt;a href=&quot;http://uneplive.unep.org/media/docs/graphs/aggregation_methods.pdf&quot;&gt;http://uneplive.unep.org/media/docs/graphs/aggregation_methods.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data availability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data covers more than 170 countries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Time series:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data set covers each nation individually, over a time period of 47 years (1970-2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DMC indicator can be disaggregated into imports, domestic extraction and exports by a large number of material follow categories. At the highest level of aggregation biomass, fossil fuels, metal ores and non-metallic minerals are distinguished. DMC is usually reported for 11 material categories, DE for 44 material categories. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EUROSTAT (2013). Economy-wide material flow accounts. Compilation guide 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wiedmann, T., H. Schandl, M. Lenzen, D. Moran, S. Suh, J. West, K. Kanemoto, (2013) The Material Footprint of Nations, Proc. Nat. Acad. Sci. Online before print.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lenzen, M., Moran, D., Kanemoto, K., Geschke, A. (2013) Building Eora: A global Multi-regional Input-Output Database at High Country and Secotr Resolution, Economic Systems Research, 25:1, 20-49. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 8: Promover el crecimiento económico sostenido, inclusivo y sostenible, el empleo pleno y productivo y el trabajo decente para todos&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 8.4: Mejorar progresivamente, de aquí a 2030, la producción y el consumo eficientes de los recursos mundiales y procurar desvincular el crecimiento económico de la degradación del medio ambiente, conforme al Marco Decenal de Programas sobre Modalidades de Consumo y Producción Sostenibles, empezando por los países desarrollados&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 8.4.2: Consumo material interno en términos absolutos, consumo material interno per cápita y consumo material interno por PIB&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Última actualización: 12 de febrero de 2018&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicadores relacionados&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicador 12.2.2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Información institucional &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Organización (es): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Programa de las Naciones Unidas para el Medio Ambiente (PNUMA) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definición:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El consumo interno de materiales (DMC, por sus siglas en inglés) es un indicador estándar de la contabilidad de flujos de materiales (CFM) e informa del consumo aparente de materiales en una economía nacional. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El consumo interno de materiales (DMC) y el FM deben considerarse conjuntamente, ya que abarcan los dos aspectos de la economía, la producción y el consumo. El DMC informa de la cantidad real de material en una economía, el FM de la cantidad virtual necesaria en toda la cadena de suministro para atender la demanda final. Un país puede, por ejemplo, tener un DMC muy alto porque tiene un gran sector de producción primaria para la exportación o un DMC muy bajo porque ha externalizado la mayor parte del proceso industrial intensivo en materiales a otros países. La huella de materiales corrige ambos fenómenos. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La base de datos de flujos de materiales a nivel mundial se basa en las cuentas de flujos de materiales de los países de la Unión Europea y Japón y en datos estimados para el resto del mundo. Los datos estimados se elaboran a partir de los datos disponibles en diferentes conjuntos de datos nacionales o internacionales en el ámbito de la agricultura, la silvicultura, la pesca, la minería y las estadísticas energéticas. Las fuentes estadísticas internacionales para DMC y FM incluyen las bases de datos de la AIE, el USGS, la FAO y COMTRADE. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Proceso de recolección:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; El grupo de trabajo Flujos globales de materiales y productividad de recursos de IRP compila los datos de países y de otras fuentes. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendario&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recolección de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En discusión&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publicación de datos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11 de septiembre de 2017&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oficinas nacionales de estadística &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; PNUMA, OCDE y EUROSTAT&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El DMC informa de la cantidad de materiales que se utilizan en una economía nacional. El DMC es un indicador territorial (del lado de la producción). El DMC también presenta la cantidad de material que debe manejarse dentro de una economía, que se añade a las existencias de material de los edificios y de las infraestructuras de transporte o que se utiliza para alimentar la economía como flujo de material. El DMC describe la dimensión física de los procesos e interacciones económicas. También puede interpretarse como un equivalente de residuos a largo plazo. El DMC per cápita describe el nivel medio de uso de materiales en una economía &amp;#x2013;, un indicador de presión ambiental &amp;#x2013; y también se denomina perfil metabólico. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El DMC no puede desagregarse por sectores económicos, lo que limita su potencial para convertirse en una cuenta satélite del Sistema de Cuentas Nacionales (SCN). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método de cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se calcula como las importaciones directas (IM) de materiales más la extracción nacional (EN) de materiales menos las exportaciones directas (EX) de materiales medidas en toneladas métricas. El DMC mide la cantidad de materiales que se utilizan en los procesos económicos. No incluye los materiales que se movilizan en el proceso de extracción nacional pero que no entran en el proceso económico. El DMC se basa en las estadísticas económicas oficiales y requiere cierta modelización para adaptar los datos de origen a los requisitos metodológicos del FMA. La norma contable y los métodos de contabilidad se establecen en las guías de EUROSTAT para las cuentas de la FMA en la última edición de 2013. La contabilidad de la FMA también forma parte del marco central del Sistema de Cuentas Económicas y Medioambientales integradas (SEEA). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Tratamiento de valores faltantes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel de país:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se imputa un cero cuando no se ha registrado oficialmente ningún valor real positivo, en los conjuntos de datos base utilizados, para ninguno de los componentes subyacentes que conforman este total agregado. Por lo tanto, &amp;#x201C;0.0&amp;#x201D; puede representar un valor nulo o un verdadero 0.0, o (fundamentalmente) una combinación de ambos, que es una situación común. Esto permite que los valores sean fácilmente agregados en otras agregaciones; sin embargo, debe tenerse en cuenta que, debido a la imputación de los valores que faltan como &amp;#x2018;0.0&amp;#x2019;, las agregaciones pueden representar un valor inferior a la situación real. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A nivel regional y mundial:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Asimismo, los valores que faltan se imputan como cero en las agregaciones regionales y globales. Sin embargo, en el caso de que no se disponga de ningún dato para un país concreto, las estimaciones per cápita y por PIB son medias ponderadas de los datos disponibles. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agregados regionales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ver: &lt;a href=&quot;http://uneplive.unep.org/media/docs/graphs/aggregation_methods.pdf&quot;&gt;http://uneplive.unep.org/media/docs/graphs/aggregation_methods.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos abarcan más de 170 países. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El conjunto de datos cubre cada nación individualmente, durante un período de tiempo de 47 años (1970-2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Desagregación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador DMC puede desagregarse en importaciones, extracción nacional y exportaciones por un gran número de categorías de seguimiento de materiales. En el nivel más alto de agregación se distinguen la biomasa, los combustibles fósiles, los minerales metálicos y los minerales no metálicos. El DMC se suele notificar para 11 categorías de materiales, la EN para 44 categorías de materiales. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Fuentes de discrepancias:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Referencias:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EUROSTAT (2013). Cuentas de flujo de materiales a nivel de la economía. Guía de compilación 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wiedmann, T., H. Schandl, M. Lenzen, D. Moran, S. Suh, J. West, K. Kanemoto, (2013) The Material Footprint of Nations, Proc. Nat. Acad. Sci. en línea antes de la impresión.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lenzen, M., Moran, D., Kanemoto, K., Geschke, A. (2013) Building Eora: A global Multi-regional Input-Output Database at High Country and Secotr Resolution, Economic Systems Research, 25:1, 20-49. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 8 : Promouvoir une croissance économique soutenue, partagée et durable, le plein emploi productif et un travail décent pour tous.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 8.4: Améliorer progressivement, jusqu’en 2030, l’efficacité de l’utilisation des ressources mondiales dans les modes de consommation et de production et s’attacher à dissocier croissance économique et dégradation de l’environnement, comme prévu dans le Cadre décennal de programmation concernant les modes de consommation et de production durables, les pays développés montrant l’exemple en la matière&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 8.4.2: Consommation matérielle nationale, consommation matérielle nationale par habitant et consommation matérielle nationale par unité de PIB&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dernière mise à jour : 12 février 2018&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicateur connexe&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 12.2.2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Information institutionnelle&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Organisation(s):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Programme des Nations Unies pour l’environnement (PNUE)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Définition : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La consommation matérielle nationale (CMN) est un indicateur standard de la comptabilité des flux de matières (CFM) et rapporte la consommation apparente de matières dans une économie nationale. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La CMN et les flux de matière (FM) doivent être regardés en combinaison puisqu&apos;ils couvrent les deux aspects de l&apos;économie, soit la production et la consommation. La CMN rapporte la quantité réelle de matériel dans une économie, alors que les FM rapportent le montant virtuel nécessaire à l&apos;échelle de l&apos;ensemble de la chaîne d&apos;approvisionnement afin de répondre à la demande finale. Un pays peut, par exemple, avoir une très grande CMN car il a un grand secteur de production primaire pour l&apos;exportation ou avoir une très faible CMN parce qu&apos;il a sous-traité à d&apos;autres pays la plupart des processus industriel intensifs en matériel. L&apos;empreinte matérielle corrige les deux phénomènes. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Sources de données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La base de données mondiale sur les flux de matières est basée sur les comptes de flux de matières des pays de l&apos;Union européenne et du Japon, et sur des données estimées pour le reste du monde. Les données estimées sont produites sur la base des données disponibles à partir de différents ensembles de données nationaux ou internationaux dans le domaine des statistiques de l&apos;agriculture, de la foresterie, de la pêche, des mines et de l&apos;énergie. Les sources statistiques internationales pour la CMN et le FM comprennent les bases de données de l&apos;Agence internationale de l’énergie, de l&apos;Institut d&apos;études géologiques des États-Unis, de la FAO et de COMTRADE. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Processus de collecte : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le groupe de travail sur les flux de matières mondiaux et la productivité des ressources du Groupe international d&apos;experts sur les ressources compile les données provenant des pays et d&apos;autres sources.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Calendrier &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Collecte de données : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; En discussion. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Diffusion des données : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 11 septembre 2017 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fournisseurs de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bureaux nationaux de statistique&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Compilateurs de données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; PNUE, OCDE et EUROSTAT &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justification :&lt;/h2&gt;
La CMN correspond à la quantité de matériaux utilisés dans une économie nationale. La CMN est un indicateur territorial (côté production). La CMN représente également la quantité de matériaux qui doit être manipulée dans une économie, et qui est soit ajoutée aux stocks de matériaux des bâtiments et des infrastructures de transport, soit utilisée pour alimenter l&apos;économie en tant qu&apos;intrant matériel. La CMN décrit la dimension physique des processus économiques et des interactions. Elle peut également être interprétée comme l&apos;équivalent d&apos;une perte à long terme. La CMN par habitant décrit le niveau moyen d&apos;utilisation des matériaux dans une économie &amp;#x2013; un indicateur de pression environnementale &amp;#x2013; et est également appelé profil métabolique. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Commentaires et limites : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La CMN ne peut pas être ventilé par secteur économique, ce qui limite son potentiel à devenir un compte satellite du Système de comptabilité nationale (SCN). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Méthodologie &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Méthode de calcul : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L&apos;indicateur correspond aux importations directes (IM) de matières plus l&apos;extraction intérieure (DE) de matières moins les exportations directes (EX) de matières mesurées en tonnes métriques. La CMN mesure la quantité de matériaux utilisés dans les processus économiques. Cela n&apos;inclut pas les matières utilisées dans le processus d&apos;extraction domestique mais n&apos;entrant pas dans le processus économique. La CMN est basée sur les statistiques économiques officielles et nécessite une modélisation pour adapter les données de base aux exigences méthodologiques de la CFM. Les normes et les méthodes comptables sont définies dans la dernière édition (2013) du guide EUROSTAT pour les comptes CFM. La CFM fait également partie du cadre central du Système de comptabilité économique et environnementale intégrée (SCEE). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Traitement des valeurs manquantes : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Au niveau national : &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Une valeur de zéro est imputée lorsqu&apos;aucune valeur réelle positive n&apos;a été officiellement enregistrée, dans les ensembles de données de base utilisés, pour aucune des composantes sous-jacentes qui composent ce total agrégé. Ainsi &amp;#x201C; 0,0 &amp;#x201D; peut représenter soit s. o., soit un véritable 0,0, soit une combinaison des deux, ce qui constitue une situation courante. Cela permet aux valeurs d&apos;être facilement agrégées dans d&apos;autres agrégations. Il convient cependant de noter qu&apos;en raison de l&apos;imputation de valeurs manquantes à &amp;#x201C; 0,0 &amp;#x201D;, les agrégations peuvent représenter une valeur inférieure à la situation réelle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Aux niveaux régional et mondial : &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; De la même manière, les valeurs manquantes sont imputées à zéro dans les agrégations régionales et mondiales. Cependant, dans le cas où aucune donnée n&apos;est disponible pour un pays particulier, les estimations par habitant et par PIB représentent des moyennes pondérées des données disponibles. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Agrégats régionaux : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Voir : &lt;a href=&quot;http://uneplive.unep.org/media/docs/graphs/aggregation_methods.pdf&quot;&gt; http://uneplive.unep.org/media/docs/graphs/aggregation_methods.pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Disponibilité des données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les données couvrent plus de 170 pays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Séries chronologiques : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L&apos;ensemble de données couvre chaque pays individuellement, sur une période de 47 ans (1970-2017). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Désagrégation : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La CMN peut être ventilée en importations, extraction intérieure et exportations par un grand nombre de catégories de matières. Au niveau le plus élevé d&apos;agrégation, la biomasse, les combustibles fossiles, les minerais métalliques et les minéraux non métalliques sont distincts. La CMN est généralement rapportée pour 11 catégories de matériaux, et la DE pour 44 catégories de matériaux. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sources des divergences : &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Références &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; URL : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Références : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; EUROSTAT (2013). Comptes des flux de matières à l&apos;échelle de l&apos;économie. Guide de compilation 2013. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Wiedmann, T., H. Schandl, M. Lenzen, D. Moran, S. Suh, J. West et K. Kanemoto, (2013) L&apos;empreinte matérielle des nations, Proc. Nat. Acad. Sci. En ligne avant impression. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Lenzen, M., Moran, D., Kanemoto, K. et A. Geschke (2013) Building Eora: A global Multi-regional Input-Output Database at High Country and Sector Resolution, Economic Systems Research, 25: 1, 20-49. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 8: Содействие поступательному, всеохватному и устойчивому экономическому росту, полной и производительной занятости и достойной работе для всех&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 8.4: На протяжении всего срока до конца 2030 года постепенно повышать глобальную эффективность использования ресурсов в системах потребления и производства и стремиться к тому, чтобы экономический рост не сопровождался ухудшением состояния окружающей среды, как это предусматривается Десятилетней стратегией действий по переходу к использованию рациональных моделей потребления и производства, причем первыми этим должны заняться развитые страны&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 8.4.2: Совокупное  внутреннее материальное потребление, внутреннее материальное потребление на душу населения и внутреннее материальное потребление в процентном отношении к ВВП&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Последнее обновление: 12 февраля 2018 года&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Связанные показатели &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель 12.2.2 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Институциональная информация &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Организация(и): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Программа Организации Объединенных Наций по окружающей среде (ЮНЕП) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Совокупное внутреннее материальное потребление (СВМП) является стандартным показателем учета материальных потоков (УМП) и отражает видимое потребление материалов в национальной экономике. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Совокупное внутреннее материальное потребление (СВМП) и материальный поток (МП) необходимо рассматривать в сочетании, поскольку они охватывают два аспекта экономики: производство и потребление. Совокупное внутреннее материальное потребление отражает фактическое количество материалов в экономике, материальный поток - виртуальное количество, необходимое по всей цепочке поставок для обслуживания конечного спроса. Страна может, например, иметь очень высокое совокупное внутреннее материальное потребление, потому что у нее большой сектор первичного производства для экспортных поставок, или очень низкое внутреннее материальное потребление, потому что она передала на аутсорсинг другим странам большую часть материалоемких производственных процессов. Материальная область охвата корректируется для обоих явлений. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Глобальная база данных по материальным потокам основана на учете материальных потоков стран Европейского союза и Японии и оценочных данных по остальному миру. Оценочные данные составляются на основе данных, имеющихся в различных национальных или международных базах данных в области статистики сельского хозяйства, лесоводства, рыболовства, добычи полезных ископаемых и энергетики. Международные источники статистической информации по совокупному внутреннему материальному потреблению (СВМП) и материальным потокам (МП) включают базы данных Международного энергетического агентства, Геологической службы США, ФАО и Базу данных статистики международной торговли Организации Объединенных Наций (COMTRADE). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Рабочая группа Международной исследовательской панели по глобальным материальным потокам и продуктивности ресурсов собирает данные от стран и из иных источников.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Календарь &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Сбор данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Находится в процессе обсуждения &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Выпуск данных: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 11 сентября 2017 года &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Поставщики данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Национальные статистические управления &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Составители данных&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Программа Организации Объединенных Наций по окружающей среде (ЮНЕП), Организация экономического сотрудничества и развития (ОЭСР) и Евростат&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Совокупное внутреннее материальное потребление (СВМП) отражает количество материалов, используемых в национальной экономике. СВМП является территориальным (по отношению к производству) показателем. СВМП также представляет количество материалов, которые должны быть переработаны в рамках экономики, и это количество либо добавляется к материальным запасам зданий и транспортной инфраструктуры, либо используется для активирования экономики в качестве подсобного материала. СВМП описывает физические параметры экономических процессов и взаимодействий. Его также можно интерпретировать как долгосрочные эквивалентные потери. Внутреннее материальное потребление на душу населения описывает средний уровень использования материалов в экономике, показатель давления на окружающую среду, а также этот показатель рассматривается как метаболический профиль. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Совокупное внутреннее материальное потребление не может быть дезагрегировано по секторам экономики, что ограничивает его потенциал стать вспомогательным счетом для Системы национальных счетов (СНС). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель рассчитывается как прямой импорт (ИМ) материалов плюс внутренняя добыча (ВД) материалов минус прямой экспорт (ЭКС) материалов, измеряемые в метрических тоннах. Совокупное внутреннее материальное потребление показывает количество материалов, используемых в экономических процессах. Оно не включает материалы, которые используются для содействия процессу внутренней добычи, но не входят в экономический процесс. Совокупное внутреннее материальное потребление основывается на данных официальной экономической статистики и требует некоторого моделирования для адаптации исходных данных к методологическим требованиям учета материальных потоков. Стандарт бухгалтерского учета и методы бухгалтерского учета изложены в Справочнике Евростата по учету материальных потоков в последнем издании 2013 года. Учет материальных потоков также является частью центральной структуры Системы природно-экономического учета (СПЭУ). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обработка отсутствующих значений: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;На страновом уровне:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Нулевое значение вменяется, когда ни одно из положительных реальных значений не было официально внесено в используемые базовые наборы данных для любого из основных компонентов, входящих в этот агрегированный итог. Таким образом, 0.0 может представлять собой либо &quot;нет в наличии&quot;, либо подлинное значение 0.0, либо (что крайне важно) комбинацию обоих значений, что является обычной ситуацией. Это позволяет легко агрегировать значения в процессах последующих агрегаций; тем не менее, следует отметить, что из-за вменения отсутствующих значений, таких как 0.0, агрегаты могут принимать меньшее значение, чем оно есть на самом деле. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;На региональном и глобальном уровнях:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Точно так же, нулевые значения вменяются на место отсутствующих значений в региональных и глобальных агрегатах. Однако в случае, если данных по какой-либо конкретной стране вообще нет в наличии, оценки на душу населения и на единицу ВВП представляют собой средневзвешенные значения имеющихся данных. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Региональные агрегаты: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; См.: &lt;a href=&quot;http://uneplive.unep.org/media/docs/graphs/aggregation_methods.pdf&quot;&gt;http://uneplive.unep.org/media/docs/graphs/aggregation_methods.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные охватывают более 170 стран. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Набор данных охватывает в отдельности каждую страну на протяжении 47 лет (1970-2017 годы)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Дезагрегирование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель совокупного внутреннего материального потребления может быть дезагрегирован по импорту, внутренней добыче и экспорту по большому количеству категорий материалов. На самом высоком уровне агрегирования выделяются биомасса, ископаемое топливо, металлические руды и неметаллические минеральные продукты. Показатель совокупного внутреннего материального потребления обычно отражает 11 категорий материалов, показатель внутренней добычи - 44 категории материалов. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Источники расхождений:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Ссылки: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EUROSTAT (2013). Economy-wide material flow accounts. Compilation guide 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wiedmann, T., H. Schandl, M. Lenzen, D. Moran, S. Suh, J. West, K. Kanemoto, (2013) The Material Footprint of Nations, Proc. Nat. Acad. Sci. Online before print.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lenzen, M., Moran, D., Kanemoto, K., Geschke, A. (2013) Building Eora: A global Multi-regional Input-Output Database at High Country and Secotr Resolution, Economic Systems Research, 25:1, 20-49. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
