<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 8-5-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 8: Promote sustained, inclusive and sustainable economic growth, full and productive employment and decent work for all&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 8.5: By 2030, achieve full and productive employment and decent work for all women and men, including for young people and persons with disabilities, and equal pay for work of equal value&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 8.5.2: Unemployment rate, by sex, age and persons with disabilities&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last updated: March 2020&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Related indicators&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Institutional information&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organization(s):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ILO&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts and definitions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unemployment rate conveys the percentage of persons in the labour force who are unemployed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unemployed persons are defined as all those of working age (usually aged 15 and above) who were not in employment, carried out activities to seek employment during a specified recent period and were currently available to take up employment given a job opportunity, where: (a) &amp;#x201C;not in employment&amp;#x201D; is assessed with respect to the short reference period for the measurement of employment; (b) to &amp;#x201C;seek employment&amp;#x201D; refers to any activity when carried out, during a specified recent period comprising the last four weeks or one month, for the purpose of finding a job or setting up a business or agricultural undertaking; (c) the point when the enterprise starts to exist should be used to distinguish between search activities aimed at setting up a business and the work activity itself, as evidenced by the enterprise&amp;#x2019;s registration to operate or by when financial resources become available, the necessary infrastructure or materials are in place or the first client or order is received, depending on the context; (d) &amp;#x201C;currently available&amp;#x201D; serves as a test of readiness to start a job in the present, assessed with respect to a short reference period comprising that used to measure employment (depending on national circumstances, the reference period may be extended to include a short subsequent period not exceeding two weeks in total, so as to ensure adequate coverage of unemployment situations among different population groups). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Persons in employment are defined as all those of working age (usually aged 15 and above) who, during a short reference period such as one week or one day, were engaged in any activity to produce goods or provide services for pay or profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The labour force corresponds to the sum of persons in employment and in unemployment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the definitions of employment and unemployment refer to the Resolution concerning statistics of work, employment and labour underutilization Adopted by the 19&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; International Conference of Labour Statisticians.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The preferred official national data source for this indicator is a household-based labour force survey. In the absence of a labour force survey, a population census and/or other type of household surveys with an appropriate employment module may also be used to obtain the required data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that unemployment data derived from employment office records or unemployment registers would not refer to unemployment (as defined for the purposes of this indicator, using the three-criteria of being without a job, seeking employment and available for employment) but to registered unemployment, and thus, it would not be comparable with indicator 8.5.2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Collection process:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ILO Department of Statistics sends out its annual questionnaire on labour statistics to all relevant agencies within each country (national statistical office, labour ministry, etc.) requesting for the latest annual data available and any revisions on numerous labour market topics and indicators, including many SDG indicators. Indicator 8.5.2 is calculated from statistics submitted to the ILO via this questionnaire as well as through special agreements with regional and national statistical offices or through the processing of microdata sets of national labour force surveys.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendar&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Data collection:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ILO Department of Statistics sends out its annual questionnaire on labour statistics, usually in the 2nd quarter, with a view to receiving the requested statistics by the 3rd quarter or the end of the year at the latest. Data received in batch from regional and national statistical offices and data obtained through the processing of microdata sets of national household surveys by the ILO Department of Statistics are continuously updated in ILOSTAT (as they become available to the ILO).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Data release:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ILO&amp;#x2019;s online database ILOSTAT is continuously updated to reflect statistics compiled and processed every week. In general, statistics for EUROSTAT and OECD countries are available around the 2nd or 3rd quarter of the year following the year of reference, whereas they are usually available around the 3rd or 4th quarter of the year following the year of reference for other countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data providers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainly national statistical offices, and in some cases labour ministries or other related agencies, at the country-level. In some cases, regional or international statistical offices can also act as data providers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data compilers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ILO&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Rationale:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unemployment rate is a useful measure of the underutilization of the labour supply. It reflects the inability of an economy to generate employment for those persons who want to work but are not doing so, even though they are available for employment and actively seeking work. It is thus seen as an indicator of the efficiency and effectiveness of an economy to absorb its labour force and of the performance of the labour market. Short-term time series of the unemployment rate can be used to signal changes in the business cycle; upward movements in the indicator often coincide with recessionary periods or in some cases with the beginning of an expansionary period as persons previously not in the labour market begin to test conditions through an active job search.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comments and limitations:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though in most developed countries the unemployment rate is useful as an indicator of labour market performance, and specifically, as a key measure of labour underutilization, in many developing countries, the significance and meaning of the unemployment rate could be questioned. In the absence of unemployment insurance systems or social safety nets, persons of working age must avoid unemployment, resorting to engaging in some form of economic activity, however insignificant or inadequate. Thus, in this context, other measures should supplement the unemployment rate to comprehensively assess labour underutilization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computation method:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Unemployment rate = (Total unemployment/Total labour force) x 100&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Treatment of missing values:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At country level:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multivariate regression techniques are used to impute missing values at the country level. However, the imputed missing country values are only used to calculate the global and regional estimates; they are not used for international reporting on the SDG indicators by the ILO. For further information on the estimates, please refer to the the ILO modelled estimates methodological overview, available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilo.org/ilostat-files/Documents/TEM.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.ilo.org/ilostat-files/Documents/TEM.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At regional and global levels:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Regional aggregates:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address the problem of missing data, the ILO designed several econometric models which are used to produce estimates of labour market indicators in the countries and years for which real data are not available. The unemployment estimates derived from the ILO modelled estimates are used to produce global and regional estimates on unemployment rates. These models use multivariate regression techniques to impute missing values at the country level, which are then aggregated to produce regional and global estimates. For further information on the estimates, please refer to the the ILO modelled estimates methodological overview, available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilo.org/ilostat-files/Documents/TEM.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.ilo.org/ilostat-files/Documents/TEM.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Methods and guidance available to countries for the compilation of the data at the national level:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to calculate this indicator (according to the ILO definitions of unemployment and unemployment rate), data is needed on both the labour force and the unemployed, by sex and age (and eventually disability status). This data is collected at the national level mainly through labour force surveys (or other types of household surveys with an employment module). For the methodology of each national household survey, one must refer to the most comprehensive survey report or to the methodological publications of the national statistical office in question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decent Work and the Sustainable Development Goals: A Guidebook on SDG Labour Market Indicators, available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ILO Manual &amp;#x2013; Decent Work Indicators, Concepts and Definitions &amp;#x2013; Chapter 1, Employment opportunities &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/integration/resources/pubs/WCMS_229374/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/integration/resources/pubs/WCMS_229374/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; (second version, pages 34 and 49)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resolution concerning statistics of work, employment and labour underutilization &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutions-adoptedby-international-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_230304/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutions-adoptedby-international-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_230304/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ILOSTAT (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ILOSTAT Indicator descriptions (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/resources/methods/description-unemployment-rate/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/resources/methods/description-unemployment-rate/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ILOSTAT&amp;#x2019;s topic page on Unemployment and Labour Underutilization (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/topics/unemployment-and-labour-underutilization/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/topics/unemployment-and-labour-underutilization/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Quality assurance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data consistency and quality checks regularly conducted for validation of the data before dissemination in the ILOSTAT database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many cases, data are obtained through ILO processing of microdata sets of national household surveys. Data are also reported by national statistical offices or other relevant national agencies to the ILO Department of Statistics through its annual questionnaire on labour statistics. The primary source of the data as well as the repository where applicable are indicated in the relevant metadata and/or footnotes in ILOSTAT and in the SDG Indicators Global Database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data availability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is widely available based on real observations provided by countries and derived from national labour force surveys, other types of household surveys or population census.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the disaggregation by disability is not widely available. It is increasingly reported but coverage is still very low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Time series:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data for this indicator is available as of 2000 in the SDG Indicators Global Database, but time series going back further are available in ILOSTAT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator should, ideally, be disaggregated by sex, age group and disability status.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h1&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decent Work and the Sustainable Development Goals: A Guidebook on SDG Labour Market Indicators, available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm%20&quot;&gt;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ILOSTAT (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ILOSTAT Indicator descriptions (https://ilostat.ilo.org/resources/methods/description-unemployment-rate/)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ILOSTAT&amp;#x2019;s topic page on Unemployment and Labour Underutilization (https://ilostat.ilo.org/topics/unemployment-and-labour-underutilization/).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decent Work Indicators Manual: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---stat/documents/publication/wcms_223121.pdf%20&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---stat/documents/publication/wcms_223121.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resolution concerning statistics of work, employment and labour underutilization, adopted by the 19th ICLS in 2013: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutions-adoptedby-international-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_230304/lang--en/index.htm%20&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutions-adoptedby-international-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_230304/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trends Econometric Models: A Review of Methodology: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---ed_emp/---emp_elm/---trends/documents/publication/wcms_120382.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---ed_emp/---emp_elm/---trends/documents/publication/wcms_120382.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Meta 8: Promover el crecimiento económico sostenido, inclusivo y sostenible, el empleo pleno y productivo y el trabajo decente para todos&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 8.5: De aquí a 2030, lograr el empleo pleno y productivo y el trabajo decente para todas las mujeres y los hombres, incluidos los jóvenes y las personas con discapacidad, así como la igualdad de remuneración por trabajo de igual valor&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 8.5.2: Tasa de desempleo, desglosada por sexo, edad y personas con discapacidad&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Última actualización: marzo de 2020 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicadores relacionados&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; OIT&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Fuentes de discrepancias:&lt;/h2&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 8 : Promouvoir une croissance économique soutenue, partagée et durable, le plein emploi productif et un travail décent pour tous.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 8.5: D’ici à 2030, parvenir au plein emploi productif et garantir à toutes les femmes et à tous les hommes, y compris les jeunes et les personnes handicapées, un travail décent et un salaire égal pour un travail de valeur égale&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 8.5.2: Taux de chômage, par sexe, âge et situation au regard du handicap&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Dernière mise à jour : Mars 2020 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Indicateurs connexes&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Informations institutionnelles&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Organisation(s) :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; OIT&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Concepts et définitions &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Définition :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le taux de chômage exprime le pourcentage de personnes sans emploi dans la population active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Concepts : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les chômeurs sont définis comme toutes les personnes en âge de travailler (généralement âgées de 15 ans et plus) qui n&apos;avaient pas d&apos;emploi, qui ont effectué des activités de recherche d&apos;emploi au cours d&apos;une période récente spécifiée et qui étaient actuellement disponibles pour prendre un emploi si une opportunité se présentait, lorsque : (a) &amp;#x201C;ne pas avoir d&apos;emploi&amp;#x201D; est évalué par rapport à la courte période de référence pour la mesure de l&apos;emploi ; (b) &amp;#x201C;chercher un emploi&amp;#x201D; se réfère à toute activité lorsqu&apos;elle est réalisée, au cours d&apos;une période récente spécifiée comprenant les quatre dernières semaines ou un mois, dans le but de trouver un emploi ou de créer une entreprise commerciale ou agricole ; (c) le moment où l&apos;entreprise commence à exister devrait être utilisé pour distinguer les activités de recherche visant à créer une entreprise de l&apos;activité de travail proprement dite, comme en témoigne l&apos;enregistrement de l&apos;entreprise pour fonctionner ou le moment où les ressources financières deviennent disponibles, où l&apos;infrastructure ou les matériaux nécessaires sont en place ou encore où le premier client ou la première commande est reçu, selon le contexte ; (d) &amp;#x201C;actuellement disponible&amp;#x201D; sert à tester l&apos;aptitude à commencer un travail dans le présent, évaluée par rapport à une courte période de référence comprenant celle utilisée pour mesurer l&apos;emploi (selon les circonstances nationales, la période de référence peut être étendue pour inclure une courte période ultérieure ne dépassant pas deux semaines au total, de manière à assurer une couverture adéquate des situations de chômage parmi les différents groupes de population). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les personnes ayant un emploi sont définies comme étant toutes les personnes en âge de travailler (généralement âgées de 15 ans et plus) qui, au cours d&apos;une courte période de référence telle qu&apos;une semaine ou un jour, étaient engagées dans une activité quelconque de production de biens ou de prestation de services contre rémunération ou profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La population active correspond à la somme des personnes ayant un emploi et des personnes au chômage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour plus d&apos;informations sur les définitions de l&apos;emploi et du chômage, voir la Résolution concernant les statistiques du travail, de l&apos;emploi et de la sous-utilisation de la main-d&apos;œuvre adoptée par la 19&lt;sup&gt;e&lt;/sup&gt; Conférence internationale des statisticiens du travail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Sources de données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La source de données nationale officielle privilégiée pour cet indicateur est une enquête sur les forces de travail basée sur les ménages. En l&apos;absence d&apos;une enquête sur les forces de travail, un recensement de la population et/ou d&apos;autres types d&apos;enquêtes sur les ménages avec un module emploi approprié peuvent également être utilisés pour obtenir les données requises. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il est important de noter que les données sur le chômage dérivées des registres de l&apos;agence pour l&apos;emploi ou des registres du chômage ne se référeraient pas au chômage (tel que défini pour les besoins de cet indicateur, en utilisant les trois critères d&apos;être sans emploi, à la recherche d&apos;un emploi et disponible pour l&apos;emploi) mais au chômage enregistré, et ne seraient donc pas comparables à l&apos;indicateur 8.5.2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Processus de collecte :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Département des statistiques de l&apos;OIT envoie son questionnaire annuel sur les statistiques du travail à toutes les agences concernées dans chaque pays (bureau national de statistique, ministère du travail, etc.) en demandant les dernières données annuelles disponibles et toute révision sur de nombreux sujets et indicateurs du marché du travail, y compris de nombreux indicateurs des ODD. L&apos;indicateur 8.5.2 est calculé à partir des statistiques soumises à l&apos;OIT par le biais de ce questionnaire ainsi que par des accords spéciaux avec les bureaux statistiques régionaux et nationaux ou par le traitement des ensembles de microdonnées des enquêtes nationales sur la main-d&apos;œuvre.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Calendrier &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Collecte des données : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le Département des statistiques du BIT envoie son questionnaire annuel sur les statistiques du travail, généralement au cours du 2e trimestre, en vue de recevoir les statistiques demandées au 3e trimestre ou à la fin de l&apos;année au plus tard. Les données reçues en lot des bureaux statistiques régionaux et nationaux et les données obtenues par le traitement des ensembles de microdonnées des enquêtes nationales sur les ménages par le Département des statistiques du BIT sont continuellement mises à jour dans ILOSTAT (au fur et à mesure qu&apos;elles sont disponibles pour le BIT).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Publication des données :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La base de données en ligne ILOSTAT de l&apos;OIT est continuellement mise à jour pour refléter les statistiques compilées et traitées chaque semaine. En général, les statistiques pour les pays d&apos;EUROSTAT et de l&apos;OCDE sont disponibles vers le 2e ou 3e trimestre de l&apos;année suivant l&apos;année de référence, alors qu&apos;elles sont habituellement disponibles vers le 3e ou 4e trimestre de l&apos;année suivant l&apos;année de référence pour les autres pays.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fournisseurs de données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Principalement les offices statistiques nationaux et, dans certains cas, les ministères du travail ou d&apos;autres organismes connexes, au niveau national. Dans certains cas, les offices statistiques régionaux ou internationaux peuvent également faire office de fournisseurs de données.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Compilateurs de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; OIT&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justification : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le taux de chômage est une mesure utile de la sous-utilisation de l&apos;offre de travail. Il reflète l&apos;incapacité d&apos;une économie à créer des emplois pour les personnes qui veulent travailler mais ne le font pas, même si elles sont disponibles pour l&apos;emploi et recherchent activement du travail. Il est donc considéré comme un indicateur de l&apos;efficience et de l&apos;efficacité d&apos;une économie à absorber sa main-d&apos;œuvre et de la performance du marché du travail. Les séries chronologiques à court terme du taux de chômage peuvent être utilisées pour signaler des changements dans le cycle économique ; les mouvements à la hausse de l&apos;indicateur coïncident souvent avec des périodes de récession ou, dans certains cas, avec le début d&apos;une période d&apos;expansion, lorsque des personnes qui n&apos;étaient pas sur le marché du travail auparavant commencent à tester les conditions par une recherche active d&apos;emploi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires et limites :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Même si, dans la plupart des pays développés, le taux de chômage est utile en tant qu&apos;indicateur de la performance du marché du travail et, plus précisément, en tant que mesure clé de la sous-utilisation de la main-d&apos;œuvre, dans de nombreux pays en développement, l&apos;importance et la signification du taux de chômage pourraient être remises en question. En l&apos;absence de systèmes d&apos;assurance chômage ou de filets de sécurité sociale, les personnes en âge de travailler doivent éviter le chômage, en recourant à une forme d&apos;activité économique, aussi insignifiante ou inadéquate soit-elle. Ainsi, dans ce contexte, d&apos;autres mesures devraient compléter le taux de chômage pour évaluer de manière exhaustive la sous-utilisation de la main-d&apos;œuvre.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Méthodologie &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Méthode de calcul : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Taux de chômage = (Chômage total / Population active totale) x 100 &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Traitement des valeurs manquantes : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Au niveau national :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des techniques de régression multivariée sont utilisées pour imputer les valeurs manquantes au niveau du pays. Cependant, les valeurs manquantes imputées au niveau des pays ne sont utilisées que pour calculer les estimations mondiales et régionales ; elles ne sont pas utilisées pour les rapports internationaux sur les indicateurs des ODD par l&apos;OIT. Pour plus d&apos;informations sur les estimations, veuillez vous référer à l&apos;aperçu méthodologique des estimations modélisées de l&apos;OIT, disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilo.org/ilostat-files/Documents/TEM.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.ilo.org/ilostat-files/Documents/TEM.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aux niveaux régional et mondial :&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Agrégats régionaux : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour résoudre le problème des données manquantes, le BIT a conçu plusieurs modèles économétriques qui sont utilisés pour produire des estimations des indicateurs du marché du travail dans les pays et les années pour lesquels les données réelles ne sont pas disponibles. Les estimations du chômage dérivées des modèles du BIT sont utilisées pour produire des estimations mondiales et régionales sur les taux de chômage. Ces modèles utilisent des techniques de régression multivariée pour imputer les valeurs manquantes au niveau des pays, qui sont ensuite agrégées pour produire des estimations régionales et mondiales. Pour plus d&apos;informations sur les estimations, veuillez vous référer à l&apos;aperçu méthodologique des estimations modélisées du BIT, disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilo.org/ilostat-files/Documents/TEM.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.ilo.org/ilostat-files/Documents/TEM.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Méthodes et instructions à la disposition des pays pour la compilation des données au niveau national :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour calculer cet indicateur (selon les définitions du chômage et du taux de chômage de l&apos;OIT), il faut disposer de données sur la population active et sur les chômeurs, par sexe et par âge (et éventuellement par statut d&apos;invalidité). Ces données sont collectées au niveau national principalement par le biais d&apos;enquêtes sur les forces de travail (ou d&apos;autres types d&apos;enquêtes sur les ménages comportant un module sur l&apos;emploi). Pour la méthodologie de chaque enquête nationale auprès des ménages, il faut se référer au rapport d&apos;enquête le plus complet ou aux publications méthodologiques de l&apos;office statistique national en question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Le travail décent et les Objectifs de développement durable : A Guidebook on SDG Labour Market Indicators, disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manuel de l&apos;OIT &amp;#x2013; Indicateurs du travail décent, concepts et définitions &amp;#x2013; Chapitre 1, Possibilités d&apos;emploi &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/integration/resources/pubs/WCMS_229374/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/integration/resources/pubs/WCMS_229374/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; (deuxième version, pages 34 et 49) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Résolution concernant les statistiques du travail, de l&apos;emploi et de la sous-utilisation de la main-d&apos;œuvre &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutions-adoptedby-international-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_230304/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutions-adoptedby-international-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_230304/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ILOSTAT (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ILOSTAT Descriptions des indicateurs (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/resources/methods/description-unemployment-rate/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/resources/methods/description-unemployment-rate/&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Page thématique d&apos;ILOSTAT sur le chômage et la sous-utilisation de la main-d&apos;œuvre (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/topics/unemployment-and-labour-underutilization/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/topics/unemployment-and-labour-underutilization/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Assurance qualité&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des contrôles de cohérence et de qualité des données sont régulièrement effectués pour valider les données avant leur diffusion dans la base de données d&apos;ILOSTAT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dans de nombreux cas, les données sont obtenues par le traitement par l&apos;OIT des ensembles de microdonnées des enquêtes nationales sur les ménages. Les données sont également communiquées par les bureaux nationaux de statistique ou d&apos;autres organismes nationaux compétents au Département des statistiques du BIT par le biais de son questionnaire annuel sur les statistiques du travail. La source primaire des données ainsi que le référentiel, le cas échéant, sont indiqués dans les métadonnées et/ou notes de bas de page pertinentes dans ILOSTAT et dans la base de données mondiale des indicateurs des ODD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilité des données &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Description :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&apos;indicateur est largement disponible sur la base d&apos;observations réelles fournies par les pays et dérivées d&apos;enquêtes nationales sur les forces de travail, d&apos;autres types d&apos;enquêtes sur les ménages ou de recensements de la population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cependant, la désagrégation par handicap n&apos;est pas largement disponible. Elle est de plus en plus souvent rapportée mais la couverture est encore très faible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Séries chronologiques :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Les données pour cet indicateur sont disponibles à partir de 2000 dans la base de données mondiale des indicateurs des ODD, mais des séries chronologiques remontant plus loin sont disponibles dans ILOSTAT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Désagrégation :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cet indicateur devrait, dans l&apos;idéal, être ventilé par sexe, groupe d&apos;âge et statut de handicap.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Sources des divergences : &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Références &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Le travail décent et les Objectifs de développement durable : A Guidebook on SDG Labour Market Indicators, disponible sur &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm%20&quot;&gt;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ILOSTAT (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&quot;&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Descriptions des indicateurs d&apos;ILOSTAT (https://ilostat.ilo.org/resources/methods/description-unemployment-rate/) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Page thématique d&apos;ILOSTAT sur le chômage et la sous-utilisation de la main-d&apos;œuvre (https://ilostat.ilo.org/topics/unemployment-and-labour-underutilization/).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manuel des indicateurs du travail décent : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---stat/documents/publication/wcms_223121.pdf%20&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---stat/documents/publication/wcms_223121.pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Résolution concernant les statistiques du travail, de l&apos;emploi et de la sous-utilisation de la main-d&apos;œuvre, adoptée par la 19e CIST en 2013 : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutions-adoptedby-international-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_230304/lang--en/index.htm%20&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutions-adoptedby-international-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_230304/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modèles économétriques tendanciels : Une revue de la méthodologie : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---ed_emp/---emp_elm/---trends/documents/publication/wcms_120382.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---ed_emp/---emp_elm/---trends/documents/publication/wcms_120382.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 8: Содействие поступательному, всеохватному и устойчивому экономическому росту, полной и производительной занятости и достойной работе для всех&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 8.5: К 2030 году обеспечить полную и производительную занятость и достойную работу для всех женщин и мужчин, в том числе молодых людей и инвалидов, и равную оплату за труд равной ценности&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 8.5.2: Уровень безработицы в разбивке по полу, возрасту и признаку инвалидности&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Последнее обновление: март 2020 года &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Связанные показатели&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Составители данных&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;МОТ&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Источники расхождений:&lt;/h2&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
