<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 8-8-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 8: Promote sustained, inclusive and sustainable economic growth, full and productive employment and decent work for all&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 8.8: Protect labour rights and promote safe and secure working environments for all workers, including migrant workers, in particular women migrants, and those in precarious employment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 8.8.1: Fatal and non-fatal occupational injuries per 100,000 workers, by sex and migrant status&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2021-01-01&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.3.1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;ILO&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;ILO&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator provides information on the number of fatal and non-fatal occupational injuries per 100,000 workers in the reference group during the reference period. It is a measure of the personal likelihood or risk of having a fatal or a non-fatal occupational injury for each worker in the reference group. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of occupational injuries expressed per a given number of workers in the reference group is also known as the incidence rate of occupational injuries &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitions of the main concepts presented below are derived from the Resolution concerning statistics of occupational injuries (resulting from occupational accidents), adopted by the 16th ICLS in 1998 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutions-adopted-byinternational-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_087528/lang--en/index.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutions-adopted-byinternational-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_087528/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occupational accident: an unexpected and unplanned occurrence, including acts of violence, arising out of or in connection with work which results in one or more workers incurring a personal injury, disease or death. Occupational accidents are to be considered travel, transport or road traffic accidents in which workers are injured and which arise out of or in the course of work; that is, while engaged in an economic activity, or at work, or carrying out the business of the employer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occupational injury: any personal injury, disease or death resulting from an occupational accident. An occupational injury is different from an occupational disease, which comes as a result of an exposure over a period of time to risk factors linked to the work activity. Diseases are included only in cases where the disease arose as a direct result of an accident. An occupational injury can be fatal or non-fatal (and non-fatal injuries could entail the loss of work days). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fatal occupational injury: an occupational injury leading to death within one year of the day of the occupational accident. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Case of occupational injury: the case of one worker incurring one or more occupational injuries as a result of one occupational accident. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workers in the reference group: workers in the reference group refer to the average number of workers in the particular group under consideration and who are covered by the source of the statistics on occupational injuries (for example, those of a specific sex or in a specific economic activity, occupation, region, age group, or any combination of these, or those covered by a particular insurance scheme, accident notification systems, or household or establishment survey). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ratio of cases per 100&amp;#x2019;000 workers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Migrant status is determined according to country of birth (native-born or foreign-born) or country of citizenship (citizen or non-citizen). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The recommended data sources are different types of administrative records, such as records of national systems for the notification of occupational injuries (labour inspection records and annual reports; insurance and compensation records, death registers), supplemented by household surveys (especially in order to cover informal sector enterprises and the self-employed) and/or establishment surveys. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The metadata should clearly specify (i) whether the statistics relate to cases of occupational injury which have been reported (to an accident notification system or to an accident compensation scheme), compensated (by an accident insurance scheme) or identified in some other way (for example through a survey of households or establishments) and (ii) whether cases of occupational disease and cases of injury due to commuting accidents are excluded from the statistics, as recommended. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ILO Department of Statistics processes national household survey microdatasets in line with internationally-agreed indicator concepts and definitions set forth by the International Conference of Labour Statisticians. For data that could not be obtained through this processing or directly from government websites, the ILO sends out an annual ILOSTAT questionnaire to all relevant agencies within each country (national statistical office, labour ministry, etc.) requesting the latest annual data and any revisions on numerous labour market topics and indicators, including many SDG indicators. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuous&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuous&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Labour ministries, labour inspection, national insurance, and/or national statistical offices &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;ILO &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ILO is the UN focal point for labour statistics. It sets international standards for labour statistics through the International Conference of Labour Statisticians. It also compiles and produces labour statistics with the goal of disseminating internationally-comparable datasets, and provides technical assistance and training to ILO member States to support their efforts to produce high quality labour market data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This indicator provides valuable information that could be used to formulate policies and programmes for the prevention of occupational injuries, diseases and deaths. It could also be used to monitor the implementation of these programmes and to signal particular areas of increasing risk such as a particular occupation, industry or location. Although the principal objective of this indicator is to provide information for prevention purposes, it may be used for a number of other purposes, such as to identify the occupations and economic activities with the highest risk of occupational injuries; to detect changes in the pattern and occurrence of occupational injuries, so as to monitor improvements in safety and reveal any new areas of risk; to inform employers, employers&amp;#x2019; organizations, workers and workers&amp;#x2019; organizations of the risks associated with their work and workplaces, so that they can take an active part in their own safety; to evaluate the effectiveness of preventive measures; to estimate the consequences of occupational injuries, particularly in terms of days lost or costs; and to provide a basis for policymaking aimed at encouraging employers, employers&amp;#x2019; organizations, workers and workers&amp;#x2019; organizations to introduce accident prevention measures. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There may be problems of under reporting of occupational injuries, and proper systems should be put in place to ensure the best reporting and data quality. Under reporting is thought to be present in countries at all levels of development, but may be particularly problematic in some developing countries. Data users should be aware of this issue when analysing the data. Double-counting of cases of occupational injury may also happen in cases where data from several registries (records kept by different agencies, for example) are consolidated to have more comprehensive statistics. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because data quality issues may be present, it may be more relevant to analyse indicator trends rather than levels. When measured over a period of time, the data can reveal progress or deterioration in occupational safety and health, and thus point to the effectiveness of prevention measures. This indicator is volatile and strong annual fluctuations may occur due to unexpected but significant accidents or national calamities. The underlying trend should therefore be analysed. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The incidence rates of fatal and non-fatal occupational injuries will be calculated separately, since statistics on fatal injuries tend to come from a different source than those on non-fatal injuries, which would make their sum into total occupational accidents inaccurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fatal occupational injury incidence rate is expressed per 100,000 workers in the reference group, and thus, is calculated as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;F&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;j&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;y&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;w&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;j&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;y&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;g&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;y&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;W&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;k&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;g&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;g&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;y&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;&amp;#xD7;&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;100&lt;/mn&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;,&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;000&lt;/mn&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the non-fatal occupational injury incidence rate is calculated as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;j&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;y&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;=&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;N&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;w&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;j&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;y&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;g&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;y&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;W&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;k&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;g&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;p&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;g&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;y&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi mathvariant=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
    &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;&amp;#xD7;&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;100&lt;/mn&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;,&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;000&lt;/mn&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In calculating the average number of workers, the number of part-time workers should be converted to full-time equivalents. For the calculation of rates, the numerator and the denominator should have the same coverage. For example, if self-employed persons are not covered by the source of statistics on fatal occupational injuries, they should also be taken out of the denominator. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ILO engages in annual consultations with member States through the ILOSTAT questionnaire and related Statistics Reporting System (StaRS). National data providers receive a link to the portal where they can review all national SDG data available on ILOSTAT.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This indicator could come from a variety of sources at the national level, including various kinds of administrative records (insurance records, labour inspection records, etc.), household surveys and establishment surveys. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ILO Guidebook - Decent Work and the Sustainable Development Goals: A Guidebook on SDG Labour Market Indicators (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ILO Manual &amp;#x2013; Decent Work Indicators, Concepts and Definitions &amp;#x2013; Chapter 8, Safe work environment &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/integration/resources/pubs/WCMS_229374/lang--%20en/index.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://www.ilo.org/integration/resources/pubs/WCMS_229374/lang-- en/index.htm&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (second version, page 156) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resolution concerning statistics of occupational injuries (resulting from occupational accidents) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutionsadopted-by-international-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_087528/lang--en/index.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutionsadopted-by-international-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_087528/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Global database on occupational safety and health legislation &amp;#x2013; LEGOSH &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/safework/info/publications/WCMS_217849/lang--en/index.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://www.ilo.org/safework/info/publications/WCMS_217849/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Occupational injuries statistics from household surveys and establishment surveys &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_173153/lang--en/index.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_173153/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ILOSTAT (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ILOSTAT Metadata &amp;#x2013; Indicator descriptions (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/resources/methods/description-occupational-injuries/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/resources/methods/description-occupational-injuries/&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data consistency and quality checks are regularly conducted for validation of the data before dissemination in the ILOSTAT database. . &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data for this indicator is available for 87 countries and territories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The submission covers data from 2000 to 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator should be disaggregated by both sex and migrant status. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wherever possible, it would also be useful to have information disaggregated by economic activity and occupation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The variety of possible sources of data on occupational injuries hinders the comparability of data across countries since each type of source provides information on different specific concepts. Data derived from administrative records are not strictly comparable since they include numerous types of records that follow different rules and are maintained by different agencies. Two main sources of data are records of notifications by employers to the competent authority and insurance records of the authority compensating the victims. These two would clearly yield different results, since it is possible that not all injuries that were compensated to workers were reported by the employer and vice versa. It is also possible that these records have a different geographical coverage or that they cover different economic activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When statistics come from an establishment survey, the results would be closer to those from records of notifications made by employers since it is also the employer who provides the establishment survey information. However, establishment surveys tend not to cover the informal sector, establishments of a very small size and sometimes the agricultural sector. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When statistics come from a household survey, their reliability depends heavily on the accuracy of the respondents, who may be subjective in the information given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ILO Guidebook - Decent Work and the Sustainable Development Goals: A Guidebook on SDG Labour Market Indicators (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://www.ilo.org/stat/Publications/WCMS_647109/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; ) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ILOSTAT database: https://ilostat.ilo.org &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ILOSTAT Metadata &amp;#x2013; Indicator Descriptions (&lt;a href=&quot;https://ilostat.ilo.org/resources/methods/description-occupational-injuries/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;https://ilostat.ilo.org/resources/methods/description-occupational-injuries/&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decent Work Indicators Manual: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---stat/documents/publication/wcms_223121.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://www.ilo.org/wcmsp5/groups/public/---dgreports/---stat/documents/publication/wcms_223121.pdf&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Resolution concerning statistics of occupational injuries (resulting from occupational accidents) adopted by the 16th ICLS in 1998: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutions-adopted-byinternational-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_087528/lang--en/index.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://www.ilo.org/global/statistics-and-databases/standards-and-guidelines/resolutions-adopted-byinternational-conferences-of-labour-statisticians/WCMS_087528/lang--en/index.htm&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Janvier 2021&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organisation internationale du travail (OIT)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;OIT&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continu&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L&apos;OIT est le point focal des Nations Unies pour les statistiques du travail. Elle établit des normes internationales pour les statistiques du travail par le biais de la Conférence internationale des statisticiens du travail. Elle compile et produit également des statistiques du travail dans le but de diffuser des ensembles de données comparables au niveau international, et fournit une assistance technique et une formation aux états membres de l&apos;OIT afin de soutenir leurs efforts pour produire des données sur le marché du travail de haute qualité. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;L&apos;OIT procède à des consultations annuelles avec les Etats membres par le biais du questionnaire d&apos;ILOSTAT et du système connexe de rapports statistiques (Statistics Reporting System (StaRS)). Les fournisseurs de données nationaux reçoivent un lien vers le portail où ils peuvent examiner toutes les données nationales sur les ODD disponibles dans ILOSTAT.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sans objet.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
