<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>All metadata fields for indicator 9-3-2, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar">اخر تحديث
			</language>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;Goal 9: Build resilient infrastructure, promote inclusive and sustainable industrialization and foster innovation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target 9.3: Increase the access of small-scale industrial and other enterprises, in particular in developing countries, to financial services, including affordable credit, and their integration into value chains and markets&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicator 9.3.2: Proportion of small-scale industries with a loan or line of credit&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Proportion of small-scale industries with a loan or line of credit (%)&lt;/p&gt;2022-03-31&lt;p&gt;9.3.1: Proportion of small-scale industries in total industry value added&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;United Nations Industrial Development Organization (UNIDO)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World Bank&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;United Nations Industrial Development Organization (UNIDO)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World Bank&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definitions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-2&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small-scale industrial enterprises, in the SDG framework also called &amp;#x201C;small-scale industries&amp;#x201D;, defined here for the purpose of statistical data collection and compilation refer to statistical units, generally enterprises, engaged in production of goods and services for market below a designated size class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This indicator shows the number of &amp;#x201C;small-scale industries&amp;#x201D; with an active line of credit or a loan from a financial institution in the reference year in percentage to the total number of such enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International recommendations for industrial statistics 2008 (IRIS 2008) (United Nations, 2011) define an &lt;strong&gt;enterprise&lt;/strong&gt; as the smallest legal unit that constitutes an organizational unit producing goods or services. The enterprise is the basic statistical unit at which all information relating to its production activities and transactions, including financial and balance-sheet accounts, are maintained. It is also used for institutional sector classification in the 2008 System of National Accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An &lt;strong&gt;establishment&lt;/strong&gt; is defined as an enterprise or part of an enterprise that is situated in a single location and in which only a single productive activity is carried out or in which the principal productive activity accounts for most of the value added. An establishment can be defined ideally as an economic unit that engages, under single ownership or control, that is, under a single legal entity, in one, or predominantly one, kind of economic activity at a single physical location. Mines, factories and workshops are examples. This ideal concept of an establishment is applicable to many of the situations encountered in industrial inquiries, particularly in manufacturing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the definition of an establishment allows for the possibility that there may be one or more secondary activities carried out in it, their magnitude should be small compared with that of the principal activity. If a secondary activity within an establishment is as important, or nearly as important, as the principal activity, then the unit is more like a local unit. It should be subdivided so that the secondary activity is treated as taking place within an establishment separate from the establishment in which the principal activity takes place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of most &lt;strong&gt;small-sized businesses&lt;/strong&gt;, the enterprise and the establishment will be identical. Some enterprises are large and complex with different kinds of economic activities undertaken at different locations. Such enterprises should be broken down into one or more establishments, provided that smaller and more homogeneous production units can be identified for which production data may be meaningfully compiled. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As introduced in IRIS 2008 (United Nations, 2011), an &lt;strong&gt;economic activity&lt;/strong&gt; is understood as referring to a process, that is , the combination of actions carried out by a certain entity that uses labor, capital, goods and services to produce specific products (goods and services). In general, industrial statistics reflect the characteristics and economic activities of units engaged in a class of industrial activities that are defined in terms of the International Standard Industrial Classification of All Economic Activities, Revision 4 (ISIC Rev.4) (United Nations, 2008) or International Standard Industrial Classification of All Economic Activities, Revision 3.1 (ISIC Rev. 3) (United Nations, 2002).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total numbers of persons employed&lt;/strong&gt; is defined as the total number of persons who work in or for the statistical unit, whether full-time or part-time, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Working proprietors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Active business partners&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unpaid family workers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paid employees (for more details see United Nations, 2011).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The size of a statistical unit based on employment should be defined primarily in terms of the average number of persons employed in that unit during the reference period. If the average number of persons employed is not available, the total number of persons employed in a single period may be used as the size criterion. The size classification should consist of the following classes of the average number of persons employed: 1-9, 10-19, 20-49, 50-249, 250 and more. This should be considered a minimum division of the overall range; more detailed classifications, where required, should be developed within this framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;loan&lt;/strong&gt; is a financial instrument that is created when a creditor lends funds directly to a debtor and receives a non-negotiable document as evidence of the asset. This category includes overdrafts, mortgage loans, loans to finance trade credit and advances, repurchase agreements, financial assets and liabilities created by financial leases, and claims on or liabilities to the International Monetary Fund (IMF) in the form of loans. Trade credit and advances and similar accounts payable/receivable are not loans. Loans that have become marketable in secondary markets should be reclassified under debt securities. However, if only traded occasionally, the loan is not reclassified under debt securities (IMF, 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lines of credit&lt;/strong&gt; and loan commitments provide a guarantee that undrawn funds will be available in the future, but no financial liability/asset exists until such funds are provided. Undrawn lines of credit and undisbursed loan commitments are contingent liabilities of the issuing institutions&amp;#x2014; generally, banks (IMF, 2011). A loan or line of credit refers to regulated financial institutions only.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-2&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Some of the text on concepts and definition may be identical to Metadata submitted for Indicators 9.3.1. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-2&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Percent (%)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/seriesm/seriesm_4rev4e.pdf&quot;&gt;International Standard Industrial Classification of all Economic Activities (ISIC) Revision 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/seriesm/seriesm_4rev3_1e.pdf&quot;&gt;International Standard Industrial Classification of all Economic Activities (ISIC) Revision 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data were collected from the World Bank Enterprise Surveys as a pilot study on this indicator, however the preferable source of data are national statistical offices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the main sources of data for this indicator currently available is the Enterprise Survey conducted by the World Bank (www.enterprisesurveys.org), which covers the formal sector and contains data for small and medium enterprises only (with 5 or more employees). In some countries, additional surveys, including Informal Surveys of unregistered enterprises and/or Micro Surveys for registered firms with less than five employees, are conducted and available at country level. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Enterprise Survey is based on a representative sample of enterprises run by the private sector. The surveys cover a broad range of business environment topics including access to finance, corruption, infrastructure, crime, competition, and performance measures. Since 2002, the World Bank has collected these data from face-to-face interviews with top managers and business owners in over 174,000 companies in 151 economies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The surveys have been conducted since 2002 by different units within the World Bank. Since 2005-06, most data collection efforts have been centralized within the Enterprise Analysis Unit. Data from 2006 onward is comparable across countries. The raw individual country datasets, aggregated datasets (across countries and years), panel datasets, and all relevant survey documentation are publicly available on the Enterprise Surveys web site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator uses a simple weighted percentage formula, where the weights are the sampling weights. The strata for Enterprise Surveys are firm size, business sector, and geographic region within a country. Enterprise Surveys provide indicators covering manufacturing and services activities. Proportion of &amp;#x201C;small-scale industries&amp;#x201D; with a loan or line of credit for manufacturing only can be extracted from the micro data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enterprises are classified as small, medium or large based on the number of employees as follows: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;Size of enterprise&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;Number of employees&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Small&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;5 to 19 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Medium&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;20 to 99 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Large&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;more than 99&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey also defines an enterprise with female ownership as an enterprise having at least one female owner, and female-managed is measured by whether the top manager is a woman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data are collected through the World Bank Enterprise Surveys conducted in countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The data are regularly updated on the World Bank Enterprise Surveys website. The Enterprise Surveys are implemented every year in around 20 countries. Data frequency for each country is around 4 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UNIDO SDG-9 database is updated between March and April every year including the 9.3.2 indicator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;World Bank Enterprise Surveys&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;United Nations Industrial Development Organization (UNIDO)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World Bank Enterprise Surveys&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;UNIDO, as the specialized UN agency on industrial development, has the international mandate for collecting, producing and disseminating internationally comparable industrial statistics. UNIDO&amp;#x2019;s mandate covers (i) the maintenance and updating of international industrial statistics databases; (ii) methodological and analytical products based on statistical research and experience of maintaining internationally comparable statistics; (iii) contributions to the development and implementation of international statistical standards and methodology; and (iv) technical cooperation services to countries in the field of industrial statistics. With the repositioning of UNIDO as the focal agency for inclusive and sustainable industrial development (ISID), its statistical mandate was expanded to cover all dimensions of industrial development, including its inclusiveness and environmental sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Industrial enterprises are classified to small compared to large or medium for their distinct nature of economic organization, production capability, scale of investment and other economic characteristics. &amp;#x201C;Small-scale industries&amp;#x201D; can be run with a small amount of capital, relatively unskilled labor and using local materials. Despite their small contribution to total industrial output, their role in job creation, especially in developing countries is recognized to be significant where the scope of absorbing surplus labor force from traditional sectors such as agriculture or fishery is very high. &amp;#x201C;Small-scale industries&amp;#x201D; are capable of meeting domestic demand of basic consumer goods such as food, clothes, furniture, etc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus &amp;#x201C;small-scale industries&amp;#x201D; play an important role in the economy. However, it has quite limited access to financial services, especially in developing countries. In order to improve the skill of workers and technology for production, small-scale industrial enterprises require financial support in the form of preferential loan, credit etc. This indicator shows how widely financial institutions are serving the &amp;#x201C;small-scale industries&amp;#x201D;. Together with the indicator SDG 9.3.1, this indicator reflects the main message of the target 9.3 which seeks to increase the access of &amp;#x201C;small-scale industries&amp;#x201D; to financial services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main limitation of existing national data is varying size classes by country indicating that data are obtained from different target populations. Data of one country are not comparable to another. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The definition of size class in many countries is tied up with the legal and policy framework of the country. It has implications on registration procedure, taxation and different waivers aimed to promote &amp;#x201C;small-scale industries&amp;#x201D;. Therefore, countries may agree on a common size class for compilation purposes. In this context, UNIDO proposes that all countries compile the data by a size class of &amp;#x201C;small-scale industries&amp;#x201D; as with less than 20 persons employed. From such data, an internationally comparable data on the share of &amp;#x201C;small-scale industries&amp;#x201D; in total could be derived.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The proportion of &amp;#x201C;small-scale industries&amp;#x201D; with a loan or line of credit is calculated as the number of &amp;#x201C;small-scale industries&amp;#x201D; with an active line of credit or a loan from a financial institution in the reference year in percentage to the total number of such enterprises:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;math xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML&quot;&gt;
    &lt;mfrac&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;m&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;b&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;m&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;-&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;w&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;h&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
      &lt;mrow&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;T&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;m&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;b&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;o&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;f&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;m&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;-&lt;/mo&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;c&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;a&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;l&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;n&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;d&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;u&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;t&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;r&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;i&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;e&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mi&gt;s&lt;/mi&gt;
        &lt;mo&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/mo&gt;
      &lt;/mrow&gt;
    &lt;/mfrac&gt;
    &lt;mo&gt;&amp;#xD7;&lt;/mo&gt;
    &lt;mn&gt;100&lt;/mn&gt;
  &lt;/math&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indicator is calculated as a share of small-scale manufacturing enterprises with a loan or line of credit in the total number of small-scale manufacturing enterprises. Calculation of the indicator can be extended for other economic activities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This indicator is computed using data collected from the World Bank&amp;#x2019;s Enterprise Surveys. A detailed manual and guide on the Enterprise Surveys implementation is found here (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.enterprisesurveys.org/content/dam/enterprisesurveys/documents/methodology/Enterprise-Surveys-Manual-and-Guide.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.enterprisesurveys.org/content/dam/enterprisesurveys/documents/methodology/Enterprise-Surveys-Manual-and-Guide.pdf&lt;/a&gt;). Section 4.4 &amp;#x201C;Data Collection Cycle&amp;#x201D; of this document describes the processes in place used to validate or check the survey data which is collected to ensure quality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For any given survey, during the quality checks outlined in the Enterprise Surveys manual and guide (section 4.4), if inconsistencies or mistakes are found in the data, the World Bank transmits this feedback to the fieldwork team that is conducting the survey in the first place. The fieldwork team should make sure that any data mistakes are corrected (or if the data is indeed correct, provide the justification to the World Bank) when submitting the final survey dataset.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;At country level&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No treatment of missing values is applied at country level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#x2022;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;At regional and global levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No treatment of missing values is applied at regional and global levels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Enterprise Surveys are implemented every year in around 20 countries. Data frequency is limited for each country around 4 years. Regional and global averages are thus computed by taking a simple average of country-level point estimates. For each economy, only the latest available year of survey data is used in this computation. Only surveys adhering to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.enterprisesurveys.org/content/dam/enterprisesurveys/documents/methodology/ES_QuestionnaireManual_2019.pdf&quot;&gt;Enterprise Surveys Global Methodology&lt;/a&gt; are used to compute these regional and global aggregates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;International Recommendations for Industrial Statistics. (2008).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/seriesM/seriesm_90e.pdf&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/seriesM/seriesm_90e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International Standard Industrial Classification of All Economic Activities (ISIC). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/classifications/Econ/isic&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/classifications/Econ/isic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International Monetary Fund. (2011). Public Sector Debt Statistics: Guide for Compilers and Users. Washington, DC: International Monetary Fund. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elibrary.imf.org/view/IMF069/11874-9781616351564/11874-9781616351564/front.xml?language=en&amp;amp;redirect=true&quot;&gt;https://www.elibrary.imf.org/view/IMF069/11874-9781616351564/11874-9781616351564/front.xml?language=en&amp;amp;redirect=true&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World Bank Enterprise Surveys methodology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.enterprisesurveys.org/en/methodology&quot;&gt;https://www.enterprisesurveys.org/en/methodology&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A detailed manual and guide on the Enterprise Surveys implementation is found here (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.enterprisesurveys.org/content/dam/enterprisesurveys/documents/methodology/Enterprise-Surveys-Manual-and-Guide.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.enterprisesurveys.org/content/dam/enterprisesurveys/documents/methodology/Enterprise-Surveys-Manual-and-Guide.pdf&lt;/a&gt;). This manual provides a comprehensive overview of the quality management of the Enterprise Surveys.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The process of quality assurance includes the review of survey questionnaires/documentations/metadata, examination of reliability of data, and making sure they comply with international standards (e.g. workforce concepts in the survey questions correspond to ILO standards), and examining the consistency and coherence within the data set as well as with the time series of data and the resulting indicators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UNIDO quality assurance framework is followed to check data quality and consistency before data dissemination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UNIDO (2009). UNIDO Data Quality: A quality assurance framework for UNIDO statistical activities &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.unido.org/api/documents/4814740/download/UNIDO-Publication-2009-4814740&quot;&gt;https://open.unido.org/api/documents/4814740/download/UNIDO-Publication-2009-4814740&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For any given survey, quality checks outlined in the Enterprise Surveys manual and guide (section 4.4), are implemented during data collection (survey fieldwork), and the World Bank transmits the resulting feedback to the fieldwork team that is conducting the survey in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data availability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data for around 150 economies were collected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time series:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surveys are implemented every year in around 20 countries. Data frequency for each country is around 4 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaggregation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No disaggregation available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sources of discrepancies:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discrepancies might arise due to the natural evolution of questionnaire design and survey methodology over time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;URL:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.enterprisesurveys.org/&quot;&gt;https://www.enterprisesurveys.org/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unido.org/statistics&quot;&gt;www.unido.org/statistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stat.unido.org/&quot;&gt;https://stat.unido.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;International Monetary Fund. (2011). Public Sector Debt Statistics: Guide for Compilers and Users. Washington, DC: International Monetary Fund. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elibrary.imf.org/view/IMF069/11874-9781616351564/11874-9781616351564/front.xml?language=en&amp;amp;redirect=true&quot;&gt;https://www.elibrary.imf.org/view/IMF069/11874-9781616351564/11874-9781616351564/front.xml?language=en&amp;amp;redirect=true&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations. (2002). International Standard Industrial Classification of All Economic Activities (ISIC Revision 4). New York: United Nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/seriesm/seriesm_4rev4e.pdf&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/seriesm/seriesm_4rev4e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations. (2008). International Standard Industrial Classification of All Economic Activities (ISIC Revision 3.1). New York: United Nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/SeriesM/seriesm_4rev3_1e.pdf&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/SeriesM/seriesm_4rev3_1e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Nations. (2011). International Recommendations for Industrial Statistics 2008 (IRIS 2008), New York: United Nations. &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.18356/677c08dd-en&quot;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.18356/677c08dd-en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World Bank Enterprise Surveys. 2020. Methodology. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.enterprisesurveys.org/methodology&quot;&gt;http://www.enterprisesurveys.org/methodology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;p&gt;Objetivo 9: Construir infraestructuras resilientes, promover la industrialización inclusiva y sostenible y fomentar la innovación&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meta 9.3: Aumentar el acceso de las pequeñas industrias y otras empresas, particularmente en los países en desarrollo, a los servicios financieros, incluidos créditos asequibles, y su integración en las cadenas de valor y los mercados&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicador 9.3.2: Proporción de las pequeñas industrias que han obtenido un préstamo o una línea de crédito&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Febrero de 2021 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Información institucional &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Organización (es): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Organización de las Naciones Unidas para el Desarrollo Industrial (ONUDI) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Conceptos y definiciones&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Definition:&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-1&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Las empresas industriales de pequeña escala&lt;/strong&gt;, en el marco de los ODS también denominadas &amp;#x201C;&lt;strong&gt;industrias de pequeña escala&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#x201D;, definidas aquí a efectos de la recolección y compilación de datos estadísticos, se refieren a unidades estadísticas, generalmente empresas, dedicadas a la producción de bienes y servicios para el mercado por debajo de una clase de tamaño designada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Este indicador muestra el número de &amp;#x201C;pequeñas industrias&amp;#x201D; con una línea de crédito activa o un préstamo de una institución financiera en el año de referencia en porcentaje del número total de dichas empresas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conceptos:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las recomendaciones internacionales para las estadísticas industriales 2008 (IRIS 2008) (Naciones Unidas, 2011) definen una &lt;strong&gt;empresa&lt;/strong&gt; como la unidad legal más pequeña que constituye una unidad organizativa que produce bienes o servicios. La empresa es la unidad estadística básica en la que se mantiene toda la información relativa a sus actividades y transacciones de producción, incluidas las cuentas financieras y de balance. También se utiliza para la clasificación del sector institucional en el Sistema de Cuentas Nacionales de 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Un &lt;strong&gt;establecimiento&lt;/strong&gt; se define como una empresa o parte de una empresa que está situada en un solo lugar y en la que se realiza una sola actividad productiva o en la que la actividad productiva principal representa la mayor parte del valor agregado. Un establecimiento puede definirse idealmente como una unidad económica que se dedica, bajo una única propiedad o control, es decir, bajo una única entidad jurídica, a un tipo de actividad económica, o a una actividad predominante, en un único emplazamiento físico. Las minas, las fábricas y los talleres son ejemplos de ello. Este concepto ideal de establecimiento es aplicable a muchas de las situaciones que se dan en las investigaciones industriales, especialmente en la industria manufacturera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aunque la definición de establecimiento admite la posibilidad de que en él se desarrollen una o varias actividades secundarias, su magnitud debe ser pequeña en comparación con la de la actividad principal. Si una actividad secundaria dentro de un establecimiento es tan importante, o casi tan importante, como la actividad principal, entonces la unidad es más bien una unidad local. Debe subdividirse de modo que la actividad secundaria se trate como si tuviera lugar dentro de un establecimiento distinto del establecimiento en el que se desarrolla la actividad principal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En el caso de la mayoría de las &lt;strong&gt;pequeñas empresas&lt;/strong&gt;, la empresa y el establecimiento serán idénticos. Algunas empresas son grandes y complejas, con diferentes tipos de actividades económicas realizadas en diferentes lugares. Dichas empresas deben desglosarse en uno o varios establecimientos, siempre que puedan identificarse unidades de producción más pequeñas y homogéneas para las que puedan recopilarse datos de producción de forma significativa. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tal y como se introduce en IRIS 2008 (Naciones Unidas, 2011), se entiende que una &lt;strong&gt;actividad económica&lt;/strong&gt; se refiere a un proceso, es decir, a la combinación de acciones llevadas a cabo por una determinada entidad que utiliza mano de obra, capital, bienes y servicios para producir productos específicos (bienes y servicios). En general, las estadísticas industriales reflejan las características y actividades económicas de las unidades dedicadas a una clase de actividades industriales que se definen en términos de la Clasificación Industrial Internacional Uniforme de Todas las Actividades Económicas, Revisión 4 (CIIU Rev.4) (Naciones Unidas, 2008) o de la Clasificación Industrial Internacional Uniforme de Todas las Actividades Económicas, Revisión 3.1 (CIIU Rev. 3) (Naciones Unidas, 2002).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;El número total de personas empleadas&lt;/strong&gt; se define como el número total de personas que trabajan en o para la unidad estadística, ya sea a tiempo completo o parcial, incluyendo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Propietarios activos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Socios comerciales activos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trabajadores familiares no remunerados&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Asalariados (para más detalles, véase Naciones Unidas, 2011)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El tamaño de una unidad estadística basada en el empleo debería definirse principalmente en términos del número medio de personas empleadas en esa unidad durante el período de referencia. Si no se dispone del número medio de personas empleadas, puede utilizarse como criterio de tamaño el número total de personas empleadas en un solo período. La clasificación por tamaños debe consistir en las siguientes clases del número medio de personas empleadas: 1-9, 10-19, 20-49, 50-249, 250 y más. Esto debe considerarse como una división mínima de la gama global; dentro de este marco deben desarrollarse clasificaciones más detalladas, cuando sea necesario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Un &lt;strong&gt;préstamo&lt;/strong&gt; es un instrumento financiero que se crea cuando un acreedor presta fondos directamente a un deudor y recibe un documento no negociable como prueba del activo. Esta categoría incluye los descubiertos, los préstamos hipotecarios, los préstamos para financiar créditos y anticipos comerciales, los acuerdos de recompra, los activos y pasivos financieros creados por los arrendamientos financieros y los créditos o pasivos frente al Fondo Monetario Internacional (FMI) en forma de préstamos. Los créditos y anticipos comerciales y las cuentas por pagar/deudoras similares no son préstamos. Los préstamos que se han convertido en negociables en los mercados secundarios deben reclasificarse en títulos de deuda. Sin embargo, si sólo se negocian ocasionalmente, el préstamo no se reclasifica en títulos de deuda (FMI, 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Las líneas de crédito&lt;/strong&gt; y los compromisos de préstamo proporcionan una garantía de que los fondos no dispuestos estarán disponibles en el futuro, pero no existe ningún pasivo/activo financiero hasta que dichos fondos se proporcionen realmente. Las líneas de crédito no dispuestas y los compromisos de préstamo no desembolsados son pasivos contingentes de las instituciones emisoras&amp;#x2014; generalmente, los bancos (FMI, 2011). Un préstamo o línea de crédito se refiere únicamente a las instituciones financieras reguladas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;p&gt; Parte del texto sobre los conceptos y la definición puede ser idéntico a los metadatos presentados para los indicadores 9.3.1. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fuentes de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los datos se recogen de las Encuestas de Empresas del Banco Mundial como estudio piloto sobre este indicador, aunque la fuente de datos preferible son las oficinas nacionales de estadística.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Proceso de recolección:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Una de las principales fuentes de datos para este indicador disponible en la actualidad es la Encuesta de Empresas realizada por el Banco Mundial, que cubre el sector formal y contiene datos sólo para las pequeñas y medianas empresas (con 5 o más empleados). En algunos países, se realizan encuestas adicionales, incluidas las encuestas informales de empresas no registradas y/o las microencuestas para empresas registradas con menos de cinco empleados, que están disponibles a nivel nacional. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Encuesta de Empresas se basa en una muestra representativa de las empresas del sector privado. Las encuestas cubren una amplia gama de temas relacionados con el entorno empresarial, como el acceso a la financiación, la corrupción, las infraestructuras, la delincuencia, la competencia y las medidas de rendimiento. Desde 2002, el Banco Mundial ha recopilado estos datos a partir de entrevistas cara a cara con altos directivos y propietarios de empresas en más de 130.000 empresas de 135 economías.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las encuestas han sido realizadas desde 2002 por diferentes unidades del Banco Mundial. Desde 2005-06, la mayor parte de los esfuerzos de recopilación de datos se han centralizado en la Unidad de Análisis Empresarial. Los datos a partir de 2006 son comparables entre países. Los conjuntos de datos brutos de cada país, los conjuntos de datos agregados (entre países y años), los conjuntos de datos de panel y toda la documentación pertinente de la encuesta están disponibles públicamente en el sitio web de Enterprise Surveys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador utiliza una fórmula porcentual ponderada simple, en la que las ponderaciones son las ponderaciones de muestreo. Los estratos de las Encuestas de Empresa son el tamaño de la empresa, el sector empresarial y la región geográfica dentro de un país. Las encuestas de empresas proporcionan indicadores que cubren las actividades de fabricación y de servicios. De los microdatos se puede extraer la proporción de &amp;#x201C;pequeñas industrias&amp;#x201D; con un préstamo o una línea de crédito sólo para la fabricación.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las empresas se clasifican como pequeñas, medianas o grandes en función del número de empleados, de la siguiente manera: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;Tamaño de la empresa&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt; Número de empleados &lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Pequeño&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;5 a 19 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Medio&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;20 a 99 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Grande&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;más de 99&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La encuesta también define la empresa con propiedad femenina como aquella que tiene al menos una propietaria, y la gestión femenina se mide por el hecho de que el máximo responsable sea una mujer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Proveedores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Encuestas empresariales del Banco Mundial&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Compiladores de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Organización de las Naciones Unidas para el Desarrollo Industrial (ONUDI)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Justificación:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las empresas industriales se clasifican en pequeñas en comparación con las grandes o medianas por su distinta naturaleza de organización económica, capacidad de producción, escala de inversión y otras características económicas. &amp;#x201C;Las industrias de pequeña escala&amp;#x201D; pueden funcionar con una pequeña cantidad de capital, mano de obra relativamente no cualificada y utilizando materiales locales. A pesar de su pequeña contribución a la producción industrial total, se reconoce que su papel en la creación de empleo, especialmente en los países en desarrollo, es significativo cuando el margen de absorción de la mano de obra excedente de sectores tradicionales como la agricultura o la pesca es muy alto. &amp;#x201C;Las pequeñas industrias&amp;#x201D; son capaces de satisfacer la demanda interna de bienes de consumo básicos como alimentos, ropa, muebles, etc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Así pues, &amp;#x201C;la pequeña industria&amp;#x201D; desempeña un papel importante en la economía. Sin embargo, tiene un acceso bastante limitado a los servicios financieros, especialmente en los países en desarrollo. Para mejorar la cualificación de los trabajadores y la tecnología de producción, las pequeñas empresas industriales necesitan apoyo financiero en forma de préstamo preferente, crédito, etc. Este indicador muestra la amplitud con la que las instituciones financieras atienden a las &amp;#x201C;pequeñas industrias&amp;#x201D;. Junto con el indicador ODS 9.3.1, este indicador refleja el mensaje principal de la meta 9.3 que promueve aumentar el acceso de las &amp;#x201C;pequeñas industrias&amp;#x201D; a los servicios financieros.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Comentarios y limitaciones:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La principal limitación de los datos nacionales existentes es que las clases de tamaño varían según el país, lo que indica que los datos se obtienen de diferentes poblaciones objetivo. Los datos de un país no son comparables con los de otro. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La definición de clase de tamaño en muchos países está vinculada al marco legal y político del país. Tiene implicaciones en el procedimiento de registro, en la fiscalidad y en las diferentes exenciones destinadas a promover las &amp;#x201C;pequeñas industrias&amp;#x201D;. Por lo tanto, los países pueden acordar una clase de tamaño común a efectos de compilación. En este contexto, la ONUDI propone que todos los países recopilen los datos por una clase de tamaño de &amp;#x201C;pequeñas industrias&amp;#x201D; como con menos de 20 personas empleadas. A partir de estos datos, se podría derivar un dato internacionalmente comparable sobre la proporción de &amp;#x201C;pequeñas industrias&amp;#x201D; en el total. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Metodología&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Método del cálculo:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La proporción de &amp;#x201C;industrias de pequeña escala&amp;#x201D; con un préstamo o línea de crédito se calcula como el número de &amp;#x201C;industrias de pequeña escala&amp;#x201D; con una línea de crédito activa o un préstamo de una institución financiera en el año de referencia en porcentaje del número total de dichas empresas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(el número de &amp;#x201C;industrias de pequeña escala&amp;#x201D; con préstamo o línea de crédito/número total de &amp;#x201C;industrias de pequeña escala&amp;#x201D;) * 100&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El indicador se calcula como una proporción de pequeñas empresas manufactureras con un préstamo o línea de crédito en el número total de pequeñas empresas manufactureras. El cálculo del indicador puede extenderse a otras actividades económicas. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Disponibilidad de datos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Descripción:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Se han recolectado datos de unas 130 economías.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#xA0;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Series temporales:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Las encuestas se realizan cada año en unos 20 países. La frecuencia de los datos de cada país es de unos 4 años.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fondo Monetario Internacional. (2011). Estadísticas de la deuda del sector público: Guía para compiladores y usuarios. Washington, DC: Fondo Monetario Internacional. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tffs.org/pdf/method/2013/psds2013.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.tffs.org/pdf/method/2013/psds2013.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naciones Unidas. (2002). Clasificación Industrial Internacional Uniforme de Todas las Actividades Económicas (CIIU Revisión 4). Nueva York : Naciones Unidas. &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/seriesm/seriesm_4rev4e.pdf&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/seriesm/seriesm_4rev4e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naciones Unidas. (2008). Clasificación Industrial Internacional Uniforme de Todas las Actividades Económicas (CIIU Revisión 3.1). Nueva York : Naciones Unidas. &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/SeriesM/seriesm_4rev3_1e.pdf&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/SeriesM/seriesm_4rev3_1e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naciones Unidas. (2011). Recomendaciones internacionales para las estadísticas industriales 2008 (IRIS 2008), Nueva York: Naciones Unidas. &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.18356/677c08dd-en&quot;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.18356/677c08dd-en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Encuestas de empresas del Banco Mundial. 2019. Metodología. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.enterprisesurveys.org/methodology&quot;&gt;http://www.enterprisesurveys.org/methodology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;Objectif 9 : Bâtir une infrastructure résiliente, promouvoir une industrialisation durable qui profite à tous et encourager l&apos;innovation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cible 9.3: Accroître, en particulier dans les pays en développement, l&apos;accès des entreprises, notamment des petites entreprises industrielles, aux services financiers, y compris aux prêts consentis à des conditions abordables, et leur intégration aux chaînes de valeur et aux marchés&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indicateur 9.3.2: Proportion des petites entreprises industrielles ayant contracté un prêt ou une ligne de crédit&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2021-02-01&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Informations institutionnelles&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Organisation(s) :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Organisation des Nations Unies pour le développement industriel (ONUDI)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Concepts et définitions &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Définition: &lt;sup&gt; &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-1&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt; [1] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Petites entreprises industrielles &lt;/strong&gt;, dans le cadre des ODD également appelées &amp;#x201C; &lt;strong&gt; petites industries &lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#x201D;, définies ici aux fins de la collecte et de la compilation de données statistiques. à des unités statistiques, généralement des entreprises, engagées dans la production de biens et de services destinés au marché en dessous d&apos;une classe de taille désignée. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Cet indicateur montre le nombre de &amp;#x201C; petites industries &amp;#x201D; disposant d&apos;une ligne de crédit active ou d&apos;un prêt d&apos;une institution financière au cours de l&apos;année de référence, en pourcentage par rapport au nombre total de ces entreprises. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Concepts: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les recommandations internationales pour les statistiques industrielles 2008 (IRIS 2008) (Nations Unies, 2011) définissent une &lt;strong&gt; entreprise &lt;/strong&gt; comme la plus petite unité juridique qui constitue une unité organisationnelle produisant des biens ou des services. L&apos;entreprise est l&apos;unité statistique de base dans laquelle toutes les informations relatives à ses activités et transactions de production, y compris les comptes financiers et de bilan, sont conservées. Il est également utilisé pour la classification des secteurs institutionnels dans le Système de comptabilité nationale de 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Un &lt;strong&gt; établissement &lt;/strong&gt; est défini comme une entreprise ou une partie d&apos;entreprise qui est située dans un seul endroit et dans laquelle une seule activité productive est exercée ou dans laquelle l&apos;activité productive principale représente la majeure partie la valeur ajoutée. Un établissement peut idéalement être défini comme une unité économique qui exerce, sous un contrôle ou une propriété unique, c&apos;est-à-dire sous une seule entité juridique, dans un, ou principalement un, type d&apos;activité économique dans un seul lieu physique. Les mines, les usines et les ateliers en sont des exemples. Ce concept idéal d&apos;établissement est applicable à de nombreuses situations rencontrées dans les enquêtes industrielles, en particulier dans le secteur manufacturier. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Bien que la définition d&apos;un établissement permette la possibilité qu&apos;une ou plusieurs activités secondaires y soient exercées, leur ampleur devrait être faible par rapport à celle de l&apos;activité principale. Si une activité secondaire au sein d&apos;un établissement est aussi importante, ou presque aussi importante, que l&apos;activité principale, alors l&apos;unité ressemble plus à une unité locale. Il devrait être subdivisé de manière à ce que l&apos;activité secondaire soit considérée comme exercée dans un établissement distinct de l&apos;établissement dans lequel l&apos;activité principale a lieu. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Dans le cas de la plupart des &lt;strong&gt; petites entreprises &lt;/strong&gt;, l&apos;entreprise et l&apos;établissement seront identiques. Certaines entreprises sont grandes et complexes avec différents types d&apos;activités économiques menées à différents endroits. Ces entreprises devraient être décomposées en un ou plusieurs établissements, à condition que des unités de production plus petites et plus homogènes puissent être identifiées pour lesquelles des données de production peuvent être établies de manière significative. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Telle qu&apos;introduite dans IRIS 2008 (Nations Unies, 2011), une &lt;strong&gt; activité économique &lt;/strong&gt; s&apos;entend comme faisant référence à un processus, c&apos;est-à-dire à la combinaison d&apos;actions menées par une certaine entité qui utilise travail, capital, biens et services pour produire des produits spécifiques (biens et services). En général, les statistiques industrielles reflètent les caractéristiques et les activités économiques des unités engagées dans une catégorie d&apos;activités industrielles qui sont définies selon la Classification internationale type par industrie de toutes les activités économiques, révision 4 (CITI Rév.4) (Nations Unies, 2008) ou Classification internationale type par industrie de toutes les activités économiques, révision 3.1 (CITI Rév. 3) (Nations Unies, 2002). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Le nombre total de personnes occupées &lt;/strong&gt; est défini comme le nombre total de personnes qui travaillent dans ou pour l&apos;unité statistique, à temps plein ou à temps partiel, y compris: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Propriétaires actifs &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Partenaires commerciaux actifs &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Travailleurs familiaux non rémunérés &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Employés rémunérés (pour plus de détails, voir Nations Unies, 2011). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La taille d&apos;une unité statistique basée sur l&apos;emploi devrait être définie principalement en fonction du nombre moyen de personnes employées dans cette unité pendant la période de référence. Si le nombre moyen de personnes occupées n&apos;est pas disponible, le nombre total de personnes employées au cours d&apos;une même période peut être utilisé comme critère de taille. La classification par taille devrait comprendre les catégories suivantes du nombre moyen de personnes employées: 1 à 9, 10 à 19, 20 à 49, 50 à 249, 250 et plus. Cela devrait être considéré comme une division minimale de la gamme globale; des classifications plus détaillées, le cas échéant, devraient être élaborées dans ce cadre. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Un &lt;strong&gt; prêt &lt;/strong&gt; est un instrument financier qui est créé lorsqu&apos;un créancier prête des fonds directement à un débiteur et reçoit un document non négociable comme preuve de l&apos;actif. Cette catégorie comprend les découverts, les prêts hypothécaires, les prêts pour financer le crédit commercial et les avances, les accords de pension, les actifs et passifs financiers créés par des contrats de location-financement et les créances ou engagements envers le Fonds monétaire international (FMI) sous forme de prêts. Les crédits commerciaux et avances et autres comptes créditeurs / débiteurs ne sont pas des prêts. Les prêts devenus négociables sur les marchés secondaires doivent être reclassés en titres de créance. Cependant, s&apos;il n&apos;est négocié qu&apos;occasionnellement, le prêt n&apos;est pas reclassé dans les titres de créance (FMI, 2011). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Les marges de crédit &lt;/strong&gt; et les engagements de prêt garantissent que les fonds non utilisés seront disponibles à l&apos;avenir, mais aucun passif / actif financier n&apos;existera tant que ces fonds ne seront pas effectivement fournis. Les lignes de crédit non tirées et les engagements de prêts non décaissés sont des engagements conditionnels des institutions émettrices &amp;#x2014; généralement, des banques (FMI, 2011). Un prêt ou une ligne de crédit se réfère uniquement aux institutions financières réglementées. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-1&quot;&gt; 1 &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p&gt; Certains textes sur les concepts et la définition peuvent être identiques aux métadonnées soumises pour les indicateurs 9.3. 1. &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt; &amp;#x2191; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Sources de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les données ont été recueillies à partir des enquêtes sur les entreprises de la Banque Mondiale dans le cadre d’une étude pilote sur cet indicateur, mais la source de données préférable est les bureaux statistiques nationaux. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Processus de collecte:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L’une des principales sources de données pour cet indicateur actuellement disponible est l’Enquête sur les entreprises menée par la Banque mondiale qui couvre le secteur formel et ne contient des données pour les petites et moyennes entreprises que (avec 5 employés ou plus). Dans certains pays, d’autres enquêtes, y compris des enquêtes informelles auprès d’entreprises non enregistrées et/ou des micro-enquêtes pour les entreprises enregistrées de moins de cinq employés, sont menées et disponibles au niveau national. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L’enquête sur les entreprises est basée sur un échantillon représentatif d’entreprises gérées par le secteur privé. Les enquêtes couvrent un large éventail de sujets liés à l’environnement des affaires, y compris l’accès au financement, à la corruption, aux infrastructures, à la criminalité, à la concurrence et aux mesures du rendement. Depuis 2002, la Banque mondiale a recueilli ces données lors d’entretiens en personne avec des cadres supérieurs et des propriétaires d’entreprises dans plus de 130 000 entreprises dans 135 économies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les enquêtes ont été menées depuis 2002 par différentes unités de la Banque mondiale. Depuis 2005-2006, la plupart des efforts de collecte de données ont été centralisés au sein de l’Unité d’analyse d’entreprise. Les données de 2006 sont comparables d’un pays à l’autre. Les ensembles de données brutes de chaque pays, les ensembles de données agrégés (entre les pays et les années), les ensembles de données de panel et toute la documentation pertinente de l’enquête sont accessibles au public sur le site Web des enquêtes auprès des entreprises. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L’indicateur utilise une formule de pourcentage pondérée simple, où les poids sont les poids d’échantillonnage. Les strates des enquêtes auprès des entreprises sont la taille de l’entreprise, le secteur des affaires et la région géographique d’un pays. Les enquêtes auprès des entreprises fournissent des indicateurs couvrant les activités manufacturières et de services. La proportion de &amp;#x201C;petites industries&amp;#x201D; avec un prêt ou une marge de crédit pour la fabrication seulement peut être extraite des microdonnées. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les entreprises sont classées comme petites, moyennes ou grandes en fonction du nombre d’employés comme suit : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt; Taille de l’entreprise&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt; Nombre d’employés&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Petit&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;5 à 19 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Moyen&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;20 à 99 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Grand&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;plus de 99&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L’enquête définit également une entreprise dont la propriété est féminine comme une entreprise ayant au moins une femme propriétaire, et la gestion par les femmes se mesure à la question de savoir si le cadre supérieur est une femme. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Fournisseurs de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Enquêtes auprès des entreprises de la Banque Mondiale&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Compilateurs de données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Organisation des Nations Unies pour le développement industriel (ONUDI)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Justification:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Les entreprises industrielles sont classées comme petites par rapport aux grandes ou moyennes entreprises en raison de leur nature distincte d’organisation économique, de leur capacité de production, de leur échelle d’investissement et d’autres caractéristiques économiques. &amp;#x201C; Les petites industries&amp;#x201D; peuvent être gérées avec une petite quantité de capital, une main-d’œuvre relativement peu qualifiée et en utilisant des matériaux locaux. Malgré leur faible contribution à la production industrielle totale, leur rôle dans la création d’emplois, en particulier dans les pays en développement, est reconnu comme important lorsque la marge d’absorption de la main-d’œuvre excédentaire des secteurs traditionnels tels que l’agriculture ou la pêche est très élevée. &amp;#x201C; Les petites industries&amp;#x201D; sont capables de répondre à la demande intérieure de biens de consommation de base tels que la nourriture, les vêtements, les meubles, etc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Ainsi&amp;#x201C;, les petites industries&amp;#x201D; jouent un rôle important dans l’économie. Toutefois, l’accès aux services financiers est assez limité, en particulier dans les pays en développement. Afin d’améliorer les compétences des travailleurs et la technologie pour la production, les petites entreprises industrielles ont besoin d’un soutien financier sous forme de prêt préférentiel, de crédit, etc. Cet indicateur montre à quel point les institutions financières servent largement les petites industries &amp;#x201C;&amp;#x201D;. Avec l’indicateur ODD 9.3.1, cet indicateur reflète le message principal de l’objectif 9.3 qui favorise l’accès des petites industries &amp;#x201C;&amp;#x201D; aux services financiers. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Commentaires et limitations:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La principale limitation des données nationales existantes est la variation des classes de taille par pays, ce qui indique que les données sont obtenues auprès de différentes populations cibles. Les données d’un pays ne sont pas comparables à celles d’un autre. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La définition de la classe de taille dans de nombreux pays est liée au cadre juridique et politique du pays. Elle a des répercussions sur la procédure d’enregistrement, la fiscalité et les différentes dérogations visant à promouvoir &amp;#x201C;les petites industries&amp;#x201D;. Par conséquent, les pays peuvent s’entendre sur une classe de taille commune à des fins de compilation. Dans ce contexte, l’ONUDI propose que tous les pays compilent les données par une classe de taille de &amp;#x201C;petites industries&amp;#x201D; comme pour moins de 20 personnes employées. À partir de ces données, on pourrait tirer au total des données comparables à l’échelle internationale sur la part des &amp;#x201C;petites industries&amp;#x201D;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Méthodologie&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Méthode de calcul:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; La proportion de &amp;#x201C;petites industries&amp;#x201D; avec un prêt ou une marge de crédit est calculée comme le nombre de &amp;#x201C;petites industries&amp;#x201D; avec une marge de crédit active ou un prêt d’une institution financière au cours de l’année de référence en pourcentage du nombre total de ces entreprises:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt; (le nombre &amp;#x201C;petites industries&amp;#x201D; avec prêt ou marge de crédit/nombre total de &amp;#x201C;petites industries&amp;#x201D;) * 100&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; L’indicateur est calculé comme une part des petites entreprises manufacturières ayant un prêt ou une marge de crédit dans le nombre total de petites entreprises manufacturières. Le calcul de l’indicateur peut être prolongé pour d’autres activités économiques. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Disponibilité des données&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Description:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Des données pour environ 130 économies ont été recueillies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &amp;#xA0; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Série de temps:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Des enquêtes sont mises en œuvre chaque année dans une vingtaine de pays. La fréquence des données pour chaque pays est d’environ 4 ans. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Références&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; fonds monétaire international. (2011). Statistiques de la dette du secteur public : Guide pour les compilateurs et les utilisateurs. Washington, DC : Fonds monétaire international. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tffs.org/pdf/method/2013/psds2013.pdf&quot;&gt;http://www.tffs.org/pdf/method/2013/psds2013.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; nations unies. (2002). Classification industrielle standard internationale de toutes les activités économiques (révision 4 de l’ISIC). New York : Nations Unies. &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/seriesm/seriesm_4rev4e.pdf&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/seriesm/seriesm_4rev4e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; nations unies. (2008). Classification industrielle standard internationale de toutes les activités économiques (révision 3.1 de l’ISIC). New York : Nations Unies. &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/SeriesM/seriesm_4rev3_1e.pdf&quot;&gt;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/SeriesM/seriesm_4rev3_1e.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; nations unies. (2011). Recommandations internationales pour les statistiques industrielles 2008 (IRIS 2008), New York : Nations Unies. &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.18356/677c08dd-en&quot;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.18356/677c08dd-fr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; enquêtes auprès des entreprises de la Banque mondiale. 2019. Méthodologie. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.enterprisesurveys.org/methodology&quot;&gt;http://www.enterprisesurveys.org/methodology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;p&gt;Цель 9: Создание стойкой инфраструктуры, содействие всеохватной и устойчивой индустриализации и инновациям&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Задача 9.3: Расширить доступ мелких промышленных и прочих предприятий, особенно в развивающихся странах, к финансовым услугам, в том числе к недорогим кредитам, и усилить их интеграцию в производственно-сбытовые цепочки и рынки&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Показатель 9.3.2: Доля мелких предприятий, имеющих кредит или кредитную линию&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Последнее обновление: март 2020 года &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Институциональная информация &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Организация (и): &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Организация Объединенных Наций по промышленному развитию (ЮНИДО) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Понятия и определения &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Определение: &lt;sup&gt; &lt;sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-1&quot; id=&quot;footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt; [1] &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Малые промышленные предприятия &lt;/strong&gt; в структуре ЦУР также называемые &amp;#x201C;&lt;strong&gt;малые производства&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#x201D;, определенные здесь для целей сбора и обработки статистических данных, относятся к статистическим единицам, как правило, предприятиям ниже определенного размера класса, занимающимся производством рыночных товаров и услуг. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Этот показатель отражает количество &quot;малых производств&quot;, имеющих действующий кредит или кредитную линию, полученные от финансового учреждения в отчетном году, в процентах от общего количества таких предприятий. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Понятия: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Международные рекомендации по статистике промышленности 2008 года (МРСП 2008 года) (ООН, 2011 год) определяют &lt;strong&gt; предприятие &lt;/strong&gt; как наименьшую юридическую единицу, которая представляет собой организационную единицу, производящую товары или услуги. Предприятие является базовой статистической единицей, в которой ведется вся информация, связанная с его производственной деятельностью и операциями, включая финансовые и балансовые счета. Предприятие также используется для классификации институциональных секторов в Системе национальных счетов 2008 года.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Заведение &lt;/strong&gt;определяется как предприятие или часть предприятия, которое находится в каком-то одном месте и на котором осуществляется только один вид производственной деятельности или на котором основному виду производственной деятельности соответствует превосходящая часть добавленной стоимости. В идеальном случае заведение можно определить как экономическую единицу, которая, находясь в единоличной собственности или под единоличным контролем, т. е. под контролем одного юридического лица, осуществляет
только один или преимущественно один вид экономической деятельности в каком-то одном физическом месте. Примерами являются рудники, заводы и мастерские. Такое идеальное понятие заведения применимо ко многим ситуациям, появляющимся в ходе обследований в сфере промышленности, в частности, в обрабатывающей промышленности. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Хотя определение любого заведения допускает возможность осуществления одного или более видов второстепенной деятельности, эти виды деятельности должны иметь небольшие масштабы по сравнению с основным видом деятельности. Если второстепенная деятельность в рамках того или иного заведения играет такую же или почти такую же важную роль, как и основная деятельность, тогда данное заведение скорее имеет признаки местной единицы. Такое заведение должно быть дополнительно разделено таким образом, чтобы второстепенная деятельность рассматривалась как осуществляемая в рамках отдельного заведения, отличного от заведения, в котором проводится основная деятельность. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Применительно к большинству &lt;strong&gt; малых компаний &lt;/strong&gt; понятия «предприятие» и «заведение» будут идентичными. Некоторые крупные и сложные по своей структуре предприятия осуществляют различные виды экономической деятельности в разных местах. Такие предприятия необходимо разделять на два или несколько заведений при условии, что можно выделить более мелкие и более однородные производственные единицы, по которым имеется возможность получения достаточных производственных данных. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Как приведено в МРСП 2008 года (ООН, 2011 год), под &lt;strong&gt; экономической деятельностью &lt;/strong&gt; понимается процесс, а именно комбинация действий, осуществляемых неким хозяйствующим субъектом, который использует трудовые ресурсы, капитал, товары и услуги для производства конкретных видов продукции (товаров или услуг). В целом, статистика промышленности отражает характеристики и экономическую деятельность единиц, занимающихся тем или иным видом промышленной деятельности, который определяется в рамках Международной стандартной отраслевой классификации всех видов экономической деятельности, ред. 4 (МСОК, ред. 4) (Организация Объединенных Наций, 2008 год) или Международной стандартной отраслевой классификацией всех видов экономической деятельности, ред. 3.1 (МСОК ред.3) (Организация Объединенных Наций, 2002 год). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Общее количество занятых &lt;/strong&gt; определяется как общее количество лиц, которые работают в статистической единице или для нее, как в условиях полной, так и неполной занятости, включая: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Работающих собственников &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Активных деловых партнеров &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Неоплачиваемых семейных работников &lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt; Наемных сотрудников (подробнее см. ООН, 2011 год). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Размер статистической единицы, устанавливаемый по количеству занятых, должен определяться прежде всего исходя из средней численности работников, занятых на данном предприятии в течение отчетного периода. Если отсутствуют данные по средней численности занятых работников, то в качестве критерия размера предприятия можно использовать общую численность занятых работников за какой-то отдельный период времени. Классификация размера единиц должна включать в себя следующие классы по средней численности занятых работников: 1–9, 10–19, 20–49, 50–249, 250 человек и более. Такая классификация должна рассматриваться как минимально возможное разделение всего диапазона размеров; при необходимости должна разрабатываться более детальная классификация в рамках указанной структуры. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Кредит &lt;/strong&gt; - это финансовый инструмент, который образуется, когда кредитор ссужает средства непосредственно должнику и получает необоротный документ в качестве доказательства актива. В эту категорию входят овердрафты, ипотечные кредиты, ссуды для финансирования торговых кредитов и авансов, соглашения об обратной покупке, финансовые активы и обязательства, возникающие в результате финансовой аренды, а также требования или обязательства перед Международным валютным фондом (МВФ) в форме кредитов. Торговые кредиты и авансы и аналогичная кредиторская / дебиторская задолженность не являются кредитами. Кредиты, которые стали продаваться на вторичных рынках, следует реклассифицировать в долговые ценные бумаги. Однако, если этот кредит торгуется только время от времени, он не реклассифицируется в долговые ценные бумаги (МВФ, 2011 год). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Кредитные линии &lt;/strong&gt; и обязательства по займам обеспечивают гарантию того, что неиспользованные средства будут доступны в будущем, но никаких финансовых обязательств / активов не существует до тех пор, пока такие средства не будут фактически предоставлены. Невыбранные кредитные линии и неиспользованные обязательства по предоставлению кредитов являются условными обязательствами учреждений-эмитентов - как правило, банков (МВФ, 2011 год). Кредит или кредитная линия относятся только к регулируемым финансовым учреждениям. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-number&quot; id=&quot;footnote-1&quot;&gt; 1 &lt;/sup&gt; &lt;p&gt; Некоторая часть текста о понятиях и определениях может быть идентична метаданным, представленным для показателя 9.3.1.&lt;a href=&quot;#footnote-ref-1&quot;&gt;&amp;#x2191;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Источники данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Данные были получены из Обследований предприятий, проведенных Всемирным банком в качестве пилотного исследования по этому показателю, однако предпочтительным источником данных являются национальные статистические управления. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Процесс сбора: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Одним из основных источников данных для этого показателя, доступных в настоящее время, является обследование предприятий, проводимое Всемирным банком, которое охватывает формальный сектор и содержит данные только по малым и средним предприятиям (имеющим 5 или более работников). В некоторых странах проводятся и доступны на страновом уровне дополнительные обследования, в том числе неформальные обследования незарегистрированных предприятий и / или микро-обследования зарегистрированных фирм, имеющих менее пяти работников. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Обследование предприятий основано на репрезентативной выборке предприятий частного сектора. Обследования охватывают широкий спектр тем бизнес-среды, включая доступ к финансам, коррупцию, инфраструктуру, преступность, конкуренцию и показатели эффективности. С 2002 года Всемирный банк собирает эти данные путем проведения личных интервью с топ-менеджерами и владельцами бизнеса в более чем 130 000 компаниях в 135 странах мира. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Обследования проводятся с 2002 года различными подразделениями Всемирного банка. С 2005-06 годов большая часть усилий по сбору данных была централизована в рамках подразделения Enterprise Analysis Unit (Отдел анализа деятельности предприятий). Данные, начиная с 2006 года, сопоставимы по странам. Необработанные наборы данных по отдельным странам, агрегированные наборы данных (по странам и годам), панельные наборы данных и вся соответствующая документация обследований общедоступна на веб-сайте Enterprise Surveys (Обследования предприятий). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В показателе используется простая формула взвешенного процента, где веса - это веса выборки. Стратами для обследований предприятий являются размер фирмы, сектор бизнеса и географический регион в стране. Обследования предприятий предоставляют показатели, охватывающие производственную деятельность и услуги. Доля &quot;малых предприятий&quot;, имеющих кредит или кредитную линию только в обрабатывающей промышленности, может быть получена при обработке микроданных. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Предприятия классифицируются как малые, средние и крупные в зависимости от количества работников следующим образом: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt; Размер предприятия &lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt; Количество работников &lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Малое &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 5–19 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Среднее &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; 20–99 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; Крупное &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; более 99 &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt; В обследовании также определяется предприятие, которым владеют женщины, как предприятие, имеющее по крайней мере одну женщину-собственника, а предприятие считается управляемым женщиной, если руководителем высшего звена является женщина.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Поставщики данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Обследования предприятий, проводимые Всемирным банком &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Составители данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Организация Объединенных Наций по промышленному развитию (ЮНИДО) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Обоснование: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Промышленные предприятия классифицируются как малые по сравнению с крупными или средними из-за их особого характера экономической организации, производственных возможностей, масштабов инвестиций и других экономических характеристик. &quot;Малые предприятия&quot; могут управляться небольшим капиталом, иметь относительно неквалифицированную рабочую силу и использовать местные материалы. Несмотря на их небольшой вклад в общий объем промышленного производства, их роль в создании рабочих мест, особенно в развивающихся странах, признана значительной, где масштабы поглощения избыточной рабочей силы из традиционных секторов, таких как сельское хозяйство или рыболовство, очень высоки. &quot;Малые предприятия&quot; способны удовлетворять внутренний спрос на основные потребительские товары, такие как продукты питания, одежда, мебель и т. д. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Таким образом, &quot;малые предприятия&quot; играют важную роль в экономике. Однако у них довольно ограниченный доступ к финансовым услугам, особенно в развивающихся странах. Для повышения квалификации рабочих и подъема уровня технологической оснащённости производства малым промышленным предприятиям требуется финансовая поддержка в виде льготных займов, кредитов и т. д. Этот показатель отражает, насколько широко финансовые учреждения обслуживают &quot;малые предприятия&quot;. Вместе с показателем ЦУР 9.3.1 этот показатель отражает основной посыл задачи 9.3, которая призывает способствовать расширению доступа &quot;малых предприятий&quot; к финансовым услугам. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Комментарии и ограничения: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Основным ограничением существующих национальных данных является различие в размерах классов в зависимости от страны, что указывает на то, что данные получены из различных целевых совокупностей. Данные одной страны несопоставимы с данными другой страны. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Определение размера класса во многих странах связано с нормативно-правовой и политической базой страны. Эти факторы имеют значение при процедуре регистрации, налогообложении и различных отступлениях от норм, направленных на развитие &quot;малых предприятий&quot;. В этой связи, страны могли бы согласовать общий размер класса для целей составления показателей. В этом контексте ЮНИДО предлагает, чтобы все страны составляли данные по размеру класса &quot;малых предприятий&quot;, где занято менее 20 человек. На основе таких данных можно было бы получить сопоставимые на международном уровне данные по доле &quot;малых предприятий&quot; в общем объеме. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Методология &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Метод расчета: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Доля &quot;малых предприятий&quot;, имеющих кредит или кредитную линию, рассчитывается как количество &quot;малых предприятий&quot;, имеющих действующий кредит или кредитную линию от финансового учреждения в отчетном году в процентном отношении к общему количеству таких предприятий. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;em&gt; (количество &quot;малых предприятий&quot;, имеющих кредит или кредитную линию / общее количество &quot;малых предприятий&quot;) * 100 &lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Показатель рассчитывается как доля малых предприятий сектора обрабатывающей промышленности, имеющих кредит или кредитную линию, в общем количестве малых предприятий сектора обрабатывающей промышленности. Расчет показателя можно распространить на другие виды экономической деятельности. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Доступность данных &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Описание: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Были собраны данные примерно по 130 странам. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Временные ряды: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Обследования проводятся ежегодно примерно в 20 странах. Периодичность сбора данных в каждой стране составляет около 4 лет. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h1&gt; Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Международный валютный фонд. (2011 год). Статистика долга государственного сектора: Руководство для составителей и пользователей. Вашингтон, округ Колумбия: Международный валютный фонд. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tffs.org/pdf/method/2013/psds2013.pdf&quot;&gt; http://www.tffs.org/pdf/method/2013/psds2013.pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Организация Объединенных Наций. (2002 год). Международная стандартная отраслевая классификация всех видов экономической деятельности (МСОК ред. 4). Нью-Йорк: Организация Объединенных Наций. &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/seriesm/seriesm_4rev4e.pdf&quot;&gt; https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/seriesm/seriesm_4rev4e.pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Организация Объединенных Наций. (2008 год). Международная стандартная отраслевая классификация всех видов экономической деятельности (МСОК, ред. 3.1). Нью-Йорк: Организация Объединенных Наций. &lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/SeriesM/seriesm_4rev3_1e.pdf&quot;&gt; https://unstats.un.org/unsd/publication/SeriesM/seriesm_4rev3_1e.pdf &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Организация Объединенных Наций. (2011). Международные рекомендации по статистике промышленности, 2008 год. (МРСП 2008 год), Нью-Йорк: Организация Объединенных Наций. &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.18356/677c08dd-en&quot;&gt; http://dx.doi.org/10.18356/677c08dd-en &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Обследования предприятий, проводимые Всемирным банком. 2019 год. Методология. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.enterprisesurveys.org/methodology&quot;&gt; 
http://www.enterprisesurveys.org/methodology &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
