<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The OTHER_DOC field for indicator 3-9-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.who.int/data/gho/data/themes/air-pollution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonjour S, Adair-Rohani H, Wolf J, Bruce NG, Mehta S, Pr&amp;#xFC;ss-Ust&amp;#xFC;n A, Lahiff M, Rehfuess EA, Mishra V, Smith KR. (2013). Solid fuel use for household cooking: country and regional estimates for 1980-2010. Environ Health Perspect. 121(7):784-90. doi: 10.1289/ehp.1205987. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burnett RT, Pope CA 3rd, Ezzati M, Olives C, Lim SS, Mehta S, Shin HH, Singh G, Hubbell B, Brauer M, Anderson HR, Smith KR, Balmes JR, Bruce NG, Kan H, Laden F, Pr&amp;#xFC;ss-Ust&amp;#xFC;n A, Turner MC, Gapstur SM, Diver WR, Cohen A. (2014). An integrated risk function for estimating the global burden of disease attributable to ambient fine particulate matter exposure. Environ Health Perspect. 122(4):397-403. doi: 10.1289/ehp.1307049. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burnett R, Cohen A. (2020). Relative Risk Functions for Estimating Excess Mortality Attributable to Outdoor PM2.5 Air Pollution: Evolution and State-of-the-Art. Atmosphere, 11, 589. &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos11060589&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos11060589&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cohen AJ, Brauer M, Burnett R, Anderson HR, Frostad J, Estep K, Balakrishnan K, Brunekreef B, Dandona L, Dandona R, Feigin V, Freedman G, Hubbell B, Jobling A, Kan H, Knibbs L, Liu Y, Martin R, Morawska L, Pope CA 3rd, Shin H, Straif K, Shaddick G, Thomas M, van Dingenen R, van Donkelaar A, Vos T, Murray CJL, Forouzanfar MH. (2017). Estimates and 25-year trends of the global burden of disease attributable to ambient air pollution: an analysis of data from the Global Burden of Diseases Study 2015. Lancet. 389(10082):1907-1918. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(17)30505-6. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ezzati M, Hoorn SV, Rodgers A, Lopez AD, Mathers CD, Murray CJ. (2003). Comparative Risk Assessment Collaborating Group. Estimates of global and regional potential health gains from reducing multiple major risk factors. Lancet. 362(9380):271-80. doi: 10.1016/s0140-6736(03)13968-2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forouzanfar MH, Alexander L, Anderson HR, Bachman VF, Biryukov S, Brauer M, Burnett R, Casey D, Coates MM, Cohen A, Delwiche K, Estep K, Frostad JJ, Astha KC, Kyu HH, Moradi-Lakeh M, Ng M, Slepak EL, Thomas BA, Wagner J, Aasvang GM, Abbafati C, Abbasoglu Ozgoren A, Abd-Allah F, Abera SF, Aboyans V, Abraham B, Abraham JP, Abubakar I, Abu-Rmeileh NM, Aburto TC, Achoki T, Adelekan A, Adofo K, Adou AK, Adsuar JC, Afshin A, Agardh EE, Al Khabouri MJ, Al Lami FH, Alam SS, Alasfoor D, Albittar MI, Alegretti MA, Aleman AV, Alemu ZA, Alfonso-Cristancho R, Alhabib S, Ali R, Ali MK, Alla F, Allebeck P, Allen PJ, Alsharif U, Alvarez E, Alvis-Guzman N, Amankwaa AA, Amare AT, Ameh EA, Ameli O, Amini H, Ammar W, Anderson BO, Antonio CA, Anwari P, Argeseanu Cunningham S, Arnl&amp;#xF6;v J, Arsenijevic VS, Artaman A, Asghar RJ, Assadi R, Atkins LS, Atkinson C, Avila MA, Awuah B, Badawi A, Bahit MC, Bakfalouni T, Balakrishnan K, Balalla S, Balu RK, Banerjee A, Barber RM, Barker-Collo SL, Barquera S, Barregard L, Barrero LH, Barrientos-Gutierrez T, Basto-Abreu AC, Basu A, Basu S, Basulaiman MO, Batis Ruvalcaba C, Beardsley J, Bedi N, Bekele T, Bell ML, Benjet C, Bennett DA, Benzian H, Bernab&amp;#xE9; E, Beyene TJ, Bhala N, Bhalla A, Bhutta ZA, Bikbov B, Bin Abdulhak AA, Blore JD, Blyth FM, Bohensky MA, Bora Ba&amp;#x15F;ara B, Borges G, Bornstein NM, Bose D, Boufous S, Bourne RR, Brainin M, Brazinova A, Breitborde NJ, Brenner H, Briggs AD, Broday DM, Brooks PM, Bruce NG, Brugha TS, Brunekreef B, Buchbinder R, Bui LN, Bukhman G, Bulloch AG, Burch M, Burney PG, Campos-Nonato IR, Campuzano JC, Cantoral AJ, Caravanos J, C&amp;#xE1;rdenas R, Cardis E, Carpenter DO, Caso V, Casta&amp;#xF1;eda-Orjuela CA, Castro RE, Catal&amp;#xE1;-L&amp;#xF3;pez F, Cavalleri F, &amp;#xC7;avlin A, Chadha VK, Chang JC, Charlson FJ, Chen H, Chen W, Chen Z, Chiang PP, Chimed-Ochir O, Chowdhury R, Christophi CA, Chuang TW, Chugh SS, Cirillo M, Cla&amp;#xDF;en TK, Colistro V, Colomar M, Colquhoun SM, Contreras AG, Cooper C, Cooperrider K, Cooper LT, Coresh J, Courville KJ, Criqui MH, Cuevas-Nasu L, Damsere-Derry J, Danawi H, Dandona L, Dandona R, Dargan PI, Davis A, Davitoiu DV, Dayama A, de Castro EF, De la Cruz-G&amp;#xF3;ngora V, De Leo D, de Lima G, Degenhardt L, del Pozo-Cruz B, Dellavalle RP, Deribe K, Derrett S, Des Jarlais DC, Dessalegn M, deVeber GA, Devries KM, Dharmaratne SD, Dherani MK, Dicker D, Ding EL, Dokova K, Dorsey ER, Driscoll TR, Duan L, Durrani AM, Ebel BE, Ellenbogen RG, Elshrek YM, Endres M, Ermakov SP, Erskine HE, Eshrati B, Esteghamati A, Fahimi S, Faraon EJ, Farzadfar F, Fay DF, Feigin VL, Feigl AB, Fereshtehnejad SM, Ferrari AJ, Ferri CP, Flaxman AD, Fleming TD, Foigt N, Foreman KJ, Paleo UF, Franklin RC, Gabbe B, Gaffikin L, Gakidou E, Gamkrelidze A, Gankp&amp;#xE9; FG, Gansevoort RT, Garc&amp;#xED;a-Guerra FA, Gasana E, Geleijnse JM, Gessner BD, Gething P, Gibney KB, Gillum RF, Ginawi IA, Giroud M, Giussani G, Goenka S, Goginashvili K, Gomez Dantes H, Gona P, Gonzalez de Cosio T, Gonz&amp;#xE1;lez-Castell D, Gotay CC, Goto A, Gouda HN, Guerrant RL, Gugnani HC, Guillemin F, Gunnell D, Gupta R, Gupta R, Guti&amp;#xE9;rrez RA, Hafezi-Nejad N, Hagan H, Hagstromer M, Halasa YA, Hamadeh RR, Hammami M, Hankey GJ, Hao Y, Harb HL, Haregu TN, Haro JM, Havmoeller R, Hay SI, Hedayati MT, Heredia-Pi IB, Hernandez L, Heuton KR, Heydarpour P, Hijar M, Hoek HW, Hoffman HJ, Hornberger JC, Hosgood HD, Hoy DG, Hsairi M, Hu G, Hu H, Huang C, Huang JJ, Hubbell BJ, Huiart L, Husseini A, Iannarone ML, Iburg KM, Idrisov BT, Ikeda N, Innos K, Inoue M, Islami F, Ismayilova S, Jacobsen KH, Jansen HA, Jarvis DL, Jassal SK, Jauregui A, Jayaraman S, Jeemon P, Jensen PN, Jha V, Jiang F, Jiang G, Jiang Y, Jonas JB, Juel K, Kan H, Kany Roseline SS, Karam NE, Karch A, Karema CK, Karthikeyan G, Kaul A, Kawakami N, Kazi DS, Kemp AH, Kengne AP, Keren A, Khader YS, Khalifa SE, Khan EA, Khang YH, Khatibzadeh S, Khonelidze I, Kieling C, Kim D, Kim S, Kim Y, Kimokoti RW, Kinfu Y, Kinge JM, Kissela BM, Kivipelto M, Knibbs LD, Knudsen AK, Kokubo Y, Kose MR, Kosen S, Kraemer A, Kravchenko M, Krishnaswami S, Kromhout H, Ku T, Kuate Defo B, Kucuk Bicer B, Kuipers EJ, Kulkarni C, Kulkarni VS, Kumar GA, Kwan GF, Lai T, Lakshmana Balaji A, Lalloo R, Lallukka T, Lam H, Lan Q, Lansingh VC, Larson HJ, Larsson A, Laryea DO, Lavados PM, Lawrynowicz AE, Leasher JL, Lee JT, Leigh J, Leung R, Levi M, Li Y, Li Y, Liang J, Liang X, Lim SS, Lindsay MP, Lipshultz SE, Liu S, Liu Y, Lloyd BK, Logroscino G, London SJ, Lopez N, Lortet-Tieulent J, Lotufo PA, Lozano R, Lunevicius R, Ma J, Ma S, Machado VM, MacIntyre MF, Magis-Rodriguez C, Mahdi AA, Majdan M, Malekzadeh R, Mangalam S, Mapoma CC, Marape M, Marcenes W, Margolis DJ, Margono C, Marks GB, Martin RV, Marzan MB, Mashal MT, Masiye F, Mason-Jones AJ, Matsushita K, Matzopoulos R, Mayosi BM, Mazorodze TT, McKay AC, McKee M, McLain A, Meaney PA, Medina C, Mehndiratta MM, Mejia-Rodriguez F, Mekonnen W, Melaku YA, Meltzer M, Memish ZA, Mendoza W, Mensah GA, Meretoja A, Mhimbira FA, Micha R, Miller TR, Mills EJ, Misganaw A, Mishra S, Mohamed Ibrahim N, Mohammad KA, Mokdad AH, Mola GL, Monasta L, Monta&amp;#xF1;ez Hernandez JC, Montico M, Moore AR, Morawska L, Mori R, Moschandreas J, Moturi WN, Mozaffarian D, Mueller UO, Mukaigawara M, Mullany EC, Murthy KS, Naghavi M, Nahas Z, Naheed A, Naidoo KS, Naldi L, Nand D, Nangia V, Narayan KM, Nash D, Neal B, Nejjari C, Neupane SP, Newton CR, Ngalesoni FN, Ngirabega Jde D, Nguyen G, Nguyen NT, Nieuwenhuijsen MJ, Nisar MI, Nogueira JR, Nolla JM, Nolte S, Norheim OF, Norman RE, Norrving B, Nyakarahuka L, Oh IH, Ohkubo T, Olusanya BO, Omer SB, Opio JN, Orozco R, Pagcatipunan RS Jr, Pain AW, Pandian JD, Panelo CI, Papachristou C, Park EK, Parry CD, Paternina Caicedo AJ, Patten SB, Paul VK, Pavlin BI, Pearce N, Pedraza LS, Pedroza A, Pejin Stokic L, Pekericli A, Pereira DM, Perez-Padilla R, Perez-Ruiz F, Perico N, Perry SA, Pervaiz A, Pesudovs K, Peterson CB, Petzold M, Phillips MR, Phua HP, Plass D, Poenaru D, Polanczyk GV, Polinder S, Pond CD, Pope CA, Pope D, Popova S, Pourmalek F, Powles J, Prabhakaran D, Prasad NM, Qato DM, Quezada AD, Quistberg DA, Racap&amp;#xE9; L, Rafay A, Rahimi K, Rahimi-Movaghar V, Rahman SU, Raju M, Rakovac I, Rana SM, Rao M, Razavi H, Reddy KS, Refaat AH, Rehm J, Remuzzi G, Ribeiro AL, Riccio PM, Richardson L, Riederer A, Robinson M, Roca A, Rodriguez A, Rojas-Rueda D, Romieu I, Ronfani L, Room R, Roy N, Ruhago GM, Rushton L, Sabin N, Sacco RL, Saha S, Sahathevan R, Sahraian MA, Salomon JA, Salvo D, Sampson UK, Sanabria JR, Sanchez LM, S&amp;#xE1;nchez-Pimienta TG, Sanchez-Riera L, Sandar L, Santos IS, Sapkota A, Satpathy M, Saunders JE, Sawhney M, Saylan MI, Scarborough P, Schmidt JC, Schneider IJ, Sch&amp;#xF6;ttker B, Schwebel DC, Scott JG, Seedat S, Sepanlou SG, Serdar B, Servan-Mori EE, Shaddick G, Shahraz S, Levy TS, Shangguan S, She J, Sheikhbahaei S, Shibuya K, Shin HH, Shinohara Y, Shiri R, Shishani K, Shiue I, Sigfusdottir ID, Silberberg DH, Simard EP, Sindi S, Singh A, Singh GM, Singh JA, Skirbekk V, Sliwa K, Soljak M, Soneji S, S&amp;#xF8;reide K, Soshnikov S, Sposato LA, Sreeramareddy CT, Stapelberg NJ, Stathopoulou V, Steckling N, Stein DJ, Stein MB, Stephens N, St&amp;#xF6;ckl H, Straif K, Stroumpoulis K, Sturua L, Sunguya BF, Swaminathan S, Swaroop M, Sykes BL, Tabb KM, Takahashi K, Talongwa RT, Tandon N, Tanne D, Tanner M, Tavakkoli M, Te Ao BJ, Teixeira CM, T&amp;#xE9;llez Rojo MM, Terkawi AS, Texcalac-Sangrador JL, Thackway SV, Thomson B, Thorne-Lyman AL, Thrift AG, Thurston GD, Tillmann T, Tobollik M, Tonelli M, Topouzis F, Towbin JA, Toyoshima H, Traebert J, Tran BX, Trasande L, Trillini M, Trujillo U, Dimbuene ZT, Tsilimbaris M, Tuzcu EM, Uchendu US, Ukwaja KN, Uzun SB, van de Vijver S, Van Dingenen R, van Gool CH, van Os J, Varakin YY, Vasankari TJ, Vasconcelos AM, Vavilala MS, Veerman LJ, Velasquez-Melendez G, Venketasubramanian N, Vijayakumar L, Villalpando S, Violante FS, Vlassov VV, Vollset SE, Wagner GR, Waller SG, Wallin MT, Wan X, Wang H, Wang J, Wang L, Wang W, Wang Y, Warouw TS, Watts CH, Weichenthal S, Weiderpass E, Weintraub RG, Werdecker A, Wessells KR, Westerman R, Whiteford HA, Wilkinson JD, Williams HC, Williams TN, Woldeyohannes SM, Wolfe CD, Wong JQ, Woolf AD, Wright JL, Wurtz B, Xu G, Yan LL, Yang G, Yano Y, Ye P, Yenesew M, Yent&amp;#xFC;r GK, Yip P, Yonemoto N, Yoon SJ, Younis MZ, Younoussi Z, Yu C, Zaki ME, Zhao Y, Zheng Y, Zhou M, Zhu J, Zhu S, Zou X, Zunt JR, Lopez AD, Vos T, Murray CJ. (2015). Global, regional, and national comparative risk assessment of 79 behavioural, environmental and occupational, and metabolic risks or clusters of risks in 188 countries, 1990-2013: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2013. Lancet. 386(10010):2287-323. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(15)00128-2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shaddick G, Thomas ML, Green A, Brauer M, van Donkelaar A, Burnett R, Chang HH, Cohen A, Van Dingenen R, Dora C, Gumy S, Liu Y, Martin R, Waller LA, West J, Zidek JV, Pr&amp;#xFC;ss-Ust&amp;#xFC;n A. (2018). Data integration model for air quality: a hierarchical approach to the global estimation of exposures to ambient air pollution. Journal of the Royal Statistical Society. Series C (Applied Statistics), 67(1), 231&amp;#x2013;253. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jstor.org/stable/44682225&quot;&gt;http://www.jstor.org/stable/44682225&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shaddick G, Salter JM, Peuch VH, Ruggeri G, Thomas ML, Mudu P, Tarasova O, Baklanov A, Gumy S. (2021). Global Air Quality: An Inter-Disciplinary Approach to Exposure Assessment for Burden of Disease Analyses. Atmosphere, 12, 48. https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos12010048&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smith KR, Bruce N, Balakrishnan K, Adair-Rohani H, Balmes J, Chafe Z, Dherani M, Hosgood HD, Mehta S, Pope D, Rehfuess E; HAP CRA Risk Expert Group. (2014). Millions dead: how do we know and what does it mean? Methods used in the comparative risk assessment of household air pollution. Annu Rev Public Health. 35:185-206. doi: 10.1146/annurev-publhealth-032013-182356&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHO (2014a). Methods description for the burden of disease attributable to household air pollution. Access at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/phe/health_topics/outdoorair/database/HAP_BoD_methods_March2014.pdf?ua=1&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/phe/health_topics/outdoorair/database/HAP_BoD_methods_March2014.pdf?ua=1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WHO (2019b). Global Health Estimates 2019: Deaths by Cause, Age and Sex, by Country, 2000-2019 (provisional estimates). Geneva, World Health Organization, 2019. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es">&lt;h1&gt;Referencias&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;URL:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;www.who.int/gho/phe&quot;&gt;www.who.int/gho/phe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Referencias:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonjour et al (2013). Environ Health Perspect, doi:10.1289/ehp.1205987.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burnett et al (2014). Environ Health Perspect,Vol 122, Issue 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ezzati et al (2003). The Lancet, 362:271-80.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ezzati et al (2002). The Lancet. 360(9343):1347-60.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forouzanfar et al (2015). The Lancet, 386:2287-323.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lim et al (2012). The Lancet, 380(9859):2224-60.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smith et al (2014). Annu.Rev.Public Health, Vol 35.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OMS (2014a). Descripción de métodos para la carga de enfermedad atribuible a la contaminación atmosférica doméstica. Acceso en: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/phe/health_topics/outdoorair/database/HAP_BoD_methods_March2014.pdf?ua=1&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/phe/health_topics/outdoorair/database/HAP_BoD_methods_March2014.pdf?ua=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OMS (2014b). Estimaciones de la salud mundial 2013: Muertes por causa, edad y sexo, por país, 2000-2012 (estimaciones provisionales). Ginebra, Organización Mundial de la Salud, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OMS (2016, de próxima publicación). Contaminación del aire: evaluación mundial de la exposición y la carga de morbilidad, OMS Ginebra.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;p&gt;(Toutes les références sont en anglais)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;www.who.int/gho/phe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Références :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonjour et al (2013). Environmental Health Perspectives, doi:10.1289/ehp.1205987. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burnett et al (2014). Environmental Health Perspectives, vol. 122, numéro 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ezzati et al (2003). The Lancet, 362:271-80. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ezzati et al (2002). The Lancet. 360(9343):1347-60.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forouzanfar et al (2015). The Lancet, 386:2287-323. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lim et al (2012). The Lancet, 380(9859):2224-60. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smith et al (2014). Annual Review of Public Health, Vol 35. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OMS (2014a). « Methods description for the burden of disease attributable to household air pollution ». Accès à l&apos;adresse : http://www.who.int/phe/health_topics/outdoorair/database/HAP_BoD_methods_March2014.pdf?ua=1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OMS (2014b). « Global Health Estimates 2013: Deaths by Cause, Age and Sex, by Country, 2000-2012 » (estimations provisoires). Genève, Organisation mondiale de la Santé, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OMS (2016, à paraître). « Air pollution: a global assessment of exposure and burden of disease », OMS Genève. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="pt"/>
			<language lang="ru">&lt;h1&gt; Ссылки &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; URL: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;www.who.int/gho/phe&quot;&gt; www.who.int/gho/phe &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; Ссылки: &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonjour et al (2013). Environ Health Perspect, doi:10.1289/ehp.1205987.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burnett et al (2014). Environ Health Perspect, Vol 122, Issue 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ezzati et al (2003). The Lancet, 362:271-80.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ezzati et al (2002). The Lancet. 360(9343):1347-60.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forouzanfar et al (2015). The Lancet, 386:2287-323.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lim et al (2012). The Lancet, 380(9859):2224-60.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smith et al (2014). Annu.Rev.Public Health, Vol 35.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ВОЗ (2014a). Описание методов сокращения бремени заболеваний, вызываемых загрязненным воздухом в жилых помещениях. Доступно по адресу: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/phe/health_topics/outdoorair/database/HAP_BoD_methods_March2014.pdf?ua=1&quot;&gt; http://www.who.int/phe/health_topics/outdoorair/database/HAP_BoD_methods_March2014.pdf?ua=1 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ВОЗ (2014b). Глобальные оценки состояния здоровья, 2013 год: Смертность по причинам смерти, возрасту и полу, по странам, 2000–2012 годы. (Предварительные оценки). Женева, Всемирная организация здравоохранения, 2014 год. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ВОЗ (2016 г., готовится к печати). Загрязнение воздуха: глобальная оценка воздействия внешних факторов и бремени заболеваний, ВОЗ, Женева. &lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
