<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The REC_USE_LIM field for indicator 3-9-1, translated into all languages</message>
	<data>
		<languages>
			<language lang="ar"/>
			<language lang="en">&lt;h2&gt;Comments and limitations:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An approximation of the combined effects of risk factors is possible if independence and little correlation between risk factors with impacts on the same diseases can be assumed (Ezzati et al, 2003). In the case of air pollution, however, there are some limitations to estimate the joint effects: limited knowledge on the distribution of the population exposed to both household and ambient air pollution, correlation of exposures at individual level as household air pollution is a contributor to ambient air pollution, and non-linear interactions (Lim et al, 2012; Smith et al, 2014). In several regions, however, household air pollution remains mainly a rural issue, while ambient air pollution is predominantly an urban problem. Also, in some continents, many countries are relatively unaffected by household air pollution, while ambient air pollution is a major concern. If assuming independence and little correlation, a rough estimate of the total impact can be calculated, which is less than the sum of the impact of the two risk factors.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="es"/>
			<language lang="fr">&lt;h2&gt;Commentaires et limites : &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Une approximation des effets combinés des facteurs de risque est possible si l&apos;on peut supposer une indépendance et une faible corrélation entre les facteurs de risque ayant un impact sur les mêmes maladies (Ezzati et al, 2003). Dans le cas de la pollution de l&apos;air, cependant, l&apos;estimation des effets conjoints présente certaines limites : connaissances limitées sur la répartition de la population exposée à la fois à la pollution de l&apos;air domestique et à la pollution de l&apos;air ambiant, corrélation des expositions au niveau individuel, la pollution de l&apos;air domestique contribuant à la pollution de l&apos;air ambiant, et interactions non linéaires (Lim et al, 2012 ; Smith et al, 2014). Dans plusieurs régions, cependant, la pollution de l&apos;air domestique reste principalement un problème rural, alors que la pollution de l&apos;air ambiant est principalement un problème urbain. En outre, sur certains continents, de nombreux pays sont relativement peu touchés par la pollution de l&apos;air domestique, alors que la pollution de l&apos;air ambiant est une préoccupation majeure. En supposant une indépendance et une faible corrélation, il est possible de calculer une estimation approximative de l&apos;impact total, qui est inférieur à la somme de l&apos;impact des deux facteurs de risque.&lt;/p&gt;
			</language>
			<language lang="ru"/>
</languages>
</data>
</root>
