<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The STAT_CONC_DEF field for indicator 15-a-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a twin indicator consisting of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a) Official development assistance on conservation and sustainable use of biodiversity, defined as gross disbursements of total Official Development Assistance (ODA) from all donors for biodiversity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b) revenue generated and finance mobilised from biodiversity-relevant economic instruments, defined as revenue generated and finance mobilised from biodiversity-relevant economic instruments, covering biodiversity-relevant taxes, fees and charges, and positive subsidies. (New on-going work is underway to collect data on payments for ecosystem services and biodiversity offsets -- including the finance they mobilise for biodiversity).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a) The Development Assistance Committee (DAC) defines ODA as those flows to countries and territories on the DAC list of ODA recipients and multilateral institutions which are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provided by official agencies, including state and local governments, or by their executive agencies; and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each transaction of which:&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; is administered with the promotion of the economic development and welfare of developing countries as its main objective; and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;is concessional in character.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;(See &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;http://www.oecd.org/dac/stats/officialdevelopmentassistancedefinitionandcoverage.htm&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b) The Environmental Policy Committee (EPOC) collects data on Policy Instruments for the Environment (to the OECD PINE database), including biodiversity-relevant economic instruments. Currently more than 110 countries are contributing data. For 2020 data, see &lt;u&gt; &lt;/u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oecd.org/environment/resources/tracking-economic-instruments-and-finance-for-biodiversity-2020.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Tracking Economic Instruments and Finance for Biodiversity -2020&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
