<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root>
	<status>success</status>
	<message>The COLL_METHOD field for indicator 9-4-1, translated into en</message>
	<data>&lt;p&gt;The IEA collects energy data at the national level according to harmonised international definitions and questionnaires, as described in the UN International Recommendations for Energy Statistics available at: (&lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/energy/ires/&quot;&gt;unstats.un.org/unsd/energy/ires/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The estimates of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions from fuel combustion are calculated by the IEA based on the IEA energy data and the default methods and emission factors from the 2006 IPCC Guidelines for National GHG Inventories available at: (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipcc-nggip.iges.or.jp/public/2006gl/&quot;&gt;ipcc-nggip.iges.or.jp/public/2006gl/&lt;/a&gt;). More information on methodologies from the IEA is available at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://iea.blob.core.windows.net/assets/d755e4d6-9572-4549-9421-7d2bc377cd2f/WORLD_GHG_Documentation.pdf&quot;&gt;https://iea.blob.core.windows.net/assets/d755e4d6-9572-4549-9421-7d2bc377cd2f/WORLD_GHG_Documentation.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most recent GDP estimates published by the World Bank with reference year of 2017 have been used when calculating CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions per unit of GDP indicator. Additionally, missing years for countries with at least one data point for GDP reported by the World Bank have been estimated using National Accounts &amp;#x2013; Analysis of Main Aggregates (AMA) growth rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the calculation of the CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; emissions from manufacturing industries per unit of MVA indicator, the MVA and GDP country data are collected through a national account questionnaire (NAQ) sent by UNSD. More information on the methodology is available at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://unstats.un.org/unsd/snaama/methodology.pdf&quot;&gt;unstats.un.org/unsd/snaama/methodology.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</data>
</root>
